<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" xml:id="b3_ch1"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_b9b9u">
    <title>Why Estimate Peak Discharges?</title>

    <para>As outlined in earlier books, there are many alternative forms of
    design flood problems and hence there are many alternative flood
    characteristics requiring estimation of a design flood quantile. For many
    fluvial design flood problems (i.e. problems associated with estimating
    design flood quantiles at a riverine locationl), estimation of the
    quantile of the peak discharge is the critical flood characteristic. This
    estimation is required as part of the design process for many structures
    in rural and urban environments (for example culverts and small to medium
    bridges) and particularly so for small and medium sized catchments. In
    many of these discharge dominated design problems, an estimation of the
    full hydrograph and other flood characteristics is not necessary and hence
    only the peak characteristics of the flood hydrograph require estimation.
    Where estimation of the full flood hydrograph is required, techniques
    outlined in other sections of ARR are required in preference to the
    approaches presented in this book.</para>

    <para>Following the concepts outlined in Book 1 for estimation of design
    flood parameters, where adequate data of sufficient quality are available,
    it is recommended that an at-site Flood Frequency Analysis (FFA) be used
    for estimation of the design peak flood discharges quantiles. Details of
    suitable approaches are outlined<emphasis role="bold">
    </emphasis>in<emphasis role="bold"> </emphasis><xref
    linkend="b3_ch2"/>.</para>

    <para>For many other situations no observed data of a suitable quality for
    at-site Flood Frequency Analysis are available for estimation of the
    desired flood quantiles. It is recommended that in these situations,
    Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) techniques be applied. Details
    of suitable approaches are outlined in <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>.</para>

    <para>While a consistent methodology for Regional Flood Frequency
    Estimation for any region in Australia is outlined in <xref
    linkend="b3_ch3"/>, designers are reminded of the guidance provided in
    Book 1 Chapter 1 Section 1.1; namely, where circumstances warrant, flood
    engineers have a duty to use other procedures and data that are more
    appropriate for their design flood problem than those recommended in this
    Edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff. This guidance is particularly
    relevant where approaches have been developed for limited regions of the
    country without the aim of these approaches being suitable for application
    across the whole country or being subject to same development testing as
    the RFFE model proposed herein. An example of this situation is the
    Pilbara Region of Western Australia where independent studies by Davies
    and Yip (2014) and Flavell (2012) have developed Regional Flood Frequency
    Estimation techniques for this region.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_uqb9d">
    <title>Book Contents</title>

    <para>This book contains three chapters with the final two chapters
    dealing with alternative approaches to the estimation of the peak flood
    discharge for design purposes. Provided in the first chapter (this
    chapter) is a general introduction to the contents of this book. Following
    this introduction, at-site Flood Frequency Analysis is presented in
    Chapter 2. While these analysis techniques are applicable only to
    catchments where gauged information is available, the philosophy of Flood
    Frequency Analysis and its application underpin many of the approaches
    presented in the subsequent chapter for rural ungauged catchments. It is
    considered, therefore, to be a fundamental component of the estimation of
    peak flood quantiles.</para>

    <para>Presented in Chapter 3 is a range of regional flood methods for
    estimation of peak flood discharge quantiles in ungauged catchments. These
    techniques use the results of at-site flood frequency analyses at gauged
    sites to derive peak discharge estimation procedures for ungauged
    locations in the same hydrologic region. As the flood characteristics vary
    considerably between different regions, a range of methods (similar
    philosophical development but differing in parameter values) have been
    developed to suit the specific conditions and requirements in different
    regions.</para>

    <para>Different to previous versions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, in
    the development of this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff there
    has been an assumption that users will have computing resources available.
    The techniques presented in the following sections therefore require
    computing resources for their implementation. Therefore, the discussion in
    the following sections focusses on both the theoretical basis of the
    techniques and their implementation.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_ssfm8">
    <title>Selection of Method</title>

    <para>Following the discussion in Book 1, the primary criterion for the
    selection of the methods recommended in ARR is that the methods should be
    based on observed flood data in the region of interest and have been peer
    reviewed by the profession.</para>

    <para>In early editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, application of
    this criterion was not always possible because of the paucity of observed
    flood data technology limitations and the limited analysis of the
    available data. Hence it was necessary to recommend many arbitrary methods
    based purely on engineering judgement. The previous approaches towards
    estimation of the Rational Method runoff coefficient (“C”) for urban
    catchments is an example of this necessity. As discussed by Hicks
    <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>. (2009), the approach for
    estimation of the urban runoff coefficient presented by O’Loughlin and
    Robinson (1987) did not have a scientific foundation but was included to
    provide the necessary guidance in the application of this method.</para>

    <para>For significant portions of Australia, this is no longer the case,
    and data are available for the development of techniques that have
    undergone review by the profession from both a scientific and a practical
    perspective. In these regions, the continued use of arbitrary design
    methods and information cannot be justified.</para>

    <para>It is worthwhile noting that the continued collection of data is
    necessary to enable ongoing and continued improvements in the design
    methods, particularly in the robustness of predictions and the detection
    of inappropriate flood quantile estimates.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_2yu0i">
    <title>Scope</title>

    <para>This book has been prepared as a guide or manual, rather than a
    mandatory code of practice. Rules and methods appropriate to various
    situations are presented, together with relevant background information.
    Since catchments and the problems involved are diverse, and the related
    technology is changing, recommendations herein should not be taken as
    binding. They should be considered together with other information and
    local experience when being implemented.</para>

    <para>The contents of this book within Australian Rainfall and Runoff are
    intended for a wide readership including engineers, students, technicians,
    surveyors and planners. Readers should be familiar with the basic concepts
    of catchment hydrology and hence have a basic knowledge of hydrology and
    hydraulics.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_l5pk9">
    <title>Terminology</title>

    <para>Many terms associated with design flow estimation have been used in
    a loose manner, and sometimes quite incorrectly and in a misleading
    fashion. As outlined in Book 1, the National Committee on Water
    Engineering of Engineers Australia had three major concerns:</para>

    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
        <para>Clarity of meaning</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Technical correctness</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Practicality and acceptability</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>In view of the loose and frequently incorrect manner in which many
    terms often are used, it was considered that Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff should adopt terminology that is technically correct, as far as
    this is possible and in harmony with other objectives. Even if this
    terminology is not entirely popular with all users, it was considered that
    Engineers Australia has a responsibility to encourage and educate
    engineers regarding correct and consistent terminology. It was recognised
    also by the National Committee on Water Engineering that as well as being
    correct technically, the terms adopted should be relatively simple and
    suitable for use in practical design as this would facilitate acceptance
    by the profession.</para>

    <para>The issue of terminology is particularly relevant to the usage of
    the term model. There are many and varied usages of this term within the
    field of design flood estimation. For example, the software used for
    implementation of a particular approach commonly is called a model by
    users while others refer to the model as the encapsulation of the design
    flood estimation approach, the calculations necessary for implementation
    of the approach (usually in software but could be hand calculations) and
    the data necessary for implementation of the approach. In the following
    definitions of the terms “model”, “technique” and “approach”, the
    explanations used are suitable for the guidance contained within this
    book.</para>

    <para>While the major terminology is discussed in Book 1 of Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff, those terms pertinent only to the contents of this
    book are presented herein.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP)</emphasis></para>

    <para>Annual exceedance probability is the probability of exceedance of a
    given discharge within a period of one year. X% or 1 in Y.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Annual Maximum Series (AMS)</emphasis></para>

    <para>This is the most common method of selecting the floods to be
    analysed in Flood Frequency Analysis. The series is comprised of the
    highest instantaneous rate of discharge in each year of record. The year
    may be a calendar year or a water year, the latter usually commencing at
    the end of the period of lowest average discharge during the year. The
    highest discharge in each year is selected whether it is a major flood or
    not, and all other floods are neglected, even though some will be much
    larger than the maximum discharges selected from some other years. For N
    years of data, the annual flood series will consist of N values.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Bayesian Approach</emphasis></para>

    <para>Bayesian refers to methods in probability and statistics named after
    Thomas Bayes (c. 1702–61), in particular methods related to statistical
    inference: In particular, Bayesian inference is a method of statistical
    inference in which Bayes' rule is used to update the probability for a
    hypothesis as evidence is acquired.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Catchment Characteristics</emphasis></para>

    <para>The catchment characteristics are the physical attributes of a
    catchment which affect its response and behaviour to flood producing
    rainfall. These characteristics may provide independent variables for
    regional flood estimation (e.g. catchment area, stream slope, drainage
    density) and may vary significantly and discontinuously over a geographic
    region.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Climate Characteristics</emphasis></para>

    <para>The climate characteristics are the climate-related attributes of a
    region which act as causative or modifying factors in the generation of
    floods and which may provide independent variables for regional flood
    estimation (e.g. rainfall, evaporation). In general, these characteristics
    can be assumed to vary smoothly over a region.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Confidence Limits</emphasis></para>

    <para>Confidence limits are the lower and upper boundaries / values of a
    confidence interval, that is, the values which define the range of a
    confidence interval. A confidence interval gives an estimated range of
    values which is likely to include an unknown population parameter, the
    estimated range being calculated from a given set of sample data.
    Typically 90% confidence limits are determined (i.e. 5-95%).</para>

    <para><emphasis>Correlation </emphasis></para>

    <para>A statistical measure of the strength of the relationship
    (specifically the linear relationship) between two random variables;
    correlation between flood data at different locations in a region
    (inter-station or spatial dependence) reduces the information available
    for regional analysis.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Flood Frequency Analysis</emphasis></para>

    <para>Flood frequency analyses are used to predict design floods for
    locations along a river or creek. The technique involves using observed
    annual peak discharge data to calculate statistical information such as
    mean values, standard deviations, skewness, and recurrence intervals.
    These statistical data are used to construct statistical models relating
    the Annual Exceedance Probability of a flood characteristic with the
    magnitude of the flood characteristic.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Flood Probability Model</emphasis></para>

    <para>The flood probability model is the statistical model relating the
    Annual Exceedance Probability of a flood characteristic with the magnitude
    of the flood characteristic.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Flood Quantile</emphasis></para>

    <para>The value or magnitude of a design flood characteristic (e.g. peak
    flow, peak level, or flood volume) at a selected Annual Exceedance
    Probability.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Homogeneous Region</emphasis></para>

    <para>For the purpose of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation, a
    homogeneous region comprises of all catchments with sufficiently similar
    flood producing characteristics to allow the joint analysis of their flood
    data; such a region may be defined directly by proximity of catchments
    (geographically contiguous region) or by proximity in catchment and
    climate characteristics space.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Hydrologic Similarity</emphasis></para>

    <para>Two catchments can be considered similar with respect to hydrologic
    flood frequency characteristics if, after appropriate standardisation and
    allowing for the effects of sampling variability, their flood frequency
    distributions can be assumed to be identical.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Independent Random Values</emphasis></para>

    <para>Two random variables are independent if they convey no information
    about each other and, as a consequence, receiving information about one of
    the two does not change our assessment of the probability distribution of
    the other.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Independent Variables</emphasis></para>

    <para>The set of measurable characteristics (also referred to as
    explanatory variables) used in explanatory or predictive relationships for
    flood characteristics such as peak flow or flood volume; they include
    catchment and climate characteristics.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Index Flood Method</emphasis></para>

    <para>A Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) method in which the
    frequency curves at different stations in a homogeneous region are assumed
    to be identical after standardisation by the index variable (usually taken
    as the mean annual event); the standardised regional frequency curve is
    referred to as the regional growth curve.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Inter-station Dependence </emphasis></para>

    <para>The effect of any correlation between the flood data at different
    locations in a region; this spatial dependence reduces the information
    content of the pooled data set from stations in the region compared to a
    set of independent stations (as assumed in the Station-Year Method)</para>

    <para><emphasis>Peak Over Threshold (POT) Series </emphasis></para>

    <para>One method of analyzing extreme values is called the Peak Over
    Threshold (POT) method. To use the POT method, the dataset must be
    sufficiently large so that it would be infeasible or inaccurate to
    directly analyse. The POT method involves choosing some threshold value,
    collecting the extreme values above that threshold into a sample, and then
    drawing conclusions based on that sample. It is that sample that is
    referred to as the POT series.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Regional Flood Frequency Estimation </emphasis></para>

    <para>Methods of estimating the flood frequency characteristics for a
    location by using flood data and related information from a number of
    locations in a homogeneous region; the Regional Flood Frequency Estimation
    (RFFE) methods are a subset of these regional methods.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Regionalisation</emphasis></para>

    <para>The process of identifying homogeneous regions for the purpose of
    regional estimation, specifically Regional Flood Frequency
    Estimation.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Regional Growth Curve </emphasis></para>

    <para>The dimensionless regional flood frequency curve produced by the
    Index Method; it relates flood quantiles at different frequencies to the
    value of the index variable.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Region of Influence Approach</emphasis></para>

    <para>A method of regionalisation which defines a specific region for each
    location of interest, using a specified number of sites in the vicinity
    (also referred to as ‘nearest neighbour’ approach).</para>

    <para><emphasis>Regression Methods </emphasis></para>

    <para>Statistical methods used to define a relationship between a selected
    flood characteristic (e.g. peak flow for a given AEP) and a number of
    explanatory variables (such as climate or catchment
    characteristics).</para>

    <para><emphasis>Sampling Variability</emphasis></para>

    <para>The deviation from the true population statistics of calculated
    sample statistics (e.g. flood frequency distribution parameters); with the
    relatively small size of the flood series (samples) typically available
    for Flood Frequency Analysis, sampling variability can be a significant
    source of uncertainty in design flood estimates.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Standardisation</emphasis></para>

    <para>The process of adjusting a data series (e.g. a flood data series) by
    one or two selected statistics of the at site distribution to render it
    homogeneous and dimensionless (e.g. for the case of the Index Method by
    dividing each data point by the index variable).</para>

    <para><emphasis>Station-Year Method </emphasis></para>

    <para>A standard method of pooling data for regional analysis if the data
    from different stations in a region can be assumed to be independent; the
    total number of station years in the pooled data set is therefore simply
    the sum of the record lengths at all the individual stations (or the
    number of stations times the average length of record) .</para>

    <para><emphasis>Transposition approaches </emphasis></para>

    <para>A range of methods to estimate flood frequency characteristics at
    ungauged sites by directly transposing to the location of interest the
    results of flood frequency analyses at one or more adjacent gauged
    locations judged to be hydrologically similar.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Ungauged Locations </emphasis></para>

    <para>Locations of interest for design flood estimation that have either
    no directly observed streamflow data available in the immediate vicinity
    or only data of insufficient quality and length of record to undertake an
    at-site Flood Frequency Analysis.</para>

    <para><emphasis>Additional terms to be added.</emphasis></para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_h22wv">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Davies, JR and Yip, E, (2014), Pilbara Regional Flood Frequency
    Analysis, <emphasis>Proc. Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium</emphasis>, Perth, February 2014, Engineers Australia, pp
    182-189.</para>

    <para>Flavell, D, (2012), Design Flood Estimation in Western
    Australia,<emphasis> Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>,
    16(1):1-20.</para>

    <para>Hicks, B, Gray, S and Ball, JE, (2009), A Critical Review of the
    Urban Rational Method, <emphasis role="italic">Proceedings of H2009,
    32<superscript>nd</superscript> Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium</emphasis>, Engineers Australia, ISBN 978-08258259461.</para>

    <para>O'Loughlin, GG and Robinson, DK, (1987), <emphasis
    role="italic">Urban stormwater drainage</emphasis>, Chapter 14 in
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff - A Guide to Flood Estimation, DH Pilgrim
    editor, I.E.Aust, Barton, ACT</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, DH, (1987), Estimation of Peak Flows for Small to Medium
    Sized Rural Catchments, <emphasis role="italic">Chapter 5 in Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff </emphasis>- A Guide to Flood Estimation, pub. by
    IEAust., Barton, ACT.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
