<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" xml:id="b3_ch1"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>
      <td>3</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>
      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Draft for industry comment</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>
      <td>Draft for industry comment</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>
      <td>N/A</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>subject to final review and consistency check</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_b9b9u">
    <title>Why Estimate Peak Discharges?</title>

    <para>As outlined in earlier books, there are many alternative forms of
    design flood problems and hence there are many alternative flood
    characteristics requiring estimation of a design flood quantile. For many
    fluvial design flood problems (i.e. problems associated with estimating
    design flood quantiles at a riverine locationl), estimation of the
    quantile of the peak discharge is the critical flood characteristic. This
    estimation is required as part of the design process for many structures
    in rural and urban environments (for example culverts and small to medium
    bridges) and particularly so for small and medium sized catchments. In
    many of these discharge dominated design problems, an estimation of the
    full hydrograph and other flood characteristics is not necessary and hence
    only the peak characteristics of the flood hydrograph require estimation.
    Where estimation of the full flood hydrograph is required, techniques
    outlined in other sections of ARR are required in preference to the
    approaches presented in this book.</para>

    <para>Following the concepts outlined in <xref linkend="book1"/> for estimation of design flood
      parameters, where adequate data of sufficient quality are available, it is recommended that an
      at-site Flood Frequency Analysis (FFA) be used for estimation of the design peak flood
      discharges quantiles. Details of suitable approaches are outlined<emphasis role="bold"
        > </emphasis>in<emphasis role="bold"> </emphasis><xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>.</para>

    <para>For many other situations no observed data of a suitable quality for
    at-site Flood Frequency Analysis are available for estimation of the
    desired flood quantiles. It is recommended that in these situations,
    Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) techniques be applied. Details
    of suitable approaches are outlined in <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>.</para>

    <para>While a consistent methodology for Regional Flood Frequency Estimation for any region in
      Australia is outlined in <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>, designers are reminded of the guidance
      provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch1_s_juh46"/>; namely, where circumstances warrant, flood
      engineers have a duty to use other procedures and data that are more appropriate for their
      design flood problem than those recommended in this Edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff.
      This guidance is particularly relevant where approaches have been developed for limited
      regions of the country without the aim of these approaches being suitable for application
      across the whole country or being subject to same development testing as the RFFE model
      proposed herein. An example of this situation is the Pilbara Region of Western Australia where
      independent studies by Davies and Yip (2014) and Flavell (2012) have developed Regional Flood
      Frequency Estimation techniques for this region.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_uqb9d">
    <title>Book Contents</title>

    <para>This book contains three chapters with the final two chapters dealing with alternative
      approaches to the estimation of the peak flood discharge for design purposes. Provided in the
      first chapter (this chapter) is a general introduction to the contents of this book. Following
      this introduction, at-site Flood Frequency Analysis is presented in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>.
      While these analysis techniques are applicable only to catchments where gauged information is
      available, the philosophy of Flood Frequency Analysis and its application underpin many of the
      approaches presented in the subsequent chapter for rural ungauged catchments. It is
      considered, therefore, to be a fundamental component of the estimation of peak flood
      quantiles.</para>

    <para>Presented in <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/> is a range of regional flood methods for estimation
      of peak flood discharge quantiles in ungauged catchments. These techniques use the results of
      at-site flood frequency analyses at gauged sites to derive peak discharge estimation
      procedures for ungauged locations in the same hydrologic region. As the flood characteristics
      vary considerably between different regions, a range of methods (similar philosophical
      development but differing in parameter values) have been developed to suit the specific
      conditions and requirements in different regions.</para>

    <para>Different to previous versions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, in
    the development of this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff there
    has been an assumption that users will have computing resources available.
    The techniques presented in the following sections therefore require
    computing resources for their implementation. Therefore, the discussion in
    the following sections focusses on both the theoretical basis of the
    techniques and their implementation.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_ssfm8">
    <title>Selection of Method</title>

    <para>Following the discussion in <xref linkend="book1"/>, the primary criterion for the
      selection of the methods recommended in ARR is that the methods should be based on observed
      flood data in the region of interest and have been peer reviewed by the profession.</para>

    <para>In early editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, application of
    this criterion was not always possible because of the paucity of observed
    flood data technology limitations and the limited analysis of the
    available data. Hence it was necessary to recommend many arbitrary methods
    based purely on engineering judgement. The previous approaches towards
    estimation of the Rational Method runoff coefficient (“C”) for urban
    catchments is an example of this necessity. As discussed by Hicks
    <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>. (2009), the approach for
    estimation of the urban runoff coefficient presented by O’Loughlin and
    Robinson (1987) did not have a scientific foundation but was included to
    provide the necessary guidance in the application of this method.</para>

    <para>For significant portions of Australia, this is no longer the case,
    and data are available for the development of techniques that have
    undergone review by the profession from both a scientific and a practical
    perspective. In these regions, the continued use of arbitrary design
    methods and information cannot be justified.</para>

    <para>It is worthwhile noting that the continued collection of data is
    necessary to enable ongoing and continued improvements in the design
    methods, particularly in the robustness of predictions and the detection
    of inappropriate flood quantile estimates.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_2yu0i">
    <title>Scope</title>

    <para>This book has been prepared as a guide or manual, rather than a
    mandatory code of practice. Rules and methods appropriate to various
    situations are presented, together with relevant background information.
    Since catchments and the problems involved are diverse, and the related
    technology is changing, recommendations herein should not be taken as
    binding. They should be considered together with other information and
    local experience when being implemented.</para>

    <para>The contents of this book within Australian Rainfall and Runoff are
    intended for a wide readership including engineers, students, technicians,
    surveyors and planners. Readers should be familiar with the basic concepts
    of catchment hydrology and hence have a basic knowledge of hydrology and
    hydraulics.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_l5pk9">
    <title>Terminology</title>

    <para>Many terms associated with design flow estimation have been used in
    a loose manner, and sometimes quite incorrectly and in a misleading
    fashion. As outlined in <xref linkend="b1_ch2"/>, the National Committee
    on Water Engineering of Engineers Australia had three major
    concerns:</para>

    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
        <para>Clarity of meaning</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Technical correctness</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Practicality and acceptability</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>In view of the loose and frequently incorrect manner in which many
    terms often are used, it was considered that Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff should adopt terminology that is technically correct, as far as
    this is possible and in harmony with other objectives. Even if this
    terminology is not entirely popular with all users, it was considered that
    Engineers Australia has a responsibility to encourage and educate
    engineers regarding correct and consistent terminology. It was recognised
    also by the National Committee on Water Engineering that as well as being
    correct technically, the terms adopted should be relatively simple and
    suitable for use in practical design as this would facilitate acceptance
    by the profession.</para>

    <para>The issue of terminology is particularly relevant to the usage of
    the term model. There are many and varied usages of this term within the
    field of design flood estimation. For example, the software used for
    implementation of a particular approach commonly is called a model by
    users while others refer to the model as the encapsulation of the design
    flood estimation approach, the calculations necessary for implementation
    of the approach (usually in software but could be hand calculations) and
    the data necessary for implementation of the approach. In the following
    definitions of the terms “model”, “technique” and “approach”, the
    explanations used are suitable for the guidance contained within this
    book.</para>

    <para>While the major terminology is discussed in <xref linkend="book1"/> of Australian Rainfall
      and Runoff, those terms pertinent only to the contents of this book are presented
      herein.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch1_s_h22wv">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Davies, JR and Yip, E, (2014), Pilbara Regional Flood Frequency
    Analysis, <emphasis>Proc. Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium</emphasis>, Perth, February 2014, Engineers Australia, pp
    182-189.</para>

    <para>Flavell, D, (2012), Design Flood Estimation in Western
    Australia,<emphasis> Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>,
    16(1):1-20.</para>

    <para>Hicks, B, Gray, S and Ball, JE, (2009), A Critical Review of the
    Urban Rational Method, <emphasis role="italic">Proceedings of H2009,
    32<superscript>nd</superscript> Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium</emphasis>, Engineers Australia, ISBN 978-08258259461.</para>

    <para>O'Loughlin, GG and Robinson, DK, (1987), <emphasis
    role="italic">Urban stormwater drainage</emphasis>, Chapter 14 in
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff - A Guide to Flood Estimation, DH Pilgrim
    editor, I.E.Aust, Barton, ACT</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, DH, (1987), Estimation of Peak Flows for Small to Medium
    Sized Rural Catchments, <emphasis role="italic">Chapter 5 in Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff </emphasis>- A Guide to Flood Estimation, pub. by
    IEAust., Barton, ACT.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
