<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b3_ch1"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         status = "External Review">
         
  <info>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section>
    <title>Why Estimate Peak Flows ?</title>

    <para>As outlined in earlier books, there are many alternative forms of
    design flood problems and hence there are many alternative flood
    characteristics requiring estimation of a design flood quantile. For many
    fluvial design flood problems (i.e. problems associated with estimating
    design flood quantiles in a channel), estimation of the quantile of the
    peak flow is the critical flood characteristic. This estimation is
    required as part of the design for many structures in rural and urban
    environments (for example culverts and bridges) and particularly so for
    small and medium sized catchments. In many of these flow dominated design
    problems, an estimation of the full hydrograph is not necessary and hence
    only the peak characteristics of the flood hydrograph require estimation.
    Where estimation of the full flood hydrograph is required, techniques
    outlined in other sections of Australian Rainfall and Runoff are required
    in preference to the approaches presented in this book.</para>

    <para>Following the concepts outlined in <xref linkend="book1"/> for
    estimation of design flood parameters, where adequate data of sufficient
    quality are available, it is recommended that at-site flood frequency
    analysis be used for estimation of the design peak flood flow quantiles.
    Details of suitable approaches are outlined in <emphasis role="bold"><xref
    linkend="b3_ch2"/> </emphasis> of this book of Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff.</para>

    <para>For many other situations no observed data of a suitable quality for
    at-site flood frequency analysis are available for estimation of the
    desired flood quantiles. It is recommended that, for estimation of the
    desired design peak flood flow quantiles in these situations, Regional
    Flood Methods be applied. Details of suitable approaches are outlined in
    <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/> of this book of Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Selection of Method</title>

    <para>Following the discussion in Book I of Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff, the primary criterion for the selection of the methods recommended
    in this book of Australian Rainfall and Runoff is that the methods should
    be based on observed flood data in the region of interest and have been
    peer reviewed by the profession.</para>

    <para>In early editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, application of
    this criterion was not really possible because of the paucity of observed
    flood data and the limited analysis of the available data. Hence it was
    necessary to recommend many arbitrary methods based purely on judgement.
    The previous approaches towards estimation of the Rational Method runoff
    coefficient (“C”) for urban catchments is an example of this necessity. As
    discussed by Hicks <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>. (2009), the
    approach for estimation of the urban runoff coefficient presented by
    O’loughlin and Robinson (1987) did not have a scientific foundation but
    was included to provide the necessary guidance in the application of this
    method.</para>

    <para>For significant portions of Australia, this is no longer the case,
    and data are available for the development of techniques that have
    undergone review by the profession from both a scientific and a practical
    perspective. In these regions, the continued use of arbitrary design
    methods and information cannot be justified.</para>

    <para>It is worthwhile noting that the continued collection of data is
    necessary to enable ongoing and continued improvements in the design
    methods, particularly in the robustness of predictions and the detection
    of inappropriate flood quantile estimates.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Scope</title>

    <para>This book has been prepared as a guide or manual, rather than a
    mandatory code of practice. Rules and methods appropriate to various
    situations are presented, together with relevant background information.
    Since catchments and the problems involved are diverse, and the related
    technology is changing, recommendations herein should not be taken as
    binding. They should be considered together with other information and
    local experience when being implemented.</para>

    <para>The contents of this book within Australian Rainfall and Runoff are
    intended for a wide readership including engineers, students, technicians,
    surveyors and planners. Readers should be familiar with the basic concepts
    of catchment hydrology and hence have a basic knowledge of hydrology and
    hydraulics.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Terminology</title>

    <para>Many terms associated with design flow estimation have been used in
    a loose manner, and sometimes quite incorrectly and in a misleading
    fashion. As outlined in Book 1, the National Committee on Water
    Engineering of Engineers Australia had three major concerns:</para>

    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
        <para>Clarity of meaning</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Technical correctness</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Practicality and acceptability</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>In view of the loose and frequently incorrect manner in which many
    terms often are used, it was considered that Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff should adopt terminology that is technically correct, as far as
    this is possible and in harmony with other objectives. Even if this
    terminology is not entirely popular with all users, it was considered that
    Engineers Australia has a responsibility to encourage and educate
    engineers regarding correct and consistent terminology. It was recognised
    also by the National Committee on Water Engineering that as well as being
    correct technically, the terms adopted should be relatively simple and
    suitable for use in practical design as this would facilitate acceptance
    by the profession.</para>

    <para>While the major terminology is discussed in Book 1 of Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff, those terms pertinent only to the contents of this
    book are presented herein.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold">INCLUDE TERMS HERE AFTER CONSIDERATION OF
    OTHER BOOKS</emphasis></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Book Contents</title>

    <para>There are three chapters within this book of Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff with the final two chapters dealing with alternative approaches to
    the estimation of the peak flood flow for design purposes. Firstly,
    at-site flood frequency analysis is presented in Chapter 2. While these
    analysis techniques are applicable only to catchments where gauged
    information is available, the philosophy of flood frequency analysis and
    its application underpin many of the approaches presented in the
    subsequent chapter for ungauged catchments. It is considered, therefore,
    to be a fundamental component of the estimation of peak flood
    quantiles.</para>

    <para>Presented in Chapter 3 is a range of regional flood methods for
    estimation of peak flood flow quantiles in ungauged catchments. These
    techniques use the results of at-site flood frequency analyses at gauged
    sites to derive peak flow estimation procedures for ungauged sites in the
    same hydrologic region. As the flood characteristics vary considerably
    between different regions, a range of methods (similar philosophical
    development but differing in parameters) have been developed to suit the
    specific conditions and requirements in different regions.</para>

    <para>Different to previous versions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, in
    the development of this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff there
    has been an assumption that users will have computing resources available.
    The techniques presented in the following sections therefore require
    computing resources for their implementation. Therefore, the discussion in
    the following sections focusses on both the theoretical basis of the
    techniques and their implementation.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Hicks, B, Gray, S and Ball, JE, (2009), A Critical Review of the
    Urban Rational Method, <emphasis role="italic">Proceedings of H2009,
    32<superscript>nd</superscript> Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium</emphasis>, Engineers Australia, ISBN 978-08258259461.</para>

    <para>O'Loughlin, GG and Robinson, DK, (1987), <emphasis
    role="italic">Urban stormwater drainage</emphasis>, Chapter 14 in
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff - A Guide to Flood Estimation, DH Pilgrim
    editor, I.E.Aust, Barton, ACT</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, DH, (1987), Estimation of Peak Flows for Small to Medium
    Sized Rural Catchments, <emphasis role="italic">Chapter 5 in Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff </emphasis>- A Guide to Flood Estimation, pub. by
    IEAust., Barton, ACT.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
