<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b1_ch5"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Risk Based Design</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/mcluckie_duncan.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_mhyfy">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Floods can cause significant impacts where they interact with the
    community and the supporting natural and built environment. However,
    flooding also has the potential to be the most manageable natural disaster
    as the likelihood and consequences of the full range of flood events can
    be understood enabling risks to be assessed and where necessary
    managed.</para>

    <para>Design flood estimation plays a key role in understanding flood
    behaviour and how this may change with alterations within the floodplain
    and catchment. It can provide essential information on a range of key
    factors that need to be considered in understanding the consequences of a
    flood and in managing these consequences. These include: flood frequency;
    flow rates, velocities and volumes; flood levels and extents; duration of
    inundation. ARR provides essential analytical tools to assist in
    estimating design floods and in understanding these factors. Books XXXX
    provide relevant information on design flood estimation. Estimates of
    design floods are an essential element in understanding flood behaviour
    and making informed decisions on:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Managing flood risk through a risk based decision making process
        (AEM 2013). Such approaches generally provide an understanding of
        flood behaviour across the full range of flood events, up to and
        including extreme events, such as the probable maximum flood. They can
        inform decision making in flood risk management, strategic and
        development scale land use planning, emergency response for floods and
        dam failure, and in estimating flood insurance premiums.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Managing flood risk through the use of design standards related
        to the probability or frequency of occurrence, rather than the broader
        assessment and management of risk.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Setting infrastructure performance criteria based upon a design
        standard, generally a probability or frequency of event, rather than
        the broader assessment and management of risk.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Managing flood risk in short term projects through a risk based
        decision making process considering the life of a project.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Understanding and managing the impacts changes within the
        catchment and floodplain may have on flood behaviour.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>This chapter provides advice and examples on using the analytical
    tools outlined in ARR to inform decision making for flood risk management,
    road and rail design, mining and agriculture and design of dams. It does
    not provide details on the design standards, risk assessment frameworks,
    the assessment of impacts on the community or built or natural
    environment, nor to estimate residual risks. Further information on risk
    management approaches, processes and frameworks can be found in
    <emphasis>AEM 2013, ANCOLD (2003) and ISO31000 (2009a). </emphasis></para>

    <para>The remainder of this chapter is structured as follows:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_cx2jp"/> provides a background on flood
        risk.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_xbbpb"/> discusses risk analysis.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_259ky"/> discusses managing risk.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu"/> discusses managing flood risk
        to communities.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_zha4n"/> discusses managing flood risk
        for mining, agriculture and infrastructure projects.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_23w6l"/> discusses the management of
        flood risk for dams</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_ih60o"/> discusses the management of
        flood risk using basins.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_la4hv"/> provides references and further
        reading material.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_cx2jp">
    <title>Flood Risk</title>

    <para>Flood risk results from the interaction of the community, through
    human occupation or use of the floodplain, with hazardous flood behaviour.
    It is the risk of flooding to people, their social or community setting,
    and the built and natural environment AEM (2013).</para>

    <para>Risk is not simply the probability of an event occurring.
    <emphasis>International Standard on Risk Management,</emphasis>
    ISO31000:2009 (ISO 2009a) defines risk as the effect of uncertainty on
    objectives. In addition, <emphasis>ISO Guide 73:2009 Risk Management
    Vocabulary </emphasis>(ISO 2009b) notes that uncertainty is the state,
    even partial, of deficiency of information related to, understanding or
    knowledge of an event, its consequence, or likelihood. An effect is a
    positive or negative deviation from the expected outcome. Objectives can
    have different aspects (financial, health and safety, environmental) and
    apply at different levels.</para>

    <para>AEM (2013) and ANCOLD (2003) express risk in terms of combinations
    of the likelihood of events (generally measured in terms of AEP) and the
    severity of their consequences of the event (see <xref
    linkend="b1_ch5_f_4qcm8"/>). Risk is higher the more frequently an area is
    exposed to the same consequence or when the same frequency of event has
    higher consequences.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_4qcm8">
      <title>Components of Flood Risk (After McLuckie (2012)</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1015.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para><emphasis>AEM (2013)</emphasis> discusses the consequences of
    flooding on the community. The consequences depend upon the vulnerability
    of the community and the built environment to flooding. Vulnerability
    varies with the element at risk, and between and within the cohorts within
    the elements. <emphasis>AEM (2015)</emphasis> advises that this may be
    measured in terms of the impacts upon:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>People – in terms of fatalities and injuries.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The economy and assets - in terms of reduced economic activity
        and asset losses.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The social setting – in terms of consequences to the community
        as a whole (rather than individuals) that can lead to the breakdown of
        community organisations and structures. This can include the temporary
        or permanent loss of community facilities or culturally important
        objects or events.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Public administration – in terms of changes to the ability of
        the governing body for the community to be able to deliver core
        functions.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The environment – in terms of destruction and degradation of
        critical environmental assets (and their processes and structures)
        and/or species extinction and habitat range reduction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The consequence to different elements from the same exposure to
    flooding can be different. For example, a flood may have major
    consequences for community assets (such as a water or sewerage treatment
    plant) but have only minor or moderate consequences in terms of potential
    fatalities and injuries in the population.</para>

    <para>The likelihood of exposure to flooding and therefore flood risk
    varies significantly between and within floodplains and flood events of
    different magnitudes. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0lntn"/> shows areas exposed
    to flooding of different AEP events.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_0lntn">
      <title>Map showing different AEP flood extents including an extreme
      event</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/placeholder.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_xbbpb">
    <title>Risk Analysis</title>

    <para>Risk analysis is a systematic approach to understanding the nature
    of and deducing the level of risk. It involves developing an understanding
    of the nature, driver for, and level of risk to rank the relative
    seriousness of risks. It is one of the steps in the risk management
    process (ISO 2009a) and is generally undertaken as part of a floodplain
    management study in the flood risk management framework <emphasis>(AEM
    2013).</emphasis></para>

    <para>Risk analysis involves understanding the varying likelihood of
    events (that result in a risk), and the severity of their consequences. It
    should also involve an assessment of confidence, which considers factors
    such as the divergence of opinion, level of expertise, uncertainty,
    quality, quantity and relevance of data. These factors are combined to
    assign a relative risk rating for an event through development of a risk
    matrix or other tools.</para>

    <para>Risk analysis may be quantitative or qualitative. In both cases the
    probability of events affecting communities may be able to be estimated
    through design flood estimates.</para>

    <para>Quantitative analysis is often used where both the probability and
    the consequences can be measured. For example, consequences may be
    estimated in terms of tangible flood damage to the community for different
    AEP events. Tangible damages are those damages that are more readily able
    to be estimated in economic terms and lend themselves to quantitative
    assessment. They typically include:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Direct damages to structures and their contents due to water
        contact.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Indirect damages of clean-up of debris and removal of damaged
        material, loss of wages, sales, production and costs of alternative
        accommodation, and opportunity costs due to loss of services.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Qualitative estimates are generally undertaken where consequences cannot be quantitatively
      measured. For example, these can include social and environmental impacts and the costs of
      fatalities and injuries which are intangible damages that cannot readily be put in economic
      terms. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_t_5ke0w"/> provides an example of a qualitative risk
      matrix.<table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch5_t_5ke0w">
        <caption>Example Qualitative Risk Matrix</caption>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th colspan="6">Consequence level</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Likelihood level</td>
            <td>Insignificant</td>
            <td>Minor</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Major</td>
            <td>Catastrophic</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Almost certain</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Likely</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Unlikely</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Rare</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Very Rare</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Extremely Rare</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
            <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table></para>

    <para>Risk analysis can be used to inform decisions on both the
    acceptability of residual risk and the effective and efficient use of
    scare resources to better understand and treat risk.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_259ky">
    <title>Managing Flood Risk</title>

    <para>Managing flood risk generally involves a combination of: managing
    changes within the floodplain that may alter flood behaviour; and altering
    the likelihood (how frequently exposure to flooding occurs) and the
    consequences of flooding (reducing vulnerability to flooding when exposed)
    to reduce the risks. Managing risk needs to consider the different
    elements at risk which may require different management techniques and
    standards. It also needs to consider the risks to the existing community
    and built and natural environment and the additional risk generated by
    introducing new development and infrastructure into the floodplain</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_u4hj4">
      <title>Managing changes to flood behaviour</title>

      <para>Changes within the floodplain that can significantly affect flood
      behaviour include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Development (including filling) within the floodplain
          (particularly in floodways and flood storage areas).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Development within the catchment even though outside the
          floodplain.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Construction or upgrade of above ground infrastructure across
          waterways and the floodplain.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Alterations to flood behaviour that may, depending upon the
      circumstances, be significant can include changes to flow paths, peak
      flow rates and velocities, flood levels and extents, distribution of
      flood waters, and the timing and duration of flooding. These changes can
      lead to adverse impacts on existing community and the built and natural
      environment.</para>

      <para>To limit impacts new projects generally have constraints relating
      to negating or minimising adverse impacts of the project on existing
      development and the environment, including from flooding.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_t5swv">
      <title>Managing flood risk by limiting likelihood and
      consequences</title>

      <para>Approaches to managing the likelihood or consequences of flood
      risk on or to a community or asset generally fall into the following
      types:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use of design standards that relate to a particular flood
          event.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Providing a certain level of service.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Use of risk based management approaches.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Use of design flood and level of service standards are generally
      less complex than risk based management approaches.</para>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_8pae4">
        <title>Design Flood Standards</title>

        <para>Design flood standards are generally aimed at limiting the
        frequency of exposure to flood risk. For example the use of a minimum
        floor levels for a building relative to a design flood level aims to
        reduce the exposure to flooding by excluding flooding from above the
        floor of the building in the design event. This approach is based upon
        accepting that the building will flood in flood events larger than the
        design flood event and the associated consequences.</para>

        <para>This approach makes the assumption that the location is suitable
        for the development. That is: the development will not impact upon
        flood behaviour and therefore have adverse impact elsewhere in the
        community; and the impacts of flooding on the building and its
        occupants, including the associated residual risks, are acceptable or
        can be managed by other means. This can limit the effectiveness of
        this approach, particularly where it is used in isolation, and may
        lead to decisions that leave individuals, communities and the built
        environment exposed to risks that may be considered unacceptable to
        the community.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_rz5ar">
        <title>Level of Service Standards</title>

        <para>Level of service standards are generally aimed at maintaining
        the availability of a service during an event of a particular scale.
        For example, having a road trafficable in a design flood event of a
        certain annual exceedance probability or having a waterway structure
        under the road pass the peak of a design flood without overtopping the
        road. This approach assumes that the:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Road will not impact upon flood behaviour and have adverse
            impact on the community.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Impacts of flooding on the road are acceptable or can be
            managed by other means. For example, the road is expected to
            overtop and the design allows for damage minimisation or
            replacement in such events.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Level of service provided is acceptable. For example, loss
            of access along the road is expected during a flood event and this
            is considered in emergency management planning.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Residual risk remaining is acceptable.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>This can limit the effectiveness of this approach, particularly
        where it is used in isolation.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_mfr1i">
        <title>Risk based decision making processes</title>

        <para>Risk based decision making processes (such as outlined in
        <emphasis>AEM 2013</emphasis>) are used to develop management
        strategies that consider the risks associated with a full range of
        potential flood events and the associated consequences to the
        community and its supporting built and natural environment. These
        techniques have been increasingly used to manage dam safety risks
        (<emphasis>ANCOLD, 2003</emphasis>).</para>

        <para>The approach can be used in a manner that is complementary to
        the use of design flood and levels of service standards by examining
        the residual risk to the community and examining whether additional
        risk management measures may be necessary.</para>

        <para>For example, in a particular instance the use a design flood for
        a standard for development within a community may reduce the frequency
        of exposure of people and property to flooding. However, due to the
        limitations of flood warnings or the flooding of evacuation routes in
        larger flood events, the risk to people in the community may remain
        high. Additional management measures such as those outlined below may
        need to be considered:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Development or improvement of a flood warning system so the
            community can be advised of the flood event and have more time to
            respond to calls for evacuation.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Upgrade of evacuation routes to improve traffic capacity to
            enable the community to be effectively evacuated within the
            available warning time.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Risk based decision making processes can also be used to examine
        risk management decisions for projects with a relatively short time
        frame, such as construction projects.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks to Communities</title>

    <para>Flooding has the potential to be the most manageable natural
    disaster as the location of flood impacts and its effect upon the
    community and the built and natural environment can be understood for the
    full range of events.</para>

    <para>Best practice in flood risk management in Australia (<emphasis>AEM
    2013</emphasis>) works towards the vision: <emphasis>Floodplains are
    strategically managed for the sustainable long-term benefit of the
    community and the environment, and to improve community resilience to
    floods.</emphasis> Best practice promotes the consideration and, where
    necessary, management of flood impacts to existing and future development
    to improve community flood resilience using a broad risk management
    hierarchy of avoidance, minimisation and mitigation to: reduce the health,
    social and financial costs of occupying the floodplain; increase the
    sustainable benefits of using the floodplain, and improve or maintain
    floodplain ecosystems dependent on flood inundation (AEM 2013).</para>

    <para>Managing flood risk provides an informed basis for the effective and
    efficient use of scare resources to:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Better understand flood risk.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Manage the growth in flood risk to the community due to the
        introduction of new development into the floodplain.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Reduce risks to the existing community where warranted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>This enables investment to be focused on understanding and managing
    flood risk where the need and benefit is greatest.</para>

    <para>Different treatment solutions may be necessary depending upon the
    element at risk (people, property and infrastructure) and the location.
    Treatment options may involve a combination of flood mitigation, emergency
    management, flood warning and community awareness, together with strategic
    and development scale land-use planning arrangements that consider the
    flood situation and hazards.</para>

    <para>Different options are also used dependent upon whether it aims to
    manage risk to existing or future development within the community.</para>

    <para>For risk to existing development it is important to understand the
    current exposure of the community to flooding and how the risks to
    different elements within the community are currently being managed and
    whether changes would be required to reduce risks to a more acceptable
    level. Where treatment measures to reduce risks are being considered the
    impacts these measures may have on flood behaviour need to be understood
    and considered in decision making.</para>

    <para>For risk to future development it is important to understand how the
    flood behaviour varies across the floodplain so that the constraints that
    this may place on development can be considered in deciding where to
    develop (and where not to develop), the types of development that may be
    suitable in different areas, and the flood related development constraints
    necessary to reduce risks to acceptable levels (in areas suitable for
    development).</para>

    <para>More information on understanding and managing flood risk is
    available in AEM (2013).</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_va2dn">
      <title>Using Design Flood Estimation to Inform Flood Risk
      Management</title>

      <para>Design flood estimation can support management of flood risk to
      the community by improving knowledge of the potential range of flood
      behaviour and providing tools and information to support decision
      making. The selection of a modelling approach needs to consider the
      capability the approach provides relative to the requirements of the
      project specification. Many management decisions, such as emergency
      management planning, rely upon an understanding of the full range of
      flood behaviour rather than a specific design event, and need
      information across of the whole event rather than just the peak of the
      event. Managing flood risk involves a range of different groups with
      different information needs (AEMI (2013) and AEMI (2014c)).</para>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_5meee">
        <title>Analysis of Historic Flood Events</title>

        <para>Managing flood risk to the community generally requires more
        knowledge than can be gained from historic flood events. The
        information available on historic events is generally incomplete and
        is unlikely to represent the full range of potential events. In
        addition, it is likely that there have been changes within the
        floodplain or catchment since the historic flood occurred that would
        alter the behaviour or impacts of a flood of the same magnitude if it
        were to occur today.</para>

        <para>The use of historic information in isolation without an
        understanding of the potential range and severity of flood events at a
        location and an understanding of how this may vary within a floodplain
        can result in poor management decisions – leaving the community
        unsustainably exposed to risk.</para>

        <para>Knowledge and experience of historic flood events provides a
        starting point for understanding flood risk. Modelling historic events
        can assist to:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Calibrate and validate models against known data and the
            community’s experience of flooding.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Better understand historic events by filling in gaps in our
            knowledge of flood behaviour and its variation along a watercourse
            and across the floodplain.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Understand the probability of floods of the scale of
            historic floods being exceeded in future.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The consequences of historic events can also provide valuable
        information for understanding flood risk. An appropriately calibrated
        and validated model can provide a sound basis for updating of the
        model to current conditions in light of changes in the catchment and
        floodplain since historic events.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_9ffsp">
        <title>Analysis of Design Flood Estimates</title>

        <para>Information from historic flood events can be improved using
        investigative techniques and more sophisticated modelling to increase
        understanding of these events, facilitate extrapolation to provide a
        greater understanding of the full range of flood behaviour and risk,
        and enable assessment of treatment options to inform management
        decisions.</para>

        <para>Design flood estimates can be used for a range of purposes
        including:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Understanding flood behaviour (flow paths, distribution,
            velocity, depth, level, timing and length of inundation) and risk
            and how this varies across the floodplain, over the duration of a
            flood event, and between flood events of different
            magnitudes.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Understanding how flood behaviour, hazards and risks may
            change due to floodplain, catchment and climate changes.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Establishing design standards based upon a specific design
            event.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Assessing whether desired levels of service are met.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Making decisions on the need for risk treatment, comparing
            and assessing treatment options, and deciding on which options to
            implement.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Designing waterway structures, basins, levees and other
            mitigation measures.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Design flood estimation for the full range of flood behaviour
        provides the basis for assessing the frequency and severity of flood
        exposure of different parts of the floodplain and the consequences of
        flooding to the community. This can provide a spatial understanding
        of:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Flood extents to understand where floods of different
            magnitudes will impact.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The variation in the flood functions of flow conveyance and
            storage within the floodplain for key events. Areas with these
            functions are generally areas where change in topography,
            vegetation or development can significantly alter flood behaviour
            which may lead to detrimental impacts to the existing
            community.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The variation in hazard across the floodplain for key flood
            events. This can delineate where flood behaviour in events is
            hazardous to people, vehicles and buildings (AEM 2014b).</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The variation in flood evacuation difficulty from areas
            within the floodplain (AEM 2014a).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Information from design flood estimation and flood risk
        management can inform government and industry databases and associated
        information systems. This can improve the accessibility of information
        on flood risk so it can be considered in investment and management
        decisions by government, industry and the community.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_fd8ui">
      <title>Using Design Flood Estimation to Support Management of Future
      Development</title>

      <para>Risk to future development is primarily managed by incorporating
      consideration of flood risk and the associated constraints (<xref
      linkend="b1_ch5_s_va2dn"/>) into strategic planning and the relevant
      land use planning system.</para>

      <para>Land use planning systems often use a flood standard as a basis
      for many flood related controls and decisions. However, they may also
      require consideration of larger flood events to examine whether
      additional development constraints are necessary to deal with residual
      risks to the new development, particularly risk to life.</para>

      <para>As new development on the floodplain can impact upon flood
      behaviour and the flood risk faced by the existing community, land use
      planning systems generally require these impacts to be assessed and
      managed.</para>

      <para>Developing on the floodplain also places the new development and
      its occupants at risk from flooding. These issues need to be considered
      in setting strategic directions for the community and determining
      development constraints.</para>

      <para>Design flood estimation provides essential information for
      understanding constraints (see <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_va2dn"/>) that
      need consideration in setting strategic land use planning directions for
      the community. These can provide:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Information to inform decisions on where to (and where not to)
          develop and the limitations on what type of development to place in
          different areas of the floodplain. For example, development within a
          floodway may have significant impacts upon flood behaviour or cause
          significant damage to structures that adversely impacts upon the
          existing community. Development in this area should be restricted to
          enable the floodway to perform its natural flood function. A further
          example, such as an area with evacuation issues that is classified
          as flooded, isolated and submerged (AEM 2014b) would not necessarily
          be an appropriate area for a development that is difficult to
          evacuate.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The assessment of the cumulative impacts of development within
          the catchment and floodplain on flood flows, and behaviour. For
          example, the assessment of the cumulative impacts of development of
          the catchment can enable the examination of catchment scale
          solutions to offset the impacts of development on flood flows in an
          efficient manner. Such solutions may include a single of series of
          basins whose interaction is considered (see <xref
          linkend="b1_ch5_s_ih60o"/>).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Development constraints that reduce the residual flood risk to
          the new development and its occupants to an acceptable level.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Design flood estimation also provides essential information to
      inform consideration of individual development proposals through the
      planning system. Studies undertaken for specific developments generally
      aim to assess whether the development will have significant impacts upon
      existing flood behaviour and the flood risk of the existing community
      and the impacts of flooding on the proposed development site and the
      residual risks to the development and its occupants.</para>

      <para>This can provide advice on the:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Suitability of the specific location for development.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Suitability of the proposed development for the
          location.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Limits on the scale of development to limit impacts on the
          existing community.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Development conditions necessary to manage residual risk to
          the new development and its occupants any impacts upon the existing
          community.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Site specific studies do not generally provide advice for setting
      strategic land use direction of the community.</para>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_5mgkf">
        <title>How Can More Information Aid in Decision Making?</title>

        <para>Having more information on flood behaviour and on flood related
        constraints can support informed decision making. The example provided
        below in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t"/> and <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/> provides an example of how additional
        information on flood behaviour and factors that influence risks to
        people and property can provide a better understanding of flood
        constraints so these can be considered in investment and development
        decisions.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t"/> shows the area affected by the
        design AEP flood event used to set design standards for developments
        in the area shown. It does not provide any breakdown of the floodplain
        to highlight the varying flood function within this area, the varying
        degrees of hazard; or the differences in emergency response
        classification within the floodplain. Nor does it provide information
        on more frequent or more extreme floods. It therefore provides limited
        information for effective management.</para>

        <para>Using this information for controlling development alone
        locations A, B, C and D appear to be exposed to the same degree of
        risk and given the information available would, most likely, result in
        the same development conditions being applied to each location.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t">
          <title>Map showing flood extents only</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/placeholder.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>However, <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_uoebi"/> shows the same floodplain but with
        information on how flood hazard, flood function and the flood
        emergency response classification varies across the floodplain. With
        this information the flood situations impacting upon Locations A to D
        can be seen to be different and require different management
        treatments.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Location A is easy to evacuate and outside the impacts of
            flood function and flood conditions are not hazardous to
            buildings.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Location B is in a floodway and development may impact upon
            flood behaviour and the flood risk of others in the
            community.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Location C is isolated and completed inundated by larger
            floods and has a more difficult flood evacuation situation.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Location D is similar to Location A but is an area where
            floods may be hazardous to houses and people.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>To effectively manage these additional risk factors need to be
        considered in setting development constraints. Mapping the constraints
        from <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_uoebi"/> can provide more clarity on where to apply
        different development controls as shown in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_6usjz">
          <title>Map showing flood extents and flood function</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/placeholder.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_iz3yu">
          <title>Map showing flood extents and flood hazard</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/placeholder.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_uoebi">
          <title>Map showing flood extents and flood emergency response
          classification</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/placeholder.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_0orhn">
          <title>Map showing variation in constraints across the
          floodplain</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/placeholder.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The additional information provided in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to<xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/>
        identifies additional risk factors in different locations. Without
        this information:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The need to consider these additional risk factors in
            decision making may not be evident.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Where it has otherwise been recognised that these additional
            risk factors may need to be considered in decision making it is
            likely that any associated constraints would be applied broadly
            across the floodplain. This would require studies for individual
            developments to determine and address these risk factors.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The additional information provided in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to<xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/> has the
        added benefit of providing improved clarity for development conditions
        by enabling these to be more effectively included in land use planning
        systems.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_vdya6">
      <title>Understanding and Treating Risk to the Existing Community</title>

      <para>In some cases the consequences of flooding and the associated
      risks may warrant changes to the existing treatment of flood risk in a
      community to reduce the residual risks to a more acceptable level. In
      other cases existing treatment of risk may be considered adequate for
      this purpose.</para>

      <para>Design flood estimation can provide the understanding of flood
      behaviour, and the drivers for this behaviour, across a range of flood
      events to support management of the flood risk. It can be used with
      other information to:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Assess the consequences of flooding on the community and the
          natural and built environment. One quantitative measure of
          consequences is the estimation of flood damages. This section
          provides an example of the use of flood damage estimation in flood
          risk management.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Assess the impacts of floods on community infrastructure such
          as electricity, water supply, the sewerage system, medical
          facilities and emergency management infrastructure (evacuation
          routes and centres), and provide information to consider in recovery
          planning for the community.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Examine the effectiveness of treatment options to reduce this
          risk where warranted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_jhh3n">
        <title>Estimation of the Current Risk to a Community</title>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d"/> provides an example of a
        graphical representation of the variation of risk to the different
        elements (people, community, property) at risk over the full range of
        flood behaviour for a particular floodplain. This can involve both
        qualitative and quantitative estimates of consequences for different
        flood events to determine risk levels using the example risk matrix
        provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_t_5ke0w"/>.</para>

        <para>In this example, for events more frequent than a 10% AEP event
        the consequences to people, and the community are insignificant and
        therefore risks are low. However, the consequences for property are
        minor and therefore risk is medium. Consequences to people are major
        for floods less frequent than the 10% AEP flood event. Consequences to
        property rise to major in unlikely, rare, very rare events and
        extremely rare floods. Impacts upon the community and its supporting
        infrastructure are moderate for events greater than the 10% AEP and do
        not reach major levels.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d">
          <title>Example of Estimated Average Risk to a Community Due to
          Flooding</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1022.PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d"/> shows the risks to people and
        property for events between a 10% and 0.01% AEP event. The risk to the
        community is low except in floods between a 10% and 0.1% event where
        they are medium.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_vh7ar">
        <title>Estimating Flood Damages to an Existing Community</title>

        <para>One of the ways to quantitatively assess impacts upon the
        community is to estimate flood damages. This generally involves an
        aggregation of estimates of flood damages on individual properties
        considering both direct costs (damages to structures and their
        content) and indirect costs (such as clean-up and disposal or
        materials, loss of earnings, sales and production, temporary
        relocation expenses) and an allowance for or estimate of
        infrastructure damages. A range of methods are used to derive damages
        for individual properties. These include:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Rapid assessment techniques which rely on flood extents to
            determine the number of properties of different development types
            (residential, commercial and industrial) affected and apply a
            fixed damage per property.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Techniques based upon the use of stage damage curves for
            different development types and in some cases styles and sizes of
            buildings (an example for residential buildings derived from DECC
            (2007) is provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_u3eyu"/>). This
            technique provides for variation in damage to structures and yards
            and their contents with depth above ground level and structure
            floor level. Approaches, such as this allow for the use of
            representative buildings within the floodplain. Whereas other
            approaches may require the style and size of houses to be
            determined and individual buildings to be considered in more
            detail.</para>

            <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_u3eyu">
              <title>Indicative Stage Damage Curve for some Residential House
              Types</title>

              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1023.png"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </figure>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para><emphasis>Note: There are many different stage damage curve
        relationships for residential development. Different damage
        relationships also exist for different types of development (e.g.
        commercial, and industrial). These may be determined based upon the
        use of historical damage or insured loss information or based upon
        building component damage at different depths. However, no definitive
        set of curves exist and work in this area continues to evolve.
        Commercial and industrial can be very complex given the changing
        nature of the occupation of individual sites. The damage to the
        structure of the building will not generally change significantly with
        use but the contents damage can vary significantly. For example, the
        same light industrial storage area could house aluminum cans for
        recycling or computer components for assembly and therefore the
        damages to contents due to flooding would vary greatly.
        </emphasis></para>

        <para>Assessment based upon stage damage curves needs information on
        flood extents to determine which properties are affected and
        information on flood levels. This information can be used with
        location and ground and structure floor level information (determined
        using survey or approximation methods) to estimate damages at an
        individual site. These can then be aggregated to estimate damages to a
        community or area.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc"/> provides an example of an
        aggregated flood damage curve across the full range of flood events
        for a community. This provides a quantitative understanding of the
        impacts of flooding upon the community and the built environment. It
        can also provide a baseline for considering the benefits of management
        options. Each point on the flood damage curve has a probability of
        exceedance in any given year. Examining this curve shows that there is
        no damage in a 20% AEP event with damage in the 0.5% event being
        approximately $20million.</para>

        <para>To use this information for flood risk management, particularly
        when examining the benefits of management measures, this information
        needs to be translated into an annual average damage. This is achieved
        by determining the area under the curve. <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/> provides an example of calculation of
        annual average damages based upon the flood damage curve in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc"/>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc">
          <title>Example of Flood Damage for a Range of AEP Flood
          Events</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1024.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_58cna">
        <title>Assessing Options to Treat Flood Risk</title>

        <para>Where treatment measures are proposed that may change flood
        behaviour the calibrated and validated models that define the existing
        flood situation need to be altered to incorporate proposed treatment
        measures and design flood estimates developed for the changed
        conditions.</para>

        <para>Comparing this information to the existing flood situation can
        indicate changes in flood behaviour, and in combination with other
        information, changes in the consequences of flooding on the community.
        Flood extents, flood function, flood hazard and emergency response
        classification and damages may alter for specific areas and different
        design events. Where changes in behaviour are significant there are
        likely to be areas where flood impacts are reduced and other areas
        where they may be increased. These changes in consequence can be used
        to assess the benefits and costs to the community and the limitations
        of the treatment measure.</para>

        <para>Section 9.4 and Table 9.3 of <emphasis>AEM (2013)</emphasis>
        outline some of the issues that should be considered when selecting
        and comparing treatment options. The benefits and costs of treatment
        options may be assessed singularly as well as in combination with
        complimentary measures as it is rare for a single treatment option
        used in isolation to effectively manage flood risk to a community. For
        example, a levee may be built to reduce flood damage in a town in
        combination with a flood warning system to provide additional warning
        and upgraded evacuation routes to improve community safety during
        floods.</para>

        <para>One quantitative way of determining the financial efficiency of
        the project involves understanding the benefits in reduction in flood
        damages and comparing this to the costs of achieving and maintaining
        this benefit. Reduction in flood damages can be assessed by
        determining the reduction in annual average damages and exposure of
        the community to flooding with treatment measures in place. For
        example the use of minimum floor levels based upon the 1% AEP flood
        for new development, or a levee designed to exclude a 1% AEP flood
        from an existing flood affected area will reduce flood damages for
        events up to but not exceeding the design flood event (in this case 1%
        AEP event). However, the consequences of floods rarer than the design
        floods may not change significantly and there may still be substantial
        impacts upon the community.</para>

        <para>Annual average damages calculated across the full range of flood
        events provides a sound basis for understanding the financial benefits
        and limitations of the project so this can be considered in decision
        making and enables the calculation of annual average benefits.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_hkk27"/> provides an example of the
        estimation of the financial benefits of a treatment measure. It shows
        the damage curve for the same flood situation as shown in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc"/> but both without any treatment and with a
        treatment measure in place.</para>

        <para>In this example the treatment measure is a levee. The aim of the
        levee is to reduce flood damages and the frequency of community
        exposure to flooding and associated risks for events up to the design
        event, in this case the 1% AEP flood. Whilst there are some benefits
        for rarer floods these can be seen to diminish quickly in rarer
        events. In a 0.2% AEP flood the damages with and without the treatment
        measures would be the same.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_hkk27">
          <title>Example of Flood Damage With and Without Treatment Options
          for a Range of AEP Flood Events</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1025.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The reduction in average annual damages (AAD) or the average
        annual benefit (AAB) can be used to determine the net present value of
        the benefits. An example is provided in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_s_13ov6"/>.</para>

        <para>This can then be compared with the net present value (NPV) of
        life cycle costs of the treatment measure to determine the benefit
        cost ratio, which provides a measure of the financial efficiency of
        the project.<xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_4u178"/> provides an example of
        estimation of net present value of life cycle costs.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5"/> provides an example of
        estimation of the benefit cost ratio. Lifecycle costs and lifecycle
        benefits for individual years are shown in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_g9f34"/>. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_dvpu3"/> shows the
        same figures altered under current day dollars assuming a 7% discount
        rate.</para>

        <para>The benefit cost ratio calculated can be used in conjunction
        with consideration of other benefits, such as reduction in risk to
        life, reduction in the impacts upon community function and
        infrastructure and with similar information for other treatment
        options (including those providing protection for different AEP
        floods) to inform decisions on managing risk.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_g9f34">
          <title>Example of Annual Life Cycle Benefits and Costs</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1026.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_dvpu3">
          <title>Example of Life Cycle Benefits and Costs Adjusted to Todays $
          Using a 7% Discount Rate</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1027.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_fkw4r"/> re-examines the risks
        identified in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d"/> to highlight how these
        have changed through the implementation of treatment measures to
        provide protection for the 1% AEP design event. This example shows a
        reduction in risk to property from a maximum of high to a maximum of
        medium in events above a 1% AEP flood but low in events less than the
        design event.</para>

        <para>However, risk to people is still high due to the impacts of
        events greater than the 1% AEP event. This may warrant additional
        treatment measures being considered which, depending upon why this
        risk remains high, may include flood warning systems, improved
        emergency management planning and improvements to evacuation
        routes.</para>

        <para>Note there is no change to the risks in extremely rare events.
        The risk to property has been reduced in rare events due to the
        reduction in damages due to risk management measures.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_fkw4r">
          <title>Example of Estimating Changing Average Risk to a Community
          Due to Flooding with Instigation of a Treatment Option</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1028.PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_zha4n">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks to Mining, Agricultural and Infrastructure
    Projects</title>

    <para>As well as flood risks for communities, there are other types of
    development with flood risks that require management. These include mining
    and agriculture as well as other infrastructure, particularly linear above
    ground infrastructure such as road and rail embankments and levees. Where
    located in the floodplain, these developments are:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Susceptible to flood risk.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>May impact upon flood behaviour with detrimental impact to
        others in the community.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>While the issues are similar, short term projects have a different
    risk profile and may be managed somewhat differently. For example, these
    include infrastructure such as mining developments with a short design
    life or temporary road side tracks required during construction.</para>

    <para>Typical issues to be considered are.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Mining. Mines developed in the floodplain may require levees or
        similar flood mitigation measures. These levees need to be designed to
        an appropriate level of flood immunity and may also have an impact on
        flood levels outside the levee. The risk and potential damage caused
        by flood inundation both inside and outside the mine need to be
        analysed, with a similar process to that used for community
        development discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu"/>. The risk
        for mining may be from flooding of the mine pit, emplacements,
        infrastructure, machinery or underground workings, which may disrupt
        production, damage equipment and result in significant erosion and
        sedimentation deposits or polluted water that is an environmental
        concern.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Agriculture. Flooding in agricultural regions can have concerns
        for crops, livestock and infrastructure. Crops may be damaged by
        inundation either: directly by floodwaters; or due to the extended
        period of inundation (where crops may be susceptible to longer term
        rather than short term inundation). Livestock may be lost if unable to
        be relocated to areas outside flood limits. The specific implications
        for livestock and crops need to be considered. In addition,
        agricultural infrastructure such as irrigation pipes, fences,
        buildings and machinery may be damaged and these can have significant
        value. In some areas of high value agriculture, the farm land may be
        protected by levees and these have similar issues to levees built for
        other flood mitigation purposes.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Road and rail projects. Road and rail embankments are built
        across floodplains in many situations. To ensure a suitable level of
        flood immunity, the infrastructure will be built on embankments which
        will usually cross water courses. In this case, the infrastructure
        must be designed to ensure a suitable level of service (i.e.
        considering the acceptable degree of disruption to transport services
        for the route), as well as withstand an acceptable risk of damage from
        scour, submergence, or overtopping of structures. The consideration of
        disruption to transport depends not only on the frequency of closure,
        or flood immunity, but also on the duration of closures, both during
        large floods and as an annual aggregate. It also needs to consider the
        intended function of a road during a flood event, particularly where
        it has an important role in community evacuation or recovery plans.
        Design of embankments associated with these structures requires
        analysis of the road or rail level as well as the sizes, locations and
        types waterway openings. This is to ensure an acceptable level of
        flood immunity, duration of closure and damage from floods as well as
        an acceptable impact on upstream flood levels. Discussion of flood
        assessment and flood risk for road and rail projects can be found in
        the Austroads Guide to Road Design – Part 5 (Drainage)<footnote>
            <para>http://www.austroads.com.au/road-construction/road-design/resources/guide-to-road-design</para>
          </footnote>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Risk associated with these different types of developments need to
    be analysed in a similar way to the community as discussed above. Costs
    and benefits can be calculated with similar processes.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_23w6l">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks in Relation to Dams</title>

    <para>The reference document for guidelines relevant to dam safety is
    provided by ANCOLD (2003). These guidelines provide an over-arching
    framework that integrates risk assessment with traditional standards-based
    engineering practice. They provide guidance on the generic steps involved
    in undertaking risk assessment for dams, and these are updated
    periodically with changing understanding and practice.</para>

    <para>The dams industry has used risk-assessment over the past two decades
    as a valuable means to establish upgrade priorities and justify the
    urgency of completing dam safety actions in a transparent and rational
    manner. However, the national ANCOLD guidelines only support risk
    assessment as an enhancement to traditional standards-based solutions for
    important and conclusive decision-making. The guidelines are currently
    being revised, and it is likely that there will be an increased focus on
    the use of risk-based criteria for final decision-making in accordance
    with changing practice (for example, NSW Dam Safety Committee,
    2006).</para>

    <para>One of the key differences between dam safety management and
    floodplain management is the probability domain of interest: the scale and
    nature of life safety risks posed by dams are generally considerably
    greater than encountered in floodplain management. The tolerable risks
    associated with these potential consequences are three to four orders of
    magnitude rarer than those associated with natural floods. The concept of
    annualising a high consequence risk based on a 10 6 loading condition is
    mathematically straightforward, but such analyses are not easily combined
    with more common risks and have little practical utility.</para>

    <para>Accordingly, risk assessment for dam safety is focussed on reducing
    the risks to life (and property) to as low a level as reasonably
    practicable. It is unusual for dam safety decisions to be governed by the
    need to balance the costs of upgrading works against damages avoided, and
    more typically such decisions are dominated by life-safety
    considerations.</para>

    <para>The most relevant guidance on dam safety in this document is
    provided in <xref linkend="book8"/>. This provides guidance on the
    procedures most relevant to the extreme flood risks of interest. It also
    includes procedures relevant to estimation of the Probable Maximum Flood,
    which represents the upper limiting magnitude of flood is relevant to
    standards-based decision-making.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_ih60o">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks using Basins</title>

    <para>Basins can have an important role in reducing downstream flood flows
    and associated flood risks to the community. They may be built to manage
    existing community flood problems or to offset the impacts of upstream
    development on downstream flood risk. A basin may be used in isolation or
    as part of a series of basins within a catchment to reduce peak design
    flood flows and risks for the design AEP event(s) at key downstream
    locations. The design performance requirement is therefore generally
    either:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>To reduce peak flows for a certain AEP design event(s) to a
        certain maximum amount. For example for a basin designed to offset the
        impacts of upstream new development this may be the pre-development
        peak downstream flow. For a basin designed to reduce downstream flood
        impacts this may be to reduce peak basins discharges to a level that
        reduces flood impacts on the downstream community to an agreed
        level.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>To maximise the potential benefit of a basin at the location on
        downstream flood behaviour to reduce impacts on the community.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>An effectively designed basin has to balance restriction of outlet
    capacity whilst having available storage capacity near the peak of a flood
    event. This enables the peak of flood flows to be stored and the stored
    volume discharged later in the event, as illustrated in the example in
    <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_sj0ig"/>.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_sj0ig">
      <title>Example of Impacts of a Basin on Flood Flows in a Design
      Event</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1029.PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>This can significantly alter the critical storm duration with the
    peak flood flow entering a basin likely to be derived from a shorter
    duration storm than the peak discharge flow from the basin. Storm pattern
    can also have a significant impact on basin operation and the storage
    volume available when the peak of flood flows arrives. For example, if the
    peak arrives later in the storm the available storage volume may be lower
    and therefore the basin may have less impact on downstream peak
    flows.</para>

    <para>In addition, critical storm durations are also likely to vary with
    the AEP of the flood being modelled. It is not unusual for the peak basin
    discharge in a more frequent flood than the design event to occur in a
    longer duration storm event as storm volumes are lower and the basin
    storage will have more impact upon peak discharge. However, for events
    larger than the design AEP event the opposite is true. There is likely to
    be less storage volume available at the storm peak so it will have less
    influence on peak basin discharge. Therefore the critical downstream
    discharge from rarer events than the design AEP event will likely occur
    from shorter duration storms. For extreme events this is likely to be
    closer to the critical storm duration at the location without the
    basin.</para>

    <para>Therefore with a basin in place the peak downstream flood flow is
    sensitive to both the storm duration and the storm pattern and the routing
    of flows through the basin. As such basin design can be particularly
    sensitive to both storm pattern and critical storm duration.</para>

    <para>Robust design approaches for basins that test and consider a wide
    range of storm durations and a range of potential variations of storm
    pattern for each of these storm durations are recommended for the full
    range of flood events. Variations in storm pattern should include testing
    of early, centrally and late weighted storm patterns for the same time
    duration to test whether the basin can meet the required design criteria
    with this variation.</para>

    <para>Other key points to consider in modelling and designing detention
    basins include:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Considering the impacts of events larger than the design event.
        The basin will generally be designed to reduce flood flows in a
        particular AEP design event. However, in the majority of cases it is
        unlikely to have significant impacts on peak flows in extreme events.
        This can mean that there is a significantly larger difference between
        the extreme and design AEP flows entering and discharging the basin.
        <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_m2dve"/> provides an example. This situation
        is likely to result in a faster rate of rise of downstream flood
        levels for events larger than the design AEP event (as these events
        result in high level spillway operation) than would have occurred
        without the basin. It is essential that this difference is understood
        and considered in basin and high level outlet design to managing the
        flood risk downstream of the basin. Residual risk downstream of the
        basin including any limitations in emergency response and associated
        planning needs to be considered and may require additional management
        measures including flood warning, community awareness, flood related
        development controls.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Upstream impacts of basins. The construction of a basin can also
        have significant upstream impacts on flood behaviour and these are an
        important consideration in the design of a basin. This should be
        examined for the full range of flood events to ensure that any impacts
        on upstream flood risk and the management of this risk (including
        emergency management planning) are understood.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Detentions basins act as dams during flood events. Therefore
        design needs to consider dam safety aspects as discussed in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_s_23w6l"/> and <xref linkend="book8"/>.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The use of multiple basins in a catchment. Where multiple basins
        are designed to provide more strategic benefits, i.e., away from the
        downstream boundary of their individual locations they should be
        designed on a catchment wide basis to ensure their interaction does
        not result in adverse impacts upon flood behaviour. Use of multiple
        basins in a catchment without consideration of interaction has the
        potential to result in adverse impacts on flood behaviour.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_m2dve">
      <title>Example of Difference in Impacts of a Basin on Flood Flows in a
      Design Event compared to an Extreme Event</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1030.PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_la4hv">
    <title>References and Further Reading</title>

    <para>AEMI 2013 (Australian Emergency Management Institute), Australian
    Emergency Management Handbook 7: Managing the Floodplain Best Practice in
    Flood Risk Management in Australia AEMI, Canberra.</para>

    <para>AEMI 2014a (Australian Emergency Management Institute), Technical
    flood risk management guideline: Flood emergency response classification
    of the floodplain, AEMI, Canberra.</para>

    <para>AEMI 2014b (Australian Emergency Management Institute), Technical
    flood risk management guideline: Flood hazard, AEMI, Canberra.</para>

    <para>AEMI 2014c (Australian Emergency Management Institute), Guideline
    for using the national generic brief for flood investigations to develop
    project-specific specifications, AEMI, Canberra.</para>

    <para>AEMI 2015 (Australian Emergency Management Institute), Australian
    Emergency Management Handbook 10: National Emergency Risk Assessment
    Guidelines AEMI, Canberra.</para>

    <para>ANCOLD (2003): Guidelines on Risk Assessment. Australian National
    Committee on Large Dams.</para>

    <para>Babister, M., Retallick, M., 2013. Benchmarking Best Practice in
    Floodplain Management, Floodplain Management Association National
    Conference, Tweed Heads, May 2013</para>

    <para>Babister, M., McLuckie, D., Retallick, M., Testoni, I. (2014).
    Comparing Modelling Approaches to End User needs, Floodplain Management
    Association Conference, Deniliquin, May 2014</para>

    <para>DECC 2007 (NSW Department of Environment and Climate Change),
    Floodplain Risk Management Guideline, Residential Flood Damage,
    Sydney.</para>

    <para>ISO 2009a (International Standard on Risk Management, ISO31000:2009,
    International Standards Organisation.</para>

    <para>ISO 2009b International Standards Organization Guide 73:2009 Risk
    Management Vocabulary, International Standards Organisation.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., Babister M., (2015). Improving national best practice
    in flood risk management, Floodplain Management Association National
    Conference, Brisbane, May 2015.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., Babister M., Smith G., Thomson R., (2014). Updating
    National best practice guidance in flood risk management, Floodplain
    Management Association National Conference, Deniliquin, May 2014.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., (2013). A guide to best practice in flood risk
    management in Australia, Floodplain Management Association National
    Conference, Tweed Heads, May 2013.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., (2012). Best Practice in Flood Risk Management in
    Australia. Presentation to Engineers Australia Queensland Water Panel,
    Brisbane, May 2012.</para>

    <para>NFRAG (2008) Flood Risk Management in Australia. The Australian
    Journal of Emergency Management. Vol 23, No. 4, November 2008.</para>

    <para>NSW Government (2006). Risk Management Policy Framework for Dam
    Safety. NSW Dam Safety Council.</para>

    <para>NSW Government (2005). Floodplain Development Manual. Department Of
    Infrastructure Planning and Natural Resources. DIPNR 05_020.</para>

    <para>Opper S, Emergency Management Planning for the Hawkesbury Nepean
    Valley, 40th Floodplain Management Authorities Conference, Parramatta, 9th
    – 12th May 2000.</para>

    <para>SCARM (2000) Floodplain Management in Australia: Best Practice
    Principles and Guidelines. Agriculture and Resource Management Council of
    Australia and New Zealand, Standing Committee on Agriculture and Resource
    Management (SCARM). Report No 73. CSIRO Publishing, 2000.</para>

    <para>Shand, T. D., Cox, R. J., Blacka, M. J. and Smith, G. P. (2011).
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 10: Appropriate Safety
    Criteria for Vehicles - Literature Review. Australian Rainfall and Runoff
    Revision Project 10. Stage 2 Report. Prepared by the Water Research
    Laboratory. P10/S2/020. February 2011.</para>

    <para>Smith, G. P., Davey, E. K., and Cox, R. J. (2014). Flood Hazard
    Water Research Laboratory Technical Report 2014/07. Prepared by the Water
    Research Laboratory. April 2014.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_uelzo">
    <title>Examples</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x">
      <title>Calculation of Average Annual Damages for a Community</title>

      <para><inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>AAD</m:mi>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>Sum from 1 to n of</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                      </m:mfrac>

                      <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>3</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                      </m:mfrac>

                      <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>3</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>...</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mfrac>
                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:msub>

                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                                <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                              </m:mrow>

                              <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:mfrac>

                        <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>

                            <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:msub>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>]</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation></para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>AAD = annual average damages in $</para>

            <para>d = damage in $</para>

            <para>p = probability</para>

            <para>points 1 to n are the different ordinates on the damage
            curve</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine the damage under the curve for <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t"/>. The table below provides the points on
            the curve.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="3">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>AEP</entry>

                    <entry>Flood Damage for Event</entry>

                    <entry>n</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.001%</entry>

                    <entry>$28,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>1</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>2</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>$20,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>3</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$17,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$9,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>5</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$3,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>6</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>$1,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>7</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>20%</entry>

                    <entry>$0</entry>

                    <entry>8</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>AAD</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>[</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>28,000,000</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>22,000,000</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>0.002</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.00001</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>22,000,000</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>20,000,000</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>0.005</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.002</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>20,000,000</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>17,000,000</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>0.01</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.005</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>17,000,000</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>9,000,000</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>0.02</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.01</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>9,000,000</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>3,000,000</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>0.05</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.02</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>3,000,000</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>1,000,000</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>0.1</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.05</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>1,000,000</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>0.2</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.1</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>]</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>

      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>AAD</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>[</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>49,750</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>63,000</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>92,500</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>130,000</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>180,000</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>100,000</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>50,000</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>]</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>

      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mi>AAD = $665,250</m:mi>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>

      <para>When it comes to examining management options it can be important
      to understand which portion of the curve is contributing significantly
      to damage and therefore a table such as follows can be useful. In this
      case events up to a 1% AEP event contribute $460,000 out of the $665,250
      toward annual average damages.</para>

      <informaltable>
        <tgroup cols="5">
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>AEP n</entry>

              <entry>AEP n-1</entry>

              <entry>Flood Damage n</entry>

              <entry>Flood Damage n-1</entry>

              <entry>Contribution to AAD</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.001%</entry>

              <entry>0.2%</entry>

              <entry>$28,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$49,750</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.2%</entry>

              <entry>0.5%</entry>

              <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$20,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$63,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.5%</entry>

              <entry>1.0%</entry>

              <entry>$20,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$17,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$92,500</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>1.0%</entry>

              <entry>2.0%</entry>

              <entry>$17,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$9,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$130,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>2.0%</entry>

              <entry>5.0%</entry>

              <entry>$9,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$3,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$180,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>5.0%</entry>

              <entry>10%</entry>

              <entry>$3,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$1,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$100,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>10%</entry>

              <entry>20%</entry>

              <entry>$1,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$0</entry>

              <entry>$50,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Total</entry>

              <entry>n/a</entry>

              <entry>n/a</entry>

              <entry>n/a</entry>

              <entry>$665,250</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_jpbhv">
      <title>Calculating Average Annual Benefits of a Treatment
      Measure</title>

      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>AAB</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>AAD</m:mi>

                <m:mi>case 0</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>-</m:mo>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>AAD</m:mi>

                <m:mi>case 1</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>AAB = annual average benefits in $</para>

            <para>AAD = annual average damages in $ - calculations see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></para>

            <para>Case 0 is the current situation or base case</para>

            <para>Case 1 is the case with treatment in place</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine the average annual benefits</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine annual average damages for the base case – done in
            <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine annual average damages for the treated case. See
            table below.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>AEP n</entry>

                    <entry>AEP n-1</entry>

                    <entry>Flood Damage n</entry>

                    <entry>Flood Damage n-1</entry>

                    <entry>Contribution to AAD</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.001%</entry>

                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>$28,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$49,750</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$15,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$55,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$15,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$2,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$42,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$2,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$750,000</entry>

                    <entry>$13,750</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$750,000</entry>

                    <entry>$500,000</entry>

                    <entry>$18,750</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>$500,000</entry>

                    <entry>$200,000</entry>

                    <entry>$17,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>20%</entry>

                    <entry>$200,000</entry>

                    <entry>$0</entry>

                    <entry>$10,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Total</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>$207,750</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 3</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine annual average damages for the base case – done in
            <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 4</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine annual average damages for the treated case. See
            table below.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>AEP n</entry>

                    <entry>AEP n-1</entry>

                    <entry>Base Case Contribution to AAD From <xref
                    linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></entry>

                    <entry>Treated Case Contribution to AAD</entry>

                    <entry>Contribution to AAB</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.001%</entry>

                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>$49,750</entry>

                    <entry>$49,750</entry>

                    <entry>$0</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>$63,000</entry>

                    <entry>$55,500</entry>

                    <entry>$7,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$92,500</entry>

                    <entry>$42,500</entry>

                    <entry>$50,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$130,000</entry>

                    <entry>$13,750</entry>

                    <entry>$116,250</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$180,000</entry>

                    <entry>$18,750</entry>

                    <entry>$161,250</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>$100,000</entry>

                    <entry>$17,500</entry>

                    <entry>$82,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>20%</entry>

                    <entry>$50,000</entry>

                    <entry>$10,000</entry>

                    <entry>$40,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Total</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>$665,250</entry>

                    <entry>$207,750</entry>

                    <entry>$457,500</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_13ov6">
      <title>Calculating Net Present Value of Benefits</title>

      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>[</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>Sum 1 to n-1 of</m:mi>

                <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>AAB</m:mi>

                    <m:msup>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>dr</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                    </m:msup>
                  </m:mfrac>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>AAB</m:mi>

                    <m:msup>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>dr</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:msup>
                  </m:mfrac>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>...</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>

                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mi>AAB</m:mi>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msup>
                    </m:mfrac>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>]</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>AAB = annual average benefits in $ - calculation see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_jpbhv"/></para>

            <para>dr = discount rate</para>

            <para>n= design life in years. Assumes no benefits during
            construction</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Note:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>A range of discount rates may be used to give a range of
            NPVs which can in turn be used to determine a range of benefit
            cost ratios (see <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5"/>) to test how
            financial benefits may vary with different financial
            situations.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculating net present value of benefits</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine the average annual benefits – done in <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_jpbhv"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Assess net present value of benefits. See table
            below.</para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <m:math display="inline">
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>Benefits</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:math>
              </inlineequation>= $6,099,257 for a discount rate (dr) of 7%.
            This could vary from $4,473,916 for a dr of 10% to $9,055,194 for
            a dr of 4%.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <colspec colname="_1"/>

                <colspec colname="_2"/>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Year N</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in Future Year AAB ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <m:math display="inline">
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:math>
                      </inlineequation> = 4% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <m:math display="inline">
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:math>
                      </inlineequation> = 7% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <m:math display="inline">
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>3</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:math>
                      </inlineequation> = 10% ($)</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>439,904</entry>

                    <entry>427,570</entry>

                    <entry>415,909</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>422,984</entry>

                    <entry>399,598</entry>

                    <entry>378,099</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>3</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>406,716</entry>

                    <entry>373,456</entry>

                    <entry>343,727</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>4</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>391,073</entry>

                    <entry>349,025</entry>

                    <entry>312,479</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>376,032</entry>

                    <entry>326,191</entry>

                    <entry>284,072</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>6</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>361,569</entry>

                    <entry>304,852</entry>

                    <entry>258,247</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>7</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>347,662</entry>

                    <entry>284,908</entry>

                    <entry>234,770</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>8</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>334,291</entry>

                    <entry>266,269</entry>

                    <entry>213,427</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>9</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>321,433</entry>

                    <entry>248,850</entry>

                    <entry>194,025</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>309,071</entry>

                    <entry>232,570</entry>

                    <entry>176,386</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>11</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>297,183</entry>

                    <entry>217,355</entry>

                    <entry>160,351</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>12</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>285,753</entry>

                    <entry>203,135</entry>

                    <entry>145,774</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>13</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>274,763</entry>

                    <entry>189,846</entry>

                    <entry>132,521</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>14</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>264,195</entry>

                    <entry>177,426</entry>

                    <entry>120,474</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>15</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>254,034</entry>

                    <entry>165,819</entry>

                    <entry>109,522</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>16</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>244,263</entry>

                    <entry>154,971</entry>

                    <entry>99,565</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>17</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>234,868</entry>

                    <entry>144,833</entry>

                    <entry>90,514</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>18</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>225,835</entry>

                    <entry>135,358</entry>

                    <entry>82,285</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>19</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>217,149</entry>

                    <entry>126,503</entry>

                    <entry>74,805</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>20</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>208,797</entry>

                    <entry>118,227</entry>

                    <entry>68,004</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>21</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>200,766</entry>

                    <entry>110,492</entry>

                    <entry>61,822</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>22</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>193,045</entry>

                    <entry>103,264</entry>

                    <entry>56,202</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>23</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>185,620</entry>

                    <entry>96,508</entry>

                    <entry>51,093</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>24</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>178,481</entry>

                    <entry>90,195</entry>

                    <entry>46,448</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>25</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>171,616</entry>

                    <entry>84,294</entry>

                    <entry>42,225</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>26</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>165,015</entry>

                    <entry>78,779</entry>

                    <entry>38,387</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>27</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>158,669</entry>

                    <entry>73,626</entry>

                    <entry>34,897</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>28</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>152,566</entry>

                    <entry>68,809</entry>

                    <entry>31,725</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>29</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>146,698</entry>

                    <entry>64,307</entry>

                    <entry>28,841</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>30</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>141,056</entry>

                    <entry>60,100</entry>

                    <entry>26,219</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>31</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>135,631</entry>

                    <entry>56,169</entry>

                    <entry>23,835</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>32</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>130,414</entry>

                    <entry>52,494</entry>

                    <entry>21,668</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>33</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>125,398</entry>

                    <entry>49,060</entry>

                    <entry>19,698</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>34</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>120,575</entry>

                    <entry>45,850</entry>

                    <entry>17,908</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>35</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>115,938</entry>

                    <entry>42,851</entry>

                    <entry>16,280</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>36</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>111,478</entry>

                    <entry>40,047</entry>

                    <entry>14,800</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>37</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>107,191</entry>

                    <entry>37,428</entry>

                    <entry>13,454</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>38</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>103,068</entry>

                    <entry>34,979</entry>

                    <entry>12,231</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>39</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>99,104</entry>

                    <entry>32,691</entry>

                    <entry>11,119</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>40</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>95,292</entry>

                    <entry>30,552</entry>

                    <entry>10,108</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry nameend="_2" namest="_1">Total</entry>

                    <entry>$9,055,194</entry>

                    <entry>$6,099,257</entry>

                    <entry>$4,473,916</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_4u178">
      <title>Calculating Net Present Value (NPV) of Life Cycle Costs</title>

      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>Capital Cost + [</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>Sum 1 to n-1 of</m:mi>

                <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>AMC</m:mi>

                    <m:msup>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>dr</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                    </m:msup>
                  </m:mfrac>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>AMC</m:mi>

                    <m:msup>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>dr</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:msup>
                  </m:mfrac>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>...</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>

                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mi>AMC</m:mi>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msup>
                    </m:mfrac>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>]</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Capital cost is all relevant upfront costs</para>

            <para>AMC = annual operation and maintenance costs</para>

            <para>dr = discount rate</para>

            <para>n= design life in years. Assumes no benefits during
            construction</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Note:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>A range of discount rates may be used to give a range of
            NPVs and in turn a range of benefit cost ratios (see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5"/>) to test how financial benefits may
            vary with changing financial situation.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculating net present value of life cycle costs</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine capital costs and annual operation and maintenance
            costs</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate net present value of life cycle costs. See table
            below.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Capital cost is $4,000,000 and annual operating and
            maintenance costs is $100,000</para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <m:math display="inline">
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>costs</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:math>
              </inlineequation>= =$5,333,171 for a discount rate (dr) of 7%.
            This could vary from $4,977,105 for a dr of 10% to $5,979,277 for
            a dr of 4%..</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <colspec colname="_1"/>

                <colspec colname="_2"/>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Year N</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in Future Year AAB ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <m:math display="inline">
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:math>
                      </inlineequation> = 4% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <m:math display="inline">
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:math>
                      </inlineequation> = 7% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <m:math display="inline">
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>dr</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>3</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>
                        </m:math>
                      </inlineequation> = 10% ($)</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>96,154</entry>

                    <entry>93,458</entry>

                    <entry>90,909</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>92,456</entry>

                    <entry>87,344</entry>

                    <entry>82,645</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>3</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>88,900</entry>

                    <entry>81,630</entry>

                    <entry>75,131</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>4</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>85,480</entry>

                    <entry>76,290</entry>

                    <entry>68,301</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>82,193</entry>

                    <entry>71,299</entry>

                    <entry>62,092</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>6</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>79,031</entry>

                    <entry>66,634</entry>

                    <entry>56,447</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>7</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>75,992</entry>

                    <entry>62,275</entry>

                    <entry>51,316</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>8</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>73,069</entry>

                    <entry>58,201</entry>

                    <entry>46,651</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>9</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>70,259</entry>

                    <entry>54,393</entry>

                    <entry>42,410</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>67,556</entry>

                    <entry>50,835</entry>

                    <entry>38,554</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>11</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>64,958</entry>

                    <entry>47,509</entry>

                    <entry>35,049</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>12</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>62,460</entry>

                    <entry>44,401</entry>

                    <entry>31,863</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>13</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>60,057</entry>

                    <entry>41,496</entry>

                    <entry>28,966</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>14</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>57,748</entry>

                    <entry>38,782</entry>

                    <entry>26,333</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>15</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>55,526</entry>

                    <entry>36,245</entry>

                    <entry>23,939</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>16</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>53,391</entry>

                    <entry>33,873</entry>

                    <entry>21,763</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>17</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>51,337</entry>

                    <entry>31,657</entry>

                    <entry>19,784</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>18</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>49,363</entry>

                    <entry>29,586</entry>

                    <entry>17,986</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>19</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>47,464</entry>

                    <entry>27,651</entry>

                    <entry>16,351</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>20</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>45,639</entry>

                    <entry>25,842</entry>

                    <entry>14,864</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>21</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>43,883</entry>

                    <entry>24,151</entry>

                    <entry>13,513</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>22</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>42,196</entry>

                    <entry>22,571</entry>

                    <entry>12,285</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>23</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>40,573</entry>

                    <entry>21,095</entry>

                    <entry>11,168</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>24</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>39,012</entry>

                    <entry>19,715</entry>

                    <entry>10,153</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>25</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>37,512</entry>

                    <entry>18,425</entry>

                    <entry>9,230</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>26</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>36,069</entry>

                    <entry>17,220</entry>

                    <entry>8,391</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>27</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>34,682</entry>

                    <entry>16,093</entry>

                    <entry>7,628</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>28</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>33,348</entry>

                    <entry>15,040</entry>

                    <entry>6,934</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>29</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>32,065</entry>

                    <entry>14,056</entry>

                    <entry>6,304</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>30</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>30,832</entry>

                    <entry>13,137</entry>

                    <entry>5,731</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>31</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>29,646</entry>

                    <entry>12,277</entry>

                    <entry>5,210</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>32</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>28,506</entry>

                    <entry>11,474</entry>

                    <entry>4,736</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>33</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>27,409</entry>

                    <entry>10,723</entry>

                    <entry>4,306</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>34</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>26,355</entry>

                    <entry>10,022</entry>

                    <entry>3,914</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>35</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>25,342</entry>

                    <entry>9,366</entry>

                    <entry>3,558</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>36</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>24,367</entry>

                    <entry>8,754</entry>

                    <entry>3,235</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>37</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>23,430</entry>

                    <entry>8,181</entry>

                    <entry>2,941</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>38</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>22,529</entry>

                    <entry>7,646</entry>

                    <entry>2,673</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>39</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>21,662</entry>

                    <entry>7,146</entry>

                    <entry>2,430</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>40</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>20,829</entry>

                    <entry>6,678</entry>

                    <entry>2,209</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry nameend="_2" namest="_1">Total</entry>

                    <entry>$5,979,277</entry>

                    <entry>$5,333,171</entry>

                    <entry>$4,977,905</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5">
      <title>Calculating Benefit Cost Ratio (BCR)</title>

      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>BCR</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mfrac>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                <m:mi>benefits</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                <m:mi>costs</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mfrac>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>BCR = Benefit Cost Ratio</para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <m:math display="inline">
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>benefits</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:math>
              </inlineequation> = Net Present Value of Benefits - see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_13ov6"/></para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <m:math display="inline">
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>costs</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:math>
              </inlineequation> = Net Present Value of Costs - see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_4u178"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Note:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>A range of discount rates may be used to give a range of
            NPVs which can in turn be used to determine a range of benefit
            cost ratios (see below) to test how financial benefits may vary
            with different financial situations.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculating BCR</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate Net Present Value of benefits = <inlineequation>
                <m:math display="inline">
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>benefits</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:math>
              </inlineequation></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate Net Present Value of Life Cycle Costs =
            <inlineequation>
                <m:math display="inline">
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>NPV</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>costs</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:math>
              </inlineequation></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 3</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate BCR. BCR = 1.14 for dr 7%, BCR = 1.51 for dr 4%,
            BCR = 0.9 for dr 10%.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="4">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Discount Rate dr %</entry>

                    <entry>NPVbenefits ($)</entry>

                    <entry>NPVcosts ($)</entry>

                    <entry>BCR</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>4</entry>

                    <entry>9,055,194</entry>

                    <entry>5,979,277</entry>

                    <entry>1.51</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>7</entry>

                    <entry>6,099,257</entry>

                    <entry>5,333,171</entry>

                    <entry>1.14</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>

                    <entry>4,473,916</entry>

                    <entry>4,977,905</entry>

                    <entry>0.90</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
