<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b1_ch5"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Risk Based Design</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/mcluckie_duncan.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/thomson_rhys.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/drynan_leo.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/toniato_angela.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Advanced draft</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_mhyfy">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Floods can cause significant impacts where they interact with the community and the
      supporting natural and built environment. However, flooding also has the potential to be the
      most manageable natural disaster as the likelihood and consequences of the full range of flood
      events can be understood enabling risks to be assessed and where necessary managed.</para>
    <para>Design flood estimation plays a key role in understanding flood behaviour and how this may
      change with changes within the floodplain and catchment and in climate and how these changes
      can influence both decisions that influence the growth and management of flood risk.</para>
    <para>Design flood estimation provide essential information on a range of key factors that need
      to be considered in understanding and managing the consequences of flooding. These include:
      flood frequency; flow rates, velocities and volumes; flood levels and extents; duration of
      inundation. ARR provides essential analytical tools to assist in estimating design floods and
      in understanding these factors. Estimates of design floods are an essential element in
      understanding flood behaviour and making informed decisions on:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Managing flood risk through a risk based decision making process
            <citation>b1_c5_r1</citation>. Such approaches generally provide an understanding of
          flood behaviour across the full range of flood events, up to and including extreme events,
          such as the Probable Maximum Flood (PMF). They can inform decision making in flood risk
          management, a broad range of land use planning activities, emergency management for floods
          and dam failure, and in estimating flood insurance premiums;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Managing flood risk through the use of design standards related to the probability or
          frequency of occurrence, rather than the broader assessment and management of risk;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Setting infrastructure performance criteria based upon a design standard, generally a
          probability or frequency of an event, rather than the broader assessment and management of
          risk;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Managing flood risk in short term projects through a risk based decision making
          process considering the life of a project; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Understanding and managing the impacts changes within the catchment and floodplain may
          have on flood behaviour and risk.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>This chapter provides advice and examples on using the analytical tools outlined in ARR to
      inform decision making for flood risk management, road and rail design, mining and agriculture
      and design of dams. It does not provide details on the design standards, risk assessment
      frameworks, the assessment of impacts on the community or built or natural environment, nor to
      estimate residual risks. Further information on risk management approaches, processes and
      frameworks can be found in <emphasis><citation>b1_c5_r1</citation>,
          <citation>b1_c5_r6+1</citation>
        <citation>b1_c5_r15+1</citation>.</emphasis></para>
    <para>The remainder of this chapter is structured as follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_cx2jp"/> provides a background on flood risk;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_xbbpb"/> discusses risk analysis;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_259ky"/> discusses managing risk;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu"/> discusses managing flood risk to communities;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_zha4n"/> discusses managing flood risk to mining, agriculture
          and infrastructure projects;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_23w6l"/> discusses the management of flood risk in relation to
          dams.;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_ih60o"/> discusses the management of flood risk using
          basins;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/> discusses the consideration of effective service life
          of infrastructure;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_lsfw7"/> discusses how flood risk changes over time due to a
          range of factors;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_39fu8"/> provides further reading material;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_uelzo"/> provides some examples of calculations; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_refs"/> provides references.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_cx2jp">
    <title>Flood Risk</title>

    <para>Flood risk results from the interaction of the community, through human occupation or use
      of the floodplain, with hazardous flood behaviour. It is the risk of flooding to people, their
      social or community setting, and the built and natural environment
        <citation>b1_c5_r1</citation>.</para>

    <para>Flood risk is not simply the probability of an event occurring. The
        <emphasis>International Standard on Risk Management,</emphasis>
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103113+1100" content="ISO31000:2009 "?><citation>b1_c5_r15</citation>
      defines risk as the effect of uncertainty on objectives. In addition, <emphasis>ISO Guide
        73:2009 Risk Management Vocabulary </emphasis><citation>b1_c5_r14</citation> notes that
      uncertainty is the state, even partial, of deficiency of information related to, understanding
      or knowledge of an event, its consequence, or likelihood. An effect is a positive or negative
      deviation from the expected outcome. Objectives can have different aspects (financial, health
      and safety, environmental) and apply at different levels (local, state, site).</para>

    <para><citation>b1_c5_r1+1</citation> and <citation>b1_c5_r6+1</citation> express risk in terms
      of combinations of the likelihood of events (generally measured in terms of Annual Exceedance
      Probability (AEP)) and the severity of the consequences of the event (see <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_4qcm8"/>). Risk is higher the more frequently an area is exposed to the
      same consequence or when the same frequency of event has higher consequences.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_4qcm8">
      <title>Components of Flood Risk (After McLuckie (2012)</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1015.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para><emphasis><citation>b1_c5_r1+1</citation></emphasis> discusses the consequences of
      flooding on the community. The consequences depend upon the vulnerability of the community and
      the built environment to flooding. Vulnerability varies with the element (people, property and
      infrastructure) at risk and within the different cohorts within the elements outlined below.
          <emphasis><citation>b1_c5_r5+1</citation></emphasis> advises that this may be measured in
      terms of the impacts upon:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>People</emphasis> – in terms of fatalities and
          injuries<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103133+1100"?>;<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103133+1100" content="."?></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The economy and assets</emphasis> - in terms of reduced economic activity
          and asset
          losses<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103136+1100"?>;<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103136+1100" content="."?></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The social setting</emphasis> – in terms of consequences to the community as
          a whole (rather than individuals) that can lead to the breakdown of community
          organisations and structures. This can include the temporary or permanent loss of
          community facilities or culturally important objects or
          events<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103138+1100"?>;<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103138+1100" content="."?></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Public administration</emphasis> – in terms of changes to the ability of the
          governing body for the community to be able to deliver its core
          functions<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103140+1100"?>;<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103140+1100" content="."?></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The environment </emphasis>– in terms of destruction and degradation of
          critical environmental assets (and their processes and structures) and/or species
          extinction and habitat range
          reduction<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103143+1100"?>;
          and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103142+1100" content="."?></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The consequence to different elements from the same exposure to
    flooding can be different. For example, a flood may have major
    consequences for community assets (such as a water or sewerage treatment
    plant) but have only minor or moderate consequences in terms of potential
    fatalities and injuries in the population.</para>

    <para>The likelihood of exposure to flooding and therefore flood risk
    varies significantly between and within floodplains and flood events of
    different magnitudes. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0lntn"/> shows areas exposed
    to flooding from events of different AEPs.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_0lntn">
      <title>Map Showing Different AEP Flood Extents Including an Extreme Event</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1016.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_xbbpb">
    <title>Risk Analysis</title>
    <para>Risk analysis is a systematic approach to understanding the nature of and deducing the
      level of risk. It involves developing an understanding of the nature of, driver for, hazard
      and the associated consequences to rank the relative severity of risk. It is one of the steps
      in the risk management process <citation>b1_c5_r15</citation> and for example is generally
      undertaken as part of a floodplain management study in the flood risk management framework
          <emphasis><citation>b1_c5_r1</citation>.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Risk analysis involves understanding the varying likelihood of events (that result in a
      consequence), and the severity of their consequences. It should also involve an assessment of
      confidence, which considers factors such as the divergence of opinion, level of expertise,
      uncertainty, quality, quantity and relevance of data. These factors are combined to assign a
      relative risk rating for an event through development of a risk matrix or other tools. Risk
      analysis may be quantitative or qualitative. In both cases the probability of events affecting
      communities may be able to be estimated through design flood estimates.</para>
    <para>Quantitative analysis is often used where both the probability and the consequences can be
      measured. For example, consequences may be estimated in terms of tangible flood damage to the
      community for events of different AEPs. Tangible damages are those damages that are more
      readily able to be estimated in economic terms and lend themselves to quantitative assessment,
      including:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Direct damages to structures and their contents due to water contact; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indirect damages of clean-up of debris and removal of damaged material, loss of wages,
          sales, production and costs of alternative accommodation, and opportunity costs due to
          loss of services.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Qualitative analyses are generally undertaken where consequences are difficult to
      quantify. For example, these can include social and environmental impacts and the costs of
      fatalities and injuries which are intangible damages that cannot readily be put in economic
      terms. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_t_5ke0w"/> provides an example of a qualitative risk
      matrix.</para>
    <table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch5_t_5ke0w">
      <caption><?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20160616T160530+1000" comment="to be replaced with figure"?>Example
        Qualitative Risk Matrix</caption>
      <col width="16%"/>
      <col width="16%"/>
      <col width="16%"/>
      <col width="16%"/>
      <col width="16%"/>
      <col width="16%"/>
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th colspan="6">Consequence Level</th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>Likelihood Level</td>
          <td>Insignificant</td>
          <td>Minor</td>
          <td>Moderate</td>
          <td>Major</td>
          <td>Catastrophic</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Almost Certain</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Likely</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Unlikely</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ed1b2f" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ed1b2f"?>Extreme</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Rare</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Very Rare</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Extremely Rare</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#61a9d3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#61a9d3"?>Very Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#39b54a" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#39b54a"?>Low</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#F4FA58" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#F4FA58"?>Medium</td>
          <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#f47920" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#f47920"?>High</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
    <?oxy_comment_end?>
    <para>Risk analysis can be used to inform decisions on both the acceptability of residual risk
      and the effective and efficient use of scare resources to better understand and manage
      risk.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_259ky">
    <title>Managing Flood Risk</title>

    <para>Managing flood risk generally involves a combination of:
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Managing changes within the floodplain that may alter flood
          behaviour;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Altering the likelihood (how frequently exposure to flooding
          occurs); and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Managing the consequences of flooding (reducing vulnerability to flooding when
            exposed) to reduce the
            risks<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103218+1100"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>Managing risk needs to consider the different elements at
    risk which may require different management techniques and standards. It
    also needs to consider the risks to the existing community and built and
    natural environment and the additional risk created by introducing new
    development and infrastructure into the floodplain.</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_u4hj4">
      <title>Managing Changes to Flood Behaviour</title>

      <para>Changes within the floodplain that can significantly affect flood
      behaviour include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Development (including filling) within the floodplain (particularly in flow
            conveyance and flood storage areas);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Development within the catchment even though outside the
          floodplain; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Construction or upgrade of above ground infrastructure across
          waterways and the floodplain.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>These activities may result in significant changes to flood behaviour including changes
        to flow paths, peak flow and velocities, flood levels and extents, distribution of flood
        waters, and the timing and duration of flooding. These changes can lead to adverse impacts
        on the existing community and the built and natural environment and the built and natural
        environment through changes to flood behaviour and the ability of the community to
        effectively respond to flood emergencies.</para>

      <para>New developments and infrastructure projects generally have
      constraints placed on them through government approvals processes
      relating to negating or minimising adverse impacts of the project on
      existing development and the environment.</para>

      <para>Broader processes such as the floodplain specific management process
          <citation>b1_c5_r1+1</citation> often examine changes through scenario testing. These may
        be managed though floodplain, catchment or community based techniques as discussed in <xref
          linkend="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu"/>.</para>

      <para>However decisions on infrastructure projects, particularly those
      developed by entities that do not manage floodplain or catchment
      development, are often made without being able to influence development
      directions or mitigation efforts. Therefore decisions of infrastructure
      projects, may need to consider these potential changes as part of
      non-stationarity considerations as part of project investigations. This
      is discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_lsfw7"/> of this chapter.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_t5swv">
      <title>Managing Flood Risk by Limiting Likelihood and
      Consequences</title>

      <para>Approaches to managing the likelihood or consequences of flood
      risk on or to a community or asset generally fall into the following
      types:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use of design standards that relate to a particular flood
          event;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Providing a certain level of service; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Use of risk based management approaches.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Risk based management approaches are generally more complex than
      the use of design flood and level of service standards.</para>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_8pae4">
        <title>Design Flood Standards</title>

        <para>The establishment of design flood standards for infrastructure design and as a basis
          for minimum protection levels for the community have often been based upon decisions to
          reduce the frequency of exposure to risk. This involves a balance between protection of an
          asset or affected communities and stakeholders from an event against the cost of the
          infrastructure to provide protection.</para>

        <para>Design flood standards are generally aimed at limiting the
        frequency of exposure to flood risk. For example, the use of a minimum
        floor levels for a building relative to a design flood level aims to
        reduce the exposure to flooding by excluding flooding from above the
        floor level of the building in the design flood event. This approach
        is based upon accepting that consequences that result from the
        building flooding in events larger than the design flood event.</para>

        <para>Design flood standards are typically adopted across an entire
        floodplain, or government service area. Generally, there is only
        limited ability to incorporate location specific issues into the
        design flood standards.</para>

        <para>When used in isolation, this approach makes the assumption that the residual risks
          remaining after development is constructed to standards are acceptable. It also assumes
          that:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>the location is suitable for the development;</para></listitem>
              <listitem><para>the development will not impact upon flood behaviour and therefore have an
                adverse impact elsewhere in the community; and</para></listitem>
              <listitem><para>the impacts of flooding on the building and its occupants, including the
                associated residual risks, are acceptable or can be managed by other means.</para>
            
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Where used in isolation this can limit the effectiveness of this
        approach and may lead to decisions that leave individuals, communities
        and the built environment exposed to risks that may be considered
        unacceptable to the community.</para>

        <para>Design flood standards are also generally based upon existing
        floodplain, catchment and climatic conditions, what can be called
        stationary conditions. However, these conditions can change over time.
        Consideration in estimating design floods is discussed in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_s_yn0u3"/> to <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_0zoe7"/>.
        Further discussion on the factors that can lead to non-stationarity
        and current literature on non-stationary risk assessment is provided
        in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_lsfw7"/>.</para>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_367th">
          <title>Design Flood Standard Terminology</title>

          <para>There are two key ways in which design flood standards are
          typically expressed:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP): the likelihood of occurrence of a flood of
                a given size or larger in any one year; usually expressed as a percentage (eg. a
                flood protection levee may adopt of Flood Design Standard that offers protection up
                to the a 1% AEP
                event);<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103246+1100"?>
                and<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Service Life Exceedance Probability (SLEP): The likelihood
              of exceedance during a project’s adopted service life, rather
              than as an annual likelihood. It is recommended that this should
              be the Effective Service Life (<xref
              linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/>), rather than the Design Service
              Life.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>AUSTROADS, the national association of road transport and
          traffic authorities in Australia use both the SLEP approach and the
          AEP method depending on the context.</para>

          <para>The AEP method is used to define the levels of service of
          roads:</para>

          <para><quote>Freeways and arterial roads – should generally be designed to pass the 50 or
              100 year ARI flood without interruption to traffic. However for arterial roads in
              remote areas, a reduced standard is commonly adopted where traffic densities are low,
                <citation>b1_c5_r8+1</citation>.</quote></para>

          <para>The SLEP method is used in the design of bridges:</para>

          <para><quote>All bridges are to be designed so that they do not fail catastrophically
              during a flood that has a 5% chance of being exceeded during the Design Service Life
              of the structure. Assuming a 100 year Design Service Life, this equates to a flood
              with an ARI of 2000 years’ <citation>b1_c5_r8+1</citation>.</quote></para>

          <para>It is considered that while design standards are commonly expressed as an annual
            exceedance probability, it may be the case that stakeholders actually interpret and
            apply this more as a SLEP or an Exceedance Frequency over the adopted service life. For
            example, when stakeholders refer to a 1% AEP flood standard (floor level) for
            residential developments, conceptually they may interpret this to mean that the floor
            level for the property will only be exceeded once in every 100 years.</para>

          <para>The SLEP approach may be more readily understandable for short term or temporary
            structures (refer <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_6qrw1"/>). Similarly, where infrastructure may
            be particular susceptible to damage from overtopping (eg. a bridge superstructure that
            is not designed for inundation or a secondary spillway), then it may be important to
            understand the likelihood of being exceeded during the structure’s effective service
            life (discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/>).</para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_rz5ar">
        <title>Level of Service Standards</title>

        <para>Level of service standards are generally aimed at maintaining
        the serviceability during an event of a particular magnitude. For
        example, having a road trafficable in a design flood event of a
        certain AEP or having a waterway structure under the road pass the
        peak of a design flood event without overtopping the road. Considered
        in isolation, this approach assumes that the:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Road will not impact upon flood behaviour and have adverse
            impact on the community;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Impacts of flooding on the road are acceptable or can be
            managed by other means. For example, the road is expected to
            overtop and the design allows for damage minimisation or
            replacement in such events;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Level of service provided is acceptable. For example, loss
            of access along the road is expected during a flood event and this
            is considered in emergency management planning; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Residual risk remaining to the community is
            acceptable.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Similarly to design flood standards, the assumptions of this
        approach can limit its effectiveness, particularly where it is used in
        isolation.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_mfr1i">
        <title>Risk Based Decision Making Processes</title>

        <para>Risk based decision making processes (such as those outlined in
            <citation>b1_c5_r1<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103312+1100"?>+1<?oxy_insert_end?></citation>)
          are used to develop management strategies that consider the risks associated with a full
          range of potential flood events and the associated consequences to the community and its
          supporting built and natural environment. It can be used to:</para>
        <para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>manage the residual risks associated with design flood standards, or</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>for management of risks for non-standard and critical infrastructure where a
                broad design flood standard may not be appropriate.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </para>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_se7my">
          <title>Non-Standard or Critical Infrastructure</title>

          <para>Some examples of this type of infrastructure include:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Dam safety risks <citation>b1_c5_r6</citation>, and design of spillways and
                outlets;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Risk management decisions for projects with a relatively
              short time frame, such as construction projects as well as
              temporary infrastructure (such as a coffer dam during
              construction);</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Structures that are particularly susceptible to
              overtopping or inundation. For example, a bridge superstructure
              that cannot withstand active flow or impacts from debris, or a
              flood levee that is not designed for overtopping and will likely
              result in failure.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Critical infrastructure that may result in significant consequences should they
                fail or be inundated. This may include economically important infrastructure (for
                example transportation routes such as those between ports and major economic hubs,
                trunk communication networks (internet, phone) or key elements of the electricity
                network) or emergency response infrastructure (eg. hospitals, evacuation centres
                etc).</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>In undertaking a risk based design process to develop
          management strategies for non-standard and critical infrastructure,
          it is important to understand the stakeholders involved in the
          decision making process. In many cases, these stakeholders may have
          different risk preferences (risk averse versus risk accepting). For
          example, a mining company may have a different risk preference for
          inundation of a mine, versus the community preferences for flood
          impacts downstream of the mine. It will be important to fully
          understand these different preferences to assist in informing the
          appropriate mitigation measures that might be required as the same
          likelihood and consequences could lead to a higher risk
          categorisation where there is a risk averse rather than a risk
          accepting preference.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_3tttw">
          <title>Management of Residual Risk</title>
          <para>When examining risks to existing and future development within a community the
            approach can be used in a manner that is complementary to the use of design flood and
            levels of service standards by examining the residual risk to the community and
            examining whether additional risk management measures may be necessary. This approach
            may involve testing whether the design flood or level of service standard is appropriate
            in the circumstances or whether additional management measures may be warranted to
            address residual risks.</para>
          <para>For example, in a particular instance the use a design flood event as a standard for
            development within a community may reduce the frequency of exposure of people and
            property to flooding. However, additional management measures may be required to address
            residual risks. For example: </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>the degree of flood damage to new buildings built to design standards mean that
                risks to property remain high. This may result in consideration of the use of a
                larger design flood event as a standard for development or other damage reduction
                approaches to broadly reduce flood damages.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>limitations to the ability to effectively warn and evacuate the community during
                the available warning time may mean that risk to life may remain high.
                Implementation of options to reduce risks to life, such as: </para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Development or improvement of a flood warning system so the community can be
                    advised of a flood event and have more time to respond to calls for evacuation;
                    or </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Upgrade of evacuation routes to improve traffic capacity to enable the
                    community to be more effectively evacuate within the available warning
                    time.</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>the effect development has on flood behaviour outside the development area may
                be significant. This may result in the need to implement, additional management
                measures such as allowance in design for areas within the floodplain to continue to
                provide their essential flood conveyance and storage functions.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks to Communities</title>

    <para>Flooding has the potential to be the most manageable natural
    disaster as the location of flood impacts and its effect upon the
    community and the built and natural environment can be understood for the
    full range of events.</para>

    <para>Best practice in flood risk management in Australia <citation>b1_c5_r1</citation> works
      towards the vision:</para>

    <para><quote>Floodplains are strategically managed for the sustainable
    long-term benefit of the community and the environment, and to improve
    community resilience to floods.</quote></para>

    <para>Best practice promotes the consideration and, where necessary, management of flood impacts
      to existing and future development to improve community flood resilience using a broad risk
      management hierarchy of avoidance, minimisation and mitigation to: reduce the health, social
      and financial costs of occupying the floodplain; increase the sustainable benefits of using
      the floodplain, and improve or maintain floodplain ecosystems dependent on flood inundation
        <citation>b1_c5_r1</citation>.</para>

    <para>Managing flood risk provides an informed basis for the effective and
    efficient use of scare resources to:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Better understand flood risk;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Manage the growth in flood risk to the community due to the
        introduction of new development into the floodplain; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Reduce risks to the existing community where warranted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>This enables investment to be focused on understanding and managing
    flood risk where the need and benefit is greatest.</para>

    <para>Different treatment solutions may be necessary depending upon the
    element at risk (people, property and infrastructure) and the location.
    Treatment options may involve a combination of flood mitigation, emergency
    management, flood warning and community awareness, together with strategic
    and development scale land-use planning arrangements that consider the
    flood situation and hazards.</para>

    <para>Different options are also used dependent upon whether the aim is to manage risk to
      existing or future development within the community.</para>

    <para>For the existing development it is important to understand the current exposure of the
      community to the full range of flooding, how the associated risks to different elements within
      the community are currently being managed and whether changes would be required to reduce
      risks to a more acceptable level. Where treatment options to reduce risks are being considered
      the impacts these measures may have on flood behaviour need to be understood and considered in
      decision making.</para>

    <para>For flood risk to future development it is important to understand
    how the flood behaviour varies across the floodplain so that the
    constraints that this may place on development can be considered in
    deciding where to develop (and where not to develop), the types of
    development that may be suitable in different areas, and the flood related
    development constraints necessary to reduce risks to acceptable levels (in
    areas suitable for development).</para>

    <para>It is also important to consider how flood behaviour and the
    associated risk will change over time due to development in the catchment
    and due to climate change and its impacts on both sea level and the
    intensity of flood producing rainfall events (discussed in <xref
    linkend="b1_ch6"/>). Assessment of these changes on design flood estimates
    are discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_yn0u3"/> to <xref
    linkend="b1_ch5_s_0zoe7"/>.</para>

    <para>More information on understanding and managing flood risk is available in
        <citation>b1_c5_r1+1</citation>.</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_va2dn">
      <title>Using Flood Estimation to Inform Flood Risk Management</title>

      <para>Design flood estimation can support management of flood risk to the community by
        improving knowledge of the potential range of flood behaviour and providing tools and
        information to support decision making. The selection of a modelling approach needs to
        consider the capability the approach provides relative to the requirements of the project
        specification. Many management decisions, such as emergency management planning, rely upon
        an understanding of the full range of floods rather than a specific design event, and need
        time varying information across a whole event rather than just the peak of the event.
        Managing flood risk involves a range of different groups with different information needs
          <citation>b1_c5_r1+1,b1_c5_r2+1</citation>.</para>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_5meee">
        <title>Analysis of Historic Flood Events</title>

        <para>Managing flood risk to the community generally requires more
        knowledge than can be gained from historic flood events. The
        information available on historic flood events is generally incomplete
        and is unlikely to represent the full range of potential flood events.
        In addition, it is likely that there have been changes within the
        floodplain or catchment since the historic flood event occurred that
        would alter the behaviour or impacts of a flood of the same magnitude
        if it were to occur today.</para>

        <para>The use of historic flood event information in isolation without
        an understanding of the potential range and severity of flood events
        at a location and an understanding of how this may vary within a
        floodplain can result in poor management decisions – leaving the
        community unsustainably exposed to risk.</para>

        <para>Knowledge and experience of historic flood events provides a
        starting point for understanding flood risk. Modelling historic flood
        events can assist to:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Calibrate and validate models against known data and the
            community’s experience of flooding;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Better understand historic flood events by filling in gaps
            in our knowledge of flood behaviour and its variation along a
            watercourse and across the floodplain; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Understand the probability of floods of the scale of
            historic flood events being exceeded in future.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The consequences of historic flood events can also provide
        valuable information for understanding flood risk. An appropriately
        calibrated and validated model can provide a sound basis for updating
        of the model to current conditions in light of changes in the
        catchment and floodplain since historic flood events.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_9ffsp">
        <title>Analysis of Design Flood Estimates for Current
        Conditions</title>

        <para>Design flood estimates can be used for a range of purposes
        including:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Understanding flood behaviour (flow paths, distribution,
            velocity, depth, level, timing and length of inundation) and risk
            and how this varies across the floodplain, over the duration of a
            flood event, and between flood events of different
            magnitudes;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Understanding how flood behaviour, hazards and risks may
            change due to floodplain, catchment and climate changes;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Establishing design standards based upon a specific design
            event;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Assessing whether desired levels of service are met;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Making decisions on the need for risk treatment, comparing
            and assessing treatment options, and deciding on which options to
            implement; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Designing waterway structures, basins, levees and other
            treatment options.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Design flood estimation for the full range of flood behaviour
        provides the basis for assessing the frequency and severity of flood
        exposure of different parts of the floodplain and the consequences of
        flooding to the community,providing a spatial understanding of:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Flood extents to understand where floods of different
            magnitudes will impact;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The variation in the flood functions of flow conveyance and
            storage within the floodplain for key events. Areas with these
            functions are generally areas where change in topography,
            vegetation or development can significantly alter flood behaviour
            which may lead to detrimental impacts to the existing
            community;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The variation in hazard across the floodplain for key flood events (see <xref
                linkend="b9_ch8"/>). This can delineate where flood behaviour in events is hazardous
              to people, vehicles and buildings <citation>b1_c5_r3</citation>; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The variation in flood evacuation difficulty from areas within the floodplain
                <citation>b1_c5_r4</citation>.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Outputs from design flood estimation and flood risk management
        processes are essential in informing government and industry through
        input to information systems. This can improve the accessibility of
        information on flood risk so it can be considered in investment and
        management decisions by government, industry and the community.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_yn0u3">
        <title>Analysis of the Impacts of Changing Infrastructure on Design
        Flood Estimates</title>

        <para>Infrastructure crossing a floodplain can often provide some control on flood behaviour
          within a floodplain. Therefore the introduction of new infrastructure or modification of
          existing infrastructure crossing the floodplain can create or modify the flood controls
          within the floodplain which can influence flood behaviour and risk to the existing
          community.</para>

        <para>The significance of these impacts can be assessed by altering
        calibrated and validated models of existing conditions to allow for
        changes and assessing the associated impacts. Management of impacts
        can lead to modifying the design of the infrastructure in
        consideration of its impacts upon the community or examination of ways
        to offset impacts upon the community.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_txuh7">
        <title>Analysis of the Impacts of Changing Development on Design Flood
        Estimates</title>

        <para>Future development within the catchment can have significant
        impacts on flood risk to the existing community. The impacts of
        development can be assessed by modifying the calibrated and validated
        models of existing flood behaviour to allow for changes to flow
        conveyance, storage and runoff conditions within the catchment.</para>

        <para>The natural flood functions of flow conveyance and flood storage occur in flow
          conveyance and flood storage areas. Filling of flow conveyance areas can impact upon
          upstream flood levels and can result in redistribution of flows, with the potential for
          new flow paths being activated, affecting other areas. Filling of flood storage areas can
          affect both upstream and downstream flood levels. </para>
        <para>Any decision to modify the flow conveyance and flood storage characteristics of the
          floodplain need careful consideration as these ramifications can be significant. The
          significance of these impacts can be assessed by altering calibrated and validated models
          of existing conditions to allow for changes and assessing the associated impacts.
          Management of impacts can lead to modifying the allowable changes in these areas in
          consideration of its impacts upon the community.</para>

        <para>Flows at a downstream point in the catchment can also change
        significantly with upstream development within the catchment, even
        where flow conveyance and flood storage areas maintain their essential
        flood functions. These changes can occur due to increase in impervious
        areas and flow paths being shortened or having a higher proportion of
        impervious area. This can reduce losses leading to a higher proportion
        of rainfall running off and the time of concentration of flows within
        the catchment being reduced.</para>

        <para>Assessment of the potential cumulative impacts of such broad
        changes is best undertaken in community rather than development scale
        flood investigations. It can provide the basis for understanding the
        relative significance of this change and where considered significant,
        assessing options to offset these impacts on a catchment basis. For
        example impacts on peak flood flows may, in some cases, be able to be
        managed using centralised or strategic scale basins or distributed
        (development site related) treatment measures.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_0zoe7">
        <title>Analysis of Climate Change Impacts Upon Design Flood Estimates</title>

        <para>Climate change can have impacts on both flood producing rainfall
        events and on sea level and this can influence flood behaviour,
        frequency and impacts on the community in waterways. Assessment of the
        potential scale of impacts of climate change on flood producing
        rainfall events and its significance are discussed in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch6"/>.</para>

        <para>Sea level rise will directly influence ocean conditions that can influence flood
          behaviour in coastal waterways. Any rise in ocean conditions will directly translate to an
          increase in any relevant ocean boundary condition that is used in flood studies and will
          influence both the scale and balance of interaction of oceanic inundation with catchment
          flooding. <xref linkend="b6_ch5"/> provides information on the potential for coincidence
          of oceanic inundation and catchment or river flooding. Other guidance, such as OEH 2015
          for NSW, may also be relevant and need consideration in particular jurisdictions.</para>

        <para>The significance of these impacts of flood behaviour can be assessed by altering
          calibrated and validated models of existing conditions to allow for changes in flood
          producing rainfall events and the coincidence of oceanic inundation. Understanding these
          impacts can lead to an understanding of where they occur and whether management may be
          necessary. Management may involve strategies to allow for changes upfront or strategies
          that allow for adaptation over time.</para>

        <para>Climate change may also have influence on the effective service
        life of infrastructure. This is discussed in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/>.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_fd8ui">
      <title>Using Design Flood Estimation to Support Management of Future
      Development</title>

      <para>Flood risk to future development is primarily managed by
      incorporating consideration of flood risk and the associated constraints
      (<xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_va2dn"/>) into strategic planning and the
      relevant land use planning system.</para>

      <para>Land use planning systems often use a flood standard as a basis for many flood related
        controls and decisions. These systems may also consider changes in climate and the influence
        development within the catchment will have on flood behaviour. These considerations are
        often made in addition to existing conditions to provide an understanding of how changes may
        impact upon flood behaviour and the existing community.</para>

      <para>Systems may also require consideration of larger or extreme flood events to examine
        whether additional development constraints are necessary to deal with residual risks to the
        new development, particularly risk to life.</para>

      <para>As new development on the floodplain can impact upon flood
      behaviour and the flood risk faced by the existing community, land use
      planning systems generally require these impacts to be assessed and
      managed.</para>

      <para>Developing on the floodplain places the new development and its
      occupants at risk from flooding. These issues need to be considered in
      setting strategic directions for the community and determining
      development constraints.</para>

      <para>Design flood estimation provides essential information for
      understanding constraints (see <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_va2dn"/>) that
      need consideration in setting strategic land use planning directions for
      the community, including:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Information to inform decisions on where to (and where not to) develop and the
            limits on what type of development to place in different areas of the floodplain. For
            example, development within a flow conveyance area may have significant impacts upon
            flood behaviour or cause significant damage to structures. Development in this area
            should be restricted to enable the flow conveyance area to perform its natural flood
            function. A further example, such as an area with evacuation issues that is classified
            as flooded, isolated and submerged <citation>b1_c5_r3</citation> would not necessarily
            be an appropriate area for a development whose occupants may be vulnerable in emergency
            response and therefore difficult to evacuate eg. aged care facilities or a
            hospital;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The assessment of the cumulative impacts of development within
          the catchment and floodplain on flood flows and behaviour. For
          example, the assessment of the cumulative impacts of development of
          the catchment can enable the examination of catchment scale
          solutions to offset the impacts of development on flood flows in an
          efficient manner. Such solutions may include a single series of
          basins whose interaction is considered (see <xref
          linkend="b1_ch5_s_ih60o"/>); and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Information to inform the derivation and implementation of development constraints
            that reduce the residual flood risk to the new development and its occupants to an
            acceptable level.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Design flood estimation also provides essential information to
      inform consideration of individual development proposals through the
      planning system. Studies undertaken for specific developments generally
      aim to assess whether the development will have significant impacts upon
      existing flood behaviour and the flood risk of the existing community
      and the impacts of flooding on the proposed development site and the
      residual risks to the development and its occupants.</para>

      <para>For individual development proposals design flood estimation can
      advise on the:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Suitability of the specific location for development;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Suitability of the proposed development for the
          location;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Limits on the scale of development to limit impacts on the
          existing community; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Development conditions necessary to manage residual risk to the new development and
            its occupants and any impacts of the development upon the existing community.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Site specific studies do not generally provide advice for setting
      strategic land use direction of the community.</para>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_5mgkf">
        <title>How Can More Information Aid in Decision Making?</title>

        <para>Having more information on flood behaviour and on flood related
        constraints can support informed decision making. The example provided
        below in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t"/> and <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/> provides an example of how additional
        information on flood behaviour and factors that influence the risk to
        people and property can provide a better understanding of flood
        constraints so these can be considered in investment and development
        decisions.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t"/> shows the area affected by the
        design flood event used to set design standards for developments in
        the area. It does not provide any breakdown of the floodplain to
        highlight the varying flood function within this area, the varying
        degrees of hazard; or the differences in emergency response
        classification within the floodplain. Nor does it provide information
        on more frequent or more extreme floods. It therefore provides limited
        information for effective management.</para>

        <para>Using the information from <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t"/>
        alone, Locations A, B, C and D appear to be exposed to the same degree
        of risk. The availability of this limited information would, most
        likely, result in the same development restrictions being applied to
        each location.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t">
          <title>Map of Flood Extents</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1017.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>However, <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_uoebi"/> shows the same floodplain but with
        information on how flood hazard, flood function and the flood
        emergency response classification varies across the floodplain. This
        information shows the flood situations impacting upon Locations A to D
        to be different and may require different management
        treatments.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Location A is easy to evacuate and outside the impacts of
            flood function and flood conditions are not hazardous to
            buildings;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Location B is in a flow conveyance area and development may impact upon flood
              behaviour and the flood risk of others in the community;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Location C is isolated and completed inundated by larger
            floods and has a more difficult flood evacuation situation;
            and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Location D is similar to Location A but is an area where
            floods may be hazardous to houses and people.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>If these additional risk factors are considered in setting
        development constraints flood risk at a location can more effectively
        be managed at the different locations reducing the residual risks
        remaining. Mapping the constraints from <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_uoebi"/> can
        provide more clarity on where to apply different development controls
        as shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_6usjz">
          <title>Map of Flood Extents and Flood Function</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1018.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_iz3yu">
          <title>Map of Flood Extents and Flood Hazard</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1019.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_uoebi">
          <title>Map of Flood Extents and Flood Emergency Response
          Classification</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1020.png"
                ><?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20160616T163143+1000" comment="terminology to be consistent with National guideline =&gt; low flooded island = flooded isolated inundated etc"?></imagedata>
              <?oxy_comment_end?>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_0orhn">
          <title>Map of Variation in Constraints Across the Floodplain</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1021.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The additional information provided in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/>
        identifies additional risk factors in different locations without
        which:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The need to consider these additional risk factors in
            decision making may not be evident; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Where it has otherwise been recognised that these additional
            risk factors may need to be considered in decision making it is
            likely that any associated constraints would be applied broadly
            across the floodplain. This would require studies for individual
            developments to determine and address these risk factors.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The additional information provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_6usjz"/> to <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_f_0orhn"/> has the added benefit of enabling the provision of improved
          clarity for development conditions by enabling these to be more effectively inform land
          use planning systems. <citation>b1_c5_r50+1</citation> discusses the extension of this
          work as part of the development of best practice guidance on flood information to support
          land use planning being developed by the National Flood Risk Advisory Group and expected
          to be releases in the second half of 2016.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_vdya6">
      <title>Understanding and Treating Risk to the Existing Community</title>

      <para>In some cases the consequences of flooding and the associated
      risks may warrant changes to the existing treatment of flood risk in a
      community to reduce the residual risks to a more acceptable level. In
      other cases existing treatment of risk may be considered adequate for
      this purpose.</para>

      <para>Design flood estimation can provide the understanding of flood
      behaviour, and the drivers for this behaviour, across a range of flood
      events to support management of the flood risk. It can be combined with
      other information to:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Assess the consequences of flooding on the community and the
          natural and built environment. One quantitative measure of
          consequences is the estimation of flood damages. This section
          provides an example of the use of flood damage estimation in flood
          risk management;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Assess the impacts of floods on community infrastructure such
          as electricity, water supply, the sewerage system, medical
          facilities and emergency management infrastructure (evacuation
          routes and centres), and provide information to consider in recovery
          planning for the community; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Examine the effectiveness of treatment options to reduce this
          risk where warranted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_jhh3n">
        <title>Estimation of the Current Risk to a Community</title>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d"/> provides an example of a
        graphical representation of the variation of risk to the different
        elements (people, community, property) over the full range of flood
        behaviour for a particular floodplain. This can involve both
        qualitative and quantitative estimates of consequences for different
        flood events to determine risk levels using the example risk matrix
        provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_t_5ke0w"/>.</para>

        <para>In this example, for events more frequent than a 10% AEP event
        the consequences to people, and the community are insignificant and
        therefore risks are low. However, the consequences for property are
        minor and therefore risk is medium. Consequences to people are major
        for floods rarer than the 10% AEP flood event. Consequences to
        property rise to major in unlikely, rare, very rare events and
        extremely rare floods. Impacts upon the community and its supporting
        infrastructure are moderate for events greater than the 10% AEP and do
        not reach major levels.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d">
          <title>Example of Estimated Average Risk to a Community Due to
          Flooding</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1022.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d"/> shows the risks to people and
        property for events between a 10% and 0.01% AEP event. The risk to the
        community is low except in floods between a 10% and 0.01% AEP event
        where they are medium.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_vh7ar">
        <title>Estimating Flood Damages to an Existing Community</title>

        <para>One of the ways to quantitatively assess impacts to the
        community is to estimate flood damages. This generally involves an
        aggregation of estimates of flood damages on individual properties
        considering both direct costs (damages to structures and their
        content) and indirect costs (such as clean-up and disposal or
        materials, loss of earnings, sales and production, temporary
        relocation expenses) and an allowance for or estimate of
        infrastructure damages. However, it is important to note that this
        typically does not incorporate all risk factors, such as risk to life,
        and these additional risk factors may need to be accounted for through
        a qualitative assessment.</para>

        <para>A range of methods are used to derive damages for individual
        properties. These include:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis>Rapid assessment techniques</emphasis> - which
            rely on flood extents to determine the number of properties of
            different development types (residential, commercial and
            industrial) affected and apply a fixed damage per property.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis>Techniques based upon the use of stage damage curves</emphasis> - for
              different development types and in some cases styles and sizes of buildings (an
              example for residential buildings derived from <citation>b1_c5_r11+1</citation> is
              provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_u3eyu"/>). This technique provides for variation
              in damage to structures and yards and their contents with depth above ground level and
              structure floor level. Approaches, such as this allow for the use of representative
              buildings within the floodplain. Whereas other approaches may require the style and
              size of houses to be determined and individual buildings to be considered in more
              detail.</para>

            <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_u3eyu">
              <title>Indicative Stage Damage Curve for some Residential House
              Types</title>

              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1023.png"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </figure>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para><emphasis>Note: There are many different stage damage curve relationships for
            residential development. Different damage relationships also exist for different types
            of development (eg. commercial and industrial). These may be determined based upon the
            use of historical damage, insured loss information or based upon building component
            damage at different depths. However, no definitive set of curves exist and work in this
            area continues to evolve. Commercial and industrial damages can be very complex given
            the changing nature of the occupation of individual sites. The damage to the structure
            of the building will not generally change significantly with use but the contents damage
            can vary significantly. For example, the same light industrial storage area could house
            aluminium cans for recycling or computer components for assembly and therefore the
            damages to contents due to flooding would vary greatly. </emphasis></para>

        <para>Assessment based upon stage damage curves requires information
        on flood extents to determine which properties are affected and flood
        levels. This information can be used with location, ground level and
        structure floor level information (determined using survey or
        approximation methods) to estimate damages at an individual site.
        These can then be aggregated to estimate damages to a community or
        area.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc"/> provides an example of an
        aggregated flood damage curve across the full range of flood events
        for a community. This provides a quantitative understanding of the
        impacts of flooding upon the community and the built environment. It
        can also provide a baseline for considering the benefits of management
        options or infrastructure projects. Each point on the flood damage
        curve has a probability of exceedance in any given year. Examining
        this curve shows that there is no damage in a 20% AEP event with
        damage in the 0.5% AEP event being approximately $20 Million.</para>

        <para>To use this information for flood risk management, particularly
        when examining the benefits of management measures, this information
        needs to be translated into an Annual Average Damage (AAD). This is
        achieved by determining the area under the curve. <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/> provides an example of calculation of
        Annual Average Damages based upon the flood damage curve in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc"/>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc">
          <title>Example of Flood Damage Curve for a Range of AEP Flood
          Events</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1024.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_58cna">
        <title>Assessing Options to Treat Flood Risk</title>

        <para>Where treatment options are proposed that may change flood behaviour the calibrated
          and validated models that define the existing flood situation need to be altered to
          incorporate proposed treatment options and design flood estimates developed for the
          changed conditions.</para>

        <para>Comparing this information to the existing flood situation can
        indicate changes in flood behaviour, and in combination with other
        information, changes in the consequences of flooding on the community.
        Flood extents, flood function, flood hazard and emergency response
        classification and damages may alter for specific areas and different
        design flood events. Where changes in behaviour are significant there
        are likely to be areas where flood impacts are reduced and other areas
        where they may be increased. These changes in consequence can be used
        to assess the benefits and costs to the community and the limitations
        of the treatment option.</para>

        <para>Section 9.4 and Table 9.3 of
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103444+1100"?><citation>b1_c5_r1+1</citation><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103444+1100" content="&lt;emphasis&gt;&lt;citation&gt;b1_c5_r1+1&lt;/citation&gt;&lt;/emphasis&gt;"?>
          outline some of the issues that should be considered when selecting and comparing
          treatment options. The benefits and costs of treatment options may be assessed singularly
          as well as in combination with complimentary measures as it is rare for a single treatment
          option used in isolation to effectively manage flood risk to a community. For example, a
          levee may be built to reduce flood damage in a town in combination with a flood warning
          system to provide additional warning and upgraded evacuation routes to improve community
          safety during floods.</para>

        <para>One quantitative way of determining the financial efficiency of
        the project involves understanding the benefits in reduction in flood
        damages and comparing this to the costs of achieving and maintaining
        this benefit. A reduction in flood damages can be assessed by
        determining the reduction in Annual Average Damages and exposure of
        the community to flooding with treatment options in place. For example
        the use of minimum floor levels based upon the 1% AEP flood for new
        development, or a levee designed to exclude a 1% AEP flood from an
        existing flood affected area will reduce flood damages for events up
        to but not exceeding the design flood event (in this case 1% AEP
        event). However, the consequences of floods rarer than the design
        floods may not change significantly and there may still be substantial
        impacts upon the community.</para>

        <para>Annual Average Damages calculated across the full range of flood
        events provides a sound basis for understanding the financial benefits
        and limitations of the project so this can be considered in decision
        making and enables the calculation of Annual Average Benefits.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_hkk27"/> provides an example of the
        estimation of the financial benefits of a treatment option. It shows
        the damage curve for the same flood situation as shown in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_b5vlc"/> but both without any treatment and with a
        treatment option in place.</para>

        <para>In this example the treatment option is a levee. The aim of the
        levee is to reduce flood damages and the frequency of community
        exposure to flooding and associated risks for events up to the design
        flood event, in this case the 1% AEP event. Whilst there are some
        benefits for rarer floods these can be seen to diminish quickly in
        rarer events. In a 0.2% AEP event the damages with and without the
        treatment options would be the same.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_hkk27">
          <title>Example of Flood Damage With and Without Treatment Options
          for a Range of AEP Flood Events</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1025.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The reduction in Average Annual Damages (AAD) or the Average
        Annual Benefit (AAB) can be used to determine the net present value of
        the benefits. An example is provided in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_s_13ov6"/>.</para>

        <para>This can then be compared with the Net Present Value (NPV) of life cycle costs of the
          treatment options to determine the Benefit Cost Ratio (BCR), which provides a measure of
          the financial efficiency of the project. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_4u178"/> provides an
          example of estimation of Net Present Value of life cycle costs.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5"/> provides an example of
        estimation of the Benefit Cost Ratio. Lifecycle costs and lifecycle
        benefits for individual years are shown in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_g9f34"/>. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_dvpu3"/> shows the
        same figures altered under current day dollars assuming a 7% discount
        rate.</para>

        <para>The Benefit Cost Ratio calculated can be used in conjunction
        with consideration of other benefits, such as reduction in risk to
        life, reduction in the impacts upon community function and
        infrastructure and with similar information for other treatment
        options (including those providing protection for different AEP
        events) to inform decisions on managing risk.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_g9f34">
          <title>Example of Annual Lifecycle Benefits and Costs</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1026.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_dvpu3">
          <title>Example of Lifecycle Benefits and Costs Adjusted to Todays $
          Using a 7% Discount Rate</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1027.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_fkw4r"/> re-examines the risks
        identified in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_0dw0d"/> to highlight how these
        have changed through the implementation of treatment options to
        provide protection for the 1% AEP event. This example shows a
        reduction in risk to property from a maximum of high to a maximum of
        medium in events above a 1% AEP event but low in events less than the
        design event.</para>

        <para>However, risk to people is still high due to the impacts of
        events greater than the 1% AEP event. This may warrant additional
        treatment options being considered which, depending upon why this risk
        remains high, may include flood warning systems, improved emergency
        management planning and improvements to evacuation routes.</para>

        <para>Note: there is no change to the risks in extreme events. The risk to property has been
          reduced in rare events due to the reduction in damages as a result of risk management
          measures.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_fkw4r">
          <title>Example of Estimating Changing Average Risk to a Community
          Due to Flooding with Instigation of a Treatment Option</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1028.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_zha4n">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks to Mining, Agricultural and Infrastructure
    Projects</title>

    <para>As well as considering flood risks for existing and future
    development within communities as discussed above, the interaction of
    mining, agricultural and infrastructure (particularly linear above ground
    infrastructure such as road and rail embankments and levees) require
    management. Where located in the floodplain, these developments
    are:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Susceptible to flood risk; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>May impact upon flood behaviour with detrimental impact to
        others in the community.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>In many cases, a design flood standard may not be available or
    appropriate, and a risk management approach as described in <xref
    linkend="b1_ch5_s_mfr1i"/> may need to be undertaken. A general overview
    of some of the issues to be considered are included in <xref
    linkend="b1_ch5_s_vl7nv"/> to <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_8f4m9"/>.</para>

    <para>Some of these projects or related projects with building of
    infrastructure can be considered short term projects due to their short
    term exposure to risk. Assessment of the risks associated with short term
    projects is discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_6qrw1"/>.</para>

    <para>In the same way that short term projects need special consideration,
    potential changes over the effective service life may need to be
    considered specifically for longer term infrastructure. Effective service
    life is discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/>, while potential
    implications of changes over the life of the project are discussed in
    <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_lsfw7"/>.</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_vl7nv">
      <title>Mines</title>

      <para>Mines developed in the floodplain may require levees or similar
      flood mitigation measures. These levees need to be designed to an
      appropriate level of flood immunity and may also have an impact on flood
      levels outside the levee. The risk and potential damage caused by flood
      inundation both inside and outside the mine needs to be analysed, with a
      similar process to that used for community development discussed in
      <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu"/>.</para>

      <para>There are usually key issues of concern for the mine:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Risks associated with inundation of the mine and its operations. The risk for mining
            may be from flooding of the mine pit, emplacements, infrastructure, machinery or
            underground workings, which may disrupt production, damage equipment and result in a
            risk to life<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103518+1100"?>;
            and<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Risks associated with changes to flood behaviour for
          communities upstream or downstream. The risk may be associated with
          changes in flood behaviour, potential significant erosion and
          sedimentation deposits, polluted water from tailings dams
          etc.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The key difference between the two elements is that there will
      generally be two distinct groups of stakeholders in the risk assessment.
      These different stakeholders may have different risk profiles and this
      will need to be considered as a part of the assessment. Risks associated
      with the inundation of the mine will be typically be associated with the
      mining company, which may also incorporate workers’ unions and insurance
      companies. Risks associated with the community may be associated with
      government, the local community, community interest and environmental
      groups.</para>

      <para>As a result of these different stakeholders, the risks and
      associated risk profiles may need to be considered separately. There is
      also unlikely to be specific design flood standards associated with
      inundation of the mine, as it may be more driven by acceptable closure
      periods etc. Therefore, a full risk assessment (<xref
      linkend="b1_ch5_s_mfr1i"/>) may be required to derive appropriate
      management measures.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_hq7rq">
      <title>Agriculture</title>

      <para>Flooding in agricultural regions can have concerns for crops,
      livestock and infrastructure. Crops may be damaged by inundation either:
      directly by floodwaters; or due to the extended period of inundation
      (where crops may be susceptible to longer term rather than short term
      inundation). Livestock may be lost if unable to be relocated to areas
      outside flood limits.</para>

      <para>In order to determine appropriate risk mitigation measures for
      agriculture, the specific implications for livestock and crops need to
      be considered, and the risk assessment will need to incorporate these
      factors. In addition, agricultural infrastructure such as irrigation
      pipes, fences, buildings and machinery may be damaged and these can have
      significant value. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_mfr1i"/> provides guidance on
      determining appropriate mitigation measures incorporating some of these
      different factors.</para>

      <para>In some areas of high value agriculture, the farm land may be
      protected by levees (or other infrastructure) and these have similar
      issues to levees built for other flood mitigation purposes. The
      appropriate protection level of these infrastructure would be based on a
      risk assessment considering the above factors, as well as potential
      impacts to the community upstream and downstream.</para>

      <para>The key stakeholder groups for undertaking a risk assessment may
      include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The farming operation(s) who will be directly impacted by the
            flooding<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103527+1100"?>;
            and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T103527+1100" content="."?></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Community both upstream and downstream, who may be represented
          by local government, community interest groups, environmental groups
          etc.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_8f4m9">
      <title>Road and Rail Projects</title>

      <para>Road and rail embankments are built across floodplains in many situations. To ensure a
        suitable level of flood immunity, the infrastructure will be built on embankments which will
        usually cross watercourses. In this case, the infrastructure must be designed to ensure a
        suitable level of service (ie. considering the acceptable degree of disruption to transport
        services for the route), as well as withstand an acceptable risk of damage from scour,
        submergence, or overtopping of structures. The consideration of disruption to transport
        depends not only on the frequency of closure, or flood immunity, but also on the duration of
        closures, both during large floods and as an annual aggregate.</para>

      <para>It also needs to consider the intended function of a road during a flood event,
        particularly where it has an important role in community evacuation or recovery plans.
        Design of embankments associated with these structures requires analysis of the road or rail
        level as well as the sizes, locations and types waterway openings. This is to ensure an
        acceptable level of flood immunity, duration of closure and damage from floods as well as an
        acceptable impact on upstream flood levels. Discussion of flood assessment and flood risk
        for road and rail projects can be found in the Austroads Guide to Road Design – Part 5 (Drainage)<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T134920+1100"?><footnote>
          <para>http://www.austroads.com.au/road-construction/road-design/resources/guide-to-road-design</para>
        </footnote><?oxy_insert_end?>.<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T134920+1100" content="&lt;footnote&gt;&lt;para&gt;http://www.austroads.com.au/road-construction/road-design/resources/guide-to-road-design&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/footnote&gt;"?></para>

      <para>Key stakeholders may involve:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Relevant road authority;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Community groups, potentially represented by local government, community interest
            groups etc;<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T134927+1100"?>
            and<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Relevant emergency response authorities and groups.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_6qrw1">
      <title>Short Term Projects</title>

      <para>Short term or temporary projects are those that will only have a
      limited effective service life (refer <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/>).
      Some examples might include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Construction projects. For example, a coffer dam protecting an
          excavated area for a period of 6 months;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A planned festival or community event in the floodplain, which occurs over a 2 day
            period;<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T134935+1100"?>
            and<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Short term mining operations. For example, a levee to protect
          a portion of a quarry for a period of 3 months.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>With short term projects, it is particularly important to
      understand the likelihood component of the risk assessment as well as
      the effective service life (refer <xref
      linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/>).</para>

      <para>Flood design standards are typically developed for long term
      projects and are based on an assumed effective service life that is
      generally many years. For example, a residential house might have an
      effective service life of 50 years. Therefore, when a 1% AEP design
      flood standard is adopted for the floor level, for example, that is
      equivalent to an approximate 39% chance that the floor level will be
      exceeded during the effective service life (using a SLEP terminology, as
      identified in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_8pae4"/>).</para>

      <para>However, if a 1% AEP flood design level is adopted for a coffer dam for excavation for
        an effective service life of 6 months (ie. a 6 month construction period), then the chance
        that it will be exceeded will be roughly 0.5% during its service life. Therefore, assuming
        that the consequences remain the same, then the risk profile is significantly more
        conservative. If a 39% chance of exceedance during its effective service life was assumed to
        be more appropriate, then that would be equivalent to somewhere between a 50% and a 100% AEP
        event.</para>

      <para>Therefore, a SLEP approach to flood design standards and flood
      levels can be more readily understandable for short term
      infrastructure.</para>

      <para>However, a full risk assessment will typically be required to
      understand all the likelihoods and consequences and therefore the risks.
      For example, the risk to life for a coffer dam may be significant where
      sufficient warning is not available.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_23w6l">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks in Relation to Dams</title>

    <para>The guidelines relevant to dam safety is provided by <citation>b1_c5_r6+1</citation>.
      These guidelines provide an over-arching framework that integrates risk assessment with
      traditional standards-based engineering practice. They provide guidance on the generic steps
      involved in undertaking risk assessment for dams, and these are updated periodically with
      changing understanding and practice.</para>

    <para>The dams industry has used risk assessment over the past two decades as a valuable means
      to establish upgrade priorities and justify the urgency of completing dam safety actions in a
      transparent and rational manner. However, the national ANCOLD guidelines only support risk
      assessment as an enhancement to traditional standards-based solutions for important and
      conclusive decision making.
      <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20160616T163446+1000" comment="has this been revised"?>The
      guidelines are currently being revised, and it is likely that there will be an increased focus
      on the use of risk-based criteria for final decision making in accordance with changing
      practice (for example, NSW Dam Safety Committee,
      2006)<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T135332+1100"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T135327+1100" content="&lt;citation&gt;b1_c5_r10&lt;/citation&gt;"?><?oxy_comment_end?></para>
    <para>One of the key differences between dam safety management and floodplain management is the
      probability domain of interest: the scale and nature of life safety risks posed by dams are
      generally considerably greater than encountered in floodplain management. The tolerable risks
      associated with these potential consequences are three to four orders of magnitude rarer than
      those associated with natural floods. The concept of annualising a high consequence risk based
      on a 10<superscript>-6</superscript> loading condition is mathematically straightforward, but
      such analyses are not easily combined with more common risks and have little practical
      utility.</para>

    <para>Accordingly, risk assessment for dam safety is focussed on reducing
    the risks to life (and property) to as low a level as reasonably
    practicable. It is unusual for dam safety decisions to be governed by the
    need to balance the costs of upgrading works against damages avoided, and
    more typically such decisions are dominated by life-safety
    considerations.</para>

    <para>The most relevant guidance on dam safety in this document is
    provided in <xref linkend="book8"/>. This provides guidance on the
    procedures most relevant to the extreme flood risks of interest. It also
    includes procedures relevant to estimation of the Probable Maximum Flood,
    which represents the upper limiting magnitude of flood is relevant to
    standards-based decision making.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_ih60o">
    <title>Managing Flood Risks using Basins</title>
    <para>Basins can have an important role in reducing downstream flood flows and associated flood
      risks to the community. They may be built to manage existing community flood problems or to
      offset the impacts of upstream development on downstream flood risk. A basin may be used in
      isolation or as part of a series of basins within a catchment to reduce peak design flood
      flows and risks for the design event(s) at key downstream locations. The design performance
      requirement is therefore generally either:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>To reduce peak flows for a certain design event(s) to a certain maximum amount. For
          example, for a basin designed to offset the impacts of upstream new development this may
          be the pre-development peak downstream flow. For a basin designed to reduce downstream
          flood impacts this may be to reduce peak basins discharges to a level that reduces flood
          impacts on the downstream community to an agreed level; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>To maximise the potential benefit of a basin at the location on downstream flood
          behaviour to reduce impacts on the community.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>An effectively designed basin has to balance restriction of outlet capacity with having
      available storage capacity near the peak of a flood event. This enables the peak of flood
      flows to be stored and the stored volume discharged later in the event, as illustrated in the
      example in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_sj0ig"/>.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_sj0ig">
      <title>Example of Impacts of a Basin on Flood Flows in a Design Event</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20160616T163520+1000" comment="diagrams could be smoothed - originals were rough
"?>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1029.png"/>
          <?oxy_comment_end?>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>This can significantly alter the critical storm duration with the peak flood flow entering
      a basin likely to be derived from a shorter duration storm than the peak discharge flow from
      the basin. Storm pattern can also have a significant impact on basin operation and the storage
      volume available when the peak of flood flows arrives. For example, if the peak arrives later
      in the storm the available storage volume may be lower and therefore the basin may have less
      impact on downstream peak flows.</para>
    <para>In addition, critical storm durations are also likely to vary with the AEP of the flood
      being modelled. It is not unusual for the peak basin discharge in a more frequent flood than
      the design event to occur in a longer duration storm event as storm volumes are lower and the
      basin storage will have more impact upon peak discharge. However, for events larger than the
      design event the opposite is true. There is likely to be less storage volume available at the
      storm peak so it will have less influence on peak basin discharge. Therefore the critical
      downstream discharge from rarer events than the design event will likely occur from shorter
      duration storms. For extreme events this is likely to be closer to the critical storm duration
      at the location without the basin.</para>
    <para>Therefore with a basin in place the peak downstream flood flow is sensitive to both the
      storm duration and the storm pattern and the routing of flows through the basin. As such basin
      design can be particularly sensitive to both storm temporal pattern and critical storm
      duration.</para>
    <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20160616T163558+1000" comment="need some words on the benefits of new techniques in adressing this issue"?>
    <para>Robust design approaches for basins that test and consider a wide range of storm durations
      and a range of potential variations of storm pattern for each of these storm durations are
      recommended for the full range of flood events. Variations in storm pattern should include
      testing of early, centrally and late weighted storm patterns for the same time duration to
      test whether the basin can meet the required design criteria with this
      variation.<?oxy_comment_end?></para>
    <para>Other key points to consider in modelling and designing detention basins include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Considering the impacts of events larger than the design event</emphasis>
          -The basin will generally be designed to reduce flood flows in a particular design event.
          However, in the majority of cases it is unlikely to have significant impacts on peak flows
          in extreme events. This can mean that there is a significantly larger difference between
          the extreme and design event flows entering and discharging the basin. <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_f_m2dve"/> provides an example. This situation is likely to result in a
          faster rate of rise of downstream flood levels for events larger than the design event (as
          these events result in high level spillway operation) than would have occurred without the
          basin. It is essential that this difference is understood and considered in basin and high
          level outlet design to manage the flood risk downstream of the basin. Residual risk
          downstream of the basin, including any limitations in emergency response and associated
          planning, needs to be considered and may require additional management measures including
          flood warning, community awareness, flood related development controls;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Upstream impacts of basins</emphasis> - The construction of a basin can also
          have significant upstream impacts on flood behaviour and these are an important
          consideration in the design of a basin. This should be examined for the full range of
          flood events to ensure that any impacts on upstream flood risk and the management of this
          risk (including emergency management planning) are understood;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Detentions basins act as dams during flood events</emphasis> - Therefore,
          basin design needs to consider dam safety aspects as discussed in <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_23w6l"/> and <xref linkend="book8"/>; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The use of multiple basins in a catchment </emphasis>- Where multiple basins
          are designed to provide more strategic benefits, ie., away from the downstream boundary of
          their individual locations they should be designed on a catchment wide basis to ensure
          their interaction does not result in adverse impacts upon flood behaviour. Use of multiple
          basins in a catchment without consideration of interaction has the potential to result in
          adverse impacts on flood behaviour.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_m2dve">
      <title>Example of Difference in Impacts of a Basin on Flood Flows in a Design Event Compared
        to an Extreme Event</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1030.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_p71ax">
    <title>Effective Service Life of Infrastructure</title>

    <para>The longer the operational life of an infrastructure proposal is,
    the greater the potential for changes to occur in terms of risk, in terms
    of likelihood and consequences due to either changes in the catchment or
    floodplain or climatic changes. Typically, the duration of a proposal may
    be considered in terms of:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Economic Service Life</emphasis> - The
        total period to the time when the asset, whilst physically able to
        provide a service, ceases to be the lowest cost option to satisfy the
        service requirement;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Design Service Life (DSL)</emphasis> -
        The total period an asset has been designed to remain in use;
        or</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Effective Service Life (ESL)</emphasis>
        - The total period an asset remains in use, regardless of its Design
        Service Life.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Currently most guidelines are based around evaluating design service life. However, the
      difference between the ESL and DSL can be significant and should be recognised in risk
      assessment of a proposal (<xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_jfne3"/>).</para>

    <para>ESL can be enhanced by factors which increase life such as
    maintenance, or diminished due to factors that reduce life such as
    significant weather events. It is considered that a proposal’s ESL is of
    primary importance in risk assessment and should be considered in
    evaluating risk and setting design flood standards.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_jfne3">
      <title>Design Service Life versus Effective Service Life (derived from
      United States Environment Protection Agency – 2007)</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1039.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_17eqs">
      <title>Estimating Effective Service Life</title>

      <para>The effective service life of a particular project may be
      difficult to estimate. The following conditions are likely to lead to
      the effective service life extending past the design service
      life:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Magnitude of infrastructure –</emphasis> very large
            infrastructure projects are more likely to remain in place longer than smaller projects
            (eg. bridges, dams), due to the difficulties in replacing them;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">High decommissioning or replacement costs –</emphasis> where
            decommissioning or replacement costs are high there may be strong economic incentives to
            continue utilisation of the project (eg. buried pipes within an urban environment);
            or</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Integrated development – </emphasis> where the project forms
            part of a broader piece of infrastructure or on-going service there may be economic
            incentives to continue utilisation of the project, particularly where a change to one
            component would require a change to others (eg. road alignment – a road may be
            reconstructed/ rehabilitated over time, but due to other constraints, will not be able
            to be changed in terms of elevation or geometry).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Determining the effective service life of infrastructure is complex as it is a product
        of infrastructure design, materials, environment, maintenance and rehabilitation regime and
        use. For example, exposed infrastructure (eg. roads) typically has a lower service life in
        tropical climates than in sub-tropical climates. Similarly, pipes that lie below a water
        table typically have shorter service lives than pipes that lie above a water table. The rate
        of degradation of construction material (eg. metal, plastic pipes) will also vary with
        circumstance (eg. saline vs non-saline conditions). Maintenance and rehabilitation of
        infrastructure may also seek to extend a project’s expected service life (for example, a
        lining installed in a stormwater pipe).</para>

      <para><xref linkend="b1_ch5_t_cgoco"/> summarises some of the typical
      life expectancies (and range in life expectancies) for various
      infrastructure types. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_t_cgoco"/> shows that the
      range within and between infrastructure is high. Within Australia, data
      for long-lived assets is limited as the majority of the infrastructure
      has not yet reached its effective service life.<table frame="void"
          xml:id="b1_ch5_t_cgoco">
          <caption>Infrastructure types and potential Effective Service
          Life<footnote>
              <para>Data represents a synthesis and interpretation of a number
              of reports including: IPART (2012), Cardno (2014), USEPA (2014),
              International Transport Forum (2013), Tonkin (2009).</para>
            </footnote></caption>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Infrastructure</th>

              <th>Effective Service Life expectancy</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Water Treatment Plants</td>

              <td>20 - 50 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Concrete Kerb and Gutters</td>

              <td>40 - 70 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Stormwater Pipes</td>

              <td>80 - 100 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Wastewater Systems</td>

              <td>50 - 80 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Residential Buildings</td>

              <td>40 - 95 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Roads</td>

              <td>35 - 110 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Commercial Buildings</td>

              <td>15 - 150 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Open Stormwater Channels</td>

              <td>10 - 100 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Locks and Weirs</td>

              <td>40 - 200 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Dams</td>

              <td>50 - 500 years</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>

      <para>For projects which have a relatively short design / effective service life (eg. less
        than five years), it may be reasonable to assume the risk profiles faced are static for the
        duration of the project as the likelihood or magnitude of changes to any risks may be
        negligible in comparison to the overall risk level. In contrast, longer life-span projects
        will be exposed to a higher level of non-stationary risk which could be considered in
        design.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_lsfw7">
    <title>Estimating Change in Risk over Time</title>

    <para>Conditions in floodplain are not static. They vary over both in the
    short and long term and can affect the likelihood or the consequences of
    flooding. Some of these potential changes (or sources of non-stationarity)
    are discussed below.</para>

    <para><quote>In many cases, flood studies reflect current conditions at best, and more likely
        past conditions since the studies often rely on old data …. …..flood risk criteria used to
        site and design a project should rely on conditions the location is likely to experience
        during the project’s lifetime, not past or current conditions.</quote>
      <citation>b1_c5_r49</citation>.</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_7n4tj">
      <title>Changes to Likelihood</title>

      <para>The likelihood of given magnitude events occurring may change over
      time due to a large number of variables including:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Seasonality -</emphasis> the
          seasonality can alter the statistical likelihood of flood events
          occurring as some events. For instance some catchments tend to have
          are prone to flooding associated with summer climates;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Climatic Variability</emphasis> -
          Various weather patterns such as El Niño influence the likelihood of
          flooding. El Niño events have a life-cycle during which the impacts
          vary, both in terms of spatial extent and timing;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Evolving hydrological / hydraulic
          estimates</emphasis> - The likelihood of a given magnitude flood
          event can vary significantly due to evolving hydrological /
          hydraulic estimates. For instance expected peak flows derived from
          flood frequency analysis can be altered by revisions made to the
          rating table or by extending the record length to include / exclude
          extreme events; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Climate Change -</emphasis>
          Fundamental changes in the climate will alter the likelihood of
          flooding. This is discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_0zoe7"/> and
          <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Changes within the catchment and
          floodplain that alter flood flows and flowpaths</emphasis> . This is
          discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_txuh7"/>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>This section discussed the first 3 dot points.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_69rjz">
      <title>Changes to Consequence</title>

      <para>Consequences of given magnitude flood events can change due to a
      wide range of variables including:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Land-use change – change to a more vulnerable land use or to
          the degrees of exposure of development to flooding.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Economic changes such as inflation.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Changes to the community exposed to risk through long term or
          seasonal changes in the total population or its demographics. For
          example increases in population at holiday destinations and during
          festivals. A change in community demographics to include a higher
          proportion of people more vulnerable in emergency response can lead
          to increased consequences due to a flood.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>level of flood awareness / education in the community. The
          higher the level of community awareness of flooding the more the
          community will be to flood risk due to both their understanding of
          the need to and how to respond to a flood and the knowledge that
          they may need to take measures, such as having flood insurance to
          address some of their residual risk to flooding.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_dhysi">
      <title>Changes to Risk Preference</title>

      <para>Further, it is noted that, just as the components of risk
      (likelihood and consequence) may vary over time, so to an individual’s
      evaluation of the ultimate importance of that risk may alter. This may
      occur through:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Altered risk profiles –</emphasis> Individuals tolerance for
            risk varies with their past and recent experience community attitudes to flood risk can
            vary significantly before and after a flood event; or</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Risk discounting –</emphasis> The
          value of a risk realised at a future time is typically considered of
          less significance than a risk realised at a current time. The rate
          at which this is applied may vary over time; typically the discount
          rate used reflects the economic discount rate in financial
          systems.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_rxmpg">
      <title>Literature</title>

      <para>There is a range of literature that discusses how changes over time non-stationarity can
        be applied in risk assessments. Much of the work to date has occurred in the academic space
        (such as those of <citation>b1_c5_r24,b1_c5_r7,b1_c5_r25</citation>). This work indicates
        that there is potential for non-stationary models to be incorporated into design
        considerations and that the scale of catchment change may be of sufficient magnitude in some
        catchments to warrant consideration in design criteria. However, the costs of developing
        such models and assessments is likely to be prohibitive and unnecessary for the majority of
        flood- affected infrastructure, and that utilisation of traditional static risk profiles
        remains the more appropriate form of assessment.</para>

      <para>For example, a method for incorporating design flood standards and design life into risk
        assessments is presented in <citation>b1_c5_r24</citation>. The paper proposes two methods
        to quantify risk for engineering design in a changing climate:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The Design Life Level aims to achieve a desired probability of exceedance (or risk
            of failure) during the Design Service Life. This method is a SLEP approach (<xref
              linkend="b1_ch5_s_367th"/>); or</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The Minimax Design Life Level is closely related, and
          complementary, but instead focuses on the maximal yearly probability
          of exceedance during the Design Service Life. This method is an AEP
          based approach.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The Design Life Level uses a Generalised Extreme Value (GEV)
      cumulative distribution function (cdf) to present the extremes in year
      <emphasis role="italic">t</emphasis>, and with increasing location and
      scale parameters (the shape parameter is constant) related to <emphasis
      role="italic">t</emphasis>, the probability changes. The example likens
      the increase in location parameter to a possible increase in water
      level, and scale parameter to an increase in climate variability.
      Another parameter is also introduced, the Expected Waiting Time (EWT) -
      the amount of time until a particular level <emphasis
      role="italic">u</emphasis> is exceeded.</para>

      <para>Under this approach, if what is considered an acceptable level of risk is constant, it
        may be desirable to design mitigation measures (eg. Design Flood Standards) such that the
        likelihood of a given consequence is constant in time. <xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_jebqn"/>
        shows that if risk is increasing through time, then to keep the standard of risk protection
        constant, it would be necessary to continuously raise a defense. Clearly for many projects
        it is not possible to continually increase the capacity of flood protection measures,
        therefore if the mitigation measure is of fixed capacity the standard of risk protection
        varies with time (<xref linkend="b1_ch5_f_jebqn"/>).</para>

      <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_jebqn">
        <title>Flood Risk Plot Versus Constant Risk Plot (derived from Rootzen et al 2012)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1041.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Similarly, <citation>b1_c5_r25+1</citation> present a framework for addressing
        non-stationarity in risk assessment. The non-stationarity is considered in terms of
        increasing frequency of events, decreasing events and random shifting events, with standard
        return period and risk parameters. In the case of increasing extreme events, the exceedance
        probability of floods affecting structures also varies through time ie. <emphasis
          role="italic">p<subscript>1</subscript>, p<subscript>2</subscript>,
            p<subscript>3</subscript>, …..,p<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis>. The sequence of
          <emphasis role="italic">p</emphasis> will also be increasing (<xref
          linkend="b1_ch5_f_krn6k"/>):</para>

      <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_krn6k">
        <title>Schematic of a Design Flood with Exceeding (<emphasis role="italic"
              >P<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis>) and Non-Exceeding (<emphasis role="italic"
              >q<subscript>t</subscript> = 1-P<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis>) Probabilities
          Varying with Time (Salas &amp; Obeysekera, 2014)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1042.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>This means that if the probability of the first flood exceeding the Design Flood
        Standard at time <emphasis role="italic">x</emphasis> = 1 is <emphasis role="italic"
            >p<subscript>1</subscript></emphasis>, then the probability at time <emphasis
          role="italic">x =2</emphasis> is <inlineequation>
          <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                  <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>p</mi>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mi>p</mi>
            </mrow>
          </math>
        </inlineequation>. In general, the probability that the first flood exceeding the Design
        Flood Standard will occur at time x is given by:</para>
      <equation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mi>f</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mi>x</mi>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mi>P</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mi>X</mi>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mi>x</mi>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>p</mi>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>p</mi>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>p</mi>
                  <mn>3</mn>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2026;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>p</mi>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                    <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                    <mi>x</mi>
                  </mrow>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mi>p</mi>
            <mi>x</mi>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>This geometric distribution is developed further for application
      in a non-stationary framework to allow the waiting time for the first
      exceedance of the Design Flood Standard to be calculated.</para>

      <para>However, given the complexities of non-stationarity, the number of practical studies
        incorporating non-stationarity within flooding infrastructure is relatively low (eg.
          <citation>b1_c5_r34+1</citation>, <citation>b1_c5_r10+1</citation>,
          <citation>b1_c5_r20+1</citation> and <citation>b1_c5_r35+1</citation>). Furthermore, there
        is limited application of these techniques in policy framework documents. In contrast, the
        majority of countries currently adopt coarse climate change adjustment factors to account
        for non-stationarity. Approaches within Australia are discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/>,
        with many assessments based upon considering a percentage increase in rainfall, ranging from
        10 to 30% or examining the impacts of rarer flood events to test the sensitivity of flood
        behaviour to changes in flood flows relative to the existing conditions. Furthermore, the
        majority of guidance aims at providing advice in relation to one particular aspect, such as
        climate change impacts on flood producing rainfall events, rather than capturing all aspects
        of non-stationarity.</para>

      <para>However, there is broad guidance, such as <citation>b1_c5_r1+1</citation> that
        highlights the importance of considering how the floodplain and catchment will change
        overtime by encouraging both the understanding of cumulative impacts of new development and
        also considering the influence of a changing climate. These are generally undertaken
        separately to identify the sensitivity of changes due to these different changing factors.
        It is rare that all non-stationarity factors are considered together.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_rgu0v">
      <title>Non-Stationary Risk Assessment</title>

      <para>Non-stationarity is typically included in community risk based assessments (<xref
          linkend="b1_ch5_s_zgoqu"/>) by considering catchment and floodplain changes and climate
        change in understanding and managing flood risk to a community. However, for other
        infrastructure project, such as those identified in<xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_zha4n"/> to <xref
          linkend="b1_ch5_s_ih60o"/>, non-stationary factors may need to be considered for the
        assessment.</para>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_ezdkn">
        <title>Is a Non-Stationary Risk Assessment Required</title>

        <para>In general, uncertainty in risk likelihood and consequence increases with a project’s
          Effective Service Life. Some discussion on estimating effective service life are provided
          in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_p71ax"/>.</para>

        <para>Once the effective service life has been determined an
        assessment of the potentially likelihood of changes to risk
        (likelihood or consequence factors) should be undertaken. A discussion
        on climate change, and whether this is important for consideration, is
        provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/>.</para>

        <para>Where a reasonable risk of change in other sources of non-stationarity is identified,
          a non-stationary risk assessment may be a preferred risk assessment approach. While this
          can be difficult to evaluate the following broad guidance is provided: in general, for
          medium to long term infrastructure (ie. with effective service life of greater than 5
          years), it is suggested that:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>If the effective service life is less than 20 years a
            stationary risk assessment should be undertaken;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>If the effective service life is greater than 20 years but
            less than 50 years it is recommended that a non-stationary risk
            assessment be considered, except in areas in which the likelihood
            of change in local and regional land uses is minimal; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>If the effective service life is greater than 50 years then
            it is recommended that a non-stationary risk assessment be
            undertaken.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The above is a general guidance, and does not take into account
        project specific issues. For both short-term and long-term
        infrastructure it is recommended that an initial review be undertaken
        that evaluates whether or not changes in likelihood and/or consequence
        (as listed above) are likely to occur over the Effective Service Life
        of the project and considering whether such changes would impair the
        project’s ability to perform its intended function.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_6kvuz">
        <title>Non-Stationary Risk Assessment</title>

        <para>Where non-stationary risk assessment is being considered, a
        process similar to non-stationary risk assessment can be undertaken.
        However, the non-stationary nature of the risks present will influence
        the design horizon over which the assessment is undertaken.</para>

        <para>Rather than adopt the more complex models identified in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_fd8ui"
          />, it is recommended to adopt a simple “time slice” approach. Primarily there are three
          approaches able to be adopted:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Undertake risk assessment at the point
            in time of highest overall risk</emphasis> <emphasis
            role="bold">(T(max))</emphasis> : Typically, this may be at the
            end of the project’s ESL. By applying the risk assessment at
            T(max), and determining appropriate design criteria for this
            point, the proponent will effectively design its infrastructure to
            be acceptable at all points of its ESL. This is considered to be
            the most conservative approach and will lead to relative
            over-engineering of infrastructure at some points of its life,
            particularly early in its life.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Undertake risk assessment based on the
            existing environment (T(0))</emphasis> : This approach accepts
            that non-stationary components have impacts on flood behaviour,
            risks will rise. This approach assumes that this growth in risk
            will be acceptable and therefore it will lead to under-engineering
            relative to current minimum design requirements as risks rise.
            This is considered the least conservative approach and the most
            likely to result in higher long term risks.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Undertake risk assessment based on the
            existing environment (T(0)a) and commit to managing residual risk
            as it arises</emphasis> : This approach will require periodic
            reassessment of risks associated with the project at agreed points
            in time. This approach may lead to under-engineering towards the
            end of the re-evaluation period and is considered the second least
            conservative approach.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Undertake risk assessment at a
            representative point in the projects ESL (T(x))</emphasis> and
            commit to managing the residual risk: This approach will likely
            lead to over-engineering in the initial (pre – T(x)) period, after
            which it will require periodic reassessment of risks associated
            with the project at agreed points in time.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Each of these four options revolve around the choice between
        conservatively over-engineering to ensure risk levels are satisfied,
        against programs of continuous upgrades in which changes in risk may
        be responded to through adaptation in design.</para>

        <para>In general the T(max) approach may be identified as the
        preferred approach where:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The magnitude of change in risk is well known and likely to
            be small;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A project’s effective service life is certain;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The costs of over-engineering are low; or</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The potential for retro-fitting / incorporating adaptability
            is low.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>In contrast, The T(0)a and T(x) approaches are more likely to be
        favourable where:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The potential change is risk is high or uncertain;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The projects effective service life is uncertain;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The costs of over-engineering are high; or</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The potential for incorporating adaptability is high.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>There may be thresholds or tipping points at which the frequency of flooding or the
          consequences (eg. loss of life, damage to residential property) of that flooding or the
          associated risks are considered unacceptable to the community. If these can be identified
          they can provide a basis for considering the limit of tolerability (LoT). With knowledge
          of the anticipated rate of change in the likelihood or consequence of flood events over
          time, it may be possible to approximate the time at which the LoT will be exceeded for any
          one consequence. Based upon current understanding of any such limits, beyond this point,
          flooding in association with a given project may be considered generate unacceptable
          risks.</para>

        <para>This concept is basically a trigger based concept. For example,
        residential properties may be designed to a 1% AEP level, which is
        acceptable to the local authority. However, they are willing to
        tolerate a 2% AEP level if unavoidable. Currently, a residential
        development is built to a 1% AEP level. However, due to changes in the
        catchment (increase in impervious areas in the catchment) and climate
        change, this is expected to reduce to a 2% AEP level after 30 years.
        This represents a trigger point at which time a mitigation measure may
        need to be implemented.</para>

        <para>Such points may be utilised as the minimum points at which
        risks, and the appetite for risk, are reassessed (T(0)a). Where
        current planning allows for adaptation, these can be considered the
        protected timeframe where this adaptation may be necessary based upon
        current knowledge and projections (T(x) <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5_f_oek3n"/>).</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch5_f_oek3n">
          <title>Change in Realised Risk Through Adopting a T(x) Design Approach.</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1043.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>From a practical perspective, consideration of the potential need for and likely
          methods for mitigating future growth in risk as part of the original decision can enable
          this work to be incorporated into upfront decisions <citation>b1_c5_r11</citation>. For
          example, land can be set aside or easements established to enable construction and
          maintenance of future mitigation measures. If this does not occur the mitigation measure
          may not be able to be implemented when required. Consideration of the costs of future
          mitigation in current decisions may in some cases influence the original decision on
          protection levels.</para>

        <para>It is also noted that any option based around the future upgrade
        of infrastructure poses potential legal and commercial risks to both
        proponents and approval authorities. Given the extent of timeframe
        over which the infrastructure may be in place, the responsibility (and
        cost) of re-evaluation and upgrade in the future may change between
        individuals and there is the potential that the decision to upgrade at
        that time is not viable. In such circumstances the project may be
        decommissioned (these costs should be considered in any supporting
        economic analysis).</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_8em63">
      <title>Economic Assessment</title>

      <para>For non-stationary risk analysis, design options may be assessed through standard CBA
        evaluation of options. However, it is recommended that the changes over time be incorporated
        into the analysis. For example, the reduction in protection provided by a levee protecting a
        coastal town as flood levels change due to the increasing influence of coastal flooding as
        sea level rises due to climate change.</para>

      <para>A simple approach for incorporating the changes over time is to
      take two or more time slices. For example, the flood inundation damages
      are calculated in year 0 and at the end of the Effective Service Life.
      Then the damages are assumed to change linearly between these two
      points. If the change is expected to occur differently, the more time
      slices may be required.</para>

      <para>Adopting the methodology in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_vh7ar"/>, the
      key change is that the Annual Average Damage will progressively change
      over the Effective Service Life of the project. This can then be
      included into the economic assessment as described in <xref
      linkend="b1_ch5_s_vh7ar"/>.</para>

      <para>There are several key considerations in undertaking economic
      analysis in non-stationary conditions:</para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Analysis
      Period</emphasis></emphasis></para>

      <para>The inclusion of non-stationarity results in benefits and costs
      that vary through time. The important implication of this is that an
      economic outcome can be dependent on when the economic analysis period
      commences. For example, if we pay to construct a levee now to protect
      against climate change, then the cost is incurred in the present, but no
      real benefit may be realised for some time, for example twenty years.
      When the time value of money is considered in this scenario, it may be
      worth not investing in the levee until twenty years have passed.</para>

      <para>This introduces a complication when comparing a number of alternative projects.
        Traditionally, you would be able to prioritise economically between projects based upon the
        larger BCR. However, the impact of non-stationarity introduces the dimension of time to the
        analysis. In other words, a project may not be viable now but may become viable in 10 years
        time. This type of assessment was applied in <citation>b1_c5_r30+1</citation> and
          <citation>b1_c5_r31+1</citation> for studies in the Solomon Islands.</para>

      <para>An economic analysis under non-stationary conditions should be expanded to incorporate
        variable option implementation timing (ie. run CBA scenarios in which the project is
        developed in different phases over time). A CBA analysis could assess a range of scenarios
        (including staged scenarios) that capture this changing nature of costs and benefits over
        time.</para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Discount
      Rate</emphasis></emphasis></para>

      <para>A challenge of non-stationary factors like climate change is that impacts which are
        experienced further into the future are diluted by standard discount rates. There is
        significant research that has been undertaken on appropriate discount rates for very long
        time periods. This is based on the argument that intergenerational equity should be
        considered, and that future generations should not be unfairly weighted compared with
        existing generations <citation>b1_c5_r28</citation>. This becomes particularly important for
        projects which are expected to have a relatively long effective service life, and therefore
        the benefits will span across multiple generations. Some recent studies, such as the Stern
        Review <citation>b1_c5_r28</citation> have adopted very low discount rates (in the case of
        the Stern Review, 1.4%).</para>

      <para>Some economists argue for zero discount rates when applied to environmental impacts.
          <citation>b1_c5_r23+1</citation> goes further and suggests that the use of zero discount
        rates is in agreement with sustainability, where</para>

      <para><quote>The interests of future generations should be given equal
      weight with our own in making decisions affecting the long term
      future</quote></para>

      <para><citation>b1_c5_r12+1</citation> suggest</para>

      <para><quote>those changes that would enhance or degrade the human life
      support capacity of the ecosystem…. would not be discounted at
      all</quote></para>

      <para><citation>b1_c5_r22+1</citation> reviewed a number of approaches, and discussed that the
        discount rate may be derived not from the consumer perspective, but on a more general
        society perspective, based on “interpersonal comparisons”. There are inherent difficulties
        with this analysis. <citation>b1_c5_r22+1</citation> argues that the current generation will
        incur costs for the benefit of future generations, but there will reach a point at which
        perceived gain for the next generation is not seen as worth the cost for the present
        generation. Therefore, a zero discount rate should not apply, as it would imply “very high
        investment by the present generation”. <citation>b1_c5_r22+1</citation> suggests a discount
        rate that decreases over time, approaching the “lowest reasonably foreseeable rate” of
        economic growth. <citation>b1_c5_r22+1</citation> also suggests potentially increasing the
        value of environmental assets, as these are progressively consumed moving into the
        future.</para>

      <para>Most of the discussion in relation to varying of discount rates
      focuses in on climate change and environmental policies. These policies,
      such as emission trading schemes, can result in costs now, in order to
      off-set potential significant costs in the future and impacts that may
      not be possible to be rectified by future generations.</para>

      <para>The challenge with varying the discount rate is that it results in
      difficulties in comparing across projects. For example, if one project
      adopts a discount rate of 7% and another a discount rate of 4%, then it
      is difficult to directly compare the BCR results of such studies without
      thoroughly understanding the underlying assumptions.</para>

      <para>For the purposes of the majority of water related infrastructure,
      and to ensure consistency across projects, it is recommended to adopt
      typical discount rates. Treasury guidance may recommend discount rates
      to provide consistency across competing projects. However, the above
      should be kept in mind for policies and planning that is targeting
      impacts well into the future.</para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Alternative Economic
      Models</emphasis></emphasis></para>

      <para>Alternatively, a more robust economic analysis approach would be the use of Real Options
        Analysis (ROA). ROA is a recognised approach to address the uncertainties of future
        conditions in flood risk management by accounting for flexibility in investment decision
          <citation>b1_c5_r36,b1_c5_r26,b1_c5_r21,b1_c5_r13</citation>.</para>

      <para>The standard CBA approach is a relatively coarse mechanism in which costs and benefits
        assessed are considered as a whole and do not allow for discernment of the manner in which
        they accrue (eg. changes in the rate at which benefits are received may not justify
        development of all project components as part of initial project construction). Neither does
        the analysis recognise that estimates of cost, benefit and risk into the future are
        inherently uncertain. As such, deferring decisions on infrastructure investment until a
        later date when more information is available may be the preferred approach. ROA allows the
        value of deferring investment decisions to be assessed.</para>

      <para>In ROA, “options” represent predefined choices over a project’s Effective Service Life
        that strategically or operationally affects the course of the project. For example, a
        project may be to build a levee. If we build the levee in such a way that it is possible for
        it to be upgraded at a later date, a real option may be to increase levee height by 0.5m.
        The analysis defines decision points at which these choices are made (eg. T(x)). The
        decision points can be points may be fixed in time or variable and triggered by internal or
        external events (eg. occurrence of a 1% AEP event). Based on the Black-Scholes model
        utilised in financial options analysis, ROA utilises estimates of volatility (ie. the
        likelihood of a particular flood event or level of damage occurring in one year) to evaluate
        expected values/damages that are likely to be incurred over the Effective Service Life. The
        establishment of appropriate volatility measures is critical to ROA, and not all systems
        will have readily discernible volatilities.</para>

      <para>For example, a flood levee may be required and it is known that currently it needs to be
        built to a 20% AEP in order to maintain an acceptable level of risk. However, it is also
        forecast that due to climate change, over 50 years, the magnitude of the 20% AEP event will
        be equivalent to the magnitude of the current 10% AEP event and that levee would need to be
        increased by one metre in height to provide the same level of risk. Assume, also that the
        volatility is such that there was 50% chance that the cost of flooding would increase by 5%
        per year and a 50% chance that the cost of flooding would increase by 1% per year. Utilising
        a numerical method for the pricing of options (eg. the Binomial Method, Black-Scholes
        Model), and based on this volatility year on year, it would be possible to estimate the
        value of implementing an option in a given year (ie. the value of waiting to make a decision
        on investing until more information is available). For example, if it turns out that by year
        10 that there have been 10 consecutive 5% increases, then the benefits of increasing the
        height of the levee at that point will be significantly greater than if there had been 10
        consecutive 1% increases per year.</para>

      <para>Other common decision-under-uncertainty making tools which may be
      utilised include Laplace’s Principle of Insufficient Reason or Walds
      Maximin Model.</para>
    </section>
  </section>



  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_39fu8">
    <title>Further Reading</title>

    <para>SCARM (2000) Floodplain Management in Australia: Best Practice
    Principles and Guidelines. Agriculture and Resource Management Council of
    Australia and New Zealand, Standing Committee on Agriculture and Resource
    Management (SCARM). Report No 73. CSIRO Publishing, 2000.</para>

    <para>Shand, T. D., Cox, R. J., Blacka, M. J. and Smith, G. P. (2011).
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 10: Appropriate Safety
    Criteria for Vehicles - Literature Review. Australian Rainfall and Runoff
    Revision Project 10. Stage 2 Report. Prepared by the Water Research
    Laboratory. P10/S2/020. February 2011.</para>

    <para>Opper S, Emergency Management Planning for the Hawkesbury Nepean
    Valley, 40th Floodplain Management Authorities Conference, Parramatta, 9th
    – 12th May 2000.</para>

    <para>NSW Government (2005). Floodplain Development Manual. Department Of
    Infrastructure Planning and Natural Resources. DIPNR 05_020.</para>

    <para>NFRAG (2008) Flood Risk Management in Australia. The Australian
    Journal of Emergency Management. Vol 23, No. 4, November 2008.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., Babister M., (2015). Improving national best practice
    in flood risk management, Floodplain Management Association National
    Conference, Brisbane, May 2015.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., Babister M., Smith G., Thomson R., (2014). Updating
    National best practice guidance in flood risk management, Floodplain
    Management Association National Conference, Deniliquin, May 2014.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., (2013). A guide to best practice in flood risk
    management in Australia, Floodplain Management Association National
    Conference, Tweed Heads, May 2013.</para>

    <para>McLuckie, D., (2012). Best Practice in Flood Risk Management in
    Australia. Presentation to Engineers Australia Queensland Water Panel,
    Brisbane, May 2012.</para>

    <para>COST 2013 - A review of applied methods in Europe for
    flood-frequency analysis in a changing environment: WG4 – Flood Frequency
    estimation methods and environmental change.</para>

    <para>Babister, M., Retallick, M., 2013. Benchmarking Best Practice in
    Floodplain Management, Floodplain Management Association National
    Conference, Tweed Heads, May 2013</para>

    <para>Babister, M., McLuckie, D., Retallick, M., Testoni, I. (2014).
    Comparing Modelling Approaches to End User needs, Floodplain Management
    Association Conference, Deniliquin, May 2014</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_uelzo">
    <title>Examples</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x">
      <title>Calculation of Average Annual Damages for a Community</title>
      <informalequation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mtext>AAD</mtext>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>[</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mtext>Sum&#x00A0;from&#x00A0;1&#x00A0;to&#x00A0;n&#x00A0;of,&#x00A0;</mtext>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>d</mi>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>d</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>p</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>p</mi>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>d</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>d</mi>
                      <mn>3</mn>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>p</mi>
                      <mn>3</mn>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>p</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>...</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>d</mi>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>d</mi>
                      <mi>n</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>p</mi>
                      <mi>n</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>p</mi>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
              <mo>]</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>AAD = Annual Average Damages in $</para>

            <para>d = damage in $</para>

            <para>p = probability</para>

            <para>points 1 to n are the different ordinates on the damage
            curve</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine the damage under the curve for <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_f_d3e0t"/>. The table below provides the points on
            the curve.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="3">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>AEP</entry>

                    <entry>Flood Damage for Event ($)</entry>

                    <entry>n</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.001%</entry>

                    <entry>$28,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>1</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>2</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>$20,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>3</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$17,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$9,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>5</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$3,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>6</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>$1,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>7</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>20%</entry>

                    <entry>$0</entry>

                    <entry>8</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <informalequation>
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mtext>AAD</m:mtext>
            <m:mo>=</m:mo>
            <m:mo stretchy="false">[</m:mo>
            <m:mtable columnalign="left">
              <m:mtr columnalign="left">
                <m:mtd columnalign="left">
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>28</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>22</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                    </m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.002</m:mn>
                    <m:mo>&#x2212;</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.0001</m:mn>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>22</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>20</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                    </m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.005</m:mn>
                    <m:mo>&#x2212;</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.002</m:mn>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>
              <m:mtr columnalign="left">
                <m:mtd columnalign="left">
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>20</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>17</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                    </m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.01</m:mn>
                    <m:mo>&#x2212;</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.005</m:mn>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>17</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>9</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                    </m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.02</m:mn>
                    <m:mo>&#x2212;</m:mo>
                    <m:mn>0.01</m:mn>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>
              <m:mtr columnalign="left">
                <m:mtd columnalign="left">
                  <m:mtable columnalign="left">
                    <m:mtr>
                      <m:mtd>
                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                        <m:mfrac>
                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mn>9</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>3</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                          </m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                        </m:mfrac>
                        <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>0.05</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>&#x2212;</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>0.02</m:mn>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                        <m:mfrac>
                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mn>3</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>1</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                          </m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                        </m:mfrac>
                        <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>0.1</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>&#x2212;</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>0.05</m:mn>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                      </m:mtd>
                    </m:mtr>
                    <m:mtr>
                      <m:mtd>
                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                        <m:mfrac>
                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mn>1</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>000</m:mn>
                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                            <m:mn>0</m:mn>
                          </m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                        </m:mfrac>
                        <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>0.2</m:mn>
                        <m:mo>&#x2212;</m:mo>
                        <m:mn>0.1</m:mn>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                        <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                      </m:mtd>
                    </m:mtr>
                  </m:mtable>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>
            </m:mtable>
            <m:mo stretchy="false">]</m:mo>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </informalequation>
      <informalequation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mtext>AAD</mtext>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>[</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mn>49</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mn>750</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>63</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mn>000</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>92</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mn>500</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>130</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mn>000</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>180</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mn>000</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>100</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mn>000</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>50</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mn>000</mn>
              </mrow>
              <mo>]</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </informalequation>
      <informalequation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mtext>AAD</mtext>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mi>&#x0024;</mi>
            <mn>665</mn>
            <mo>,</mo>
            <mn>250</mn>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </informalequation>

      <para>When it comes to examining treatment options it can be important
      to understand which portion of the curve is contributing significantly
      to damage and therefore a table such as follows can be useful. In this
      case events up to a 1% AEP event contribute $460,000 out of the $665,250
      toward Annual Average Damages.</para>

      <informaltable>
        <tgroup cols="5">
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>AEP n</entry>

              <entry>AEP n-1</entry>

              <entry>Flood Damage n ($)</entry>

              <entry>Flood Damage n-1 ($)</entry>

              <entry>Contribution to AAD ($)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.001%</entry>

              <entry>0.2%</entry>

              <entry>$28,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$49,750</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.2%</entry>

              <entry>0.5%</entry>

              <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$20,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$63,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.5%</entry>

              <entry>1.0%</entry>

              <entry>$20,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$17,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$92,500</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>1.0%</entry>

              <entry>2.0%</entry>

              <entry>$17,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$9,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$130,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>2.0%</entry>

              <entry>5.0%</entry>

              <entry>$9,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$3,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$180,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>5.0%</entry>

              <entry>10%</entry>

              <entry>$3,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$1,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$100,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>10%</entry>

              <entry>20%</entry>

              <entry>$1,000,000</entry>

              <entry>$0</entry>

              <entry>$50,000</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Total ($)</entry>

              <entry>n/a</entry>

              <entry>n/a</entry>

              <entry>n/a</entry>

              <entry>$665,250</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_jpbhv">
      <title>Calculating Average Annual Benefits of a Treatment
      Measure</title>
      <informalequation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mrow>
                <mtext>AAB&#x00A0;=&#x00A0;AAD</mtext>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mi>c</mi>
                <mi>a</mi>
                <mi>s</mi>
                <mi>e</mi>
                <mn>0</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msub>
            <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
            <mi>A</mi>
            <mi>A</mi>
            <msub>
              <mi>D</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mi>c</mi>
                <mi>a</mi>
                <mi>s</mi>
                <mi>e</mi>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msub>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>AAB = annual average benefits in $</para>

            <para>AAD = annual average damages in $ - calculations see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></para>

            <para>Case 0 is the current situation or base case</para>

            <para>Case 1 is the case with treatment in place</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine the Average Annual Benefits</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine Annual Average Damages for the base case –
            undertaken in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine Annual Average Damages for the treated case. See
            table below.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>AEP n</entry>

                    <entry>AEP n-1</entry>

                    <entry>Flood Damage n ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Flood Damage n-1 ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Contribution to AAD ($)</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.001%</entry>

                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>$28,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$49,750</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>$22,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$15,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$55,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$15,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$2,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$42,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$2,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>$750,000</entry>

                    <entry>$13,750</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$750,000</entry>

                    <entry>$500,000</entry>

                    <entry>$18,750</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>$500,000</entry>

                    <entry>$200,000</entry>

                    <entry>$17,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>20%</entry>

                    <entry>$200,000</entry>

                    <entry>$0</entry>

                    <entry>$10,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Total ($)</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>$207,750</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 3</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine Annual Average Damages for the base case –
            undertaken in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 4</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine Annual Average Damages for the treated case. See
            table below.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>AEP n</entry>

                    <entry>AEP n-1</entry>

                    <entry>Base Case Contribution to AAD From <xref
                    linkend="b1_ch5_s_vjk8x"/></entry>

                    <entry>Treated Case Contribution to AAD ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Contribution to AAB ($)</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.001%</entry>

                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>$49,750</entry>

                    <entry>$49,750</entry>

                    <entry>$0</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.2%</entry>

                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>$63,000</entry>

                    <entry>$55,500</entry>

                    <entry>$7,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0.5%</entry>

                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$92,500</entry>

                    <entry>$42,500</entry>

                    <entry>$50,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1.0%</entry>

                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$130,000</entry>

                    <entry>$13,750</entry>

                    <entry>$116,250</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2.0%</entry>

                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>$180,000</entry>

                    <entry>$18,750</entry>

                    <entry>$161,250</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5.0%</entry>

                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>$100,000</entry>

                    <entry>$17,500</entry>

                    <entry>$82,500</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10%</entry>

                    <entry>20%</entry>

                    <entry>$50,000</entry>

                    <entry>$10,000</entry>

                    <entry>$40,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Total ($)</entry>

                    <entry>n/a</entry>

                    <entry>$665,250</entry>

                    <entry>$207,750</entry>

                    <entry>$457,500</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_13ov6">
      <title>Calculating Net Present Value of Benefits</title>
      <informalequation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mtext>NPV</mtext>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>[</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mtext>Sum&#x00A0;1&#x00A0;to&#x00A0;</mtext>
                <mi>n</mi>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mtext>&#x00A0;of,&#x00A0;</mtext>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mtext>AAB</mtext>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mtext>dr</mtext>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mtext>AAB</mtext>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mtext>dr</mtext>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>...</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mtext>AAB</mtext>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mtext>dr</mtext>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mi>n</mi>
                            <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
              <mo>]</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>AAB = Annual Average Benefits in $ - calculation see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_jpbhv"/></para>

            <para>dr = discount rate</para>

            <para>n= design life in years. Assumes no benefits during
            construction.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Note:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>A range of discount rates may be used to give a range of
            NPVs which can in turn be used to determine a range of Benefit
            Cost Ratios (see <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5"/>) to test how
            financial benefits may vary with different financial
            situations.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculating Net Present Value of benefits</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine the Average Annual Benefits – undertaken in <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_jpbhv"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Assess Net Present Value of benefits. See table
            below.</para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mrow>
                        <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                      </mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mtext>Benefits</mtext>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mi>&#x0024;</mi>
                    <mn>6</mn>
                    <mo>,</mo>
                    <mn>099</mn>
                    <mo>,</mo>
                    <mn>257</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation> for a discount rate (dr) of 7%. This could vary from $4,473,916 for
              a dr of 10% to $9,055,194 for a dr of 4%.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <colspec colname="_1"/>

                <colspec colname="_2"/>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Year N</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in Future Year AAB ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                          <msub>
                            <mi>dr</mi>

                            <mi>1</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </math>
                      </inlineequation> = 4% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                          <msub>
                            <mi>dr</mi>

                            <mi>2</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </math>
                      </inlineequation> = 7% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Benefit in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                          <msub>
                            <mi>dr</mi>

                            <mi>3</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </math>
                      </inlineequation> = 10% ($)</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>0</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>439,904</entry>

                    <entry>427,570</entry>

                    <entry>415,909</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>422,984</entry>

                    <entry>399,598</entry>

                    <entry>378,099</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>3</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>406,716</entry>

                    <entry>373,456</entry>

                    <entry>343,727</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>4</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>391,073</entry>

                    <entry>349,025</entry>

                    <entry>312,479</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>376,032</entry>

                    <entry>326,191</entry>

                    <entry>284,072</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>6</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>361,569</entry>

                    <entry>304,852</entry>

                    <entry>258,247</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>7</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>347,662</entry>

                    <entry>284,908</entry>

                    <entry>234,770</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>8</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>334,291</entry>

                    <entry>266,269</entry>

                    <entry>213,427</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>9</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>321,433</entry>

                    <entry>248,850</entry>

                    <entry>194,025</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>309,071</entry>

                    <entry>232,570</entry>

                    <entry>176,386</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>11</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>297,183</entry>

                    <entry>217,355</entry>

                    <entry>160,351</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>12</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>285,753</entry>

                    <entry>203,135</entry>

                    <entry>145,774</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>13</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>274,763</entry>

                    <entry>189,846</entry>

                    <entry>132,521</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>14</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>264,195</entry>

                    <entry>177,426</entry>

                    <entry>120,474</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>15</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>254,034</entry>

                    <entry>165,819</entry>

                    <entry>109,522</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>16</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>244,263</entry>

                    <entry>154,971</entry>

                    <entry>99,565</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>17</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>234,868</entry>

                    <entry>144,833</entry>

                    <entry>90,514</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>18</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>225,835</entry>

                    <entry>135,358</entry>

                    <entry>82,285</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>19</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>217,149</entry>

                    <entry>126,503</entry>

                    <entry>74,805</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>20</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>208,797</entry>

                    <entry>118,227</entry>

                    <entry>68,004</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>21</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>200,766</entry>

                    <entry>110,492</entry>

                    <entry>61,822</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>22</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>193,045</entry>

                    <entry>103,264</entry>

                    <entry>56,202</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>23</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>185,620</entry>

                    <entry>96,508</entry>

                    <entry>51,093</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>24</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>178,481</entry>

                    <entry>90,195</entry>

                    <entry>46,448</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>25</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>171,616</entry>

                    <entry>84,294</entry>

                    <entry>42,225</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>26</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>165,015</entry>

                    <entry>78,779</entry>

                    <entry>38,387</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>27</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>158,669</entry>

                    <entry>73,626</entry>

                    <entry>34,897</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>28</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>152,566</entry>

                    <entry>68,809</entry>

                    <entry>31,725</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>29</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>146,698</entry>

                    <entry>64,307</entry>

                    <entry>28,841</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>30</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>141,056</entry>

                    <entry>60,100</entry>

                    <entry>26,219</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>31</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>135,631</entry>

                    <entry>56,169</entry>

                    <entry>23,835</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>32</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>130,414</entry>

                    <entry>52,494</entry>

                    <entry>21,668</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>33</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>125,398</entry>

                    <entry>49,060</entry>

                    <entry>19,698</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>34</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>120,575</entry>

                    <entry>45,850</entry>

                    <entry>17,908</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>35</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>115,938</entry>

                    <entry>42,851</entry>

                    <entry>16,280</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>36</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>111,478</entry>

                    <entry>40,047</entry>

                    <entry>14,800</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>37</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>107,191</entry>

                    <entry>37,428</entry>

                    <entry>13,454</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>38</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>103,068</entry>

                    <entry>34,979</entry>

                    <entry>12,231</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>39</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>99,104</entry>

                    <entry>32,691</entry>

                    <entry>11,119</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>40</entry>

                    <entry>457,500</entry>

                    <entry>95,292</entry>

                    <entry>30,552</entry>

                    <entry>10,108</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry nameend="_2" namest="_1">Total ($)</entry>

                    <entry>$9,055,194</entry>

                    <entry>$6,099,257</entry>

                    <entry>$4,473,916</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_4u178">
      <title>Calculating Net Present Value (NPV) of Lifecycle Costs</title>
      <informalequation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mtext>NPV</mtext>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mtext>Capital&#x00A0;Cost&#x00A0;+</mtext>
            <mrow>
              <mo>[</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mtext>Sum&#x00A0;1&#x00A0;to&#x00A0;</mtext>
                <mi>n</mi>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mtext>&#x00A0;of,&#x00A0;</mtext>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mtext>AMC</mtext>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mtext>dr</mtext>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mtext>AMC</mtext>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mtext>dr</mtext>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mn>...</mn>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mtext>AMC</mtext>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mtext>dr</mtext>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mi>n</mi>
                            <mo>&#x2212;</mo>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
              <mo>]</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Capital cost is all relevant upfront costs.</para>

            <para>AMC = Annual operation and Maintenance Costs</para>

            <para>dr = discount rate</para>

            <para>n= design life in years. Assumes no benefits during
            construction.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Note:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>A range of discount rates may be used to give a range of
            NPVs and in turn a range of Benefit Cost Ratios (see <xref
            linkend="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5"/>) to test how financial benefits may
            vary with changing financial situation.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculating Net Present Value of lifecycle costs</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determine capital costs and Annual operation and Maintenance
            Costs</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate Net Present Value of lifecycle costs. See table
            below.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Capital cost is $4,000,000 and Annual operation and
            Maintenance Costs is $100,000.</para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <msub>
                    <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                    <mrow>
                      <mtext>costs</mtext>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mi>&#x0024;</mi>
                  <mn>5</mn>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <mn>333</mn>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <mn>171</mn>
                </math>
              </inlineequation> for a discount rate (dr) of 7%. This could vary from $4,977,105 for
              a dr of 10% to $5,979,277 for a dr of 4%.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="5">
                <colspec colname="_1"/>

                <colspec colname="_2"/>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Year N</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in Future Year AAB ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                          <msub>
                            <mi>dr</mi>

                            <mi>1</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </math>
                      </inlineequation> = 4% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                          <msub>
                            <mi>dr</mi>

                            <mi>2</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </math>
                      </inlineequation> = 7% ($)</entry>

                    <entry>Cost in future year in current year for
                    <inlineequation>
                        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                          <msub>
                            <mi>dr</mi>

                            <mi>3</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </math>
                      </inlineequation> = 10% ($)</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>0</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>

                    <entry>4,000,000</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>1</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>96,154</entry>

                    <entry>93,458</entry>

                    <entry>90,909</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>2</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>92,456</entry>

                    <entry>87,344</entry>

                    <entry>82,645</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>3</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>88,900</entry>

                    <entry>81,630</entry>

                    <entry>75,131</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>4</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>85,480</entry>

                    <entry>76,290</entry>

                    <entry>68,301</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>5</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>82,193</entry>

                    <entry>71,299</entry>

                    <entry>62,092</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>6</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>79,031</entry>

                    <entry>66,634</entry>

                    <entry>56,447</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>7</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>75,992</entry>

                    <entry>62,275</entry>

                    <entry>51,316</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>8</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>73,069</entry>

                    <entry>58,201</entry>

                    <entry>46,651</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>9</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>70,259</entry>

                    <entry>54,393</entry>

                    <entry>42,410</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>67,556</entry>

                    <entry>50,835</entry>

                    <entry>38,554</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>11</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>64,958</entry>

                    <entry>47,509</entry>

                    <entry>35,049</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>12</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>62,460</entry>

                    <entry>44,401</entry>

                    <entry>31,863</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>13</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>60,057</entry>

                    <entry>41,496</entry>

                    <entry>28,966</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>14</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>57,748</entry>

                    <entry>38,782</entry>

                    <entry>26,333</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>15</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>55,526</entry>

                    <entry>36,245</entry>

                    <entry>23,939</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>16</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>53,391</entry>

                    <entry>33,873</entry>

                    <entry>21,763</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>17</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>51,337</entry>

                    <entry>31,657</entry>

                    <entry>19,784</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>18</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>49,363</entry>

                    <entry>29,586</entry>

                    <entry>17,986</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>19</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>47,464</entry>

                    <entry>27,651</entry>

                    <entry>16,351</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>20</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>45,639</entry>

                    <entry>25,842</entry>

                    <entry>14,864</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>21</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>43,883</entry>

                    <entry>24,151</entry>

                    <entry>13,513</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>22</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>42,196</entry>

                    <entry>22,571</entry>

                    <entry>12,285</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>23</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>40,573</entry>

                    <entry>21,095</entry>

                    <entry>11,168</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>24</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>39,012</entry>

                    <entry>19,715</entry>

                    <entry>10,153</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>25</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>37,512</entry>

                    <entry>18,425</entry>

                    <entry>9,230</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>26</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>36,069</entry>

                    <entry>17,220</entry>

                    <entry>8,391</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>27</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>34,682</entry>

                    <entry>16,093</entry>

                    <entry>7,628</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>28</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>33,348</entry>

                    <entry>15,040</entry>

                    <entry>6,934</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>29</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>32,065</entry>

                    <entry>14,056</entry>

                    <entry>6,304</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>30</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>30,832</entry>

                    <entry>13,137</entry>

                    <entry>5,731</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>31</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>29,646</entry>

                    <entry>12,277</entry>

                    <entry>5,210</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>32</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>28,506</entry>

                    <entry>11,474</entry>

                    <entry>4,736</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>33</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>27,409</entry>

                    <entry>10,723</entry>

                    <entry>4,306</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>34</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>26,355</entry>

                    <entry>10,022</entry>

                    <entry>3,914</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>35</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>25,342</entry>

                    <entry>9,366</entry>

                    <entry>3,558</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>36</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>24,367</entry>

                    <entry>8,754</entry>

                    <entry>3,235</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>37</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>23,430</entry>

                    <entry>8,181</entry>

                    <entry>2,941</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>38</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>22,529</entry>

                    <entry>7,646</entry>

                    <entry>2,673</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>39</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>21,662</entry>

                    <entry>7,146</entry>

                    <entry>2,430</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>40</entry>

                    <entry>100,000</entry>

                    <entry>20,829</entry>

                    <entry>6,678</entry>

                    <entry>2,209</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry nameend="_2" namest="_1">Total ($)</entry>

                    <entry>$5,979,277</entry>

                    <entry>$5,333,171</entry>

                    <entry>$4,977,905</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch5_s_ue1n5">
      <title>Calculating Benefit Cost Ratio (BCR)</title>
      <informalequation>
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mtext>BCR</mtext>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mrow>
                  <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                </mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mtext>benefits</mtext>
                </mrow>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mrow>
                  <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                </mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mtext>costs</mtext>
                </mrow>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </math>
      </informalequation>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Where:</term>

          <listitem>
            <informalequation>
              <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                <mtext>BCR</mtext>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mtext>Benefit&#x00A0;Cost&#x00A0;Ratio</mtext>
              </math>
            </informalequation>
            <para> </para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <msub>
                    <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                    <mrow>
                      <mtext>benefits</mtext>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mtext>Net&#x00A0;Present&#x00A0;Value&#x00A0;of&#x00A0;Benefits</mtext>
                </math>
              </inlineequation> - see <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_13ov6"/></para>

            <para><inlineequation>
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <msub>
                    <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                    <mrow>
                      <mtext>costs</mtext>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mtext>Net&#x00A0;Present&#x00A0;Value&#x00A0;of&#x00A0;Costs</mtext>
                </math>
              </inlineequation> - see <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_4u178"/></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Note:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>A range of discount rates may be used to give a range of
            NPVs which can in turn be used to determine a range of Benefit
            Cost Ratios (see below) to test how financial benefits may vary
            with different financial situations.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Example:</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculating BCR</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate <inlineequation>
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mtext>Net&#x00A0;Present&#x00A0;Value&#x00A0;of&#x00A0;Benefits</mtext>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                    <mrow>
                      <mtext>benefits</mtext>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                </math>
              </inlineequation></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate <inlineequation>
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mtext>Net&#x00A0;Present&#x00A0;Value&#x00A0;of&#x00A0;Costs</mtext>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mtext>NPV</mtext>
                    <mrow>
                      <mtext>costs</mtext>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                </math>
              </inlineequation></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Step 3</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Calculate BCR. BCR = 1.14 for dr 7%, BCR = 1.51 for dr 4%,
            BCR = 0.9 for dr 10%.</para>

            <informaltable>
              <tgroup cols="4">
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Discount Rate dr (%)</entry>

                    <entry>NPV benefits ($)</entry>

                    <entry>NPV costs ($)</entry>

                    <entry>BCR</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>4</entry>

                    <entry>9,055,194</entry>

                    <entry>5,979,277</entry>

                    <entry>1.51</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>7</entry>

                    <entry>6,099,257</entry>

                    <entry>5,333,171</entry>

                    <entry>1.14</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>

                    <entry>4,473,916</entry>

                    <entry>4,977,905</entry>

                    <entry>0.90</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>
  
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
  
</chapter>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>