<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b2_ch4"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Spatial Patterns</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/jordan_phillip.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/seed_alan.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/podger_scott.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/stensmyr_peter.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/green_janice.xml"/>
  </info>

  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>

      <td>2</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>

      <td>4</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>

      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>General</td>

      <td>Some work required</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_294vc">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723336"/>Introduction</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_26mj5">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723337"/>Context of rainfall estimation
      techniques</title>

      <para>Different to previous versions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff,
      in the development of this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff
      there has been an assumption that users will have computing resources
      available. The techniques presented in the following sections therefore
      require computing resources for their implementation. Therefore, the
      discussion in the following sections focusses on both the theoretical
      basis of the techniques and their implementation.</para>

      <para>Catchment modelling systems have been widely used by practitioners
      to estimate the characteristics of design flood events. These catchment
      modelling systems include components that estimate the time series of
      runoff across the spatial domain represented by the model and components
      that route the generated runoff within the model domain; more details on
      catchment modelling systems are presented in <xref linkend="book4"/> to
      <xref linkend="book7"/>. As previously discussed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch2"/>, results from modelling for simulation of historic
      floods and simulation of design flood events are influenced by the
      assumptions made about how the rainfall depth is distributed in space
      and time.</para>

      <para>This chapter provides practitioners with recommendations on the
      application of spatial patterns of rainfall for use in flood simulation.
      Included in these recommendations on the spatial distribution are
      recommendations for application of spatial variations in
      hyetographs.</para>

      <para>There are a number of items where the authors recognise that the
      guidance adopted in this chapter is uncertain and where benefit would be
      obtained by further research to better quantify and potentially reduce
      the impact of those uncertainties on design flood estimation practice.
      Appendix A lists and briefly discusses the residual uncertainties, as at
      August 2015, in areal reduction factors, spatial patterns and space-time
      patterns of design rainfall and recommends potential areas of future
      investigation.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_izyzj">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723338"/>Definition of space-time, spatial
      and temporal variability of rainfall</title>

      <para>Rainfall exhibits both spatial and temporal variability at all
      spatial and temporal scales that are of interest in flood hydrology.
      High resolution recording instruments have identified temporal
      variability in rainfall from time scales of less than one minute to
      several days (Marani, 2005). Similarly, observations of rainfall from
      high resolution weather radar and satellites have demonstrated spatial
      variability in rainfall at spatial resolutions from 1 km to more than
      500 km (Lovejoy and Schertzer, 2006).</para>

      <para>When combined, the spatial and temporal variability of rainfall
      will be referred to as the space-time variability of rainfall. The
      space-time pattern of rainfall over a catchment or study area is
      therefore defined in three dimensions: two horizontal dimensions, which
      are normally latitude and longitude (or easting and northing in a
      projected coordinate system) and one temporal dimension. In practice,
      the space-time pattern of rainfall will often be described as a
      three-dimensional matrix, with the value in each element of the matrix
      representing either the accumulated rainfall or the mean rainfall
      intensity for a grid cell over the catchment and a specified period of
      time for the event, as shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_f_6j8f6"/>.</para>

      <para>If the space-time pattern of rainfall is considered as a field
      defined in three-dimensions, then the temporal and spatial patterns of
      rainfall that have conventionally been used in hydrology can be
      considered as convenient statistical means of summarising that field.
      The temporal pattern of rainfall over a catchment area is derived by
      taking an average in space of the rainfall depth (or mean intensity)
      over each time increment of the storm. The spatial pattern of rainfall
      for an event is defined by taking an average in time of the rainfall
      depth (or mean intensity) over each grid cell of the catchment.
      Derivation of spatial and temporal patterns is demonstrated with the
      conceptual diagram in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_f_s18xr"/>. The spatial
      pattern is often also defined by averaging over each subarea to be used
      in a rainfall-runoff routing model of the catchment or study area,
      instead of over a grid, as shown in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_f_m31nb"/>.</para>

      <para>The space-time pattern of rainfall varies in a random manner
      between events and within events. The random variability within the
      space-time pattern is influenced by spatial and temporal correlation
      structures that are an inherent observed property of rainfall. The
      random space-time variability may make it difficult to specify typical
      or representative spatial patterns for some catchments. However, there
      are often hydrometeorological drivers, as discussed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_s_zp53d"/> below,that cause some degree of similarity in
      spatial and space-time patterns of rainfall between events for a
      particular catchment.</para>

      <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_6j8f6">
        <title><?oxy_custom_end ?>Conceptual diagram of space-time pattern of
        rainfall</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2056.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_s18xr">
        <title>Conceptual diagram showing the spatial pattern and temporal
        pattern temporal and spatial averages derived from the space-time
        rainfall field</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2058.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_m31nb">
        <title>Conceptual diagram showing the temporal pattern over a
        catchment and the spatial pattern derived over model subareas of the
        catchment</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2056.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para/>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_zp53d">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref427049610"/>Orographic enhancement and rain
      shadow effects on space-time patterns</title>

      <para>Orographic precipitation, also known as relief precipitation, is
      precipitation generated by a forced upward movement of air upon
      encountering a physiographic upland. This lifting can be caused by two
      mechanisms:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>upward deflection of large scale horizontal flow by the
          topography; or</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>anabatic or upward vertical propagation of moist air up an
          orographic slope caused by daytime heating of the mountain barrier
          surface.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>Upon ascent, the air that is being lifted will expand and cool.
      This adiabatic cooling of a rising moist air parcel may lower its
      temperature to its dew point, thus allowing for condensation of the
      water vapour contained within it, and hence the formation of a cloud.
      Rainfall can be generated from the cloud through a number of physical
      processes (Gray and Seed, 2000). The cloud liquid droplets grow through
      collisions with other droplets to the size where they fall as rain. Rain
      drops from clouds at high altitude may fall through the clouds near the
      surface that have formed because of the uplift due to topography and
      grow as a result of collisions with the cloud droplets. Air may also
      become unstable as it is lifted over higher areas of terrain and
      convective storms may be triggered by this instability. These influences
      combine to typically produce a greater incidence of rainfall on the
      upwind side of hills and mountains and also typically larger rainfall
      intensities on the upwind side than would otherwise occur in flat
      terrain.</para>

      <para>The space-time pattern will vary between every individual rainfall
      event that occurs in a catchment. In catchments that are subject to
      orographic influences, there will commonly be similarity in the
      space-time pattern of rainfall between many of the different events that
      are observed over the catchment. This will typically be the case for
      catchments that are subject to flood causing rainfall events that have
      similar hydrometeorological influences. For example, the spatial
      patterns of rainfall for different events may often demonstrate similar
      ratios of total rainfall depth in the higher elevations of the catchment
      to total rainfall depth at lower elevations.</para>

      <para>The spatial patterns of rainfall in catchments that are influenced
      by orographic effects represent a systematic bias away from a completely
      uniform spatial pattern. The influence of this systematic bias in
      spatial pattern of rainfall should be explicitly considered in design
      flood estimation. Other hydrometeorological influences, such as the
      distance from a significant moisture source like the ocean may also give
      rise to systematic bias in the spatial pattern of rainfall.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_mquih">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723340"/>Influence of space-time rainfall
      patterns on flood hydrographs for individual flood events</title>

      <para>The space-time pattern of rainfall for an individual flood event
      will often have an appreciable influence on the flow hydrograph
      generated at the outlet of a catchment. Two rainfall events may have
      identical total volumes over a defined catchment area and duration but
      differences in their space-time patterns may produce very different
      hydrographs at the outlet of the catchment. Both the runoff generation
      and runoff routing processes in catchments are typically non-linear, so
      a space-time pattern that exhibits more variability will normally
      generate a higher volume of runoff and larger peak flow at the catchment
      outlet than a space-time pattern that is more uniform.</para>

      <para>Variability in hydrographs introduced by space-time variability in
      rainfall will be accentuated in catchments that have spatial and
      temporal variability in runoff generation and routing processes. For
      example, in a partly urbanised catchment, a rain storm with a spatial
      pattern that has larger depths on the urban part of the catchment than
      the rural part would normally produce both a larger volume of runoff and
      flood peak at the catchment outlet than a storm of the same depth and
      duration that has a spatially uniform rainfall pattern. Other factors in
      catchments that may accentuate the influence of the space-time rainfall
      pattern on the variability in hydrographs produced at the catchment
      outlet include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the presence of reservoirs and lakes, for which all rainfall
          is converted to runoff;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the presence of dams, weirs, drains and other flow regulating
          structures;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>significant variations in soil type;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>significant variations in vegetation type, such as forested
          and cleared areas;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the arrangement of the drainage network of the catchment the
          dependency of alternative flowpaths on event magnitude and
          differences in contributing area with length of network;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>significant variations in stream channel and floodplain
          roughness;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>significant variations in slope of stream channels and
          floodplains;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>significant variations in antecedent climatic conditions
          across the catchment prior to the events; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>variations in elevation, snowpack depth, density and
          temperature in those catchments subject to rain-on-snow flood
          events,</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_oxd39">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723341"/>Areal reduction factors</title>

      <para>Design rainfall information for flood estimation generally is made
      available in the form of point rainfall intensities; the rainfall
      intensity-frequency-duration data discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>
      relate to points rather than areas. However, most flood estimates are
      required for catchments that are sufficiently large that design rainfall
      intensities at a point are not representative of the areal average
      rainfall intensity across the catchment. The ratio between the design
      values of areal average rainfall and point rainfall, computed for the
      same duration and annual exceedance probability (AEP), is called the
      areal reduction factor (ARF). It allows for the fact that larger
      catchments are less likely than smaller catchments to experience high
      intensity storms simultaneously over the whole of the catchment
      area.</para>

      <para>It should be noted that the ARF provides a correction factor
      between the catchment rainfall depth (for a given combination of AEP and
      duration) and the mean of the point rainfall depths across a catchment
      (for the same AEP and duration combination). Applying an ARF is a
      necessary input to computation of design flood estimates from a
      catchment model that preserves a probability neutral transition between
      the design rainfall and the design flood characteristics. The ARF merely
      influences the average depth of rainfall across the catchment, it does
      not account for variability in spatial and/or space-time patterns of its
      occurrence over the catchment.</para>

      <para>Recommendations for ARF to be adopted are provided in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_s_q7liu"/>.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_rp06y">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723342"/>Applications where flood
      estimates are required at multiple locations</title>

      <para>Design flood estimates are often required at multiple locations
      within a catchment or study area. Ideally, flood simulation (e.g. using
      Monte Carlo approaches) should consider a large number of complete storm
      events that cover the whole AEP spectrum of interest and have internal
      characteristics which automatically reproduce the critical rainfall
      bursts over a range of temporal and spatial scales. Unfortunately, such
      comprehensive ensembles of synthetic storm events are not currently
      available, and combined system-wide analysis is thus not yet feasible.
      Instead, separate analysis at the different locations (sub-catchments)
      of interest is required, using design rainfall events for the relevant
      space and time scales. To this end, it is necessary to derive design
      rainfall inputs for the catchment upstream of each required location.
      This involves:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Deriving average values of the point design rainfalls for the
          total catchment upstream of each location;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Conversion of average point design rainfall values to areal
          estimates by multiplying by the ARF applicable to the total
          catchment area upstream of each location;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Adoption of space-time patterns of rainfall relevant to the
          total catchment area upstream of each location.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>It is commonly found that design flood estimates are required at
      one or more locations in a catchment where flow gauges are not located.
      If so, it will be necessary to use the above procedure to derive design
      rainfalls for the catchment upstream of each gauge location so that the
      rainfall-based design floods estimates can be verified against estimates
      derived from flood frequency analysis at each flow gauge. Different sets
      of design rainfall intensities, ARF and space-time patterns should be
      calculated for the each of the catchments draining to the other
      locations of interest, which are not at flow gauges.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_q7liu">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref414978858"/>Areal Reduction Factors</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_9avh4">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc427134189"/>General recommendations for areal
      reduction factors for catchments up to 30,000 km², for rainfall event
      durations up to and including 168 hours (7 days) and for AEP more common
      than 0.05% (1 in 2000) inclusive</title>

      <para>Generalised guidance was derived by Podger et al. (2015a, 2015b)
      and Stensmyr et al. (2014) for Areal Reduction Factors (ARF) for
      catchments with areas up to 30,000 km², for durations up to and
      including 168 hours (7 days) and for AEP more common than 0.05% (1 in
      2000) inclusive. This guidance should be adopted unless rigorous
      subsequent research or catchment specific investigations have been
      conducted to define a more appropriate, locally specific, ARF.</para>

      <para>The ARF should be computed for the total catchment upstream of
      each location where a design flood estimate is required. The ARF should
      not be computed independently for each subarea in a rainfall-runoff
      routing model of the catchment of interest – instead the catchment
      average design intensity adjusted by the ARF for the catchment area
      should be computed for the total catchment area upstream of the location
      of interest.</para>

      <para>The ARF to be applied to design rainfall is a function of the
      total area of the catchment, the duration of the design rainfall event
      and it’s AEP. The ARF should be computed using the procedure from the
      applicable cell of <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_41edt"/>.</para>

      <para>If the selected duration is greater than 12 hours, <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> will be required as part of the calculation
      procedure and the coefficients of <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> vary
      regionally across Australia. The applicable ARF region should be
      selected by referring to <xref linkend="b2_ch4_f_p0pf9"/>. Where a
      catchment overlaps the boundary between regions, the ARF should be
      selected for the region that has the largest overlap with the boundary
      of the catchment. The coefficients to be applied with <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> should be selected from the appropriate
      region from <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_tc83g"/>.</para>

      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch4_t_41edt">
        <caption>Procedure for calculating ARF for catchments with areas less
        than 30,000 km² and for durations up to and including 7 days</caption>

        <col width="25%"/>

        <col width="25%"/>

        <col width="25%"/>

        <col width="25%"/>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Catchment area</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Duration </emphasis><emphasis
            role="bold">≤</emphasis><emphasis role="bold"> 12
            hours</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Duration between 12 and 24
            hours</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Duration </emphasis><emphasis
            role="bold">≥</emphasis><emphasis role="bold"> 24 hours and
            </emphasis><emphasis role="bold">≤</emphasis><emphasis
            role="bold"> 7 days (168 hours)</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Area </emphasis><emphasis
            role="bold">≤</emphasis><emphasis role="bold"> 1
            km²</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="3">ARF = 1</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Area between 1 and 10
            km²</emphasis></td>

            <td><orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF(10 km²) using <xref
                  linkend="b2_ch4_e_g71oo"/> for area = 10 km² and selected
                  duration</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Interpolate ARF for catchment area and selected
                  duration using <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_k5jiv"/></para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist></td>

            <td><orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF(24 h, 10 km²) using <xref
                  linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> for area = 10 km² and duration =
                  1440 min</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF(12 h, 10 km²) using <xref
                  linkend="b2_ch4_e_g71oo"/> for area = 10 km² and duration =
                  720 min</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Interpolate ARF(10 km²) for selected duration using
                  <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_xtsqw"/></para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Interpolate ARF for catchment area and selected
                  duration using <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_k5jiv"/></para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist></td>

            <td><orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF(10 km²) using <xref
                  linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> for area = 10 km²</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Interpolate ARF for catchment area and selected
                  duration using <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_k5jiv"/></para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Area between 10 and 1,000
            km²</emphasis></td>

            <td><itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF using <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_g71oo"/> for
                  catchment area and selected duration</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist></td>

            <td rowspan="2"><orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF(24 h) using <xref
                  linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> for catchment area and duration =
                  1440 min</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF(12 h) using <xref
                  linkend="b2_ch4_e_g71oo"/> for catchment area and duration =
                  720 min</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Interpolate ARF for selected duration using <xref
                  linkend="b2_ch4_e_xtsqw"/></para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist></td>

            <td rowspan="2"><para> <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Compute ARF using <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> for
                  catchment area and selected duration</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist> </para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Area between 1,000 and 30,000
            km²</emphasis></td>

            <td>Generalised equations not applicable</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Area &gt;30,000 km²</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="3">Generalised equations not applicable. It is
            recommended that the practitioner should perform their own
            frequency analysis of catchment rainfall data.</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para>Notes on <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_41edt"/>:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/>, <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_e_g71oo"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_xtsqw"/>
          require the selected duration to be provided in minutes.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>There has been limited research on ARF applicable to
          catchments that are less than 10 km². The recommended procedure is
          to adopt an ARF of unity for catchments that are less than 1 km²,
          with an interpolation to the empirically derived equations for
          catchments that are between 1 and 10 km² in area (refer to <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_e_k5jiv"/>).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The ARF equations derived by Podger et al. (2015a, 2015b) and
          Stensmyr et al. (2014) were derived over a range of AEP of 50% to
          1%. Although they have been recommended for use for a wider range of
          AEP, out to 0.05%, further verification is ongoing on the validity
          of this approach. As a result, the coefficients of <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/> (from <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_tc83g"/>)
          and/or the regional boundaries (see <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_f_p0pf9"/>) may be revised.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_p0pf9">
        <title>Regions for calculation of area reduction factors (ARF) for
        durations of 24 to 168 hours (Podger et al., 2015b)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2059.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_wedgj">
        <m:math>
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

              <m:mi>a</m:mi>

              <m:mi>l</m:mi>

              <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

              <m:mi>d</m:mi>

              <m:mi>u</m:mi>

              <m:mi>c</m:mi>

              <m:mi>t</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

              <m:mi>n</m:mi>

              <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

              <m:mi>f</m:mi>

              <m:mi>a</m:mi>

              <m:mi>c</m:mi>

              <m:mi>t</m:mi>

              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mi>M</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

              <m:mi>n</m:mi>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>b</m:mi>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>c</m:mi>

                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msup>

                      <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>f</m:mi>
                      </m:msup>

                      <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                      </m:msup>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                          <m:mfrac>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>1440</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mfrac>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msup>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>}</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamyqaiaadw
            gacaWGYbGaamyyaiaadYgacaqGGaGaamOCaiaadwgacaWGKbGaamyD
            aiaadogacaWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbGaaeiiaiaadAgacaWGHb
            Gaam4yaiaadshacaWGVbGaamOCaiabg2da9iaad2eacaWGPbGaamOB
            amaacmaabaGaaGymaiaacYcadaWadaqaaiaaigdacqGHsislcaWGHb
            WaaeWaaeaacaWGbbGaamOCaiaadwgacaWGHbWaaWbaaSqabeaacaWG
            IbaaaOGaeyOeI0Iaam4yaiGacYgacaGGVbGaai4zamaaBaaaleaaca
            aIXaGaaGimaaqabaGccaWGebGaamyDaiaadkhacaWGHbGaamiDaiaa
            dMgacaWGVbGaamOBaaGaayjkaiaawMcaaiaadseacaWG1bGaamOCai
            aadggacaWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbWaaWbaaSqabeaacqGHsisl
            caWGKbaaaOGaey4kaSIaamyzaiaadgeacaWGYbGaamyzaiaadggada
            ahaaWcbeqaaiaadAgaaaGccaWGebGaamyDaiaadkhacaWGHbGaamiD
            aiaadMgacaWGVbGaamOBamaaCaaaleqabaGaam4zaaaakmaabmaaba
            GaaGimaiaac6cacaaIZaGaey4kaSIaciiBaiaac+gacaGGNbWaaSba
            aSqaaiaaigdacaaIWaaabeaakiaadgeacaWGfbGaamiuaaGaayjkai
            aawMcaaiabgUcaRiaadIgacaaIXaGaaGimamaaCaaaleqabaGaamyA
            aiaadgeacaWGYbGaamyzaiaadggadaWcaaqaaiaadseacaWG1bGaam
            OCaiaadggacaWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbaabaGaaGymaiaaisda
            caaI0aGaaGimaaaaaaGcdaqadaqaaiaaicdacaGGUaGaaG4maiabgU
            caRiGacYgacaGGVbGaai4zamaaBaaaleaacaaIXaGaaGimaaqabaGc
            caWGbbGaamyraiaadcfaaiaawIcacaGLPaaaaiaawUfacaGLDbaaai
            aawUhacaGL9baaaaa@AB6D@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where Area is in km², Duration is in minutes and AEP is a fraction
      (between 0.5 and 0.0005).</para>

      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch4_t_tc83g">
        <caption>Coefficients of ARF equation <xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/>
        applicable in each region for durations between 1440 and 10,800
        minutes (24 and 168 hours or 1 and 7 days) inclusive</caption>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <col width="10%"/>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Region</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">a</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">b</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">c</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">d</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">e</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">f</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">g</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">h</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">i</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>East Coast North</td>

            <td>0.327</td>

            <td>0.241</td>

            <td>0.448</td>

            <td>0.36</td>

            <td>0.00096</td>

            <td>0.48</td>

            <td>-0.21</td>

            <td>0.012</td>

            <td>-0.0013</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Semi-arid Inland QLD</td>

            <td>0.159</td>

            <td>0.283</td>

            <td>0.25</td>

            <td>0.308</td>

            <td>7.3E-07</td>

            <td>1</td>

            <td>0.039</td>

            <td>0</td>

            <td>0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Tasmania</td>

            <td>0.0605</td>

            <td>0.347</td>

            <td>0.2</td>

            <td>0.283</td>

            <td>0.00076</td>

            <td>0.347</td>

            <td>0.0877</td>

            <td>0.012</td>

            <td>-0.00033</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>SW WA</td>

            <td>0.183</td>

            <td>0.259</td>

            <td>0.271</td>

            <td>0.33</td>

            <td>3.85E-06</td>

            <td>0.41</td>

            <td>0.55</td>

            <td>0.00817</td>

            <td>-0.00045</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Central NSW</td>

            <td>0.265</td>

            <td>0.241</td>

            <td>0.505</td>

            <td>0.321</td>

            <td>0.00056</td>

            <td>0.414</td>

            <td>-0.021</td>

            <td>0.015</td>

            <td>-0.00033</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>SE Coast</td>

            <td>0.06</td>

            <td>0.361</td>

            <td>0</td>

            <td>0.317</td>

            <td>8.11E-05</td>

            <td>0.651</td>

            <td>0</td>

            <td>0</td>

            <td>0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Southern Semi-arid</td>

            <td>0.254</td>

            <td>0.247</td>

            <td>0.403</td>

            <td>0.351</td>

            <td>0.0013</td>

            <td>0.302</td>

            <td>0.058</td>

            <td>0</td>

            <td>0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Southern Temperate</td>

            <td>0.158</td>

            <td>0.276</td>

            <td>0.372</td>

            <td>0.315</td>

            <td>0.000141</td>

            <td>0.41</td>

            <td>0.15</td>

            <td>0.01</td>

            <td>-0.0027</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Northern Coastal</td>

            <td>0.326</td>

            <td>0.223</td>

            <td>0.442</td>

            <td>0.323</td>

            <td>0.0013</td>

            <td>0.58</td>

            <td>-0.374</td>

            <td>0.013</td>

            <td>-0.0015</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_g71oo">
        <m:math>
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>A</m:mi>
              <m:mi>R</m:mi>
              <m:mi>F</m:mi>
              <m:mo>=</m:mo>
              <m:mi>M</m:mi>
              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
              <m:mi>n</m:mi>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>[</m:mo>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>
                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>
                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                  <m:mn>0.287</m:mn>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>e</m:mi>
                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>0.265</m:mn>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msup>
                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                      <m:mn>0.439</m:mn>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>
                      <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                      <m:mi>D</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>u</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>o</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                      <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>.</m:mo>
                  <m:mi>D</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                      <m:mn>0.36</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>
                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                  <m:mn>2.26</m:mn>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtext> x 10</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                      <m:mn>3</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>
                  <m:mtext> x </m:mtext>
                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>0.226</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>
                  <m:mo>.</m:mo>
                  <m:mi>D</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>0.125</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>
                      <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>
                      <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                      <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>E</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                      <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                  <m:mn>0.0141</m:mn>
                  <m:mtext> x </m:mtext>
                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>0.213</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>
                  <m:mtext> x </m:mtext>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                      <m:mn>0.021</m:mn>
                      <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>D</m:mi>
                                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>
                                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>
                                  <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                                  <m:mn>180</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                            <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                          </m:msup>
                        </m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>1440</m:mn>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mfrac>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>
                      <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>
                      <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>
                      <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>E</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                      <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
                <m:mo>]</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
              feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
              hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
              4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
              vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
              fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamyqaiaadk
              facaWGgbGaeyypa0JaamytaiaadMgacaWGUbWaamWaaeaacaaIXaGa
              aiilaiaaigdacqGHsislcaaIWaGaaiOlaiaaiodacaaI0aGaaGinam
              aabmaabaGaamyqaiaadkhacaWGLbGaamyyamaaCaaaleqabaGaaGim
              aiaac6cacaaIYaGaaGinaiaaiEdaaaGccqGHsislcaaIWaGaaiOlai
              aaiodacaaI3aGaaGOmaiGacYgacaGGVbGaai4zamaaBaaaleaacaaI
              XaGaaGimaaqabaGccaGGOaGaamiraiaadwhacaWGYbGaamyyaiaads
              hacaWGPbGaam4Baiaad6gacaGGPaaacaGLOaGaayzkaaGaaiOlaiaa
              dseacaWG1bGaamOCaiaadggacaWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbWaaW
              baaSqabeaacqGHsislcaaIWaGaaiOlaiaaiodacaaI1aGaaG4naaaa
              kiabgUcaRiaaiwdacaGGUaGaaGynaiaaiAdacaqGGaGaaeiEaiaabc
              cacaqGXaGaaeimamaaCaaaleqabaGaeyOeI0IaaG4maaaakiaabcca
              caqG4bGaaeiiaiaadgeacaWGYbGaamyzaiaadggadaahaaWcbeqaai
              aaicdacaGGUaGaaGymaiaaiAdacaaI2aaaaOGaaiOlaiaadseacaWG
              1bGaamOCaiaadggacaWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbWaaWbaaSqabe
              aacaaIWaGaaiOlaiaaicdacaaIYaGaaGynaiaaiodaaaGcdaqadaqa
              aiaaicdacaGGUaGaaG4maiabgUcaRiGacYgacaGGVbGaai4zamaaBa
              aaleaacaaIXaGaaGimaaqabaGccaGGOaGaamyqaiaadweacaWGqbGa
              aiykaaGaayjkaiaawMcaaiabgUcaRiaaicdacaGGUaGaaGimaiaaig
              dacaaIZaGaaGinaiaabccacaqG4bGaaeiiaiaadgeacaWGYbGaamyz
              aiaadggadaahaaWcbeqaaiaaicdacaGGUaGaaGOmaiaaigdacaaIZa
              aaaOGaaeiiaiaabIhacaqGGaGaaGymaiaaicdadaahaaWcbeqaaiab
              gkHiTiaaicdacaGGUaGaaGimaiaaigdacaaI5aGaaGioamaalaaaba
              WaaeWaaeaacaWGebGaamyDaiaadkhacaWGHbGaamiDaiaadMgacaWG
              VbGaamOBaiabgkHiTiaaigdacaaI4aGaaGimaaGaayjkaiaawMcaam
              aaCaaameqabaGaaGOmaaaaaSqaaiaaigdacaaI0aGaaGinaiaaicda
              aaaaaOWaaeWaaeaacaaIWaGaaiOlaiaaiodacqGHRaWkciGGSbGaai
              4BaiaacEgadaWgaaWcbaGaaGymaiaaicdaaeqaaOGaaiikaiaadgea
              caWGfbGaamiuaiaacMcaaiaawIcacaGLPaaaaiaawUfacaGLDbaaaa a@CE02@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where Area is in km², Duration is in minutes and AEP is a fraction
      (between 0.5 and 0.0005).</para>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_xu7cs">
        <m:math>
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

              <m:mi>R</m:mi>

              <m:mi>F</m:mi>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

              <m:mi>R</m:mi>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mn>12</m:mn>

                  <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>24</m:mn>

                      <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>12</m:mn>

                      <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mfrac>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                      <m:mn>720</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mn>720</m:mn>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mfrac>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamyqaiaadk
            facaWGgbGaeyypa0JaamyqaiaadkfacaWGgbWaaSbaaSqaaiaaigda
            caaIYaGaamiAaiaad+gacaWG1bGaamOCaaqabaGccqGHRaWkdaqada
            qaaiaadgeacaWGsbGaamOramaaBaaaleaacaaIYaGaaGinaiaadIga
            caWGVbGaamyDaiaadkhaaeqaaOGaeyOeI0IaamyqaiaadkfacaWGgb
            WaaSbaaSqaaiaaigdacaaIYaGaamiAaiaad+gacaWG1bGaamOCaaqa
            baaakiaawIcacaGLPaaadaWcaaqaamaabmaabaGaamiraiaadwhaca
            WGYbGaamyyaiaadshacaWGPbGaam4Baiaad6gacqGHsislcaaI3aGa
            aGOmaiaaicdaaiaawIcacaGLPaaaaeaacaaI3aGaaGOmaiaaicdaaa
            aaaa@62D7@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where Duration is in minutes.</para>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_s6w9n">
        <m:math/>

        <m:math>
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

              <m:mi>R</m:mi>

              <m:mi>F</m:mi>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mn>1</m:mn>

              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

              <m:mn>0.6614</m:mn>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>10</m:mn>

                      <m:mi>k</m:mi>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>m</m:mi>

                        <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                      </m:msup>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>0.4</m:mn>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamyqaiaadk
            facaWGgbGaeyypa0JaaGymaiabgkHiTiaaicdacaGGUaGaaGOnaiaa
            iAdacaaIXaGaaGinamaabmaabaGaaGymaiabgkHiTiaadgeacaWGsb
            GaamOramaaBaaaleaacaaIXaGaaGimaiaadUgacaWGTbWaaWbaaWqa
            beaacaaIYaaaaaWcbeaaaOGaayjkaiaawMcaamaabmaabaGaamyqam
            aaCaaaleqabaGaaGimaiaac6cacaaI0aaaaOGaeyOeI0IaaGymaaGa
            ayjkaiaawMcaaaaa@4FE5@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>Where Area is in km²</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_5w6qc">
      <title>Recommended approach for events that are rarer than an AEP of
      0.05%</title>

      <para>The ARF equations are only recommended for use for events with an
      AEP of 0.05% or greater (i.e. more common than 1 in 2000 AEP). For more
      extreme events, the procedures recommended in <xref linkend="book8"/>
      should be used to determine catchment average design rainfall depths.
      The interpolation procedure recommended in <xref linkend="book8"/> uses
      the catchment average design rainfall depth for 0.05% AEP, which would
      be calculated using the average of the point design intensities across
      the catchment multiplied by the ARF estimates recommended above and the
      PMP depth, which is already estimated as a catchment average
      value.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_8o7l5">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref427046526"/>Recommended approaches for
      catchments with areas greater than 30,000 km²</title>

      <para>The largest (circular) catchments used by Podger et al. (2015) to
      estimate ARF were 30,000 km² and this set the upper limit of
      applicability of the ARF equations. As the catchment area increases
      beyond 30,000 km², it becomes increasingly likely that storm events
      would only influence part of the overall catchment area, which increases
      the uncertainty associated with adjusting point design intensities using
      an ARF.</para>

      <para>Design rainfall depths for catchments larger than 30,000 km²
      should be derived from frequency analysis of catchment average rainfall
      depths over the specific catchment. The design rainfall depths from the
      catchment specific frequency analysis should be checked by dividing them
      by the average of the point rainfall depths from point IFD analysis for
      the catchment (from Bureau of Meteorology, 2013) to infer the ARF for
      the catchment for each duration and AEP. It would be expected that for a
      catchment larger than 30,000 km², the ARF inferred from this check for
      each duration and AEP should be less than the ARF calculated from the
      regional method (<xref linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/>) for the corresponding
      duration and AEP combination. It would also be expected that the
      inferred ARF (for a given AEP) should increase with duration.</para>

      <para>For catchments larger than 30,000 km², it becomes increasingly
      likely that rainfall events that would give rise to flooding would be
      concentrated in one part of the catchment. For catchments larger than
      30,000 km² it is strongly recommended that partial area storms are
      explicitly modelled (using Monte Carlo or other joint-probability
      approaches). Explicit modelling of partial area storms should also be
      considered for catchments in the range between 5,000 km² and 30,000
      km².</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_v5tqp">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref414975995"/>Methods for deriving spatial
    patterns of rainfall for events</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_63bjd">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723348"/>Precipitation observation methods
      and uncertainties associated with reconstructing space-time rainfall
      patterns</title>

      <para>There is no accepted method for determining the space-time pattern
      of rainfall that is not influenced by the resolution and accuracy of our
      networks of rainfall observations.</para>

      <para>Rainfall gauges provide data on the rainfall depths observed at
      the point location of the rainfall gauge over different periods of time.
      Daily reporting rainfall gauges provide rainfall depths recorded at the
      gauge over the preceding day period, with the Australian Bureau of
      Meteorology’s typical practice being that these gauges report at 9:00 am
      local time on each day. Pluviograph or tipping bucket raingauges can
      provide rainfall depths observed at a point location for sub-daily
      temporal resolution. They can provide rainfall depths with temporal
      resolutions down to less than one minute.</para>

      <para>Rainfall gauges are subject to some observational errors but they
      typically provide relatively accurate measurements of the time series of
      rainfall recorded at a point location. They can under-record rainfall
      during periods of high winds, particularly for snow or for when rainfall
      intensities are low. There can be errors associated with estimating
      rainfall rates from tipping bucket rainfall gauges over defined periods
      of time from the recorded times of the bucket tips. During periods of
      very high rainfall intensity, tipping bucket gauges can be subject to
      errors induced by the bucket failing to tip or tipping when it is
      partially full. Rainfall gauges can also be subject to errors in manual
      recording of the data or electronic transmission of data from
      telemetered rainfall sites.</para>

      <para>The chief uncertainty introduced by a network of rainfall gauges
      is in accurately observing the space-time pattern of rainfall across an
      area because they cannot observe variations in rainfall patterns between
      the gauges (Seed and Austin 1990; Barnston 1991; Bradley <emphasis
      role="italic">et al</emphasis>. 1997).</para>

      <para>Remote sensing approaches can provide estimates of rainfall
      intensity observed on a spatial grid across a wide observation domain
      for a given period of time. The two most commonly available remote
      sensing approaches for rainfall estimation are ground-based weather
      radar and satellite observing systems.</para>

      <para>Weather radars measure the reflectivity returned by rain drops,
      hail stones or snow, which are converted into a rainfall intensity
      estimate. There are several different types of errors in this process
      that degrade the accuracy of the radar rainfall measurement (Joss and
      Waldvogel 1990; Collier 1996). The analysis of radar data to derive
      space-time patterns requires specialist expertise that lies outside the
      scope of these guidelines. However, such analysis could be considered
      for large studies which are able to secure the specialist expertise
      required. Weather radar approaches typically provide estimates of
      rainfall intensities that are more accurate on a relative basis within
      the space-time field of the event than in absolute magnitude
      terms.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_kusdg">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723349"/>Data availability</title>

      <para>Rainfall gauge observations are available at many locations across
      Australia for very long time periods, with data available at some sites
      since the middle of the 19th century. By contrast, reliable archives of
      data from remote sensing (weather radar and satellite based instruments)
      are only available from about the mid-1990’s. For many events, the only
      data that will be available to the practitioner to reconstruct the
      space-time pattern of rainfall will be from rainfall gauges.</para>

      <para>The practitioner should make use of the available data to
      reconstruct the space-time pattern of rainfall across the catchment or
      study area for the events that are to be utilised in model calibration
      and design flood simulation. The practitioner should assess the
      suitability of the rainfall data that is available for the event for
      reconstructing the space-time pattern, including rainfall gauges and any
      data that is available from remote sensing.</para>

      <para>The practitioner should consider the events that are to be used
      for constructing the space-time patterns of rainfall. Factors that
      should be considered in selecting events are the:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>number of sites and locations, relative to the catchment, of
          daily recording rainfall gauges;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>number of sites and locations, relative to the catchment, of
          continuous recording rainfall gauges;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>existence or otherwise of remotely sensed data;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>likely accuracy of quantitative rainfall estimates derived
          from remotely sensed data;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>purpose of estimating the space-time rainfall pattern, whether
          it is for hydrological model calibration, deriving a space-time
          pattern or spatial pattern for inclusion in design flood simulation
          or both;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>existence and quality of recorded flood levels, flood extents
          and gauged flows for the event, which make it a candidate for model
          calibration; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>estimated AEP of flood or the rainfall total for the event
          over the catchment of interest, relative to the AEP of the design
          floods that are to be estimated.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The practitioner may need to make judgements between using the
      space-time pattern for an older event, for which there is no remote
      sensing data and relatively poor coverage of rain gauge data but which
      produced high flood levels and a more recent event that has remotely
      sensed data and/or better coverage of rain gauge data but which produced
      a smaller flood.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_7picz">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723350"/>Construction of space-time
      patterns of rainfall from rainfall gauge networks</title>

      <para>There is uncertainty introduced in estimating the space-time
      pattern of rainfall from rainfall gauge estimates due to the attempt to
      interpolate the unobserved rainfall at locations between the gauges (see
      for example, Urbonas, <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>., 1992;
      Ball &amp; Luk, 1998).</para>

      <para>The conventional approach applied in flood hydrology for
      estimating the space-time pattern of rainfall from gauge networks has
      been:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>To estimate the spatial pattern of rainfall for the whole
          rainfall event; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>To disaggregate the rainfall accumulation for each part of the
          spatial domain, often a model subarea or subcatchment, using the
          temporal pattern observed at a particular rainfall gauge.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>The conventional approach articulated above is a valid approach in
      most situations but it may be that a more sophisticated approach
      involving construction of different spatial patterns for different
      increments of the event are required when spatial or temporal
      variability of the rainfall pattern for the event is large (Umakhanthan
      and Ball, 200). Considerations for application of each of the two steps
      are discussed below. Potential alternative approaches are discussed in
      the third subsection.</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_9uuis">
        <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref415058837"/>Construction of spatial
        patterns</title>

        <para>The spatial pattern should be constructed using rainfall totals
        from daily recording rainfall gauges and continuous recording rainfall
        gauges, where available. Gauges should be obtained from both within
        the catchment or study area and for a region around the catchment. As
        an indicative value, the region used for constructing the spatial
        pattern should extend to include gauges that are within at least 10 km
        of the catchment or study region boundary.</para>

        <para>There is no preferred technique for constructing a spatial
        pattern of rainfall for an event. Hand drawing of rainfall contours
        informed by the rainfall totals at the gauges remains a valid approach
        that will produce acceptable results for many rainfall events.</para>

        <para>Mathematical techniques for spatial interpolation implemented
        using computers are also acceptable. Spatial interpolation techniques
        usually involve interpolation between the point observations onto a
        grid, defined in either a geographic or projected Cartesian coordinate
        system. The grid resolution should be sufficiently fine to capture the
        spatial variability in the rainfall field at a meaningful scale for
        the catchment. It is recommended that the resolution of the grid
        should be 1 km (for a projected grid) or 0.01° (for a geographic grid)
        or finer. There are many potential approaches that have been developed
        for spatial interpolation (Verworn and Haberlandt, 2011 and the
        references therein), including:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Construction of Thiessen polygons, which is equivalent to
            adopting the rainfall depth from the nearest neighbour rainfall
            gauge when applied using a grid;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Weighting of rainfall using the inverse of the square of the
            distances to the gauges;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Natural neighbours;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Spline interpolation algorithms;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Ordinary Kriging; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Variants on Kriging, such as indicator Kriging, regression
            Kriging and Kriging with external drift.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Some Kriging and spline interpolation algorithms allow for the
        use of a covariate in the interpolation algorithm, which may improve
        the accuracy of the interpolation. Either elevation or design
        intensities for a relevant AEP and duration may provide appropriate
        covariates that improve the accuracy of the interpolation,
        particularly in catchments or study areas that are subject to
        appreciable and consistent orographic effects.</para>

        <para>Gridded daily rainfall data sets are available from SILO and the
        Australian Water Availability Project (Jones et al., 2009). These data
        sets may be useful for providing spatial patterns of rainfall events
        but they should be used with caution as they were not derived with the
        intention of being used for design flood estimation.</para>

        <para>Regardless of the approach that is used to produce the spatial
        pattern, the practitioner should check the spatial pattern produced by
        mapping it against the point values observed at rainfall gauges. If
        the mapping reveals anomalies in the interpolation approach, an
        alternative method should be adopted. Where large gaps in rain gauge
        coverage exist (particularly in mountainous areas) careful review of
        the simplifying assumptions made in the interpolation procedure should
        be undertaken by the practitioner to avoid unrealistic spatial
        patterns.</para>

        <para>Rainfall totals for each model subarea should be estimated from
        the spatially interpolated rainfall field for the event by averaging
        the rainfall totals at all grid cells that intersect with the spatial
        extent of the model subarea. Mathematically, this is represented
        by</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_xtsqw">
          <m:math>
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>S</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>s</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mfrac>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mstyle displaystyle="true">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>s</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>∩</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:msub>

                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>ρ</m:mi>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:msub>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mstyle>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mstyle displaystyle="true">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>s</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>∩</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:msub>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mstyle>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
              feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
              hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
              4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
              vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
              fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaam4uamaaBa
              aaleaacaWGZbaabeaakiabg2da9maalaaabaWaaabeaeaacaWGbbWa
              aSbaaSqaaiaadohacqGHPiYXcaWGPbGaaiilaiaadQgaaeqaaOGaeq
              yWdi3aaSbaaSqaaiaadMgacaGGSaGaamOAaaqabaaabaGaamyAaiaa
              cYcacaWGQbaabeqdcqGHris5aaGcbaWaaabeaeaacaWGbbWaaSbaaS
              qaaiaadohacqGHPiYXcaWGPbGaaiilaiaadQgaaeqaaaqaaiaadMga
              caGGSaGaamOAaaqab0GaeyyeIuoaaaaaaa@5294@</m:annotation>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where <emphasis role="italic">Ss</emphasis> is the rainfall
        depth for the total event applied to model subarea, <emphasis
        role="italic">s</emphasis>, <inlineequation>
            <m:math>
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>s</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>∩</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
                feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
                hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
                4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
                vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
                fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamyqamaaBa
                aaleaacaWGZbGaeyykICSaamyAaiaacYcacaWGQbaabeaaaaa@3C0C@</m:annotation>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation>is the area of overlap between grid cell at
        coordinate location (<emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis>,<emphasis
        role="italic">j</emphasis>) in the interpolated grid and the model
        subarea <emphasis role="italic">s</emphasis>, and <inlineequation>
            <m:math>
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>ρ</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
                feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
                hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
                4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
                vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
                fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaeqyWdi3aaS
                baaSqaaiaadMgacaGGSaGaamOAaaqabaaaaa@3A70@</m:annotation>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation>is the interpolated rainfall total for the grid
        cell.</para>

        <para>For rainfall events that extend for a period longer than 24
        hours, it may be useful to construct spatial patterns for separate
        time periods of the event to investigate the temporal evolution of the
        event.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_0kk62">
        <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref415057842"/>Disaggregation using temporal
        patterns from observed pluviograph data</title>

        <para>A conventional approach adopted is to disaggregate the total
        rainfall for each subarea of a rainfall runoff model using the
        temporal pattern recorded at a recording rain gauge, using the
        formula:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_k5jiv">
          <m:math>
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>s</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mfrac>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>S</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>s</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>

                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>g</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mstyle displaystyle="true">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>g</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:msub>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mstyle>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
              feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
              hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
              4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
              vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
              fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamOuamaaBa
              aaleaacaWGZbGaaiilaiaadMgaaeqaaOGaeyypa0ZaaSaaaeaacaWG
              tbWaaSbaaSqaaiaadohaaeqaaOGaamOCamaaBaaaleaacaWGNbGaai
              ilaiaadMgaaeqaaaGcbaWaaabeaeaacaWGYbWaaSbaaSqaaiaadEga
              caGGSaGaamyAaaqabaaabaGaamyAaaqab0GaeyyeIuoaaaaaaa@46E0@</m:annotation>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where <emphasis role="italic">Rs,i</emphasis> is the rainfall
        depth applied to model subarea, <emphasis role="italic">s,</emphasis>
        for model time increment, <emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis>;
        <emphasis role="italic">Ss</emphasis> is the total event rainfall for
        model subarea <emphasis role="italic">s</emphasis>; <emphasis
        role="italic">rg,i</emphasis> is the rainfall depth recorded at gauge,
        <emphasis role="italic">g, </emphasis>for model time increment,
        <emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis>; and the summation is formed for
        all time increments over the event.</para>

        <para>Where data is available from more than one recording rain gauge,
        this provides options to the practitioner on which gauge to select to
        provide the temporal pattern for each subarea of the model. An
        assumption is often made that the most appropriate pattern would be
        provided by the recording rainfall gauge that is located closest, by
        horizontal distance, from the centroid of the model subarea. Whilst
        the closest gauge by physical distance makes intuitive sense, it is
        not necessarily the case that it must provide the most appropriate
        pattern for allocating the temporal pattern of a particular subarea.
        The practitioner may consult other information, such as catchment
        topography, data on wind velocities during the event or remote sensing
        data to guide the selection of an alternative to the nearest gauge for
        providing the temporal pattern. The practitioner may also use other
        information on the meteorology of the event to justify use of an
        adjusted temporal pattern for disaggregation. For example, if
        information was available that a particular rainfall event was moving
        in a particular direction at an average velocity of 15 km/h and a
        model subarea was located 30 km downwind of a recording rainfall
        gauge, it may be justified to adjust the temporal pattern recorded at
        this gauge by moving it backward in time by two hours, to represent
        the estimated travel time of the storm from the rainfall gauge to the
        model subarea.</para>

        <para>The time series of rainfall at each recording gauge should be
        checked before it is used for disaggregation. The event total rainfall
        at each recording gauge should be checked, where available, against
        the event total rainfall at other daily recording and continuously
        recording gauges in the vicinity. A gauge should not be used if
        significant anomalies are identified in the recorded data for the
        site.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_kcr90">
        <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723353"/>Alternative approaches to
        construction of space-time patterns from rain gauge data</title>

        <para>A potential alternative approach to construct the space-time
        pattern of rainfall for an event from rain gauge data only is to
        construct a three dimensional space-time pattern grid. In this
        approach, the overall event spatial pattern would be interpolated onto
        a grid, using one of the potential approaches discussed in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch4_s_9uuis"/>. The total rainfall for each grid cell
        would then be disaggregated using the temporal pattern from an
        assigned recording rainfall gauge, using a similar method as discussed
        in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_0kk62"/>. For each time increment, a
        summation is formed for all of the grid cells that intersect spatially
        with each model subarea. Each subarea would then have its own,
        potentially unique, temporal pattern for the event.</para>

        <para>In a catchment that is well instrumented with recording rainfall
        gauges, it is possible to perform a spatial interpolation on to a grid
        for each time increment. The gridded rainfall for each time increment
        would then be summed to produce a temporal pattern for each model
        subarea. If this approach is used, the total rainfall across the event
        should be calculated for each subarea and then compared to the
        rainfall computed from spatially interpolating the event total
        rainfall only. Adjustments should be considered to the approach if the
        totals for any subarea differ by more than 5%.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_vmrah">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref414976014"/>Space-time patterns for
      calibration of rainfall runoff models to historical floods</title>

      <para>Rainfall-runoff routing models typically have a number of
      parameters that control the simulation of runoff generation and routing
      processes in the model. Similarly, rainfall on grid hydraulic models
      have parameters that control runoff generation processes and roughness
      and eddy viscosity parameters that manipulate flows between model grid
      cells.</para>

      <para>Where data is available, it is recommended that models should be
      calibrated to gauged flows, recorded levels and/or recorded flood
      extents for historical floods. The calibration process involves tuning
      of model parameters to achieve an adequate match between the simulated
      and observed flood data. Where possible, the model should be calibrated
      to a number of different flood events, with the focus on flood events
      that are of similar magnitudes to the range of design floods that will
      be estimated using the model.</para>

      <para>Simulation of historical flood events for calibration purposes
      includes reconstruction of the space-time pattern of rainfall over the
      catchment by the practitioner. The values of the apparent optimum set of
      model parameters for a given event can be influenced by the approach
      taken to estimate the space-time pattern of rainfall for the event. For
      example, if a catchment is simulated using an initial loss-continuing
      loss runoff generation model, then if all other parameters and inputs
      are the same a lower continuing loss rate is likely to be required to
      generate the same volume of runoff if a uniform spatial pattern is
      adopted compared with a non-uniform spatial pattern. The practitioner
      should consider and articulate the influence of assumptions made in
      deriving the space-time pattern of rainfall for the event on the values
      of the rainfall runoff model parameters calibrated for the event.</para>

      <para>The spatial coverage of pluviographs around a catchment may be
      relatively sparse. This introduces uncertainty into the estimation of
      the actual temporal pattern of rainfall for any given subarea or grid
      cell of a model. Whilst a reasonable assumption may be that the temporal
      pattern for a given model subarea would be defined by the pluviograph
      that is nearest in horizontal distance, this may not necessarily produce
      the most accurate temporal pattern for the model subarea. As discussed
      in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_0kk62"/>, a more accurate representation of
      the space-time rainfall pattern over a model subarea may be produced by
      judicious adjustment of the temporal pattern observed at a gauge or
      selection of a temporal pattern from a gauge that is not physically
      closest to the subarea centroid. Adjusting the assignment of temporal
      patterns to subareas in this manner may assist the practitioner in
      achieving a more robust calibration of the model parameters to the
      event. Adjustment of temporal patterns and temporal pattern assignment
      is therefore allowable, particularly if meteorological evidence is
      provided to support the decision.</para>

      <para>The spatial or space-time pattern should be interpolated on to a
      regular grid that is constructed over the catchment. The resolution of
      the grid should be sufficiently fine to allow for spatial variations to
      be adequately represented. In most situations, the grid resolution
      should be selected so that there are at least 4 grid cells overlapping
      with the smallest subcatchment to be adopted in the model.</para>

      <para>Remote sensing data, where available, may be used to estimate the
      space-time rainfall field of an event for flood model calibration. If
      used, the space-time rainfall field should be corrected using data from
      rainfall gauges, using a recommended approach for adjusting for the mean
      field bias.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_smesd">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref414976020"/>Spatial and space-time patterns for
    design flood estimation</title>

    <para>The aim of a design flood estimation model should be to provide an
    AEP neutral transformation between the design rainfall inputs and the most
    important characteristics of the design flood estimates.</para>

    <para>The space-time pattern or set of space-time patterns adopted for
    design flood estimation should be chosen in a manner that, when coupled
    with other aspects of the flood estimation modelling system, preserves the
    AEP of the design flood when derived from its causative rainfall.</para>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_jcjfw">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref436381451"/>Minimum guidance for catchments
      up to and including 20km² in area: single uniform spatial
      pattern</title>

      <para>Catchments up to and including 20 km² in area are sufficiently
      small that there is little generally available data to derive a spatial
      pattern. For these catchments, it is usually acceptable to adopt a
      uniform spatial pattern.</para>

      <para>If there is sufficient density of continuously recording rainfall
      gauges that have recorded a number of rainfall events, using this data
      to derive alternative (non-uniform) design spatial patterns may be
      considered.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_wxnds">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref427056836"/>Minimum guidance for catchments
      with areas greater than 20 km²: single non-uniform spatial
      pattern</title>

      <para>As a minimum, it is recommended that a single non-uniform spatial
      pattern is applied. The non-uniform spatial pattern should be derived
      with the aim of replicating the systematic variation in spatial
      variability that would be expected across the catchment during rainfall
      events of similar AEP to the design floods that are being
      estimated.</para>

      <para>For estimation of design flood events of 1% AEP and more frequent,
      the spatial pattern should be estimated using the spatial pattern
      derived from the Bureau of Meteorology (2013) design rainfall grids
      across the catchment for the 1% AEP and for a duration that is
      anticipated to correspond to the duration of the rainfall burst that is
      likely to be critical at the specified location. Different spatial
      patterns could be applied for different durations. Alternatively, one
      spatial pattern may be estimated for the estimated critical duration and
      this single spatial pattern may then be applied for all
      durations.</para>

      <para>For estimation of design flood events rarer than 1% AEP and
      durations of 6 hours and less on catchments less than 1000 km² in area,
      the spatial pattern should be derived in accordance with Bureau of
      Meteorology (1994) for the relevant duration. Use of different spatial
      patterns for different AEP ranges may introduce inconsistences at the
      adjacent limits of each method, and if this is the case then any such
      inconsistencies should be smoothed in an appropriate fashion.</para>

      <para>For estimation of design flood events rarer than 1% AEP and
      durations of 9 hours and greater or on catchments greater than 1000 km²
      in area, the spatial pattern should be derived from the topographic
      adjustment factor (TAF) database derived from the generalised PMP method
      that is relevant for zone that the catchment is located in. Use of
      different spatial patterns for different AEP ranges may introduce
      inconsistences at the adjacent limits of each method, and if this is the
      case then any such inconsistencies should be smoothed in an appropriate
      fashion.</para>

      <para>For large studies and particularly for large catchments the
      practitioner should investigate and analyse the variability in spatial
      patterns between events. Where topography is dominant or large events
      are generally produced by a single rainfall mechanism there is likely to
      be only moderate variability between events but for some catchments
      there can be significant variations in space-time patterns between
      events. The practitioner should prepare and examine maps of the spatial
      pattern of precipitation each event as a whole and for time slices, for
      example each 24 hour period, of the each event, using an approach
      described in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_v5tqp"/>. These spatial patterns
      should be compared to rainfall accumulations from
      intensity-frequency-duration analysis for a relevant duration and AEP
      (see Jordan et al., 2015 for an example of this approach). Consistency
      in spatial patterns between events may reveal that it is acceptable to
      apply a single spatial pattern for all design flood estimates,
      particularly if it is consistent with the intensity-frequency-duration
      analysis.</para>

      <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_8o7l5"/>, partial area
      storms should always be explicitly considered for catchments with an
      area exceeding 30,000 km² and it should be considered for catchments
      larger than 5,000 km².</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_crij9">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723358"/>Alternative approach: Monte-Carlo
      sampling from separate populations of spatial and temporal
      patterns</title>

      <para>A more advanced approach that may be justified would be
      Monte-Carlo simulation by sampling from a set of space-time rainfall
      patterns across the catchment of interest. There are two potential
      options that may be considered for implementing this approach: (1)
      sampling from separate populations of spatial and temporal patterns for
      the catchment; or (2) sampling from a single set of “linked” space-time
      patterns for the catchment.</para>

      <para>The first approach requires the assembly of:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>a set (or population) of spatial patterns across the catchment
          of interest from a number of observed rainfall events; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>a set of temporal patterns from a number of observed rainfall
          events.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The spatial pattern of rainfall should be assembled for each event
      in the population, in accordance with the methods discussed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_s_v5tqp"/>. The catchment average rainfall accumulation
      should be computed for each event and continuously recording rainfall
      gauges located in or near the catchment should be used to estimate the
      duration over which most of the total rainfall accumulation was likely
      to have fallen in the catchment. The estimated catchment average depth
      for the event and the estimated rainfall event duration should be used
      with the table of design intensity-frequency-duration estimates for the
      catchment, after application of the applicable ARF, to estimate the AEP
      of the rainfall for each event.</para>

      <para>Similarly, the temporal pattern of rainfall should be assembled
      for each event in the population. The temporal pattern may be assembled
      at a single continuously recording rainfall gauge or from a combination
      of a number of continuously recording rainfall gauges located in the
      vicinity of the catchment or study area. The temporal pattern should be
      analysed to extract the maximum burst for a number of different
      durations. The rainfall accumulations over these bursts should be
      compared to the design intensity-frequency-duration estimates at the
      location of the recording rainfall gauge, without the application of the
      ARF, to estimate the AEP of the rainfall for each event.</para>

      <para>A sample of patterns for use in the Monte-Carlo simulation should
      be selected from the set of historical events that are available. A
      sufficient number of events should be selected to allow for a
      meaningfully large sample in the Monte-Carlo simulation. It is expected
      that a minimum of five patterns would be required each of the sets of
      spatial and temporal patterns. However, events should only be selected
      for inclusion in the sample if they are relatively similar in terms of
      the AEP of the rainfall to the range of AEP that design flood estimates
      are required for. Ideally, the spatial patterns and temporal patterns of
      events selected for the Monte-Carlo sample should have an estimated AEP
      that is between 1/10 and ten times the AEP of the design flood event to
      be simulated. Adding more historic spatial patterns to an ensemble does
      not necessarily improve the simulation accuracy of a Monte Carlo model,
      as the additional patterns that are most likely to be added would be at
      the more common end of the AEP range. In many catchments, design floods
      of interest are caused by rainfall events with a specific
      hydrometeorological mechanism, which is then associated with a range of
      space-time rainfall patterns that are different to those observed in
      rainfall events caused by more commonly occurring hydrometeorological
      conditions.</para>

      <para>Unless there is hydrometeorological evidence to the contrary, all
      potential spatial and temporal patterns in the sets available for
      sampling should be given equal probability of selection in the
      Monte-Carlo simulation scheme.</para>

      <para>After the spatial and temporal patterns for the design rainfall
      burst have been selected stochastically, the patterns should be scaled
      so that the catchment average rainfall depth for the design rainfall
      burst matches the depth generated stochastically by the sampling
      scheme.</para>

      <para>There has been limited assessment on methods for selection of
      space-time patterns for use in Monte-Carlo simulation schemes for design
      flood estimation. Further research should be conducted in this area to
      provide more robust guidance on the minimum number of temporal and
      spatial patterns in the sampling populations, the range of AEP
      represented by the populations of spatial and temporal patterns to be
      sampled compared to the AEP of the depth of the rainfall burst and the
      relative probabilities to be applied in the selection of spatial and
      temporal patterns.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_idvch">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref415221234"/>Alternative approach: Monte-Carlo
      sampling from single population of space-time patterns</title>

      <para>The foregoing approach ignores the potential dependency that
      exists between the temporal and spatial characteristics of storms.
      According, an alternative approach would involve sampling the space-time
      pattern for the event from a single population of space-time rainfall
      patterns over the catchment. The sample of space-time patterns may be
      assembled from space-time patterns of rainfall observed during
      historical rainfall events in the catchment. The space-time patterns
      should be assembled in accordance with the methods discussed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_s_v5tqp"/>. The estimated catchment average depth for
      different burst durations within the event and the estimated rainfall
      event duration should be used with the table of design
      intensity-frequency-duration estimates for the catchment, after
      application of the applicable ARF, to estimate the AEP of the rainfall
      for each event.</para>

      <para>It may be an option to transpose space-time rainfall patterns from
      an area with a good observational network for rainfall to a catchment
      with a poorer observational network. If this is done, the practitioner
      should only transpose (non-dimensional) space-time rainfall patterns
      from an area that is subject to rainfall events that are driven by
      similar hydrometeorological processes. The transposition region should
      be subject to similar orographic influences. In some cases, the
      space-time patterns may need to be rotated to maintain consistency
      between the spatial gradients in the space-time patterns and
      orographically influenced gradients in the design
      intensity-frequency-duration gridded data.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_euwbb">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723360"/>Spatial patterns for pre-burst
      and post-burst rainfall</title>

      <para>If pre-burst or post-burst rainfall is to be applied, it is
      recommended that, unless there is evidence to the contrary, the spatial
      pattern applied to the pre-burst or post-burst rainfall should be the
      same as the spatial pattern applied for the design rainfall
      burst.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_66sze">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723361"/>Spatial Patterns for Continuous
      Rainfall Series</title>

      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5"/> discusses the production of continuous
      rainfall time series for production of design flood estimation using
      continuous simulation approaches. <xref linkend="b2_ch5"/> includes an
      approach to post-process the sequence of generated rainfall data for the
      catchment of interest so that the characteristics of the large and
      extreme rainfall events in the sequence reflect the
      intensity-frequency-duration (IFD) statistics for the catchment of
      interest. If such an adjustment is conducted then it is recommended that
      the IFD statistics used as the basis of the adjustment are calculated
      for the catchment of interest after multiplying by the ARF that is
      applicable for the catchment area.</para>

      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5"/> recommends that the IFD adjustment is applied for a set of
        target durations of either 6 minutes, 1 hour and 3 hours or for a set of durations of 6
        minutes, 30 minutes, 1 hour, 3 hours, 6 hours and 12 hours. It is recommended therefore that
        the following procedure is adopted:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The IFD statistics for each of the target durations are
          calculated as the average of the point IFD statistics across the
          catchment, for each of the standard AEP (1EY to 1% AEP);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The ARF are computed for each of the target durations, at each
          of the standard AEP, for the total area of the catchment to be
          modelled;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The catchment IFD statistics are computed for each of the
          target durations, at each of the standard AEP, as the product of the
          point IFD statistics (from step 1) and the ARF (from step 2);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The catchment IFD statistics (from step 3) are applied in the
          modification procedure as the depths at the selected target
          durations.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>The practitioner may be adopting a catchment model that allows for
      spatial distribution of the simulated rainfall sequence across the
      catchment. If this is the case, it is recommended that the generated
      sequence of rainfall is scaled for each portion of the model
      (subcatchment or grid-cell as applicable to the particular model) to
      reflect the spatial distribution of rainfall that would be typically
      observed across the catchment. Parts of the catchment that are typically
      wetter would have rainfall depths applied in the model that are larger
      than the generated mean rainfall depth across the catchment but with the
      same timing and sequencing. Conversely, parts of the catchment that are
      typically drier would have rainfall depths applied in the model that are
      smaller than the generated mean rainfall depth across the catchment but
      with the same timing and sequencing.</para>

      <para>Selection of an appropriate means of deriving the spatial pattern
      for a continuous simulation model that includes spatial distribution
      depends upon the AEP of the design events that are of most interest and
      the flood response characteristics of the catchment:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>When the focus is on estimation of floods with relatively
          common AEP (around 10% or more common) and for catchments with large
          moisture stores having significant relation between antecedent
          rainfall and the annual maximum flood, it is recommended that the
          spatial pattern applied in the model should be estimated from
          contours of mean annual rainfall;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>However when the focus is on estimation on floods with rarer
          AEP (5% or rarer) and for catchments where the influence of large
          moisture stores are less significant, it is recommended that the
          spatial pattern should be selected in a manner that is consistent
          with the recommendation for design event simulation (refer to <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_s_jcjfw"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_wxnds"/>
          above).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_4ho8s">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref414979144"/>Potential influences of climate
    change on areal reduction factors, spatial and space-time patterns</title>

    <para>The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change’s Fifth Assessment
    Report (2013) found that heavy precipitation events over most of the
    mid-latitude land masses and over wet tropical regions will very likely
    (i.e., with at least 90 percent probability) become more intense and more
    frequent by the end of this century, as global mean surface temperature
    increases. Engineers Australia (2014) provided interim guidance on
    accommodating climate change in estimates of design rainfall intensities
    for rainfall bursts used in design flood estimation.</para>

    <para>There is very little credible guidance on how climate change is
    projected to influence ARF, spatial patterns or space-time patterns of
    rainfall events used in design flood estimation. Abbs et al. (2007) used
    dynamic downscaling using a regional climate model to identify that
    increases in rainfall intensity are likely to be greater in those areas of
    southeast Queensland that are subject to orographic enhancement than those
    areas that are not. There is insufficient evidence to confirm whether this
    projection is an artefact of the downscaling approach and whether it would
    still apply if the dynamic downscaling model were forced with Global
    Circulation Model results from the more recent Intergovernmental Panel on
    Climate Change’s Fifth Assessment Report (2013). Even if it were proven
    for Southeast Queensland, it is not clear that the guidance would be more
    generally applicable to other parts of Australia.</para>

    <para>It is recommended that until credible further studies are completed
    showing otherwise, for simulations applying projected climate change ARF,
    spatial patterns and space-time patterns of design rainfall should be the
    same as derived under existing climatic conditions.</para>

    <para/>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_tzg2j">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723363"/>Worked examples</title>

    <para>All of the worked examples in this chapter use data for the Stanley
    River catchment, which is in the upper part of the Brisbane River basin in
    Southeast Queensland. Worked example 1 demonstrates three different
    mathematical algorithms for estimating the spatial pattern of design
    rainfall for a particular rainfall event that occurred in January 2013.
    Worked examples 2 through 4 demonstrate the process for design flood
    estimation, from calculation of ARF and catchment average design rainfall
    estimates (worked example 2), through calculation of a representative
    spatial pattern (worked example 3), to production of design flood
    estimates using a rainfall runoff routing model (worked example 4).</para>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_4kglo">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723364"/>Catchment used for worked
      examples</title>

      <para>The Stanley River catchment drains into Somerset Dam, which is in
      the upper part of the Brisbane River basin in Southeast Queensland.
      <xref linkend="b2_ch4_f_s18xr"/> shows a map of the 1324 km². catchment
      area, with Somerset Dam located in the southwestern corner. For this
      worked example, rainfall runoff modelling of the Stanley River catchment
      is conducted using a rainfall runoff routing model that has been created
      using 76 subcatchments, with sub-area as shown in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_f_avrt3"/>.</para>

      <para>For this worked example, design rainfall estimates are developed
      for the Stanley River at Woodford, which has a catchment area of 245
      km². The catchment to Woodford is the north-eastern portion of the
      catchment to Somerset Dam and for this worked example it includes
      fifteen subcatchments in the rainfall runoff routing model.</para>

      <para>A significant feature of the Stanley River catchment is the
      appreciable gradient in rainfall that is typically observed during large
      rainfall events. Tropical cyclones, ex-Tropical Cyclones, East Coast
      Lows and other rainfall producing systems typically feed moisture into
      the catchment from the Pacific Ocean. Since the north eastern part of
      the catchment is only 20 km from the coast but the western side of the
      catchment is almost 70 km from the coast, the typical direction of storm
      movement and typical direction of flow of warm moist air from the ocean
      results in a gradient of rainfall totals that reduce from east to west
      across the catchment in most rainfall events. The strength of the
      rainfall gradient is enhanced by orographic effects with the highest
      totals typically also occurring in the north eastern part of the
      catchment.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_avrt3">
        <title>Map of the Stanley River catchment, showing rainfall runoff
        model subcatchments and the locations of daily rainfall and
        pluviograph gauges</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2060.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_7kk9d">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723365"/>Worked Example 1: Interpolation
      of spatial patterns for an event using various methods</title>

      <para>Tropical Cyclone Oswald generated heavy rainfall in the Stanley
      River catchment between 23 and 29 January 2013, generating flooding in
      the catchment. Rainfall totals were observed at 20 continuously
      recording gauges around the Stanley River catchment, as shown in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_f_hgj5a"/>(rainfall data supplied by SeqWater).</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_hgj5a">
        <title>Rainfall totals in mm recorded at rainfall gauges for the
        January 2013 event in the vicinity of the Stanley River catchment. The
        blue circles are scaled in proportion to the rainfall depth recorded
        at the gauge.</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2061.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The January 2013 rainfall event was used in this worked example to
      demonstrate various approaches to interpolation of spatial patterns of
      historical rainfall events, for the purpose of calibration of rainfall
      runoff routing models. For all of the algorithms, the rainfall totals
      were first interpolated onto a 0.5 km resolution grid over the
      catchment. Rainfall totals for each of the 76 rainfall runoff model
      subcatchments were then computed from the average of the rainfall totals
      at the grid cells that overlapped each subcatchment.</para>

      <para>Rainfall totals were spatially interpolated using:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Thiessen polygons, as shown in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_f_vn5xg"/>;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Inverse distance weighting, as shown in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_f_isixl"/>;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Ordinary Kriging, as shown in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_f_6on8f"/>. Ordinary Kriging was applied using a
          linear semi-variogram that was fitted to observed rainfall totals at
          the 20 gauges from the January 2013 event, as shown in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch4_f_c27k4"/>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_vn5xg">
        <title>Application of Thiessen Polygons for spatial interpolation of
        rainfall totals for the January 2013 event across the Stanley River
        catchment. Observed totals at gauges are shown as blue circles in both
        panels. The top panel shows interpolation to a 0.5 km grid (red
        shading), whilst the bottom panel shows calculated subcatchment
        average depths in mm (red circles).</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2062.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_isixl">
        <title>Application of Inverse Distance Weighting for spatial
        interpolation of rainfall totals for the January 2013 event across the
        Stanley River catchment. Observed totals at gauges are shown as blue
        circles in both panels. The top panel shows interpolation to a 0.5 km
        grid (red shading), whilst the bottom panel shows calculated
        subcatchment average depths in mm (red circles).</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2064.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_6on8f">
        <title>Application of Ordinary Kriging for spatial interpolation of
        rainfall totals for the January 2013 event across the Stanley River
        catchment. Observed totals at gauges are shown as blue circles in both
        panels. The top panel shows interpolation to a 0.5 km grid (red
        shading), whilst the bottom panel shows calculated subcatchment
        average depths in mm (red circles).</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2065.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_c27k4">
        <title>Observed semi-variogram and fitted linear semi-variogram for
        the January 2013 rainfall event across the Stanley River catchment,
        which was applied in the Ordinary Kriging algorithm</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2066.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_qodd4">
      <title>Worked Example 2: Calculation of catchment average design
      rainfall depths and areal reduction factors</title>

      <para>Design rainfall intensities were extracted at the centroids of
      each of the fifteen rainfall runoff model subcatchments in the catchment
      of the Stanley River to Woodford from Bureau of Meteorology (2013) for
      the 1% AEP and 24 hour duration. The weighted average of the point
      rainfall depths was computed, as shown in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_t_k3lyj"/>.</para>

      <para>The catchment area for the Stanley River to Woodford is 245.07
      km². The ARF for 24 hour duration was computed by applying <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_e_wedgj"/>, with the relevant coefficients for the East
      Coast North region (from the 1st row of <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_t_tc83g"/>). For the 1% AEP event the relevant ARF is
      given by:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_smrvd">
        <m:math>
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mtable columnalign="left">
              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>l</m:mi>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>c</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>c</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>

              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>M</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                          <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                              <m:msup>
                                <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                                <m:mi>b</m:mi>
                              </m:msup>

                              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                              <m:mi>c</m:mi>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                              <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>f</m:mi>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>

                              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                              <m:mfrac>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>D</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>1440</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:mfrac>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>

                              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>}</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>
            </m:mtable>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aqatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGceaqabeaacaWGbb
            GaamyzaiaadkhacaWGHbGaamiBaiaabccacaWGYbGaamyzaiaadsga
            caWG1bGaam4yaiaadshacaWGPbGaam4Baiaad6gacaqGGaGaamOzai
            aadggacaWGJbGaamiDaiaad+gacaWGYbaabaGaeyypa0Jaamytaiaa
            dMgacaWGUbWaaiWaaeaacaaIXaGaaiilamaadmaabaGaaGymaiabgk
            HiTiaadggadaqadaqaaiaadgeacaWGYbGaamyzaiaadggadaahaaWc
            beqaaiaadkgaaaGccqGHsislcaWGJbGaciiBaiaac+gacaGGNbWaaS
            baaSqaaiaaigdacaaIWaaabeaakiaadseacaWG1bGaamOCaiaadgga
            caWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbaacaGLOaGaayzkaaGaamiraiaadw
            hacaWGYbGaamyyaiaadshacaWGPbGaam4Baiaad6gadaahaaWcbeqa
            aiabgkHiTiaadsgaaaGccqGHRaWkcaWGLbGaamyqaiaadkhacaWGLb
            GaamyyamaaCaaaleqabaGaamOzaaaakiaadseacaWG1bGaamOCaiaa
            dggacaWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbWaaWbaaSqabeaacaWGNbaaaO
            WaaeWaaeaacaaIWaGaaiOlaiaaiodacqGHRaWkciGGSbGaai4Baiaa
            cEgadaWgaaWcbaGaaGymaiaaicdaaeqaaOGaamyqaiaadweacaWGqb
            aacaGLOaGaayzkaaGaey4kaSIaamiAaiaaigdacaaIWaWaaWbaaSqa
            beaacaWGPbGaamyqaiaadkhacaWGLbGaamyyamaalaaabaGaamirai
            aadwhacaWGYbGaamyyaiaadshacaWGPbGaam4Baiaad6gaaeaacaaI
            XaGaaGinaiaaisdacaaIWaaaaaaakmaabmaabaGaaGimaiaac6caca
            aIZaGaey4kaSIaciiBaiaac+gacaGGNbWaaSbaaSqaaiaaigdacaaI
            WaaabeaakiaadgeacaWGfbGaamiuaaGaayjkaiaawMcaaaGaay5wai
            aaw2faaaGaay5Eaiaaw2haaaaaaa@AB74@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_gmgb0">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mtable columnalign="left">
              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>l</m:mi>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>c</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>c</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>

              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>M</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>n</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                          <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                          <m:mn>0.327</m:mn>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msup>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>245.07</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>0.241</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msup>

                              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                              <m:mn>0.448</m:mn>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                              <m:mn>1440</m:mn>

                              <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>1440</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                              <m:mn>0.36</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mn>0.00096</m:mn>

                          <m:mtext> x 245</m:mtext>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mtext>.07</m:mtext>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>0.48</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>1440</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                              <m:mn>0.21</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>

                              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                              <m:mn>0.01</m:mn>

                              <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                          <m:mn>0.012</m:mn>

                          <m:mtext> x </m:mtext>

                          <m:msup>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                              <m:mn>0.001</m:mn>

                              <m:mtext> x </m:mtext>

                              <m:mn>245.07</m:mn>

                              <m:mtext> x </m:mtext>

                              <m:mfrac>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>1440</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>1440</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:mfrac>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msup>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mn>0.3</m:mn>

                              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>10</m:mn>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mn>0.01</m:mn>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>}</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>
            </m:mtable>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aaatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGceaqabeaacaWGbb
            GaamOCaiaadwgacaWGHbGaamiBaiaabccacaWGYbGaamyzaiaadsga
            caWG1bGaam4yaiaadshacaWGPbGaam4Baiaad6gacaqGGaGaamOzai
            aadggacaWGJbGaamiDaiaad+gacaWGYbaabaGaeyypa0Jaamytaiaa
            dMgacaWGUbWaaiWaaeaacaaIXaGaaiilamaadmaabaGaaGymaiabgk
            HiTiaaicdacaGGUaGaaG4maiaaikdacaaI3aWaaeWaaeaacaaIYaGa
            aGinaiaaiwdacaGGUaGaaGimaiaaiEdadaahaaWcbeqaaiaaicdaca
            GGUaGaaGOmaiaaisdacaaIXaaaaOGaeyOeI0IaaGimaiaac6cacaaI
            0aGaaGinaiaaiIdaciGGSbGaai4BaiaacEgadaWgaaWcbaGaaGymai
            aaicdaaeqaaOGaaiikaiaaigdacaaI0aGaaGinaiaaicdacaGGPaaa
            caGLOaGaayzkaaGaaGymaiaaisdacaaI0aGaaGimamaaCaaaleqaba
            GaeyOeI0IaaGimaiaac6cacaaIZaGaaGOnaaaakiabgUcaRiaaicda
            caGGUaGaaGimaiaaicdacaaIWaGaaGyoaiaaiAdacaqGGaGaaeiEai
            aabccacaqGYaGaaeinaiaabwdacaqGUaGaaeimaiaabEdadaahaaWc
            beqaaiaaicdacaGGUaGaaGinaiaaiIdaaaGccaaIXaGaaGinaiaais
            dacaaIWaWaaWbaaSqabeaacqGHsislcaaIWaGaaiOlaiaaikdacaaI
            XaaaaOWaaeWaaeaacaaIWaGaaiOlaiaaiodacqGHRaWkciGGSbGaai
            4BaiaacEgadaWgaaWcbaGaaGymaiaaicdaaeqaaOGaaiikaiaaicda
            caGGUaGaaGimaiaaigdacaGGPaaacaGLOaGaayzkaaGaey4kaSIaaG
            imaiaac6cacaaIWaGaaGymaiaaikdacaqGGaGaaeiEaiaabccacaaI
            XaGaaGimamaaCaaaleqabaGaeyOeI0IaaGimaiaac6cacaaIWaGaaG
            imaiaaigdacaqGGaGaaeiEaiaabccacaaIYaGaaGinaiaaiwdacaGG
            UaGaaGimaiaaiEdacaqGGaGaaeiEaiaabccadaWcaaqaaiaaigdaca
            aI0aGaaGinaiaaicdaaeaacaaIXaGaaGinaiaaisdacaaIWaaaaaaa
            kmaabmaabaGaaGimaiaac6cacaaIZaGaey4kaSIaciiBaiaac+gaca
            GGNbWaaSbaaSqaaiaaigdacaaIWaaabeaakiaaicdacaGGUaGaaGim
            aiaaigdaaiaawIcacaGLPaaaaiaawUfacaGLDbaaaiaawUhacaGL9b
            aaaaaa@C232@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_mvo36">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

              <m:mi>a</m:mi>

              <m:mi>l</m:mi>

              <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

              <m:mi>d</m:mi>

              <m:mi>u</m:mi>

              <m:mi>c</m:mi>

              <m:mi>t</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

              <m:mi>n</m:mi>

              <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

              <m:mi>f</m:mi>

              <m:mi>a</m:mi>

              <m:mi>c</m:mi>

              <m:mi>t</m:mi>

              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                  <m:mn>24</m:mn>

                  <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mn>0.929</m:mn>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aaatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamyqaiaadk
            hacaWGLbGaamyyaiaadYgacaqGGaGaamOCaiaadwgacaWGKbGaamyD
            aiaadogacaWG0bGaamyAaiaad+gacaWGUbGaaeiiaiaadAgacaWGHb
            Gaam4yaiaadshacaWGVbGaamOCamaaBaaaleaacaGGOaGaaGOmaiaa
            isdacaWGObGaam4BaiaadwhacaWGYbGaaiykaaqabaGccqGH9aqpca
            aIWaGaaiOlaiaaiMdacaaIYaGaaGyoaaaa@5560@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch4_t_k3lyj">
          <caption>Calculation of weighted average of point rainfall depths
          for the 1% AEP and 24 hour duration design rainfall event for the
          Stanley River at Woodford</caption>

          <col width="20%"/>

          <col width="20%"/>

          <col width="20%"/>

          <col width="20%"/>

          <col width="20%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th><emphasis role="bold">Centroid Latitude (°)</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Centroid Longitude (°)</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Area (km²)</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">1% AEP, 24 hour Design Point Rainfall
              Depth at Centroid (mm)</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Design Depth x Area
              (ML)</emphasis></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>-26.8467</td>

              <td>152.8510</td>

              <td>5.66</td>

              <td>511.4</td>

              <td>2896.0</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8060</td>

              <td>152.8320</td>

              <td>17.31</td>

              <td>518.5</td>

              <td>8973.2</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.7895</td>

              <td>152.8776</td>

              <td>16.84</td>

              <td>570.4</td>

              <td>9605.7</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8201</td>

              <td>152.8719</td>

              <td>16.55</td>

              <td>530.9</td>

              <td>8787.9</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8631</td>

              <td>152.8756</td>

              <td>16.25</td>

              <td>517.7</td>

              <td>8414.3</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8110</td>

              <td>152.8000</td>

              <td>15.10</td>

              <td>527.0</td>

              <td>7956.5</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8135</td>

              <td>152.9077</td>

              <td>15.01</td>

              <td>551.3</td>

              <td>8276.7</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8998</td>

              <td>152.7978</td>

              <td>23.45</td>

              <td>467.1</td>

              <td>10954.8</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8828</td>

              <td>152.8459</td>

              <td>22.74</td>

              <td>493.3</td>

              <td>11218.6</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.9171</td>

              <td>152.7620</td>

              <td>17.78</td>

              <td>454.2</td>

              <td>8076.1</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8557</td>

              <td>152.7656</td>

              <td>16.34</td>

              <td>490.0</td>

              <td>8007.1</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.9190</td>

              <td>152.8552</td>

              <td>16.24</td>

              <td>502.6</td>

              <td>8164.3</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8568</td>

              <td>152.8185</td>

              <td>15.62</td>

              <td>484.6</td>

              <td>7571.4</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.9354</td>

              <td>152.8096</td>

              <td>15.12</td>

              <td>465.2</td>

              <td>7031.9</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>-26.8445</td>

              <td>152.7889</td>

              <td>15.04</td>

              <td>508.9</td>

              <td>7654.0</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Totals</td>

              <td/>

              <td>245.07</td>

              <td/>

              <td>123588.6</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td colspan="3">Weighted Average = 123588.6 / 245.07</td>

              <td>504.3</td>

              <td/>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>

      <para>The catchment average design rainfall depth for 1% AEP, 24 hour
      duration for the Stanley River at Woodford was therefore computed by
      multiplying the ARF by the weighted average of the design point rainfall
      depths:</para>

      <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_kodxf">
        <?oxy_custom_end ?>

        <m:math display="block">
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mtable columnalign="left">
              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mtext>Catchment average design rainfall depth (</m:mtext>

                  <m:mn>24</m:mn>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                  <m:mi>%</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                  <m:mtext>) </m:mtext>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>

              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mtext>= Areal reduction factor (</m:mtext>

                  <m:mn>24</m:mn>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mtext>)</m:mtext>

                  <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                  <m:mtext>Weighted average of design point rainfall depths (</m:mtext>

                  <m:mn>24</m:mn>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mi>h</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                  <m:mi>%</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>A</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                  <m:mtext>)</m:mtext>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>
            </m:mtable>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aaatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbiqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGceaqabeaacaqGdb
            GaaeyyaiaabshacaqGJbGaaeiAaiaab2gacaqGLbGaaeOBaiaabsha
            caqGGaGaaeyyaiaabAhacaqGLbGaaeOCaiaabggacaqGNbGaaeyzai
            aabccacaqGKbGaaeyzaiaabohacaqGPbGaae4zaiaab6gacaqGGaGa
            aeOCaiaabggacaqGPbGaaeOBaiaabAgacaqGHbGaaeiBaiaabYgaca
            qGGaGaaeizaiaabwgacaqGWbGaaeiDaiaabIgacaqGGaGaaeikaiaa
            ikdacaaI0aGaaeiiaiaadIgacaWGVbGaamyDaiaadkhacaGGSaGaae
            iiaiaaigdacaGGLaGaamyqaiaadweacaWGqbGaaeykaiaabccaaeaa
            caqG9aGaaeiiaiaabgeacaqGYbGaaeyzaiaabggacaqGSbGaaeiiai
            aabkhacaqGLbGaaeizaiaabwhacaqGJbGaaeiDaiaabMgacaqGVbGa
            aeOBaiaabccacaqGMbGaaeyyaiaabogacaqG0bGaae4Baiaabkhaca
            qGGaGaaeikaiaaikdacaaI0aGaaeiiaiaadIgacaWGVbGaamyDaiaa
            dkhacaqGPaaeaaaaaaaaa8qacqGHxdaTpaGaae4vaiaabwgacaqGPb
            Gaae4zaiaabIgacaqG0bGaaeyzaiaabsgacaqGGaGaaeyyaiaabAha
            caqGLbGaaeOCaiaabggacaqGNbGaaeyzaiaabccacaqGVbGaaeOzai
            aabccacaqGKbGaaeyzaiaabohacaqGPbGaae4zaiaab6gacaqGGaGa
            aeiCaiaab+gacaqGPbGaaeOBaiaabshacaqGGaGaaeOCaiaabggaca
            qGPbGaaeOBaiaabAgacaqGHbGaaeiBaiaabYgacaqGGaGaaeizaiaa
            bwgacaqGWbGaaeiDaiaabIgacaqGZbGaaeiiaiaabIcacaaIYaGaaG
            inaiaabccacaWGObGaam4BaiaadwhacaWGYbGaaiilaiaabccacaaI
            XaGaaiyjaiaadgeacaWGfbGaamiuaiaabMcaaaaa@BD56@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_in68w">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mtext>Catchment average design rainfall depth(</m:mtext>

              <m:mn>24</m:mn>

              <m:mi>h</m:mi>

              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

              <m:mi>u</m:mi>

              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

              <m:mo>,</m:mo>

              <m:mn>1</m:mn>

              <m:mi>%</m:mi>

              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

              <m:mi>E</m:mi>

              <m:mi>P</m:mi>

              <m:mtext>)=0</m:mtext>

              <m:mtext>.929</m:mtext>

              <m:mo>×</m:mo>

              <m:mtext>504</m:mtext>

              <m:mtext>.3mm</m:mtext>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aaatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbiqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaae4qaiaabg
            gacaqG0bGaae4yaiaabIgacaqGTbGaaeyzaiaab6gacaqG0bGaaeii
            aiaabggacaqG2bGaaeyzaiaabkhacaqGHbGaae4zaiaabwgacaqGGa
            GaaeizaiaabwgacaqGZbGaaeyAaiaabEgacaqGUbGaaeiiaiaabkha
            caqGHbGaaeyAaiaab6gacaqGMbGaaeyyaiaabYgacaqGSbGaaeiiai
            aabsgacaqGLbGaaeiCaiaabshacaqGObGaaeikaiaaikdacaaI0aGa
            amiAaiaad+gacaWG1bGaamOCaiaacYcacaaIXaGaaiyjaiaadgeaca
            WGfbGaamiuaiaabMcacaqG9aGaaeimaiaab6cacaqG5aGaaeOmaiaa
            bMdaqaaaaaaaaaWdbiabgEna0kaabwdacaqGWaGaaeinaiaab6caca
            qGZaGaaeyBaiaab2gaaaa@6FC4@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch4_e_9mwpn">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:semantics>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mtext>Catchment average design rainfall depth(</m:mtext>

              <m:mn>24</m:mn>

              <m:mi>h</m:mi>

              <m:mi>o</m:mi>

              <m:mi>u</m:mi>

              <m:mi>r</m:mi>

              <m:mo>,</m:mo>

              <m:mn>1</m:mn>

              <m:mi>%</m:mi>

              <m:mi>A</m:mi>

              <m:mi>E</m:mi>

              <m:mi>P</m:mi>

              <m:mtext>)=468</m:mtext>

              <m:mtext>.6mm</m:mtext>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
            feaagKart1ev2aaatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
            hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
            4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
            vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
            fr=xb9adbiqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaae4qaiaabg
            gacaqG0bGaae4yaiaabIgacaqGTbGaaeyzaiaab6gacaqG0bGaaeii
            aiaabggacaqG2bGaaeyzaiaabkhacaqGHbGaae4zaiaabwgacaqGGa
            GaaeizaiaabwgacaqGZbGaaeyAaiaabEgacaqGUbGaaeiiaiaabkha
            caqGHbGaaeyAaiaab6gacaqGMbGaaeyyaiaabYgacaqGSbGaaeiiai
            aabsgacaqGLbGaaeiCaiaabshacaqGObGaaeikaiaaikdacaaI0aGa
            amiAaiaad+gacaWG1bGaamOCaiaacYcacaaIXaGaaiyjaiaadgeaca
            WGfbGaamiuaiaabMcacaqG9aGaaeinaiaabAdacaqG4aGaaeOlaiaa
            bAdacaqGTbGaaeyBaaaa@6A08@</m:annotation>
          </m:semantics>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>The calculation was repeated for the catchment of the Stanley
      River to Woodford for each combination of standard durations between 3
      and 72 hours and AEP between 1 Exceedance per Year and 1% AEP. These
      computations are shown for the Stanley River catchment to Woodford in
      <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_w3pcv"/>.</para>

      <para>The catchment area for the Stanley River to Somerset Dam is 1324
      km². The calculation of catchment average design rainfall intensities,
      after application of areal reduction factors, is shown in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_t_npkju"/>. Comparing the top panels of <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_t_w3pcv"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_npkju"/>, for the
      corresponding AEP and durations the weighted averages of the point
      rainfall depths for the catchment to Somerset Dam are less than those
      for Woodford, due to the gradient in the IFD grids from Bureau of
      Meteorology (2013). Comparing the middle panels of <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_t_w3pcv"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_npkju"/>, for the
      corresponding AEP and durations the ARF catchment to Somerset Dam are
      less than those for Woodford because the catchment area to Somerset Dam
      is larger. Hence comparing the bottom panels of <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_t_w3pcv"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_npkju"/>, for the
      corresponding AEP and durations the catchment average design rainfall
      depths to Somerset Dam are less than those for Woodford.</para>

      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch4_t_w3pcv">
        <caption>Stanley River catchment to Woodford: Calculation of catchment
        average design rainfall depths (bottom panel) from weighted average of
        point rainfall depths (top panel) and areal reduction factors (middle
        panel)</caption>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="13%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td colspan="8"><emphasis role="bold">Weighted average of point
            rainfall depths (mm)</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Duration (hours)</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1 Exceedance per Year</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="6"><emphasis role="bold">Annual Exceedance
            Probability</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">50%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">20%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">10%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">5%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">2%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1%</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>3</td>

            <td>54.1</td>

            <td>61.6</td>

            <td>85.7</td>

            <td>102.8</td>

            <td>120.0</td>

            <td>143.5</td>

            <td>162.1</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>6</td>

            <td>70.5</td>

            <td>81.5</td>

            <td>117.3</td>

            <td>142.8</td>

            <td>168.7</td>

            <td>204.6</td>

            <td>233.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>12</td>

            <td>94.4</td>

            <td>110.8</td>

            <td>164.9</td>

            <td>203.8</td>

            <td>243.8</td>

            <td>299.5</td>

            <td>344.5</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>24</td>

            <td>128.1</td>

            <td>152.0</td>

            <td>231.4</td>

            <td>289.5</td>

            <td>349.8</td>

            <td>434.8</td>

            <td>504.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>48</td>

            <td>170.2</td>

            <td>202.2</td>

            <td>310.5</td>

            <td>391.2</td>

            <td>476.1</td>

            <td>598.0</td>

            <td>699.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>72</td>

            <td>195.5</td>

            <td>231.7</td>

            <td>355.3</td>

            <td>448.5</td>

            <td>547.6</td>

            <td>691.4</td>

            <td>812.1</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td colspan="8"><emphasis role="bold">Areal Reduction
            Factor</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Duration (hours)</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1 Exceedance per Year</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="6"><emphasis role="bold">Annual Exceedance
            Probability</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">50%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">20%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">10%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">5%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">2%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1%</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>3</td>

            <td>0.841</td>

            <td>0.835</td>

            <td>0.812</td>

            <td>0.794</td>

            <td>0.776</td>

            <td>0.753</td>

            <td>0.735</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>6</td>

            <td>0.879</td>

            <td>0.876</td>

            <td>0.864</td>

            <td>0.854</td>

            <td>0.845</td>

            <td>0.832</td>

            <td>0.823</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>12</td>

            <td>0.909</td>

            <td>0.907</td>

            <td>0.901</td>

            <td>0.896</td>

            <td>0.891</td>

            <td>0.884</td>

            <td>0.879</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>24</td>

            <td>0.945</td>

            <td>0.944</td>

            <td>0.940</td>

            <td>0.938</td>

            <td>0.935</td>

            <td>0.932</td>

            <td>0.929</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>48</td>

            <td>0.959</td>

            <td>0.959</td>

            <td>0.957</td>

            <td>0.955</td>

            <td>0.954</td>

            <td>0.951</td>

            <td>0.950</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>72</td>

            <td>0.966</td>

            <td>0.966</td>

            <td>0.964</td>

            <td>0.963</td>

            <td>0.962</td>

            <td>0.961</td>

            <td>0.959</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td colspan="8"><emphasis role="bold">Catchment average design
            rainfall depth (mm)</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Duration (hours)</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1 Exceedance per Year</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="6"><emphasis role="bold">Annual Exceedance
            Probability</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">50%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">20%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">10%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">5%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">2%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1%</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>3</td>

            <td>45.5</td>

            <td>51.4</td>

            <td>69.6</td>

            <td>81.6</td>

            <td>93.1</td>

            <td>108.0</td>

            <td>119.2</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>6</td>

            <td>62.0</td>

            <td>71.4</td>

            <td>101.3</td>

            <td>122.0</td>

            <td>142.5</td>

            <td>170.2</td>

            <td>191.9</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>12</td>

            <td>85.8</td>

            <td>100.5</td>

            <td>148.5</td>

            <td>182.6</td>

            <td>217.1</td>

            <td>264.8</td>

            <td>302.9</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>24</td>

            <td>121.1</td>

            <td>143.4</td>

            <td>217.6</td>

            <td>271.5</td>

            <td>327.1</td>

            <td>405.2</td>

            <td>468.6</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>48</td>

            <td>163.3</td>

            <td>193.9</td>

            <td>297.1</td>

            <td>373.6</td>

            <td>454.0</td>

            <td>569.0</td>

            <td>664.2</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>72</td>

            <td>188.8</td>

            <td>223.7</td>

            <td>342.6</td>

            <td>432.0</td>

            <td>526.8</td>

            <td>664.2</td>

            <td>779.2</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch4_t_npkju">
        <caption>Stanley River catchment to Somerset Dam: Calculation of
        catchment average design rainfall depths (bottom panel) from weighted
        average of point rainfall depths (top panel) and areal reduction
        factors (middle panel)</caption>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="13%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <col width="12%"/>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td colspan="8"><emphasis role="bold">Weighted average of point
            rainfall depths (mm)</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Duration (hours)</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1 Exceedance per Year</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="6"><emphasis role="bold">Annual Exceedance
            Probability</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">50%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">20%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">10%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">5%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">2%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1%</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">3</emphasis></td>

            <td>48.3</td>

            <td>54.8</td>

            <td>75.7</td>

            <td>90.2</td>

            <td>104.7</td>

            <td>124.2</td>

            <td>139.5</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">6</emphasis></td>

            <td>61.0</td>

            <td>70.0</td>

            <td>99.2</td>

            <td>119.7</td>

            <td>140.3</td>

            <td>168.5</td>

            <td>190.9</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">12</emphasis></td>

            <td>79.0</td>

            <td>91.9</td>

            <td>133.9</td>

            <td>163.9</td>

            <td>194.4</td>

            <td>236.6</td>

            <td>270.4</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">24</emphasis></td>

            <td>103.8</td>

            <td>121.9</td>

            <td>182.2</td>

            <td>226.1</td>

            <td>271.4</td>

            <td>335.1</td>

            <td>387.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">48</emphasis></td>

            <td>134.5</td>

            <td>158.7</td>

            <td>240.6</td>

            <td>301.7</td>

            <td>366.0</td>

            <td>458.6</td>

            <td>535.5</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">72</emphasis></td>

            <td>153.0</td>

            <td>180.4</td>

            <td>274.2</td>

            <td>345.2</td>

            <td>420.9</td>

            <td>531.1</td>

            <td>624.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td colspan="8"><emphasis role="bold">Areal Reduction
            Factor</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Duration (hours)</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1 Exceedance per Year</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="6"><emphasis role="bold">Annual Exceedance
            Probability</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">50%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">20%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">10%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">5%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">2%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1%</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">3</emphasis></td>

            <td>0.735</td>

            <td>0.727</td>

            <td>0.694</td>

            <td>0.669</td>

            <td>0.644</td>

            <td>0.611</td>

            <td>0.586</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">6</emphasis></td>

            <td>0.796</td>

            <td>0.792</td>

            <td>0.774</td>

            <td>0.761</td>

            <td>0.748</td>

            <td>0.731</td>

            <td>0.718</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">12</emphasis></td>

            <td>0.843</td>

            <td>0.841</td>

            <td>0.832</td>

            <td>0.826</td>

            <td>0.826</td>

            <td>0.811</td>

            <td>0.804</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">24</emphasis></td>

            <td>0.900</td>

            <td>0.899</td>

            <td>0.896</td>

            <td>0.894</td>

            <td>0.892</td>

            <td>0.889</td>

            <td>0.887</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">48</emphasis></td>

            <td>0.924</td>

            <td>0.924</td>

            <td>0.921</td>

            <td>0.920</td>

            <td>0.918</td>

            <td>0.916</td>

            <td>0.914</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">72</emphasis></td>

            <td>0.936</td>

            <td>0.935</td>

            <td>0.933</td>

            <td>0.932</td>

            <td>0.930</td>

            <td>0.928</td>

            <td>0.926</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td colspan="8"><emphasis role="bold">Catchment average design
            rainfall depth (mm)</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Duration (hours)</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1 Exceedance per Year</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="6"><emphasis role="bold">Annual Exceedance
            Probability</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td/>

            <td/>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">50%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">20%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">10%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">5%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">2%</emphasis></td>

            <td><emphasis role="bold">1%</emphasis></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>3</td>

            <td>35.5</td>

            <td>39.9</td>

            <td>52.5</td>

            <td>60.4</td>

            <td>67.4</td>

            <td>75.9</td>

            <td>81.8</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>6</td>

            <td>48.6</td>

            <td>55.4</td>

            <td>76.8</td>

            <td>91.1</td>

            <td>105.0</td>

            <td>123.2</td>

            <td>137.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>12</td>

            <td>66.6</td>

            <td>77.3</td>

            <td>111.4</td>

            <td>135.3</td>

            <td>159.3</td>

            <td>191.8</td>

            <td>217.4</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>24</td>

            <td>93.3</td>

            <td>109.6</td>

            <td>163.3</td>

            <td>202.2</td>

            <td>242.1</td>

            <td>298.1</td>

            <td>343.4</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>48</td>

            <td>124.3</td>

            <td>146.6</td>

            <td>221.7</td>

            <td>277.5</td>

            <td>336.0</td>

            <td>420.0</td>

            <td>489.5</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>72</td>

            <td>143.2</td>

            <td>168.7</td>

            <td>255.9</td>

            <td>321.6</td>

            <td>391.5</td>

            <td>492.9</td>

            <td>578.1</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_ipkgw">
      <title>Worked Example 3: Calculation of spatial pattern for design flood
      estimation</title>

      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_wxnds"/> recommends that estimation of
      design flood events of 1% AEP and more frequent, the spatial pattern for
      design event should be estimated using the spatial pattern derived from
      the Bureau of Meteorology (2013) design rainfall grids across the
      catchment for the 1% AEP and for a duration that is anticipated to
      correspond to the duration of the rainfall burst that is likely to be
      critical at the specified location.</para>

      <para>For the Stanley River catchment, this approach was demonstrated
      using the 24 hour duration IFD data. For the catchment to Woodford,
      point rainfall depths at each of the subcatchment centroids were divided
      by the weighted average of the point rainfall depths to derive the
      non-dimensional spatial pattern, as computed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_t_nehhn"/> and mapped in the top panel of <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_f_l3qvp"/>. To model the 24 hour, 1% AEP design flood
      event for the catchment, the non-dimensional spatial pattern was
      multiplied by the catchment average design rainfall depth to Woodford
      for this duration (468.6 mm, after application of the ARF), as computed
      in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_nehhn"/> and mapped in the top panel of <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4_f_5le2r"/>.</para>

      <para>The process was repeated for the Stanley River to Somerset Dam,
      with the map of the non-dimensional spatial pattern shown in the bottom
      panel of <xref linkend="b2_ch4_f_l3qvp"/> and the map of the design
      depths for the 1% AEP, 24 hour duration event in the bottom panel of
      <xref linkend="b2_ch4_f_5le2r"/>.</para>

      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch4_t_nehhn">
        <caption>Calculation of design spatial pattern for Stanley River at
        Woodford</caption>

        <col width="20%"/>

        <col width="20%"/>

        <col width="20%"/>

        <col width="20%"/>

        <col width="20%"/>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Centroid Latitude (°)</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Centroid Longitude (°)</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">1% AEP, 24 hour Design Point Rainfall
            Depth at Centroid (mm)</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Point Rainfall Depth divided by Weighted
            Average of Point Rainfall Depths (%)</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Depth to be applied to model 1% AEP, 24
            hour Design Event (mm)</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>-26.8467</td>

            <td>152.8510</td>

            <td>511.4</td>

            <td>101.4</td>

            <td>475.2</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8060</td>

            <td>152.8320</td>

            <td>518.5</td>

            <td>102.8</td>

            <td>481.8</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.7895</td>

            <td>152.8776</td>

            <td>570.4</td>

            <td>113.1</td>

            <td>530.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8201</td>

            <td>152.8719</td>

            <td>530.9</td>

            <td>105.3</td>

            <td>493.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8631</td>

            <td>152.8756</td>

            <td>517.7</td>

            <td>102.7</td>

            <td>481.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8110</td>

            <td>152.8000</td>

            <td>527.0</td>

            <td>104.5</td>

            <td>489.7</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8135</td>

            <td>152.9077</td>

            <td>551.3</td>

            <td>109.3</td>

            <td>512.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8998</td>

            <td>152.7978</td>

            <td>467.1</td>

            <td>92.6</td>

            <td>434.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8828</td>

            <td>152.8459</td>

            <td>493.3</td>

            <td>97.8</td>

            <td>458.4</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.9171</td>

            <td>152.7620</td>

            <td>454.2</td>

            <td>90.1</td>

            <td>422.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8557</td>

            <td>152.7656</td>

            <td>490.0</td>

            <td>97.2</td>

            <td>455.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.9190</td>

            <td>152.8552</td>

            <td>502.6</td>

            <td>99.7</td>

            <td>467.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8568</td>

            <td>152.8185</td>

            <td>484.6</td>

            <td>96.1</td>

            <td>450.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.9354</td>

            <td>152.8096</td>

            <td>465.2</td>

            <td>92.2</td>

            <td>432.3</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>-26.8445</td>

            <td>152.7889</td>

            <td>508.9</td>

            <td>100.9</td>

            <td>472.9</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td colspan="2">Weighted Average</td>

            <td>504.3</td>

            <td>100.0</td>

            <td>468.6</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para/>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_l3qvp">
        <title>Non-dimensional spatial pattern (percentage of catchment
        average design rainfall depths) for events with AEP of 1% and more
        common for Stanley River to Woodford (top panel) and Stanley River to
        Somerset Dam (bottom panel)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2067.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_5le2r">
        <title>Design spatial pattern of design rainfall depths for the 24
        hour duration, 1% AEP event for Stanley River to Woodford (top panel)
        and Stanley River to Somerset Dam (bottom panel)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2068.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_ttc2q">
      <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723368"/>Worked Example 4: Application to
      design flood estimation</title>

      <para>Design flood peak estimates were produced for the Stanley River at
      its outlet (inflow to Somerset Dam) using a RORB rainfall runoff routing
      model of the catchment. A more complete description of this case study
      is contained in Jordan et al. (2015).</para>

      <para>Design peak flow estimates at Somerset Dam inflow were produced
      from a number of Monte-Carlo simulations that were implemented within
      RORB. There were a number of common elements to all of these
      simulations:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>all adopted the same catchment average design IFD information
          from Bureau of Meteorology (2013) multiplied by the areal reduction
          factor for the applicable duration from Jordan et al. (2013);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>all were run using the stratified Monte-Carlo sampling scheme
          that is implemented within RORB (Laurenson et al., 2010)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>all were run for rainfall burst durations of 6, 9, 12, 18, 24,
          36 and 48 hours, with the peak flow defined by the highest flow from
          among these durations at each AEP;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>all simulations sampled from the same non-dimensional
          probability distribution of initial loss values defined by Illahee
          (2005), scaled by a median initial loss of 40 mm;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>all adopted a constant continuing loss rate of 1.7 mm/hour
          across all subcatchments;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>all adopted a RORB non-linearity parameter, <emphasis
          role="italic">m</emphasis> , value of 0.8;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>all simulations adopted RORB delay parameter, <emphasis
          role="italic">kc</emphasis> , values of 20 for the catchment
          upstream of Peachester, 20 for the catchment between Peachester and
          Woodford, 16 for the catchment upstream of Mount Kilcoy and 45 for
          the residual catchment to Somerset Dam inflow.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The Monte-Carlo simulations differed from one another in their
      approach to sampling of spatial, temporal and space-time patterns across
      the catchment, as shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_t_k63hj"/>.</para>

      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch4_t_k63hj">
        <caption>RORB model scenarios run for worked example on Stanley River
        catchment to Somerset Dam</caption>

        <col width="33%"/>

        <col width="33%"/>

        <col width="33%"/>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Case</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Spatial Pattern(s)</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Temporal Pattern(s)</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">1</emphasis></td>

            <td>Single spatial pattern derived from BOM (2013) IFD analysis,
            24 hour duration and 1% spatial pattern</td>

            <td>Random sampling from a set of 13 temporal patterns for each
            duration, derived from the bursts of the corresponding duration
            within the 13 selected events listed in Table 1 of Jordan et al.
            (2015)</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">2</emphasis></td>

            <td colspan="2">Random sampling from a set of 13 space-time
            patterns for each duration, derived from the bursts of the
            corresponding duration within the 13 selected events listed in
            Table 1 of Jordan et al. (2015)</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para>Sinclair Knight Merz (2013) fitted a Generalised Extreme Value
      (GEV) distribution to the estimated annual maxima inflows to Somerset
      Dam over the period between 1955 and 2013. The estimated inflow flood
      peak for the 1893 flood of 6200 m³/s was included as a censored flow in
      the analysis. The distribution fitted to the estimated observed inflows
      was used to test the performance of the RORB model simulations.</para>

      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch4_f_hwb71"/> shows that both cases of RORB
      model simulations all provide an excellent match to the fitted flood
      frequency quantiles across the range between 5% and 0.2% AEP. Design
      peak inflow floods to Somerset Dam were insensitive to whether
      space-time patterns are randomly sampled or only temporal patterns are
      randomly sampled in the Monte-Carlo simulation (case 1 versus case
      2).</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch4_f_hwb71">
        <title>Flood frequency curves for Stanley River at Somerset Dam inflow
        derived from analysis of estimated annual maxima and from RORB model
        simulations</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2069.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch4_s_k9uux">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Toc436723369"/>References</title>

    <para>Austin, P. M., 1987: Relation between measured radar reflectivity
    and surface rainfall. <emphasis role="italic">Monthly Weather
    Review</emphasis>, 115, 1053–1070.</para>

    <para>Barnston, A.G., 1991: An empirical method of estimating raingauge
    and radar rainfall measurement bias and resolution, <emphasis
    role="italic">J. Applied Meterology</emphasis>, 30, 282-296.</para>

    <para>Ball, J.E., and K.C. Luk, 1998: Modelling spatial variability of
    rainfall over a catchment, <emphasis role="italic">J. Hydrologic
    Engineering</emphasis>, 3 (2), 122-130.</para>

    <para>Bell, F.C., 1976: <emphasis role="italic">The areal reduction
    factors in rainfall frequency estimation</emphasis>, Natural Environmental
    Research Council (NERC), Report No. 35, Institute of Hydrology,
    Wallingford, United Kingdom, 25pp.</para>

    <para>Bradley, S.G., W.R. Gray, L.D. Pigott, A.W. Seed, C.D. Stow, and
    G.L. Austin, 1997: Rainfall redistribution over low hills due to flow
    perturbation, <emphasis role="italic">J. Hydrology</emphasis>, 202,
    33-47.</para>

    <para>Bureau of Meteorology, 2003: <emphasis role="italic">The Estimation
    of Probable Maximum Precipitation in Australia: GeneralisedShort-Duration
    Method</emphasis>, Hydrometeorological Advisory Service, June 2003,
    Commonwealth of Australia, Melbourne, Austraia.</para>

    <para>Bureau of Meteorology, 2006: <emphasis role="italic">Guidebook to
    the Estimation of Probable Maximum Precipitation: Generalised Southeast
    Australia Method</emphasis>, Hydrometeorological Advisory Service, October
    2006, Commonwealth of Australia, Melbourne, Austraia.</para>

    <para>Bureau of Meteorology, 2013: <emphasis role="italic">Revised Design
    Rainfall Intensity Frequency Duration Estimates for Australia</emphasis>.
    Retrieved July 2015: <link
    xlink:href="http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/revised-ifd/">http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/revised-ifd/</link></para>

    <para>Collier, C.G., 1996: <emphasis role="italic">Applications of Weather
    Radar Systems: A Guide to Uses of Radar in Meteorology and
    Hydrology</emphasis>. 2d ed. John Wiley, 383 pp.</para>

    <para>Engineers Australia, 2014: <emphasis role="italic">Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff Discussion Paper: An Interim Guideline for Considering
    Climate Change in Rainfall and Runoff</emphasis>, Engineers Australia,
    Canberra, ACT.</para>

    <para>Fabry, F., A. Bellon, M.R. Duncan, and G. Austin, 1994: High
    resolution rainfall measurements by radar for very small basins: the
    sampling problem re-examined, <emphasis role="italic">J.
    Hydrology</emphasis>, 116, 415-428.</para>

    <para>Gray, W., and A.W. Seed, 2000: The characterisation of orographic
    rainfall, <emphasis role="italic">Meteorological Applications</emphasis>,
    7, 105-119.</para>

    <para>Green, J.H., 1996: Concurrent flooding – a review of current
    methodologies, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 23rd Institution of Engineers
    Australia Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium</emphasis>, Hobart,
    Tasmania.</para>

    <para>Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, 2013: <emphasis
    role="italic">Climate Change 2013: The Physical Science Basis</emphasis>,
    Contribution of Working Group I to the Fifth Assessment Report of the
    Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change [Stocker,T.F., D. Qin, G.-K.
    Plattner, M. Tignor, S.K. Allen, J. Boschung, A. Nauels, Y. Xia, V. Bex
    and P.M. Midgley (eds.)]. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United
    Kingdom and New York, NY, USA, 1535 pp.</para>

    <para>Jones, D., Wang, W. and Fawcett, R. (2009), High-quality spatial
    climate data-sets for Australia, Australian Meteorological and
    Oceanographic Journal, 58, 233-248.</para>

    <para>Jordan, P.W., 2000: <emphasis role="italic">Effect on Flood
    Modelling of Rainfall Variability and Radar Rainfall Measurement
    Error</emphasis>, Ph.D. Thesis, 210 pp., Department of Civil Engineering,
    Monash University, Clayton, Victoria.</para>

    <para>Jordan, P.W., A.W. Seed, P.E. Weinmann, 2003: A stochastic model of
    radar measurement errors in rainfall accumulations at catchment scale,
    <emphasis role="italic">J. Hydrometeorology</emphasis>, 841-855.</para>

    <para>Jordan, P., P.E. Weinmann, P. Hill and C. Wiesenfeld, 2013:
    <emphasis role="italic">Collation and Review of Areal Reduction Factors
    from Applications of the CRC-FORGE Method in Australia</emphasis>, Final
    Report, Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 2: Spatial
    Patterns of Rainfall, Engineers Australia, Barton, ACT.</para>

    <para>Jordan, P., R. Nathan and A. Seed, 2015: Application of Spatial and
    Space-Time Patterns of Design Rainfall to Design Flood Estimation,
    <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 36th Engineers Australia Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symposium</emphasis>, Hobart, Tasmania.</para>

    <para>Joss, J., and A. Waldvogel, 1990: Precipitation measurement and
    hydrology, in <emphasis role="italic">Radar in Meteorology</emphasis>, D.
    Atlas, Ed., American Meteorological Society, 577–606.</para>

    <para>Laurenson, E.M., R.G. Mein and R.J. Nathan, 2010: <emphasis
    role="italic">RORB Version 6, Runoff Routing Program, User
    Manual</emphasis>, Version 6.14, Monash University and Sinclair Knight
    Merz, Melbourne, Victoria.</para>

    <para>Lovejoy, S. and D. Schertzer, 2006: Multifractals, cloud radiances
    and rain, <emphasis role="italic">J. Hydrology</emphasis>, 322,
    59-88.</para>

    <para>Marani, M., 2005: Non-power-law-scale properties of rainfall in
    space and time, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resour. Res</emphasis>., 41,
    W08413, doi:10.1029/2004WR003822.</para>

    <para>Nathan, R.J. and P.E. Weinmann, 1998: <emphasis
    role="italic">Estimation of Large to Extreme Floods, Book VI in Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff – A Guide to Flood Estimation</emphasis>, The
    Institution of Engineers, Australia, Barton, ACT.</para>

    <para>Natural Environmental Research Council, 1975: <emphasis
    role="italic">Flood Studies Report, Vol. 2,</emphasis> Institute of
    Hydrology, Wallingford, United Kingdom.</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, D.H., (ed)., 1987: <emphasis role="italic">Australian
    Rainfall &amp; Runoff – A Guide to Flood Estimation,</emphasis>
    Institution of Engineers, Australia, Barton, ACT.</para>

    <para>Podger, S.; Green, J.; Jolly, C.; The, C.; and Beesley, C., 2015a:
    Creating long duration areal reduction factors for the new
    Intensity-Frequency-Duration (IFD) design rainfalls, <emphasis
    role="italic">Proc. Engineers Australia Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium</emphasis>, Hobart, Tasmania, Australia.</para>

    <para>Podger, S.; Green, J.; Stensmyr, P.; and Babister, M., 2015b:
    Combining long and short duration areal reduction factors, <emphasis
    role="italic">Proc. Engineers Australia Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium</emphasis>, Hobart, Tasmania, Australia.</para>

    <para>Raymond, M, 2014: Wivenhoe Somerset Dam Optimisation Study –
    Simulating Dam Operations for Numerous Floods, <emphasis
    role="italic">Proc. Australian National Committee on Large Dams Annual
    Conference</emphasis>, Canberra, ACT.</para>

    <para>Ryan, C, 2015: <emphasis role="italic">Catchment Sim Rainfall
    Analyser</emphasis>, <link
    xlink:href="http://www.csse.com.au/index.php/products/catchmentsim/csim-guide/index.html?rainfall_analyser.htm">http://www.csse.com.au/index.php/products/catchmentsim/csim-guide/index.html?rainfall_analyser.htm</link>,
    Accessed 1 April 2015.</para>

    <para>Seed, A.W., and G.L. Austin, 1990: Sampling errors for raingauge
    derived mean-areal daily and monthly rainfall, <emphasis role="italic">J.
    Hydrology</emphasis>, 118, 163-173.</para>

    <para>Seqwater, 2014: Somerset and Wivenhoe Dams, Review of Flood
    Hydrology Models, Report released August 2014, Brisbane,
    Queensland.</para>

    <para>Sinclair Knight Merz, 2013: <emphasis role="italic">Brisbane River
    Catchment Dams and Operational Alternatives Study, Generation of Inflow
    Hydrographs and Preliminary Flood Frequency Analysis,</emphasis> Revision
    1, Brisbane, Queensland.</para>

    <para>Steiner, M., and J. A. Smith, 2002: Use of three-dimensional
    reflectivity structure for automated detection and removal of
    nonprecipitating echoes in radar data. <emphasis role="italic">J.
    Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology</emphasis>, 19, 673–686.</para>

    <para>Stensmyr, P., M. Babister and M. Retallick, 2014: Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 2: Spatial Patterns of Rainfall:
    Stage 2 Report, <emphasis role="italic">Short Duration Areal Reduction
    Factors</emphasis>, ARR Report Number P2/S2/019, ISBN
    978-085825-9614.</para>

    <para>Stephens, D., P. Hill and R. Nathan, 2012: Applying joint
    probabilistic techniques to the determination of downstream coincident
    flows and incremental consequences of dam failure, <emphasis
    role="italic">Proc. Australian National Committee on Large Dams
    Conference</emphasis>, Perth, Western Australia.</para>

    <para>Umakhanthan, K. and J.E. Ball, 2005: Rainfall models for catchment
    simulation, Australian J. of Water Resources, 9 (1), 55-67.</para>

    <para>Urbonas, B.R., J.C.Y. Guo and M.P. Janesekok, 1992: Hyetograph
    density effects on urban runoff modelling, <emphasis role="italic">Proc.
    International Conference on Computer Applications in Water
    Resources</emphasis>, Tamkang University, Tamsui, Taiwan, 32-37.</para>

    <para>Verworn, A., and U. Haberlandt, 2011: Spatial interpolation of
    hourly rainfall – effect of additional information, variogram inference
    and storm properties, <emphasis role="italic">Hydrology and Earth System
    Sciences</emphasis>, 15, 569-584.</para>

    <para>Walland D.J., J. Meighen, K.C. Xuereb, C.A. Beesley and T.M.T.
    Hoang, 2003: <emphasis role="italic">Revision of the Generalised Tropical
    Storm Method for Estimating Probable Maximum Precipitation</emphasis>
    [Online], HRS Report No. 8, Hydrology Report Series, Bureau of Meteorology
    Melbourne, Victoria, available at:
    http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/hrs8.shtml, accessed on
    10/12/2012</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Uncertainties and Recommended Areas of Further
    Investigation</title>

    <section>
      <title>Recommended further investigation into Areal Reduction
      Factors</title>

      <para>The CRC-FORGE projects for the different states and the Australian
      Capital Territory have defined a set of ARF equations for long rainfall
      durations (18 to 120 hours) that can be applied by practitioners across
      Australia. However, this ARF development work had been undertaken
      independently, and no additional work has since been done to analyse and
      review the results for individual states in a more integrated fashion.
      There are thus unanswered questions on (i) the extent to which
      variations in ARF values for different states are statistically
      significant, and (ii) whether there would be scope for a more rationally
      based delineation of boundaries between regions than the currently
      adopted regions based on state boundaries. As an initial step towards
      the resolution of both these questions, it is recommended that the
      differences in regional equations be re-examined in the light of the
      available information on estimation uncertainties. This should assist in
      the formulation of clearer recommendations for inclusion in ARR (and
      possibly reduce boundary problems).</para>

      <para>To date, no CRC-FORGE project has been conducted in the Northern
      Territory and as a result, no ARF equations have been derived for this
      region. It is recommended that a study is undertaken to derive ARFs for
      the Northern Territory.</para>

      <para>By contrast to the detailed development work on ARFs equations for
      long rainfall durations, ARFs for shorter duration events (less than 18
      hours) are “interim” guidance, extrapolated to the 1 hour duration ARF
      curve from the United Kingdom, and therefore subject to considerably
      larger uncertainty. To provide more soundly based ARF values for
      Australian regions, it is strongly recommended that work is undertaken
      to develop ARF equations for durations less than 18 hours that are
      fitted to Australian rainfall data. The development of short duration
      ARF equations should be a more tractable problem to solve now than it
      was in previous decades, given that there are relatively dense networks
      of pluviograph gauges around most of the Australian capital cities and
      in some other regions of the country; and that over the last decade the
      Bureau of Meteorology has been archiving radar rainfall data and
      undertaking quality control and calibration of the radar data using
      pluviographs to potentially make it useful for this purpose. It is
      recommended that the ARF equations developed for short durations are
      developed in such a way that there is a relatively smooth transition to
      the equations that are currently recommended for long durations in each
      region. As an initial step in this development, it would be desirable to
      collate and analyse the results of more recent work on short duration
      ARFs for Australian catchments and to compare these results to the 1
      hour duration ARF curve from the United Kingdom.</para>

      <para>The ARF equations developed in Australia have been derived using
      data-driven and empirical methods, with limited theoretical
      underpinning. ARF values for a particular catchment would derive from a
      combination of the mixture of storm types causing heavy rainfall within
      a region, the direction and speed of movement of those storms and the
      spatial and temporal characteristics of those storms. Analysis by a
      hydrometeorologist of the prevalence of different storm types within
      different parts of Australia and the advection, temporal and spatial
      characteristics of those storms is likely to provide an understanding of
      the causes of variations in ARF. Such understanding is difficult to
      infer directly, on its own, from the empirically derived ARF equations
      that are currently recommended for use in Australia. It is recommended
      that hydrometeorologists are engaged to investigate the causes of
      variations in ARF.</para>

      <para>Once the hydrometeological analysis recommended above has been
      undertaken, the outcomes of that work may enable further research and
      improvements in the following areas:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>It would be of interest to examine how well the ARFs derived
          using an empirical method such as Bell’s method used in this study,
          compare with those derived from a suitable theoretical method that
          may better account for hydrometeorological understanding of the
          drivers of variability in ARFs.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>There are some areas within each of the regions where the ARF
          values determined empirically for the circular catchments
          demonstrated a trend toward being larger or smaller than the fitted
          ARF equations, which were fitted to the mean ARF values from all
          circular catchments within the region for a given area, duration and
          AEP. Hydrometeorological understanding may enable definition of
          smaller sub-regions, combining of existing regions (with the
          existing regions largely defined using state and territory
          boundaries), or definition of new regions in order to reduce the
          uncertainty introduced by this variability.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Seasonality was found to be a significant driver of ARFs in
          Western Australia but has not been investigated for other parts of
          Australia. Hydrometeorological understanding may guide the regions
          where seasonal dependence in ARF would be likely, the start and end
          dates of seasons and how transition periods between seasons should
          be handled.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>It is recommended that after an appropriate study has been
      undertaken to determine the hydrometeorological causes of variations in
      ARF that further studies are then scoped and prioritised according to
      areas where the hydrometeorological causes are best exploited to reduce
      residual uncertainty in ARFs.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Recommended further investigation into methods for deriving
      spatial and space-time patterns of rainfall for events</title>

      <para>The capacity to collect and archive remotely sensed rainfall
      estimates and to provide that information to practitioners is growing.
      It is recommended that the Bureau of Meteorology continues to invest in
      routinely archiving remotely sensed rainfall data, particularly from its
      network of ground based weather radars. It is recommended that the
      Bureau of Meteorology continues to expand the provision of quality
      controlled and bias corrected space-time rainfall estimates to
      practitioners, for use across the industry. It is recommended that tools
      should be further developed and disseminated to practitioners to
      facilitate the use of remotely sensed rainfall data.</para>

      <para>It is recommended that further research is conducted into quality
      control of remotely sensed estimates of the space-time pattern of
      rainfall.</para>

      <para>It is recommended that further research is conducted to improve
      methods for mean field bias correction of remotely sensed rainfall data.
      The recommendations on the approaches that should be adopted for mean
      field bias correction should be updated in these guidelines in
      accordance with the findings from this research.</para>

      <para>At the time of writing, there was not an agreed optimum method for
      deriving space-time rainfall patterns from rainfall gauge data for
      Australian catchments, although Verworn and Haberlandt (2011) provide
      reasonable guidance. It is recommended that further research is
      conducted to identify a superior method (or set of potential methods)
      that are demonstrated to reliably produce more accurate estimation of
      the space-time rainfall field from gauge observations. It may be that
      the optimum method depends upon meteorological characteristics of the
      storm, density of rainfall gauges, orographic characteristics of the
      region or other factors. It is recommended that further research is
      conducted to explore these influences on the selection of optimum
      spatial and space-time interpolation methods for flood model calibration
      and design flood estimation.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Recommended further investigation into space-time patterns for
      calibration of rainfall runoff models to historical floods</title>

      <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_vmrah"/>, the calibrated
      parameter values for a rainfall runoff model for a particular flood
      event may be sensitive to the method used to derive the space-time
      rainfall field for the event, particularly where the field is
      interpolated from a network of rain gauges only. It is recommended that
      further research is conducted into the sensitivity of rainfall-runoff
      routing model parameter estimation to assumptions made in the process of
      estimating the space-time rainfall field gauged rainfall data.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Recommended further investigation into spatial and space-time
      patterns for design flood estimation</title>

      <para>It is recommended that further research is conducted into
      hydrometeorological drivers for space-time rainfall patterns that lead
      to flood events across different regions of Australia. The research
      should be used to inform practitioners on how they may choose between
      the space-time patterns of rainfall from different historical rainfall
      events to form the populations of space-time, spatial and temporal
      patterns in design flood simulation schemes. Research may investigate
      seasonal influences on space-time patterns of rainfall for use in design
      flood estimation.</para>

      <para>There has been limited assessment on methods for selection of
      space-time patterns for use in Monte-Carlo simulation schemes for design
      flood estimation. Further research should be conducted in this area, to
      provide more robust guidance on:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the minimum number of space-time or temporal and spatial
          patterns in the sampling population(s),</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the range of AEP represented by the populations of space-time
          or spatial and temporal patterns to be sampled compared to the AEP
          of the depth of the rainfall burst, and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the relative probabilities to be applied in the selection of
          patterns from the relevant populations.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>It is recommended that further research is conducted into the
      validity of transposing space-time patterns from one location to
      another. The research should assist in defining valid regions over which
      transposition of space-time patterns is acceptable and conversely
      boundaries between regions over which transposition should not occur.
      The research should also consider other aspects of transposition, such
      as the validity or otherwise of rotating space-time patterns and the
      maximum recommended angles for rotation.</para>

      <para>Further research should be conducted into methods for stochastic
      generation of space-time rainfall patterns. The research should
      investigate how orographic influences should be incorporated into the
      stochastic generation algorithms in a way that replicates the space-time
      variability of rainfall observed in historic rainfall events. Research
      should also develop more definitive guidance on appropriate statistical
      tests to demonstrate that the stochastically generated space-time
      rainfall patterns replicate the space-time statistical characteristics
      of historical rainfall events that are sufficiently large to have caused
      flood events.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Recommended further investigation into potential influences of
      climate variability and climate change on areal reduction factors,
      spatial and space-time patterns for design flood estimation</title>

      <para>Climatic variability at inter-decadal scales is likely to
      influence the relative occurrence and severity of different types of
      heavy rainfall events. Hydrometeorological understanding of the
      connection between storm types and ARFs may enable predictions of the
      future trend in ARFs that will occur as the climate changes over coming
      decades. Hydrometeorological understanding of the connection between
      storm types and space-time rainfall patterns may also allow for more
      accurate guidance to practitioners on the potential changes in
      space-time patterns that is predicted as a result of climate
      change.</para>

      <para/>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
