<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b6_ch6"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Blockage of Hydraulic Structures</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weeks_william.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/rigby_ted.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>
      <td>6</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>
      <td>6</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>
      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Draft for industry comment</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>
      <td>Draft for industry comment</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>
      <td>In preparation</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>example needed</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_7u4kb">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_8d0mf">
      <title>Background and Scope</title>

      <para>The capacity of drainage systems can be severely impacted by
      blockage. However, there are situations where significant blockage may
      not impact flood behaviour to any great extent. Determination of likely
      blockage levels and mechanisms, when estimating design flows, is
      therefore an important consideration in quantifying the potential impact
      of blockage of a particular structure on design flood behaviour.</para>

      <para>This chapter provides guidance on the assessment of blockage in
      drainage systems to assist in drainage analysis and design for both
      urban and rural catchments. While there are a range of locations and
      conditions where blockage of a drainage network may be a concern in
      hydraulic design, this chapter concentrates specifically on blockage of
      cross drainage structures, in particular culverts and small
      bridges.</para>

      <para>Blockage of drainage structures is a subject where a range of
      advice has been provided in different guidelines. Many drainage
      guidelines do not mention blockage at all (ARR, 1987), therefore
      blockage is ignored in many cases. In other situations, especially where
      there has been an observed blockage problem in historical flood events,
      blockage may be specified for extreme conditions. Other guidelines
      provide inconclusive advice.</para>

      <para>In fact, the actual evidence for the impact of blockage on design
      flood events is very limited and the evidence for any clear quantitative
      design advice is lacking. This is the case internationally as well as in
      Australia.</para>

      <para>This chapter is not a definitive approach, but is an attempt to
      provide an approach that allows a consistent analysis methodology, while
      not becoming too extreme in either direction since there are risks in
      either under- or over-estimating the influence of blockage on design
      flood levels. It draws heavily on the findings of an earlier report
      prepared by the ARR Revision Project 11 team (Weeks, 2009). Materials
      upon which this guideline has been based are referenced in the
      Bibliography of this chapter and in the earlier project reports and
      papers released on the ARR website (www.arr.org.au).</para>

      <para>It is expected that this chapter will be updated and revised as
      more information becomes available and designers gain experience in the
      assessment of blockage and how it affects the drainage system and
      calculated design flood behaviour.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_d6gqe">
      <title>Limitations of the Procedure</title>

      <para>This procedure has been developed to quantify the most likely
      blockage level and mechanism for a small bridge or culvert when impacted
      by sediment or debris laden floodwater. It has not been developed for
      and is not appropriate when considering the impact of what are known as
      hyperconcentrated flows, mudflows or debris flows, on blockage of a
      structure. Hyperconcentrated flows are typically defined by a solids
      content of 20% or more by volume (or about 40% by weight) of the water
      column. Mud and debris flows include even higher levels of solids. At
      these much higher levels of suspended or fully integrated solids,
      blockage levels are likely to be much higher than those assessed in
      accordance with this chapter. Care should be taken in the review of
      catchment conditions where bed grades are relatively steep (say &gt;
      3%), to confirm bed and banks would remain relatively stable, such that
      flows would remain in the sediment or debris laden category and not
      become hyperconcentrated during the event under consideration.</para>

      <para>While this procedure includes consideration of the impact of
      non-floating (sediment) on blockage of a structure, it is restricted to
      the likely impact of such material arriving at the structure during a
      design event. It cannot reflect the impact of any pre-existing build-up
      of sediment on the subsequent blockage of a structure.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_04c52">
    <title>Types of Structures and Drainage Systems</title>

    <para>The types of structures or drainage elements affected by blockages
    can generally be grouped as follows:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Bridges and Culverts</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>These cross drainage structures carry roads, railways,
          pipelines or other infrastructure across watercourses. These
          structures can be affected by a number of different types of
          blockage mechanisms, resulting in consequences including increased
          flood levels, changes to stream flow patterns, changes to erosion
          and deposition patterns in channels, and physical damage to the
          structure. Blockage of these structures is the subject of this
          chapter.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Drainage system inlets and pipes</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>This includes components of urban drainage systems located
          within road reserves and urban overland flow paths. Frequently
          blockage of this type of system is generally less likely to cause
          the same extent of damage associated with blockage of bridges and
          culverts, but the consequences can still be serious from a traffic
          and safety perspective, and can cause serious inconvenience and
          nuisance. However in certain circumstances, in densely developed
          urban areas, pit blockage can cause significant monetary damage due
          to flooding of buildings upstream. While this type of blockage can
          be a significant nuisance, it is not covered in this chapter.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Open channels and waterways</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Blockage of natural and constructed waterways can occur at any
          location, typically as a result of large debris snagged against bank
          vegetation, or debris passing slowly down the channel. The
          consequences of such blockage are increased flood levels, diversion
          of surface flows and the possible relocation of the waterway channel
          as a result of severe bank erosion. Blockage of these structures is
          not covered in this chapter.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Overland flow paths</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>This category covers various surface flow paths that are not
          normally recognised as drainage channels but do act to convey
          surface flows in larger events. Blockage of these flow paths can
          result from the deposition of sediment or the material blockage of
          structures built across the flow, such as property fences blocked by
          litter and grass clippings. Blockage of these structures is not
          covered in this chapter.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Weirs and dams</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Debris can cause blockage within the spillways of weirs and
          dams, especially where there is a significant constriction to the
          flow area. This could increase the water level in the storage,
          possibly threatening the security of the structure. The sudden
          release of large debris rafts from dam spillways can cause
          significant damage to downstream road crossings. Blockage of these
          structures is not covered in this chapter.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_j2caw">
    <title>Factors Influencing Blockage</title>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_qj27o">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>The factors that most influence the likely blockage of a bridge or
      culvert structure are:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Debris Type and Dimensions</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Whether floating, non-floating or urban debris present in
            the source area and its size;</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Debris Availability</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The volume of debris available in the source area;</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Debris Mobility</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The ease with which available debris can be moved into the
            stream;</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Debris Transportability</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The ease with which the mobilised debris is transported once
            it enters the stream;</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Structure Interaction</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The resulting interaction between the transported debris and
            the bridge or culvert structure; and</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Random Chance</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>An unquantifiable but significant factor.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para>These various factors which impact debris movement and interaction
      with the structure are discussed further in the following
      sections.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_o8cz3">
      <title>Debris Type and Dimensions</title>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_48lp5">
        <title>Overview</title>

        <para>All blockages that do occur arise from the arrival and build-up
        of debris at a structure. There are three different types of debris
        typically present in debris accumulated upstream of or within a
        blocked structure. This debris may be classified as</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Floating (e.g. trees);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Non-floating or depositional (e.g. sediment); and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Urban (e.g. cars and other urban debris).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Debris comprising natural materials is discussed in <xref
        linkend="b6_ch6_s_an6la"/> and <xref linkend="b6_ch6_s_zw09r"/> and
        urban debris in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_s_s0kjo"/>. A means of
        determining the relevant dimensions of the debris is discussed in
        <xref linkend="b6_ch6_s_ufqp2"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_an6la">
        <title>Floating Debris</title>

        <para>Floating debris in rural or forested streams is generally
        vegetation of various types:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Small floating debris</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>less than 150 mm long, can include small tree branches,
              sticks, leaves and refuse from yards such as litter and lawn
              clippings and all types of rural vegetation. This type of debris
              can also be introduced into a stream by earlier windstorms, bank
              erosion and land mass failures or from seasonal leaf falls. It
              is important to note that this material is available in both
              urban and rural catchments, and is usually available for
              transportation at any time.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Medium floating debris</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>typically between 150 mm and 3 m long, mainly consists of
              tree branches of various sizes. This material is usually
              introduced into the flow path by channel erosion undermining
              riparian vegetation or through wind gusts during storms. It can
              also be present as a result of the breakdown of larger floating
              debris.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Large floating debris</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>more than 3 m long, consists of logs or trees, typically
              from the same sources as for medium floating debris. Transport
              and storage of this material depends on discharge, channel
              characteristics, the size of the drift pieces relative to the
              channel dimensions, and the hydraulic characteristics (depth and
              slope) of the system. In small and intermediate size channels,
              this material is not easily transported and can easily become
              snagged mid-stream acting as a collection point for smaller
              material (i.e. a debris raft or log-jam). Whole trees can be
              retained within streams by being temporarily anchored either to
              the bed or banks of the stream. Large floating debris is usually
              transported during larger floods or prolonged periods of high
              river-stage where the floodplain is engaged and the ability of
              the debris to become snagged is reduced. This type of debris can
              cause significant problems for both culverts and bridge
              structures.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <para>Small items of vegetation will usually pass through drainage
        structures during floods, while larger items may be caught in the
        structure. Once larger items are caught, this then allows smaller
        debris to collect on the structure.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_zw09r">
        <title>Non-Floating Debris</title>

        <para>Non-floating debris in rural or forested streams is usually
        sediment of all types. These can be classified as:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fine sediments (silt and sand)</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>typically consist of particles ranging from 0.004 to 2 mm.
              The deposition of finer clay-sized particles is normally a
              concern in tidal areas, with lower flood surface gradients and
              velocities. This type of debris is either transported along the
              streambed as bed load or within the water column as suspended
              load. Such material is normally sourced from sheet and rill
              erosion, landslip and landmass failures and channel erosion.
              Yield rates for this material can be significantly influenced by
              the conditions of, and changes to, a catchment due to
              urbanisation and/or rural land use practices.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Gravels and cobbles</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>consist of rock typically ranging in size from 2 to 63 mm
              and 63 to 200 mm respectively. The source of this material may
              be from gully formation, channel erosion, landslips or land mass
              failure although landslips and/or land mass failures of any size
              will likely create hyperconcentrated or even debris flows which
              are not covered by this guideline. Once mobilised, gravels and
              cobbles are primarily transported as bed load within high
              gradient streams. The deposition of cobbles can readily block
              the entrance of culverts or reduce the flow area under
              bridges.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Boulders</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>comprise rocks greater than 200 mm. The source of boulders
              is mostly from gully and channel erosion, landslips and the
              displacement of rocks from channel stabilisation works. Like
              gravel and cobbles, this material is typically transported as
              bed load in high gradient streams. This material can readily
              block the entrance to a structure and/or cause damage to the
              structure from the force of impact/collision.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_s0kjo">
        <title>Urban Debris</title>

        <para>Urbanisation of catchments introduces many different man-made
        materials that are less common in rural or forested catchments and
        which can cause structure blockage. These include fence palings,
        building materials, mattresses, garbage bins, shopping trolleys,
        fridges, large industrial containers and vehicles. Garbage bins can
        for example be easily washed down a street and into a stream or
        drainage structure, a situation made worse if a large rainfall event
        occurs on the same day as rubbish collection within the catchment,
        when bins are placed in streets for collection. Urban Debris can be
        floating or non-floating.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_1zzea">
      <title>Debris Availability</title>

      <para>Defining the source area is an important consideration, when
      discussing debris availability and mobility. The source area is that
      area from which debris could be sourced during an event. In a small
      event it may be restricted to the immediate confines of the creek and
      its banks but in larger events will likely extend to the full extent of
      the floodplain and possibly the full extent of the upstream catchment
      area. As this procedure is used to initially establish debris potential
      in a 1% Annual Exceedence Probability (AEP) event , the relevant source
      area will typically be limited to the 1% AEP flood extents. Steep sided
      tributaries and larger rills may however extend the source area beyond
      the limits of the 1% AEP flood.</para>

      <para>The following factors affect the availability of debris material
      within a source area:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Potential for soil erosion</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Soil erosion exposes soil and rock particles, thus
            increasing their availability. The potential for soil erosion is
            dependent on a number of factors including soil erodibility,
            rainfall erosivity, surface slope length and gradient, vegetation
            cover and changes in catchment hydrology, this latter factor being
            often closely linked to the effects of urbanisation.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Local geology</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The geology of the debris source area, particularly the
            exposed geology of the watercourse, influences the availability of
            materials such as clay, silt, sand, gravel, rocks and
            boulders.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Source area</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Increasing the area supplying debris typically increases the
            quantity of available blockage material. It is noted however, that
            once blockage occurs at a given structure, the debris source area
            for the next downstream structure may be much less than that of
            the upstream structures source area.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Amount and type of vegetative cover</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Cover can vary from grasses and shrubs to thick forests and
            plantations as well as a variety of crops and agricultural uses.
            Increasing the cover density in the source area will typically
            increase the availability of debris. Some types of cover are also
            more prone to produce debris than others (eg Cora trees). The type
            of cover in the source area can also impact availability</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Land clearing</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>This is associated with both rural and urban land use
            practices. Deforestation and urbanisation can alter the long-term
            flow regime of streams and may lead to gully erosion and channel
            expansion.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Preceding wind and rainfall</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The occurrence of frequent flood events typically reduces
            the availability of debris in the source area, however, the
            occurrence of frequent windstorms will typically increase the
            quantity of debris available in the source area.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Urbanisation</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Such areas make available a wide range of debris typically
            influenced by the extent of flood inundation and proximity of such
            debris to the stream. In most circumstances this a manageable
            factor linked to town planning and drainage design.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_akrjm">
      <title>Debris Mobility</title>

      <para>The following factors affect the mobilisation of debris material
      within the catchment:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Rainfall erosivity</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Different regions experience a range of frequencies of
            rainfall intensity, and in general, those areas that experience
            more intense rainfall have a greater potential to mobilise debris
            than areas of lower rainfall intensity.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Soil erodibility</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>This can vary from weathered rocks to cohesive clays, all
            soils have different abilities to become eroded, entrained and
            available for mobilisation.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Slope</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>For sediment and boulder movement, there is a relationship
            between the mobilisation of such debris and the slope of the
            catchment, with respect to overbank areas where debris may be
            sourced and the stream channel which conveys the debris.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Storm duration</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The mobilisation of materials generally increases with
            increasing storm duration.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Vegetation cover</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Sparse vegetation cover can increase sediment
            mobility.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_hlzf1">
      <title>Debris Transportability</title>

      <para>Once debris has been mobilised, it then needs to be transported
      down the stream if it is to present a hazard to downstream structures.
      Stream power, velocity, depth, presence of snags and bends and the
      overall dimensions of the water course play a large part in determining
      whether the mobilised debris lodges where it first enters the stream or
      is transported downstream to a receiving structure. There is a
      reasonably strong correlation between the waterway width and the maximum
      size of floating debris that a stream can transport. The event magnitude
      is also a major factor in controlling the quantity of debris
      transported. Rarer events produce deeper and faster flowing floodwaters
      which are able to transport large quantities and larger sizes of debris,
      smaller events may not be able to transport larger bridging material at
      all.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_v0zm7">
      <title>Structure Interaction</title>

      <para>The likelihood of blockage at a particular structure depends on
      whether or not debris is able to bridge across the structure's inlet or
      become trapped within the structure. As bridging occurs, the clear
      expanse of each opening reduces, thus increasing the likelihood of
      further bridging and further blockage by smaller or similar material.
      Smaller blockage matter is unlikely to cause full blockage of a
      structure without the presence of suitable larger bridging matter, the
      material that initially bridges across the opening or inlet of a
      structure. Bridging matter can be as small as leaves caught on a kerb
      inlet grate, or as large as logs, cars and shipping containers caught at
      a culvert inlet or on bridge piers.</para>

      <para>Exposed services attached to the face of culverts or bridges or
      obstructing the culvert waterway opening can significantly increase the
      risk of blockage. Similarly, some through-culvert features introduced to
      improve fish passage can also collect and hold debris increasing the
      risk of internal blockage problems. Many other factors such as skew
      alignments, opening aspect ratios, opening height to overtopping height
      ratios, culvert hoods, sloping inlet walls and the smoothness of
      transitions can also modify the likely interaction between the arriving
      debris and the bridge or culvert structure.</para>

      <para>In urban drainage systems, any individual culvert in the system is
      not an individual structure, it is part of a system, generally with
      culverts and other structures in a series down the water course. As a
      consequence, upstream culverts are likely to collect a portion of the
      transported debris in the stream, reducing the quantity of debris that
      would otherwise reach the downstream culverts so the risk of blockage in
      these downstream structures is reduced.</para>

      <para>Consideration of multiple structures is discussed further in <xref
      linkend="b6_ch6_s_9pud0"/>.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_iwpak">
      <title>Random Chance</title>

      <para>While an unquantifiable factor, random chance plays a significant role in the blockage
        of structures. Antecedent conditions can in particular substantially alter the likely level
        of blockage at a structure. Recent floods can for example reduce the availability of debris
        but increase the transportability of debris of a particular size by cleaning out the
        waterway. Even the alignment of a limb approaching a structure can substantially alter its
        likelihood of being caught on the inlet and triggering a more substantial blockage. Blockage
        of a structure in any event of a particular magnitude will therefore vary in response to
        these random changes in behaviour, creating a distribution of blockage levels associated
        with such an event. This chapter attempts to quantify the average or most likely blockage
        level associated with a design event of a particular magnitude, as this presents an
        probability neutral approach to simulation of the resulting flood surface.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_ho7ss">
    <title>Assessment of Design Blockage Levels</title>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_uwo8y">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>Blockage of cross drainage structures such as culverts and bridges
      could have an impact on the capacity of these structures and also on
      flood levels. Hydraulic analysis of these structures should include some
      consideration of these impacts. This section describes a procedure for
      the inclusion of the impacts of blockage in analysis.</para>

      <para>The design blockage is the blockage condition that is most likely to occur during a
        given design storm and needs to be an “average” of all potential blockage conditions to
        ensure that the calculated design flood levels reflect the defined probability. For example,
        an assumption of a higher than average level of blockage would lead to the calculated design
        flood level upstream of the structure being higher than would be appropriate for the defined
        probability. Downstream flood levels would be lower because of the additional flood storage
        created upstream of the structure. On the other hand, an assumed lower than average level of
        blockage would result in lower flood levels upstream and higher flood levels downstream.
        This is a similar concept to that of probability neutrality used in various aspects of
        design flood event analysis. It is also noted that actual blockage levels vary greatly from
        event to event with a potential spread from “all clear” to “fully blocked” even in floods of
        comparable magnitude. Antecedent catchment conditions and random chance are major factors in
        determining blockage levels in an actual event. The selected design blockage must aim for
        probability neutrality (the concept of ensuring that the AEP of the design flood discharge
        is the same as the AEP of the design rainfall input) so design floods are appropriate for
        the particular circumstances. As with other similar aspects of design flood estimation, such
        as losses, each individual historical flood may have quite different amounts of blockage
        compared to the design event.</para>

      <para>Flood mapping is an exercise in probabilities that involves the
      estimation of ‘average’ catchment conditions for various storm and flood
      frequencies to ensure that the rainfall of the defined probability
      produces a flood event of the same probability. In such work, design
      blockage conditions must be considered when predicting flood levels of a
      given frequency. In situations where the consequences of flooding
      (including the impact of blockage) are high, planning rules typically
      require design for a lower probability (rarer) event. An increase in the
      design event probability is typically adopted for planning purposes,
      when the consequences of flooding are low.</para>

      <para>This chapter is based on a design event type analysis, where a
      flood of a defined flood probability is required. For Monte Carlo
      analysis of flood risk, a probability distribution of blockage is
      required, as an input. Considering the uncertainty in the assessment of
      blockage, analysis of probability distributions is even more difficult.
      This topic is discussed more detail in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_s_duiq5"/>.
      The procedure presented in this chapter is based on a qualitative
      assessment of debris likely to reach a structure, and the likely
      interaction between that debris and the structure regarding its
      potential for blockage. It is based on the various papers prepared by
      Barthelmess, Rigby, Silveri and others.</para>

      <para>The procedure initially involves a series of decisions leading to estimation of the
        likely magnitude of debris reaching a structure in a 1% AEP event and the most likely
        blockage level that would develop at the structure under consideration. Subsequent
        adjustments are then made to reflect the most likely design blockage levels in lesser or
        greater AEP events and to establish the associated most likely blockage mechanism. This
        procedure provides an probability neutral approach to the assessment of an appropriate level
        of blockage for the simulation of design flood behaviour , but may not reflect specific
        conditions in an equivalent historical event. Such is the random nature of the many
        variables controlling blockage behaviour.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_3qoyc">
      <title>Appropriate Investigation</title>

      <para>It is important to recognise the impact that different levels of
      investigation can have on the confidence associated with any blockage
      estimate. Estimates based on aerial imagery alone cannot for example
      provide the level of confidence that would be obtained from a field
      visit to the site, specifically aimed at assessing the various factors
      influencing blockage levels at the site or likely blockage
      mechanisms.</para>

      <para>Where the structure/site under consideration is located in a particularly flood
        sensitive area and blockage of the structure could significantly impact flood behaviour in
        that area, then a high level of investigation is warranted. This should include a field
        inspection of the upstream catchment/source area to confirm the types of debris likely to
        reach the site, their availability, mobility and transportability together with the average
        size of the largest 10% of each debris type likely to reach the site. Any structures
        upstream of the target structure/site should be inspected and consideration given to their
        ability to trap debris reaching the target structure/site. Any photographs/records of past
        blockage material and extents should be used to validate the choice of
          L<subscript>10</subscript> and debris type. Although seldom available, any photos/records
        of the blockage mechanism (Location – Type – Timing) that have been observed in past events
        will help to validate the chosen blockage mechanism to be used in the hydraulic model.
        However it must be stressed that it is the most likely (probability neutral) blockage
        mechanism that is required, not the worst case scenario. Flood mapping, aerial photography,
        annual rainfall and rainfall IFD data, rainfall and soil erosivity maps, topographic maps,
        vegetation and soil maps should be consulted when available to further consolidate
        conclusions as to the types of debris likely to reach the site and the quantum of such
        debris.</para>

      <para>Conversely, when the structure under consideration is in an area
      where changes in flood behaviour would have no significant consequences
      on safety, property damage or amenity, then an extensive investigation
      to support the blockage assessment process, as outlined above, may not
      be warranted. This decision should be documented.</para>

      <para>The final decision as to what is an appropriate level of
      investigation must ultimately be the responsibility of the person making
      the assessment. It will vary greatly between sites and will to some
      extent be constrained by what information is available. Whatever the
      approach adopted, it is important that the level of investigation
      undertaken should be relevant to the importance of the assessment of
      blockage at the site and is documented, so that others relying on the
      assessment can be aware of the confidence limits attaching to that
      particular assessment.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_iy4m9">
      <title>History of Blockage</title>

      <para>The history of blockage in the drainage system is an important
      input to any risk based approach to blockage, and should always be
      explored in so far as available data permits. While the procedure
      outlined in this chapter provides a generic assessment of likely design
      blockage levels and mechanisms, local observations and history can be
      important in ensuring that this procedure results in reasonable answers.
      All available history should be sought from relevant local stakeholders,
      including residents, in assessing the reasonableness of blockage levels
      and mechanisms produced by this chapter.</para>

      <para>In particular, if there has been no long term history of blockage
      at a particular structure and similar drainage structures in the
      catchment have not demonstrated blockage problems, blockage may not need
      to be considered, or a nominal allowance only may be appropriate in
      design.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_qr3uw">
      <title>Assessment Procedure</title>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_ufqp2">
        <title>Debris Types and Dimensions</title>

        <para>In using this procedure it is necessary to first assess the type
        of debris likely to arrive at the structure under consideration and
        the likely dimensions of that debris. Where more than one type of
        debris is present in quantity in the source area, the procedure will
        need to be repeated for each debris type to establish the debris type
        with the most impact on the performance of the blocked
        structure.</para>

        <para>The types of debris available in their respective source areas
        will normally be readily apparent during a field visit or from aerial
        photographs, but relevant dimensions may be more difficult to
        assess.</para>

        <para>The ratio of the opening width of the structure (e.g. diameter
        or width of the culvert or bridge pier spacing) to the average length
        of the longest 10% of the debris that could arrive at the site (termed
        here as L<subscript>10</subscript>) is a well correlated guide to the
        likelihood that this material could bridge the openings of the
        structure and cause blockage. This L<subscript>10</subscript> value is
        defined as the average length of the longest 10% of the debris
        reaching the site and should preferably be estimated from sampling of
        typical debris loads. However, if such data is not available, it
        should be determined from an inspection of debris on the floor of the
        source area, with due allowance for snagging and reduction in size
        during transportation to the structure.</para>

        <para>For debris of any particular type and size to reach the
        structure, the debris must:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>be available in the source area;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>be able to be mobilised into the stream and not snagged by
            bank vegetation as it enters the stream; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>be delivered into a stream able to transport the debris from
            the source area down to the structure, without floating debris
            being snagged by bank vegetation or stream bends or constrictions,
            or without non-floating debris being deposited prior to reaching
            the structure as the stream grade and velocities reduce. For
            smaller more turbulent streams (less than say 6 m bank to bank)
            the width between banks of the stream through the source area will
            normally limit the size/length of larger floating debris to less
            than the stream width. The bed grade immediately upstream of the
            structure will normally limit the size of the larger non-floating
            debris reaching the structure to that capable of being moved by
            the flow.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Any loose material and pockets of debris lying within or in
        close proximity to the channel are likely to be representative of the
        debris that could cause downstream blockage. A detailed inspection of
        the waterway upstream of the target structure, particularly after a
        flood, will assist with assessing the above factors and deriving a
        realistic value for L<subscript>10</subscript>.</para>

        <para>In an urban area the variety of available debris can be
        considerable with an equal variability in L<subscript>10</subscript>.
        In the absence of a record of past debris accumulated at the
        structure, an L<subscript>10</subscript> of at least 1.5 m should be
        considered as many urban debris sources produce material of at least
        this length such as palings, stored timber, sulo bins and shopping
        trolleys.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_cpwvo">
        <title>Debris Availability</title>

        <para>The availability of a particular type of debris (floating,
        non-floating or urban) in a source area limits the level of that
        particular debris that can be ultimately mobilised and transported to
        a structure. As noted in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_s_ufqp2"/>, there may
        be significant quantities of more than one type of debris present in
        the source area, requiring more than one type of debris to be
        assessed. The characteristics of high, medium and low availability are
        hard to quantify, so there is some judgment required in their
        evaluation. <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_2fnk8"/> describes typical source
        area characteristics and a corresponding ranking for the likely
        availability of a particular type of debris in that source area. It
        should be noted that the characteristics included are not exhaustive
        or presented in any particular order. Some will only be applicable in
        respect to certain debris types. They are provided to provoke thought
        about the factors that could be relevant to the level of availability.
        As this procedure is based on a 1% AEP flood (with later adjustment
        for other AEPs) the effective source area is that associated with a 1%
        AEP event.</para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_2fnk8">
          <caption>Debris Availability - in Source Area of a Particular
          Type/Size of Debris</caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Classification</th>

              <th>Typical Source Area Characteristics (1% AEP Event)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>High</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Natural forested areas with thick vegetation and
                    extensive canopy cover, difficult to walk through with
                    considerable fallen limbs, leaves and high levels of floor
                    litter.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Streams with boulder/cobble beds and steep bed
                    slopes and steep banks showing signs of substantial past
                    bed/bank movements.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Arid areas, where loose vegetation and exposed loose
                    soils occur and vegetation is sparse.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Urban areas that are not well maintained and/or
                    where old paling fences, sheds, cars and/or stored loose
                    material etc., are present on the floodplain close to the
                    water course.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Medium</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>State forest areas with clear understory, grazing
                    land with stands of trees.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Source areas generally falling between the High and
                    Low categories.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Low</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Well maintained rural lands and paddocks with
                    minimal outbuildings or stored materials in the source
                    area.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Streams with moderate to flat slopes and stable bed
                    and banks.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Arid areas where vegetation is deep rooted and soils
                    are resistant to scour.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Urban areas that are well maintained with limited
                    debris present in the source area.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_flk0q">
        <title>Debris Mobility</title>

        <para>The ability for debris to become mobilised from the source area
        into a stream has an effect on the amount of debris that can then be
        ultimately transported to a structure. <xref
        linkend="b6_ch6_t_zjdt3"/> describes typical source area
        characteristics and a corresponding rank for the likely mobility of
        debris from the sorce area into receiving streams.</para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_zjdt3">
          <caption>Debris Mobility - Ability of a Particular Type/Size of
          Debris to be Moved into Streams</caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Classification</th>

              <th>Typical Source Area Characteristics (1% AEP Event)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>High</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Steep source areas with fast response times and high
                    annual rainfall and/or storm intensities and/or source
                    areas subject to high rainfall intensities with sparse
                    vegetation cover.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Receiving streams that frequently overtop their
                    banks.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Main debris source areas close to streams.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Medium</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Source areas generally falling between the High and
                    Low mobility categories.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Low</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Low rainfall intensities and large, flat source
                    areas.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Receiving streams infrequently overtops their
                    banks.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Main debris source areas well away from
                    streams.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_g5otj">
        <title>Debris Transportability</title>

        <para>The ability for debris to be transported by a stream down to a
        structure has an effect on the amount of debris arriving at the
        structure. <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_irqqg"/> describes typical stream
        characteristics and a corresponding rank for the likely
        transportability of debris.</para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_irqqg">
          <caption>Debris Transportability - Ability of a Stream to Transport
          Debris Down to the Structure<footnote>
              <para>Where V = velocity, D is depth, W is width and
              L<subscript>10</subscript> is average length of the longest 10%
              of the debris that could arrive at the site</para>
            </footnote></caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Transportability</th>

              <th><para>Typical Transporting Stream Characteristics (1% AEP
              Event)</para></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>High</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Steep bed slopes (&gt; 3%) and/or high stream
                    velocity (V &gt; 2.5 m/s)</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Deep stream relative to vertical debris dimension (D
                    &gt; 0.5L<subscript>10</subscript>)</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Wide stream relative to horizontal debris
                    dimension.(W &gt; L<subscript>10</subscript>)</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Stream relatively straight and free of major
                    constrictions or snag points.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>High temporal variability in maximum stream
                    flows.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Medium</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Stream generally falling between High and Low
                    categories.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Low</td>

              <td><itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Flat bed slopes (&lt; 1%) and/or low stream velocity
                    (V &lt; 1m/s).</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Shallow depth relative to vertical debris dimension
                    (D &lt; 0.5L<subscript>10</subscript>).</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Narrow stream relative to horizontal debris
                    dimension (W &lt; L<subscript>10</subscript>).</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Stream meanders with frequent constrictions/snag
                    points.</para>
                  </listitem>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Low temporal variability in maximum stream
                    flows.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_alr8r">
        <title>Debris Potential</title>

        <para>Where reliable long term data is available on the quantity and
        type of debris typically present at a structure, this should be used
        to directly quantify the debris potential at the structure. Where such
        data is not available, the potential quantity of debris reaching a
        structure at a site from a contributing source area in a 1% AEP event
        can be estimated from <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_3oar1"/>. If there is a
        significant quantity of more than one type of debris in the source
        area that could induce blockage, this will require more than one type
        of debris to be assessed.</para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_3oar1">
          <caption>1% AEP Debris Potential</caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Classification</th>

              <th>Combinations of the Above (any order)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>High</td>

              <td>HHH or HHM</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Medium</td>

              <td>MMM or HML or HMM or HLL</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Low</td>

              <td>LLL or MML or MLL</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_nn0c6">
        <title>Adjustment for Annual Exceedence Probability</title>

        <para>Observation of debris conveyed in streams strongly suggests a
        correlation between an event’s magnitude and debris potential at a
        site. This is accommodated in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_rgr5l"/> as
        follows.</para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_rgr5l">
          <caption>AEP Adjusted Debris Potential</caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th rowspan="2">Event AEP</th>

              <th colspan="3">(1% AEP) Debris Potential at Structure</th>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <th>High</th>

              <th>Medium</th>

              <th>Low</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>AEP &gt; 5%</td>

              <td>Medium</td>

              <td>Low</td>

              <td>Low</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>AEP 5% - AEP 0.5%</td>

              <td>High</td>

              <td>Medium</td>

              <td>Low</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>AEP &lt; 0.5%</td>

              <td>High</td>

              <td>High</td>

              <td>Medium</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_umge1">
        <title>Design Blockage Level</title>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Inlet Blockage (Floating or
        Non-Floating)</emphasis></para>

        <para>In conjunction with the quantity of debris likely to arrive at
        the site, <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_pqky7"/> provides an estimate of the
        ‘most likely’ inlet blockage level should a blockage form from
        floating or non-floating debris bridging the inlet.</para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_pqky7">
          <caption>Most Likely Inlet Blockage Levels -
          B<subscript>DES</subscript>%</caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th rowspan="2">Control Dimension Inlet Clear Width (W) (m)</th>

              <th colspan="3">AEP Adjusted Debris Potential At Structure</th>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <th>High</th>

              <th>Medium</th>

              <th>Low</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>W &lt; L<subscript>10</subscript></td>

              <td>100%</td>

              <td>50%</td>

              <td>25%</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>L<subscript>10</subscript> ≤ W ≤
              3*L<subscript>10</subscript></td>

              <td>20%</td>

              <td>10%</td>

              <td>0%</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>W &gt; 3*L<subscript>10</subscript></td>

              <td>10%</td>

              <td>0%</td>

              <td>0%</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Barrel Blockage (Non
        Floating)</emphasis></para>

        <para>An alternative blockage mechanism is however possible for
        non-floating material (typically sediment) when this material
        progressively arrives and is deposited at the inlet and in the barrel
        or waterway of the structure. This typically leads to a bottom up
        blockage of both the barrel and inlet to the structure. Blockage in
        this form can arise because velocities through the structure fall
        below the level required to maintain the material in motion or, in
        extreme cases, because the depth of sediment in the bed load is
        sufficient to overwhelm the inlet, leading to sediment with little
        water completely blocking the inlet and filling a substantial
        proportion of the barrel of the structure.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_eiwzn"/> classifies the likelihood of
        deposition in the barrel or waterway based on sediment size and
        velocity through the structure. Using this likelihood of deposition
        <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_yg77l"/> then combines the likelihood of
        deposition with the debris potential to provide a most likely
        depositional barrel or waterway blockage level for the
        structure.</para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_eiwzn">
          <caption>Likelihood of Sediment Being Deposited in Barrel/Waterway
          (HML)</caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th rowspan="2">Peak Velocity Through Structure (m/s)</th>

              <th colspan="5">Mean Sediment Size Present</th>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Clay/Silt 0.001 to 0.04 mm</td>

              <td>Sand 0.04 to 2 mm</td>

              <td>Gravel 2 to 63 mm</td>

              <td>Cobbles 63 to 200 mm</td>

              <td>Boulders &gt;200 mm</td>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>&gt;= 3</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>M</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>1.0 to &lt; 3.0</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>M</td>

              <td>M</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>0.5 to &lt; 1.0</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>M</td>

              <td>H</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>0.1 to &lt; 0.5</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>M</td>

              <td>H</td>

              <td>H</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>&lt; 0.1</td>

              <td>L</td>

              <td>M</td>

              <td>H</td>

              <td>H</td>

              <td>H</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>

        <para><emphasis>Based on Hjulstrom’s diagram as modified by Sundborg
        (Sundborg, 1956)</emphasis></para>

        <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_yg77l">
          <caption>Most Likely Depositional Blockage Levels –
          B<subscript>DES</subscript>%</caption>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th rowspan="2">Likelihood that Deposition will Occur (<xref
              linkend="b6_ch6_t_eiwzn"/>)</th>

              <th colspan="3">AEP Adjusted Non Floating Debris Potential
              (Sediment) at Structure</th>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <th>High</th>

              <th>Medium</th>

              <th>Low</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>High</td>

              <td>100%</td>

              <td>60%</td>

              <td>25%</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Medium</td>

              <td>60%</td>

              <td>40%</td>

              <td>15%</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Low</td>

              <td>25%</td>

              <td>15%</td>

              <td>0%</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>

        <para>It is noted that <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_yg77l"/> (blockage
        caused by non-floating debris) is to be read in conjunction with <xref
        linkend="b6_ch6_t_pqky7"/> (blockage caused by floating debris) and
        the blockage mechanism creating the worst impact on flood behaviour
        should be used in design.</para>

        <para>While the above tables provide a means of estimating a realistic value for the
          magnitude of a likely (probability neutral) blockage, they do not address the other
          characteristics required to properly describe the blockage mechanism (viz the blockage
          type, location and timing) and its impact on the hydraulics of flow through the structure.
          These issues are discussed further in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_s_z10rt"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_v2q80">
        <title>Minimum Opening Height Considerations</title>

        <para>Consideration of likely inlet blockage levels as presented in
        <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_pqky7"/> assumes that the greatest dimension
        (length) of debris relative to the structures opening width is the
        dominant factor influencing inlet blockages. All debris however has
        three dimensions and a lesser dimension, such as the debris height,
        could also trigger vertical bridging across the opening height if the
        structure's opening height was substantially less than the structures
        opening width. In the absence of detailed data on likely debris
        geometry, it is recommended that structures be designed with a clear
        opening height of at least one third their width to reflect the
        assumptions inherent in this procedure. In an existing structure where
        the opening height is less than one third of the opening width, it is
        recommended that analysis be based on the likely vertical dimension of
        the debris and the vertical opening height of the structure in lieu of
        the likely debris length and horizontal opening width. Unless data is
        available to support the choice of L<subscript>10</subscript>
        (vertically), it should be taken as not less than one half of the
        assessed debris L<subscript>10</subscript> (length).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_q7udj">
        <title>Blockage of Multi Cell/Span Structures</title>

        <para>Limited observation of blockages at multi cell culverts or multi
        span bridges suggests that all cells/spans often do not block to the
        same extent. The main factors influencing this variability appear to
        be the main stream approach alignment and location relative to the
        multiple culverts or spans and the relative width of flow carrying
        debris to the total opening width. These two factors are somewhat
        related as they both influence the uniformity of presentation of
        debris, carried by the flow, to the individual cells or spans.</para>

        <para>Where the main stream width is considerably less than the total
        structure width, it is likely that more debris will be delivered to
        and accumulate at or in the cells/spans falling within the main stream
        width, than at the cells/spans located on the adjacent floodplains.
        This may not be the case when the mainstream flow is only a small
        proportion of the total flow reaching the structure. In such cases the
        presentation of debris to the multiple cells/spans may become more
        uniform resulting in more consistent levels of blockage.</para>

        <para>As an initial guide it is suggested that, where the width of
        that part of the approach flow that is capable of transporting the
        debris under consideration, is comparable with or greater than the
        total width of the structure, then the assessed
        B<subscript>DES</subscript> be applied uniformly to all
        cells/spans.</para>

        <para>Where the width of that part of the approach flow that is
        capable of transporting the debris under consideration is
        significantly less than the total width of the structure, then the
        culverts/spans within the effective transport width be assessed as
        blocked to B<subscript>DES</subscript> and those outside of that zone
        be reduced to half B<subscript>DES</subscript>. Measurements of
        observed distributions are however essentially non-existent at this
        time. More information, to permit refinement of guidelines for
        blockage of multiple spans/cells, is needed.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_9pud0">
        <title>Assessment of Multiple Structures</title>

        <para>It is fundamental to the consideration of the interaction
        between multiple culverts that any individual culvert/bridge could be
        ‘all clear’ or ‘guideline blocked’ in a design event.</para>

        <para>The question then arises as to what are the ‘likely’ probability neutral combinations
          of blockage that could occur across a catchment. Clearly an ‘all clear’
            (B<subscript>DES</subscript>=0) global solution is possible in any event and even
          probable in lesser events. In these lower probability events the single site
            B<subscript>DES</subscript> is probably also low so the change in catchment floods
          behaviour between different mixes of sites with B<subscript>DES</subscript>&gt;0 and
            B<subscript>DES</subscript>=0 may not be great. In larger events however substantial
          differences in flood behaviour can be created from different mixes of ‘all clear’ and
            B<subscript>DES</subscript> structures across the catchment. Simple math shows that n
          independent sites with two choices for blockage presents 2n combinations. A catchment with
          6 interacting culverts therefore could involve 64 possible blockage scenarios. In
          analysing these combinations it is therefore critical both with respect to probability
          neutrality and computation time that only likely combinations are considered. Seldom will
          all structures be responding in a truly independent manner. There is unfortunately no
          pre-prepared solution for this problem – all catchments will be different. While not a
          truly probability neutral approach, modelling all structures 'all clear' and 'guideline
          blocked' ensures individual structure impacts are properly simulated in the envelope
          solution together with the 'all clear' impacts. If these scenarios are then augmented with
          'likely' mixtures of clear and 'guideline blocked' structures, the resulting flood surface
          envelope should reasonably represent the likely envelope flood surface levels that could
          be reached at any site in the catchment. It should be noted however that in any single
          historic event of a given AEP, the recorded flood surface will likely only reach the
          envelope levels at some locations (due to the variability in actual historic
          blockages).</para>

        <para>As previously noted, where there are multiple structures on a
        contiguous water course, the debris availability will normally reduce
        downstream since debris will be captured by the upstream structures.
        Therefore for downstream structures, the debris availability, as
        defined in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_2fnk8"/> will normally be
        reduced.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_momns">
        <title>Risk Based Assessment of Blockages</title>

        <para>In general, the consequences of a flood event of given
        probability will be used to establish risk in an area or at a site and
        this level of risk will in turn be used to establish the appropriate
        event AEP to be used as the planning event for that particular area or
        site. What this approach does not reflect is the relative uncertainty
        in all of the various parameters influencing design flood estimation.
        With even the most careful approach to the selection of parameters
        like design rainfall intensity, rainfall temporal patterns, stream
        roughness or most likely blockage levels, there is a significant
        likelihood that error in the assessment of these parameters may in
        turn lead to errors in the predicted design flood behaviour.</para>

        <para>In an event based approach to modelling it is therefore prudent
        to undertake various sensitivity runs to quantify how reasonable
        variation in the chosen parameters could affect the model’s results.
        Where such an analysis generates significant changes in the flood
        surface, it indicates that the parameter creating that change needs
        very careful review to confirm that the value selected was as
        appropriate as available data permits. A sensitivity analysis of
        alternate reasonable blockage levels and mechanisms is therefore
        strongly recommended for design or analysis involving blockages. It is
        recommended that the sensitivity to such a variation in design
        blockage levels be incorporated into analysis by considering both an
        'all clear' and blocked at twice the calculated 'guideline blocked'
        level (max 100%) scenarios, to identify sites where flood behaviour
        upstream or downstream of the structure is particularly sensitive to
        the adopted design blockage level. Where such a site is identified,
        all inputs into the assessment process should be carefully reviewed to
        confirm the adopted design blockage level before proceeding with
        design or analysis based on that level.</para>

        <para>As blockage of a structure with significant upstream available
        flood storage can lead to a reduction in flood flow and levels
        downstream of the structure, effectively protecting downstream
        properties, it is important to review the all clear analysis to see if
        the all clear scenario results in significantly increased flows
        downstream of the structure. If this is found to be the case then the
        all clear and 'guideline blocked' results should be enveloped for
        design flood estimation purposes.</para>

        <para>In reviewing risk, inclusion of blockage in a Monte Carlo
        analysis is a valuable means of quantifying the impact of blockage on
        uncertainly in the flood assessment process. A distribution of
        blockage values is however needed for Monte Carlo analysis.
        Considering the uncertainty inherent in the factors influencing
        blockage levels and the lack of data in respect to the variation of
        blockage levels over time, it is however difficult to determine a
        suitable distribution. What little research has been done on this
        distribution suggests that the probability distribution is likely to
        be dual peaked with the ‘all clear’ and ‘most likely’ values ranking
        higher than adjacent values. Much more data is however needed before
        these characteristics can be confirmed.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_z10rt">
      <title>All Clear</title>

      <para>This is the condition where there is no allowance for blockage,
      and the hydraulic analysis assumes that the structure flows
      freely.</para>

      <para>This condition should be considered as referenced above as an
      important sensitivity case, since the 'all clear' condition will reduce
      the upstream flood level and may increase flood levels downstream
      depending on the storage and flood immunity of the structure being
      considered.</para>

      <para>Secondly, and perhaps more importantly, as referenced in <xref
      linkend="b6_ch6_s_iy4m9"/>, blockage may not need to be considered at
      all or may need consideration as a nominal allowance, if there is no
      history of blockage at this site or at similar neighbouring sites,
      especially if there is low risk of damage or disruption caused when
      blockage is neglected.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_z8c1g">
      <title>Implementation</title>

      <para>A form has been prepared to assist in implementing this procedure
      and is available on the ARR website<footnote>
          <para><link
          xlink:href="http://www.arr.org.au/wp-content/uploads/BLOCKAGE_ASSESSMENT_FORM.pdf">
          http://www.arr.org.au/wp-content/uploads/BLOCKAGE_ASSESSMENT_FORM.pdf</link></para>
        </footnote>.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_iwqc5">
    <title>Hydraulic Analysis of Blocked Structures</title>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_1roic">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>Where blockage has historically been included in analysis or
      design, it has often been applied as a reduction factor to the 'all
      clear' flow through the structure. This is a simple and rapid means of
      making some allowance for blockage and in the absence of information on
      likely blockage mechanisms and extents can provide an answer
      commensurate with the associated uncertainty in such an approach.</para>

      <para>This chapter enhances our understanding of likely design blockage
      mechanisms at a structure by quantifying likely blockage levels at a
      structure based on assessable catchment and structure parameters and
      understanding the blockage mechanism that will likely develop at the
      structure. Given this information, a more deliberate approach to
      hydraulic analysis of design blockages is now available, although most
      current hydraulic modelling software currently lacks the functionality
      to simulate the blockage mechanisms described in this chapter. It is
      hoped that this functionality will however be made available in the more
      capable software packages, in use in Australia, in the not too distant
      future.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_fxaih">
      <title>Blockage Types</title>

      <para>As previously noted, a blockage mechanism can be described by its
      type, its location and its timing and extents. With respect to type,
      there are three types of blockages that could occur:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>A top down blockage</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>occurs, when a floating debris raft builds up at the
            entrance to a structure, obstructing the inlet. This is a very
            dynamic type of blockage with the raft volume and elevation
            varying over time. These changes occur in response to both the
            flow rate and the difference between debris being added and lost
            from the raft as the blockage develops. On the flood recession
            this material may settle to fully block the inlet even though the
            inlet may have been only partly blocked by the raft at the flow
            peak. While rarely available, the temporal history of such a
            blockage, in an historic event, can be an important factor in
            realistically reproducing the actual flood behaviour at the
            blocked structure. While top down blockages are common in heavily
            vegetated areas, realistic simulation of this form of blockage is
            very complex.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>A bottom up blockage</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>occurs, when non-floating material is deposited at the inlet
            and/or in the barrel or waterway of the structure. This also is a
            dynamic type of blockage with sediment being both added and
            removed from the blockage as time passes. Because of the dynamic
            nature of this process, the debris apparent at the conclusion of
            the event may have little relationship to the debris level at any
            point in time during the event. As with the top down blockage, the
            temporal history of blockage in an historic event can be important
            in realistically reproducing actual flood behaviour during the
            event. Bottom up blockages are relatively common in steep lightly
            vegetated catchments with unstable stream banks or easily eroded
            stream beds. As the geometry of a bottom up blockage does not
            directly vary with flood stage (as in a top down blockage),
            hydraulic analysis of a bottom up blockage is more
            straightforward.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>A porous plug blockage</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>typically occurs when larger vegetative debris (often
            rapidly) bridges across the inlet of the structure covering the
            entire inlet but with sufficient porosity to allow some flow
            through the plug. It typically arises from a rapid bank or slope
            collapse, releasing a substantial pulse of vegetation and sediment
            into the stream. Unlike a top down or bottom up blockage, the
            porosity of this plug will likely only diminish as the event
            continues, with ever finer material being trapped on the bridging
            material that triggered the initial blockage. As blockage geometry
            does not vary with flood stage (as in a top down blockage),
            hydraulic analysis of a porous plug blockage is also more
            straightforward.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_duiq5">
      <title>Blockage Mechanisms</title>

      <para>While the number of possible blockage mechanisms is considerable,
      there appears to be a strong correlation between the dominant debris
      type arriving at a structure and the blockage mechanism it triggers.
      This correlation forms the basis of <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_ybym9"/>
      where the blockages ‘most likely’ location, timing and extents are
      described. It should be noted that this table is based heavily on
      limited observations and should be updated as further data becomes
      available.</para>

      <para>Progressive floating raft inlet blockages are assumed in this
      chapter to significantly impact flow through the structure only after
      the flow peaks (being mostly clear at higher flows as the raft lifts
      clear of the inlet and possibly overtops the structure. Pulse like
      blockages of floating material at an inlet mostly arise from vegetation
      injected into the stream from collapsing banks, as floodwater rise or
      from litter swept off the floodplain as streams overtop their banks.
      Neither of the above blockage types is likely to create a significant
      barrel/waterway or outlet blockage although non-floating debris, if
      present in any quantity can build up under the raft at the inlet and in
      the barrel, particularly as the flood recedes. It should be noted that
      factoring of 'all clear' flow will not necessarily provide a good
      estimate of the impact of either of these mechanism as both are inlet
      control mechanisms and the 'all clear' structure could be operating
      under strong outlet control.</para>

      <para>Non-floating material reaching a culvert or bridge will mostly
      build up progressively but can occur as a pulse of debris in streams
      with unstable banks. Typically, non-floating material (sediment) will
      build up throughout the structure (inlet, barrel and outlet) as
      increasing flows mobilise ever increasing amounts of bed and bank
      material. Material will be continuously lost from the accumulated debris
      mass, but the rate of supply is likely to exceed the rate at which
      material passes on downstream, at least while flows are increasing and
      new material is being mobilised.</para>

      <para>These observations and assumptions on the likely type, location
      and timing of a blockage are summarised in <xref
      linkend="b6_ch6_t_ybym9"/> In this table, the following designations are
      used to describe the timing of key trigger points in the blockage
      process.</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>T<subscript>TOTB/SA</subscript></term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Is the time when flow that first overtops the stream’s banks
            in the source area reaches the structure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>T<subscript>OT/F &amp; OT/L </subscript></term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Are the times when flow first and last overtops the
            structure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>T<subscript>P</subscript></term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Is the time at which the upstream water level peaks at the
            structure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>T<subscript>OBV/FL</subscript></term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Is the time on the falling limb when the upstream water
            level drops back to the obvert level of the structure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <table xml:id="b6_ch6_t_ybym9">
        <caption>Likely Blockage Timing and Extents</caption>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th rowspan="2">Dominant source material</th>

            <th rowspan="2">Delivery and Type</th>

            <th colspan="4">Likely Blockage Locations and Timings</th>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>Inlet</th>

            <th>Barrel</th>

            <th>Outlet<footnote>
                <para>Unlikely - but could become likely if inlet is open and
                outlet grated.</para>
              </footnote></th>

            <th>Handrails<footnote>
                <para>B<subscript>DES</subscript> is for the handrail geometry
                and will normally be much higher than for the culvert/bridge
                waterway as L<subscript>10</subscript> is likely to be much
                greater than the horizontal opening width/spacing of the
                balusters. In modelling B<subscript>DES</subscript> can be
                assumed at t=0 as the model will not apply handrail blockages
                until flow reaches the level of the handrails.</para>
              </footnote></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">FLOATING</td>

            <td>Progressive Top Down</td>

            <td>0 @ T<subscript>P</subscript> to B<subscript>DES</subscript> @
            T<subscript>OBV/FL</subscript></td>

            <td>Unlikely</td>

            <td>Unlikely</td>

            <td>B<subscript>DES</subscript> @ T<subscript>OT/F</subscript> to
            B<subscript>DES</subscript> @ &amp;
            <subscript>TOT/L</subscript></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Pulse Porous Plug</td>

            <td>B<subscript>DES</subscript> @
            T<subscript>OTB/SA</subscript></td>

            <td>N.A</td>

            <td>N.A</td>

            <td>B<subscript>DES</subscript> @ T<subscript>OT/F</subscript> to
            B<subscript>DES</subscript> @ &amp;
            T<subscript>OT/L</subscript></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">NON FLOATING</td>

            <td>Progressive Bottom Up</td>

            <td>0 @ T<subscript>OTB/SA </subscript>to
            B<subscript>DES</subscript> at T<subscript>P</subscript></td>

            <td>T<subscript>OTB/SA</subscript> to B<subscript>DES</subscript>
            at T<subscript>P</subscript></td>

            <td>T<subscript>OTB/SA</subscript> to B<subscript>DES</subscript>
            at T<subscript>P</subscript></td>

            <td>Unlikely</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Pulse<footnote xml:id="b6_ch6_fn_kjns3">
                <para>Pulse blockage is more likely in systems subject to
                irregular flooding and/or streams with unstable banks.</para>
              </footnote> Porous Plug</td>

            <td>Unlikely<footnote>
                <para>Unlikely – but could become likely if upstream bed/banks
                unstable and/or prone to scour.</para>
              </footnote></td>

            <td>N.A</td>

            <td>N.A</td>

            <td>Unlikely</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para>As previously noted in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_s_fxaih"/>, modelling
      the hydraulics of a progressively accumulating floating raft is quite
      complex as the blockage is not fixed in regard to its own geometry or in
      relation to the structure's opening geometry. While applying a blockage
      progressively from T<subscript>P</subscript> to
      T<subscript>OBV/FL</subscript> provides a reasonable approximation of
      when a floating blockage most impacts flow through a culvert or bridge
      that overtops, it does not sensibly reflect behaviour when floodwater
      carrying floating debris does not reach the obvert of the structure. In
      the absence of any better information it is recommended that a
      progressive top down blockage by floating debris that does not reach the
      structures obvert be initiated at T<subscript>OTB/SA</subscript> and
      ramped up to B<subscript>DES</subscript> at T<subscript>P</subscript>.
      It should also be noted that a floating raft creates a top down blockage
      only as a consequence of the projection of floating debris below its
      water surface. Relative to the structures opening height this projection
      will lift on the rising limb and fall on the falling limb creating a
      quite variable level of blockage of the structure itself during the
      event. Under such circumstances, blockage levels of the structure will
      be controlled by both the water depth and projection of the raft below
      the water level. Detailed simulation of such a process is however
      considered beyond the scope of this chapter. This chapter assumes that a
      top down blockage will be simplistically modelled by lowering the obvert
      of the structure over the tabulated time to then reflect the tabulated
      blockage level. Where the consequences of this form of blockage are
      high, and more realistic simulation is deemed necessary, it may be
      necessary to develop a site specific procedure. More information on this
      process can be found in Parola (2000), US DOTFHA (2005) and USGS
      (2013).</para>

      <para>While the temporal pattern of a structure's blockage when it
      blocks prior to the flood peak in a system with little flood storage
      will have minimal impact on downstream peak flows or upstream peak flood
      levels, it can substantially alter the duration that upstream flood
      levels are above a certain level (floor or structure overtopping) level.
      In a system with significant flood storage, the timing of a structure's
      blockage can significantly alter upstream peak flood level, downstream
      peak discharge and overtopping duration. Consideration of the temporal
      pattern of a blockage can therefore be extremely important in
      realistically simulating the hydraulic impact of a blockage.</para>

      <para>In establishing the key timings referred to in <xref
      linkend="b6_ch6_t_ybym9"/>, it will normally be necessary to first run a
      simulation with estimated blockage levels and timings in place.</para>

      <para>When modelling a historic event, hydraulic analysis will need to
      reflect (as far as available data permits) the actual blockage mechanism
      that developed at the structure during the event. It should be noted
      that this may vary significantly from what this chapter provides as the
      ‘most likely’ blockage scenario for the structure, such is the impact of
      near random chance on the many parameters influencing actual blockage.
      However, where data for multiple historic events is available and
      blockage appear to consistently differ from these chapter
      recommendations, further investigation is warranted, with historic data,
      if of reasonable quality, being given precedence.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_62sqq">
    <title>Management of Blockage</title>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_b1hbr">
      <title>Design Considerations</title>

      <para>Even though floodway crossings can be subject to blockage issues,
      by far the greatest attention is given to the management of blockage at
      culvert and bridge crossings.</para>

      <para>To minimise the adverse impacts of debris blockage on bridges the
      following design considerations should be given appropriate
      consideration:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Minimise the number of in-stream piers.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Minimise the exposure of services (i.e. water supply
          pipelines) on the upstream side of the bridge, and/or minimise the
          likelihood of debris being captured on exposed services.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>To minimise the effects of debris blockage on culverts the
      following design consideration should be noted:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Take all reasonable and practicable measures to maximise the
          clear height of the culvert, even if this results in the culvert
          hydraulic capacity exceeding the design standard. This minimises the
          likelihood of debris being caught between the water surface and
          obvert, and also minimises the risk of a person drowning if swept
          through the culvert (i.e. the culvert is more likely to be operating
          in a partially full condition).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The risk of debris blockage can also be reduced by using
          single-cell culverts, or in the case of floodplain culverts, spacing
          individual culvert cells such that they effectively operate as
          single-cell culverts without a common wall/leg (<xref
          linkend="b6_ch6_f_keoob"/> and <xref
          linkend="b6_ch6_f_5qmka"/>).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="b6_ch6_f_keoob">
        <title>Series of Floodplain Culverts</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6049.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b6_ch6_f_5qmka">
        <title>Floodplain Culvert</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6050.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>One means of maintaining the hydraulic capacity of culverts in
          high debris streams is to construct debris deflector walls (1V:2H)
          as shown in <xref linkend="b6_ch6_f_slvzr"/> and <xref
          linkend="b6_ch6_f_95iwr"/>. The purpose of these walls is to allow
          the debris that normally collects around the central leg to rise
          with the flood, thus maintaining a relatively clear flow path under
          the debris. Following the flood peak, the bulk of the debris rests
          at the top of the deflector wall allowing easier removal (<xref
          linkend="b6_ch6_f_k26o2"/>).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="b6_ch6_f_slvzr">
        <title>Debris Deflector Walls</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6051.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b6_ch6_f_k26o2">
        <title>Post Flood Collection of Debris on Top of Deflector
        Walls</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6052.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sedimentation problems within culverts may be managed using
          one or more of the following activities:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Formation of an in-stream sedimentation pond or trap
              upstream of the culvert.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Formation of a multi-cell culvert with variable invert
              levels such that the profile of the base slab simulates the
              natural cross section of the channel (<xref
              linkend="b6_ch6_f_vqn94"/>).</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Installation of sediment training walls on the culvert
              inlet (<xref linkend="b6_ch6_f_slvzr"/> and <xref
              linkend="b6_ch6_f_95iwr"/>). Sediment training walls reduce the
              risk of sedimentation of the outer cells by restricting minor
              flows to just one or two cells.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="b6_ch6_f_95iwr">
        <title>Sediment Training Walls Incorporated with Debris Deflector
        Walls (Catchments &amp; Creeks Pty Ltd)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/6053.jpg"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b6_ch6_f_vqn94">
        <title>Multi-Cell Culvert with Different Invert Levels</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6054.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b6_ch6_f_q3e0m">
        <title>Debris Deflector Walls and Sediment Training Wall Added to
        Existing Culvert</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6055.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Where space allows, a viable alternative to increased culvert
          capacity (in response to the effects of debris blockage) may be to
          lengthen the roadway subject to overflow (i.e. the effective
          causeway weir length).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Where high levels of floating debris are present and
          frequently become trapped on hand rails, collapsible hand rails may
          be considered. Such systems typically include pins or bolts designed
          to fail when water becomes backed up by the handrails and therefore
          require ongoing maintenance. If used as traffic barriers the
          downstream rail fixing can be problematic. They can however limit
          rises in floodwater levels upstream of the structure.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_96t4h">
      <title>Retro-fitting Existing Structures</title>

      <para>Structures can be modified to allow debris to be directed through
      the structure with a reduced risk of blockage. These modifications can
      include improved inlet performance through the use of debris deflection
      walls and/or sediment training walls (<xref linkend="b6_ch6_f_q3e0m"/>)
      or an increase in the size of the structure.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_67s7h">
      <title>Debris control structures</title>

      <para>Debris control structures or traps are structural measures
      provided in a watercourse upstream of critical structures to collect
      debris before it reaches the structure and causes problems. These can be
      (a) fences, posts or rails providing a much larger ‘interception area’
      for debris than a pipe or culvert entrance, (b) storages or dry basins
      in which boulders or other debris can collect, or (c) diversion
      structures designed to provide safe bypass of debris or water. Such
      structures can occasionally be incorporated into a water quality
      management plan for a catchment.</para>

      <para>Where debris control structures or at-source control measures have
      been implemented, these should be incorporated into the assessment of
      the drainage system, which could mean a reduction in the allowance that
      needs to be made for blockage. Ongoing maintenance is however
      fundamental to the successful operation of these measures. Unless a
      deliberate maintenance program is in place and has been demonstrated to
      work, it would not be prudent to lower design blockage levels.as a
      consequence of such works.</para>

      <para>Care should also be taken to ensure that the hydraulic impact of
      the debris control structure does not itself aggravate flooding in the
      system.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_fgjqf">
    <title>Conclusion</title>

    <para>The inclusion of blockage in the analysis of hydraulic structures in drainage systems is
      an important consideration in the realistic simulation of flood behaviour. The impact of
      blockage is however a complex and difficult problem to analyse. It is important to ensure that
      the estimate of blockage used in analysis is probability neutral and not over or
      under-estimated as this can influence the performance of the total system. This chapter has
      presented an approach to the assessment of design blockage that has been developed in
      consultation with Australian experts and provides a consistent and logical approach to assist
      in the effective planning and design of drainage systems. Future investigation will refine
      this approach.</para>

    <para>For further information on the background to this chapter, readers
    are referred to the following bibliography.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b6_ch6_s_g4ivu">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Barthelmess, A. and E. Rigby (2009) Quantification of Debris
    Potential and Evolution of a Regional Culvert Blockage Model, H2009 - 32nd
    Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Newcastle NSW, November.</para>

    <para>Boyd, M, E. Rigby, S. Roso, P. Silveri and A. Davis (2002) Causes
    and Effects of Culvert Blockage During Large Storms, 9th International
    Conference on Urban Drainage, Portland Oregon, September.</para>

    <para>Braudrick, C. and Grant, G., 2001. Transport and deposition of large
    woody debris in streams: A flume experiment: Geomorphology, 41:
    263-284.</para>

    <para>Braudrick, C. and Grant, G. E., 2000. When do logs move in rivers:
    Water Resources Research, 36(2): 571-584.</para>

    <para>CIRIA (2010) Culvert design and operation guide. CIRIA Report C689,
    CIRIA, London.</para>

    <para>Denver Urban Drainage and Flood Control District (2001, revised
    2008) Urban Storm Drainage Criteria Manual, 3 Volumes, Denver, Colorado
    (http://www.udfcd.org/downloads/down_critmanual.htm)</para>

    <para>Diehl, T.H., (1997) Potential Drift Accumulation at Bridges,
    FHWA-RD-97-28, U.S.</para>

    <para>Department of Transportation, Federal Highway Administration,
    Washington, D.C. Department of Natural Resources &amp; Water, (2007).
    Queensland Urban Drainage Manual. 2nd edition, Department of Natural
    Resources &amp; Water, Institute of Public Works Engineering Australia,
    Queensland Division Ltd. and Brisbane City Council, Brisbane,
    Australia.</para>

    <para>New South Wales Government (2005). Floodplain Development Manual,
    Sydney.</para>

    <para>A.C Parola (2000) Debris Forces on Highway Bridge Issue 445,
    Prepared by the U.S. Transport Research Board of the National Research
    Council Queensland Department of Natural Resources and Water (2008)</para>

    <para>Queensland Urban Drainage Manual, 2nd Edition, Brisbane.</para>

    <para>Roso, S., M. Boyd, E. Rigby and R. VanDrie (2004) Prediction of
    Increased Flooding in Urban Catchments due to Debris Blockage and Flow
    Diversions, Proceedings Novatech 2004, Lyon France, July 2004.</para>

    <para>Rigby E.H., Boyd M.J., Roso S., Silveri P. and Davis, A (2002).
    Causes and Effects of Culvert Blockage during Large Storms. 9th
    International Conference on Urban Drainage, Eric W. Strecker, Wayne C.
    Huber, Editors, Portland, Oregon, USA, September 8–13, 2002.</para>

    <para>Rigby, E.H. and Barthelmess, A.J. (2011), Culvert Blockage
    Mechanisms and their Impact on Flood Behaviour 34th World Congress of the
    International Association for Hydro-Environment Engineering and Research
    (IAHR) 26 June – 1 July, 2011.</para>

    <para>Rigby, E.H. and Silveri, P. (2001). The Impact of Blockages on Flood
    Behavior in the Wollongong Storm of August 1998. Conference on Hydraulics
    in Civil Engineering, Hobart 28-30 November 2001.</para>

    <para>Rigby E.H., Boyd M.J., Roso S., Silveri P. and Davis, A., (2002)
    Causes and Effects of Culvert Blockage during Large Storms. 9th
    International Conference on Urban Drainage, Eric W. Strecker, Wayne C.
    Huber, Editors Portland, Oregon, USA, September 8–13, 2002.</para>

    <para>U.S. Department of Transportation Federal Highway Administration,
    (2005). Debris Control Structures - Evaluation and Countermeasures.
    (DOTFHA) Hydraulic Engineering Circular No. 9 Third Edition, 2005.
    Publication No. FHWA-IF-04-016.</para>

    <para>U.S. Federal Highway Administration (2009) Urban Drainage Design
    Manual, Hydraulic Engineering Circular No. 22, 3rd Edition, (S. A. Brown,
    J.D. Schall, J.L. Morris, C.L. Doherty, S. M Stein and J.C. Warner),
    National Highway Institute, Arlington, VA and FHWA Office of Bridges,
    Washington.</para>

    <para>Sundborg, A., 1956, The River Klarålven: Chapter 2. The
    morphological activity of flowing water—erosion of the stream bed:
    Geografiska Annaler, v. 38, p. 165-221.</para>

    <para>U.S. Geological Survey (2013) Potential Drift Accumulation at
    Bridges. URL: http://tn.water.usgs.gov
    /pubs/FHWA-RD-97-028/accumwid.htm</para>

    <para>Van Dine, D. F., (1996). Debris flow control structures for forest
    engineering. Res. Br., B.C. Min. For., Victoria, B.C., Work. Pap.
    08/1996.</para>

    <para>Wallerstein, N. and Thorne, C.R., (1996). Debris Control at
    Hydraulic Structures – Management of Woody Debris in Natural Channels and
    at Hydraulic Structures. U.S. Corps of Engineers, Waterways Experiment
    Station.</para>

    <para>Weeks, (2009). Project 11: Blockage of Hydraulic Structures.
    Engineers Australia, Water Engineering, ACT.</para>

    <para>Weeks, W, A. Barthelmess, T. Rigby, G. Witheridge and R. Adamson,
    (2009), “Blockage in Drainage Structures”, Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium, Engineers Australia, Newcastle.</para>

    <para>Wollongong City Council (2009). Wollongong DCP 2009- Chapter E14,
    Wollongong City Council.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
