<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b1_ch2"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Fundamental Issues</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml"/>
  </info>

  <para>Real content needs to be inserted here.</para>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Th<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T180748+1100"?>is
    <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T180745+1100" content="e first "?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T180756+1100"?>chapter<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T180757+1100" content="section"?>
    <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181100+1100" content="needs to "?>introduce<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181107+1100"?>s<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    the concepts of probability and statistics with respect to flood
    estimation<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181120+1100"?>
    including the <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181124+1100" content=". Included in this discussion needs to be the "?>concepts
    of A<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181132+1100"?>nnual
    Exceedance <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181136+1100" content="E"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181142+1100"?>Probability
    (AEP)<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181153+1100" content="P"?>
    and E<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181210+1100"?>xceedances
    per <?oxy_insert_end ?>Y<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181215+1100"?>ear
    (EY)<?oxy_insert_end ?> and how they relate to statistics.<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181225+1100" content=" Risk concepts need to be included in this section but the extent needs to be determined."?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T211433+1100"?>
    Recommended probability terminology is presented. The chapter also
    discusses the difference between design and actual events, conversion of
    rainfall of a given probability to a flood of the same probability,
    closure of service routes, risk and dealing with uncertainty in flood
    estimates.<?oxy_insert_end ?></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Terminology</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_vt33jid">
      <title>Background</title>

      <para>Probability concepts are fundamental to design flood estimation.
      <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181243+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181240+1100" content="Furthermore, t"?>he
      terminology used is important if the aim is for effective communication
      of design flood estimates. Terms commonly used in the past have included
      "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence interval</emphasis>", "<emphasis
      role="italic">return period</emphasis>", and various terms involving
      "<emphasis role="italic">probability</emphasis>". It is common for these
      terms to be used in a loose manner, and sometimes quite incorrectly.
      This has resulted in misinterpretation by the profession, the general
      community impacted by floods, and other stakeholders.</para>

      <para>In considering the terminology that should be used in this edition
      of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, the National Committee on Water
      Engineering<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182012+1100"?>'s<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182010+1100" content=" had"?>
      three major concerns<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181308+1100" content=";"?>
      <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182016+1100" content="namely"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181306+1100"?>were:<?oxy_insert_end ?></para>

      <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
          <para>Clarity of meaning;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Technical correctness; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Practicality and acceptability.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_xe7xl">
      <title>Clarity of Meaning</title>

      <para>Use of the terms "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence
      interval</emphasis>" and "<emphasis role="italic">return
      period</emphasis>" has been criticised as leading to confusion in the
      minds of some decision-makers and members of the public. Although the
      terms are simple superficially, they are misinterpreted regularly as
      implying that the associated event magnitude is only exceeded at regular
      intervals, and that they are referring to the elapsed time till the next
      exceedance. This misinterpretation of the terms used for expressing
      probabilities of flood magnitudes can be misleading and result in poor
      decisions.</para>

      <para>It is believed that irrespective of the terms used, that it is
      critical that all stakeholders have a common interpretation of the
      terms. Furthermore, it is believed that it is important that
      stakeholders understand that the terms refer to long term averages. This
      means, for a given climatic environment, that the probability of an
      event of a given magnitude being equalled or exceeded in a given period
      of time (for example, one year) is unchanged throughout the life of the
      structure or the drainage network. Furthermore, it is not uncommon for
      more than one occurrence of an event to occur in a single year.</para>

      <para>Additionally, given the wet and dry phases that occur in many
      regions of Australia, these events are likely to be clustered in time.
      The occurrence of these wet and dry climatic phases highlight the
      misleading and inappropriate interpretation that flood events occur at
      regular intervals as implied by "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence
      interval</emphasis>" and "<emphasis role="italic">return
      period</emphasis>”.</para>

      <para>Flood events generally are random occurrences, and the period
      between exceedances of a given value usually is a random variate, the
      properties of which are assumed to be constant in time for a given
      location and climatic environment. The adopted terminology reflects this
      fundamental concept and is intended to convey a clear and precise
      interpretation.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_ijnsl">
      <title>Technical Correctness</title>

      <para>In view of the loose and frequently incorrect manner in which
      probability terms are often used, it was considered that Australian
      Rainfall and Runoff should adopt terminology that is technically
      correct, as far as this is possible and in harmony with other
      objectives. Additionally, even if this is not entirely popular with all
      <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182038+1100" content="users"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182038+1100"?>practitioners<?oxy_insert_end ?>,
      Engineers Australia has a responsibility to encourage and educate
      engineers regarding correct terminology.</para>

      <para>The two approaches used when describing probabilities of flood
      events in previous editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff
      were:</para>

      <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
          <para><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181659+1100" type="surround"?><emphasis><?oxy_insert_end ?>Annual
          Exceedance Probability (AEP) </emphasis>- the probability of an
          event being equalled or exceeded within a year. Typically the AEP is
          estimated by extracting the annual maximum in each year to produce
          an Annual Maxima Series (AMS); and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181703+1100" type="surround"?><emphasis><?oxy_insert_end ?>Average
          Recurrence Interval (ARI) </emphasis>- the average time period
          between occurrences equalling or exceeding a given value. Usually
          the ARI is derived from a Peak over Threshold series (PoTs) where
          every value over a chosen threshold is extracted from the period of
          record.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Details of AMS and PoTs and the background to these alternative
      techniques for extracting flood series from recorded data are presented
      in <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T181757+1100" comment="dont think this reference right
"?>Chapter 2 of Book 1<?oxy_comment_end ?> of Australian Rainfall and Runoff.
      Included in this discussion are the assumptions necessary for conversion
      of one probability terminology to the other using the Langbein formula
      (Langbein, 1949).</para>

      <para>Using the Langbein formula, in probability terms, there is little
      practical difference for events rarer than 10% AEP. Historically,
      however, there has been a reluctance to convert from the approach used
      for derivation of the design flood estimate. Furthermore, terminology
      was attached to particular design flood estimation techniques; for
      example, when AMS were used to derive design flood estimates, the
      resultant probability was expressed as an AEP while when a PoTS was used
      for the same purpose, the resultant probability was expressed as an
      ARI.</para>

      <para>In many situations, this distinction between an ARI and an AEP was
      imprecise as the design flood prediction methodology adopted did not
      explicitly note use of either an AMS or a PoTS in the methodology. As a
      result, use of ARI and AEP was considered to be interchangeable. This
      interchangeable use often resulted in confusion.</para>

      <para>The National Committee on Water Engineering believes that within
      Australian Rainfall and Runoff a terminology should be used which, while
      being technically correct, is consistent with other uses. Furthermore,
      the terminology adopted should be easily understood both by the
      profession and by other stakeholders within the community.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_c6s8d">
      <title>Practicality and Acceptability</title>

      <para>The National Committee on Water Engineering is aware that while
      the terminology adopted must be technically correct it must also be
      relatively simple and suitable for use in practice. Terminology that
      meets this criterion will be accepted by the profession and by other
      stakeholders.</para>

      <para>A change from the terminology adopted in the 1987 Edition of
      Australian Rainfall and Runoff has been deemed necessary as some
      confusion still exists with regard to the interpretation of certain
      terminology. This confusion exists both within the profession and within
      the community and other stakeholders.</para>

      <para>The interaction of the profession with the community and the
      increased public participation in decision making means that terminology
      needs to be clear not only to the profession but also to the community
      and other stakeholders, other professions involved in flood management,
      and to the managers of flood-prone land. This need has resulted in a
      strong move for a clear and unambiguous terminology by the National
      Committee on Water Engineering of Engineers Australia and the National
      Flood Risk Advisory Group (NFRAG<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182414+1100"?>,
      <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182415+1100" content="): NFRAG is "?>a
      reference group under the Australian and New Zealand Emergency
      Management Committee<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182454+1100"?>)<?oxy_insert_end ?>.
      All parties believe that terminology involving annual percentage
      probability best conveys the likelihood of flooding and is less open to
      misinterpretation by the public.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_aona4">
      <title>Adopted Terminology</title>

      <para>The term x year ARI and 1 in x AEP has caused confusion both
      within the industry and with the community and other stakeholders. It
      has been interpreted by many to imply<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183206+1100" content=" that"?>
      the periods between exceedances of a given event magnitude.</para>

      <para>To mitigate this confusion, the National Committee on Water
      Engineering has decided to adopt the terms shown in <xref
      linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/> and the suggested <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182524+1100" content="usage"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182524+1100"?>frequency
      indicators<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T182539+1100" content=" as indicated in that table"?>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="arr_pref_term_table">
        <title>Australian Rainfall and Runoff Preferred Terminology</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1044.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Navy outline indicates preferred terminology. Shading indicates
      acceptable terminology which is depends on the typical use in the far
      right column. For example in floodplain management 0.5% AEP might be
      used while in dam design this event would be described as a 1 in 200
      AEP.</para>

      <para>As shown in <xref linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/>, the term Annual
      Exceedance Probability (AEP) where AEP expresses the probability of an
      event being equalled or exceeded in any year. Additionally, AEP are to
      be expressed using percentage probability; for example, the 1% AEP
      design flood discharge. However, their will be situations where the use
      of percentage probability is not practicable; expression of extreme
      flood probabilities associated with dam spillways are one example of a
      situation where percentage probability is not appropriate. In these
      cases, it is recommended that the probability be expressed as 1 in X AEP
      where 100/X would be the equivalent percentage probability.</para>

      <para>For more frequent events an annualised exceedance probability is
      misleading and confusing. Furthermore, a recurrence interval approach
      also is misleading where strong seasonality is experienced. An example
      of strong seasonality is where the rainfall occurs predominately during
      the Summer or Winter period and as a consequence flood flows are more
      likely to occur during that period. As a result, when strong seasonality
      exists, calculating a design flood flow with a 3 month recurrence
      interval is of limited value as the expectation of the time period
      between occurrences will not be consistent throughout the year. For
      example, a flow with the magnitude of a 3 month recurrence interval
      would be expected to occur or be exceeded 4 times a year; however, in
      situations where there is strong seasonality in the rainfall, all of the
      occurrences are likely to occur in the domina<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183423+1100" content="te"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183425+1100"?>nt<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      season.</para>

      <para>Consequently, events more frequent than 50% AEP should be
      expressed as X Exceedances per Year (EY). For example, 2 EY is
      equivalent to a design event with a 6 month recurrence interval when
      there is no seasonality in flood occurrence.</para>

      <para>An additional consideration in reducing the confusion is that
      different users of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, in general, will use
      different segments of the relationship between flood magnitude and
      exceedance probability. As the desire is to reduce confusion, switching
      between different terminologies within an industry segment will not
      reduce confusion but rather increase the confusion. Hence, while the
      recommended terminology for alternative frequencies is presented in
      <xref linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/>, it is recognised that usage may
      differ from the suggestions shown in <xref
      linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/>.</para>

      <para><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183517+1100"?>These
      expressions of estimated frequencies relate to the particular time
      period for which they have been determined and ttherefore with
      <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183535+1100" content="Finally, it should be noted that "?>no
      consideration <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183545+1100" content="has been "?>given
      to the long term effects of climatic chang<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183553+1100"?>e<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183551+1100" content="e in developing this terminology"?>.
      Nonetheless, the adopted terminology is considered to be equally
      applicable to both stationary and non-stationary climatic environments
      as there is no requirement for the annual exceedance probabilities to be
      constant over time. <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183609+1100" content="In other words, t"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183611+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end ?>here
      is no requirement for a given flood characteristic magnitude to maintain
      a given AEP over different years or, conversely, for a given AEP to
      maintain a constant flood characteristic magnitude over different
      years.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Difference Between Design Events and Actual Events</title>

    <para><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183857+1100" type="surround"?><emphasis
    role="bold"><?oxy_insert_end ?>Taken from 1987:</emphasis></para>

    <para>Much confusion has resulted from lack of recognition of the
    fundamental differences between these two types of flood estimation
    problems. Although the same mathematical procedures may be involved in
    both cases, the implications and assumptions involved, and the validity of
    application, are quite different. <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183917+1100" content="As noted in Section 1.1.4, t"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183919+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end ?>he
    emphasis in this document is<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T183922+1100"?>
    largely<?oxy_insert_end ?> on design floods.</para>

    <para>A design flood is a probabilistic or statistical estimate, being
    generally based on some form of probability analysis of flood or rainfall
    data. An <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184132+1100" content="average recurrence interval or"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184132+1100"?>Annual<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184141+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184140+1100" content="e"?>xceedance
    <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184143+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184143+1100" content="p"?>robability
    is attributed to the estimate. This applies not only to normal routine
    design, but also to probable maximum estimates, where the intention is to
    obtain a design value with an extremely low probability of exceedance. If
    a design rainfall is used in the estimation of a flood, it is not intended
    to imply that if a rainfall of that amount occurred at a given time, the
    estimated flood would result. Occurrence of the rainfall when the
    catchment was wet might result in a very large flood of magnitude greater
    than the design estimate, while occurrence of the rainfall when the
    catchment was dry might result in relatively little, or even no, runoff.
    For the design situation, the conditions are not known and must be
    assumed, often implicitly in the design values that are adopted.</para>

    <para>The approach to estimating an actual <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184229+1100"?>(or
    historic) <?oxy_insert_end ?>flood from a <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151127T113101+1100" content="sectioni"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151127T113101+1100"?>parti<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T184212+1100" comment="????????"?>cular
    <?oxy_comment_end ?>rainfall is quite different in concept and is of a
    deterministic nature. All causes and effects require consideration. The
    actual antecedent conditions prevailing at the time of occurrence of the
    rain are very important and must be allowed for in estimation of the
    resulting flood. No real information is given regarding the probability of
    the estimated flood.</para>

    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>

    <para>Although the differences in these two types of problems are often
    not recognised, they have three important practical consequences. The
    first is that a <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151127T113125+1100" content="section"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151127T113125+1100"?>part<?oxy_insert_end ?>icular
    procedure may be good or satisfactory for one case, but quite unsuitable
    for the other. For example, the Rational Method using the probabilistic
    interpretation (Book IV Section 1.3.2) can be a very satisfactory approach
    for estimating design floods for small to medium sized catchments, but is
    not satisfactory for estimating the flood resulting from a given rainfall
    (French et al., 1974).<?oxy_custom_end ?></para>

    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>

    <para>The second concerns the manner in which values of parameters are
    derived from recorded data, and the manner in which designers regard these
    values and apply them. If actual floods are to be estimated, values for
    use in the calculations should be derived from calibration on individual
    observed events. If design floods are to be estimated, the values should
    be derived from statistical analyses of data from many observed floods.
    For example, if the runoff coefficient in the Rational Method is to be
    used to estimate floods resulting from actual rainfalls, values would have
    to be derived as the ratio of flood peak to observed rainfall intensity in
    individual floods. However for the design case, coefficients should be
    derived as the ratio of values taken from frequency analyses of peak
    discharge and rainfall intensity.</para>

    <para>The third practical consequence concerns the manner in which
    parameters are viewed by designers and analysts. For example, the common
    visualisation of the runoff coefficient as the fraction of rainfall that
    runs off is correct in the very unusual case where the Rational Method is
    used to estimate an actual flood, but this concept is incorrect and
    fundamentally misleading in the usual case where a design flood is to be
    estimated. These particular examples are discussed further in Book IV
    Section 1.3.2<?oxy_custom_end ?></para>

    <para/>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Flood Concepts</title>

    <para/>

    <section>
      <title>Conversion of Rainfall of a Given Probability to a Flood of the
      Same Probability</title>

      <para><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T185131+1100" type="surround"?><emphasis
      role="bold"><?oxy_insert_end ?>From 1987:</emphasis></para>

      <para>In many applications of design flood estimation, the intention is
      to derive a flood of selected probability of exceedance from a design
      rainfall of the same probability. However, each section of the design
      model introduces some joint probability, resulting in the fundamental
      problem that the true probability of the derived flood may be obscure,
      and its magnitude may be biased with respect to the true flood magnitude
      with the same probability as the design rainfall, especially at the low
      probabilities of interest in design.</para>

      <para>Three approaches have been used in Australian practice to deal
      with this problem:</para>

      <para><orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
          <listitem>
            <para>Use of median values of variables other than rainfall depth.
            Use of extreme values of losses, baseflow, temporal pattern of
            rainfall and hydrograph model parameters would be likely to
            convert the design rainfall of selected probability to a flood
            with much lower probability. For each of the variables that
            contribute to the flood estimate, the probability of occurrence of
            a value higher than the median is the same as that of a value
            lower than the median. While rigorous proof is not possible, use
            of median values is likely to lead to a flood estimate of similar
            probability to that of the design rainfall. In some regions,
            seasonality of values may need to be considered. This approach has
            been used as a basis for much of the design data in this
            <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T190345+1100" content="document"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T190346+1100"?>guideline<?oxy_insert_end ?>.
            <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>There
            is a need for research to test this approach. <?oxy_custom_end ?>“Worst”
            values of design parameters have sometimes been used to provide
            some conservatism in design. Examples are high runoff
            coefficients, the lowest derived loss rate,<?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
            or the highest peak of derived unit hydrographs.<?oxy_custom_end ?>
            This results in a flood estimate with a probability of exceedance
            lower than that of the design rainfall but of unknown value. If
            more conservative design is required, it is better to select a
            lower design probability, and then use median values of all other
            relevant variables to estimate the flood of that
            probability.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Derivation of design relations or data from comparison of
            values of the same probability obtained from frequency analyses of
            observed floods and rainfalls. The effects of other variables are
            automatically taken care of by this approach, as the flood of
            selected probability is directly linked with the rainfall of the
            same probability. T<?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>he
            probabilistic interpretation of the Rational Method (Book IV
            Section 1.3.2) is the best example of this approach, but it can
            also be used to determine design values of other
            variables.<?oxy_custom_end ?> Some of the design data in this
            <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T190607+1100" content="document"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T190607+1100"?>guideline<?oxy_insert_end ?>
            have been derived using this approach.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Consideration of the joint probabilities of the variables
            contributing to the flood discharge. The stochastic nature of the
            variables can be incorporated into the flood estimate by means of
            transition probability matrices, or a large number of simulations
            using values drawn randomly from assumed probability distributions
            of the variables. While this approach is theoretically superior to
            the two described previously, uncertainty at the low probabilities
            of interest in design is increased by lack of definition of the
            tails of the several probability distributions involved. This type
            of approach was developed by Beran and Sutcliffe (1972) and Beran
            (1973) for the UK Flood Studies Report (Natural Environment
            Research Council 1975).<?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
            Although the approach has not been used in developing any of the
            design data in this document, it is recommended as an attractive
            design approach where the work involved is warranted. The method
            is capable of further development. Some Australian applications
            are described by Laurenson (1973, 1974), Ahern and Weinmann
            (1982), Gutteridge Haskins and Davey (1982) and Goyen
            (1983).<?oxy_custom_end ?><?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T190832+1100" comment="modern references?"?></para>

            <?oxy_comment_end ?>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>

      <para/>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Expected Probability</title>

      <para><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T190839+1100" type="surround"?><emphasis
      role="bold"><?oxy_insert_end ?>From 1987:</emphasis></para>

      <para>Estimates of probabilities and of population frequency
      distributions from recorded data samples are always biased as a result
      of the relatively short length of record and hence small sample size.
      For a given event magnitude, the ARI is overestimated or the AEP is
      underestimated. If the estimate involves little or no extrapolation of
      the observed range of data, and especially if the skew is small, the
      effect of bias is small. However, if extrapolation is required and high
      skews are involved, the bias can be large. <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>The
      problem of, and methods for, obtaining unbiased estimates of the
      population probabilities (which are generally termed “expected
      probabilities”) are discussed, for example, in Beard (1960), Hardison
      and Jennings (1972), Doran and Irish (1980), Bulletin 17B of the
      Interagency Advisory Committee on Water Data (1982), and Pescod and
      Canterford (1985). <?oxy_custom_end ?></para>

      <para><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>The
      problem has been largely ignored in Australian practice in the past.
      <?oxy_custom_end ?>However, sound design requires that bias should be
      eliminated where possible. <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>In
      view of the long records of rainfall and their relatively low skews, a
      decision was made in conjunction with the Bureau of Meteorology that the
      effect of expected probabilities would not be incorporated in the
      derivation of the design rainfall data in Book II Section 1 for ARIs up
      to 100 years. <?oxy_custom_end ?>The effects for flood frequency
      analysis are greater, and these are considered explicitly as
      <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>discussed
      in Book IV Section 2.6. Suggestions are made of design situations where
      corrections for expected probability should be made, and of those where
      no correction should be made.<?oxy_custom_end ?></para>
    </section>

    <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T212655+1100" content="&lt;section&gt;&lt;title&gt;Probability of Failure of Works Involving a Series of Structures&lt;/title&gt;&lt;para&gt;&lt;emphasis role=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;From 1987:&lt;/emphasis&gt;&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;With a railway or major road, flooding of any one stream crossing will cause closure of the route. The item of real interest is the probability of this closure, and not of failure at any sectionicular site. This probability of closure will be much greater than that at an individual site. Closure of the route at any site may cause major disruption and economic losses. &lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;This problem has received little recognition in Australia, but the approaches used to provide solutions for iron ore railways of high economic importance in the Pilbara region of Western Australia are described by Ribeny (1971), Fricke et al (1983) and Netchaef (1983), as discussed in Book III Section 1.6.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/section&gt;"?>
  </section>

  <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T212227+1100"?>

  <section>
    <title>Risk</title>

    <para>Floods can cause significant impacts where they interact with the
    community and the supporting natural and built environment. However,
    flooding also has the potential to be the most manageable natural disaster
    as the likelihood and consequences of the full range of flood events can
    be understood enabling risks to be assessed and where necessary managed.
    Risk and design flood estimation is discussed in detail in<emphasis
    role="bold"><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
    Section 1.5.<?oxy_custom_end ?></emphasis></para>

    <para/>

    <section>
      <title>Probability of Failure of Works Involving a Series of
      Structures</title>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">From 1987:</emphasis></para>

      <para>With a railway or major road, flooding of any one stream crossing
      will cause closure of the route. The item of real interest is the
      probability of this closure, and not of failure at any particular site.
      This probability of closure will be much greater than that at an
      individual site. Closure of the route at any site may cause major
      disruption and economic losses. <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?></para>

      <para>This problem has received little recognition in Australia, but the
      approaches used to provide solutions for iron ore railways of high
      economic importance in the Pilbara region of Western Australia are
      described by Ribeny (1971), Fricke et al (1983) and Netchaef (1983), as
      discussed in Book III Section 1.6.<?oxy_custom_end ?></para>

      <para>This is discussed in detail in <emphasis
      role="bold"><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>SECTION
      1.<?oxy_custom_end ?>5</emphasis></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>The Importance of Data</title>

    <para>Data is fundamental to flood estimation. Data is needed to
    understand the processes and to ensure that models are accurate and
    reflect the real world issues being analysed. Flood estimation primarily
    uses data that describes the rainfall, water levels and streamflow. The
    procedures and guidelines presented in ARR could not have been developed
    without historical data, and often the reliability of the methods
    presented depends on the extent of data that has been used in
    development.</para>

    <para>For the first time, ARR has been based completely on Australian data
    to better reflect Australia’s variable landscape, including a national
    database of extreme flood hazards. A major task of the current ARR update
    was assembling national databases of rainfall and streamflow data for
    developing inputs and methodologies. ARR 1987 used 600 pluviographs
    rainfall gauge (measures the amount of rainfall which fell) with greater
    than 6 years data and 7500 daily rainfall gauges with over 30 years
    record. ARR 2015 uses almost 30 years of extra rainfall and streamflow
    data. ARR 2016 used over 2200 pluviographs and over 8000 daily rainfall
    gauges. Over 900 streamflow gauges were analysed. Over 100, 000 storm
    events were analysed. This data provides a valuable resource for the
    development of future methodologies.</para>

    <para>Major improvements have been made to design flood estimation methods
    but national databases will allow the use and parameterisation of more
    complex methods. Major advances will continue that will allow us to
    leverage the limited data we can afford to collect on the continent
    nation. Many projects have opened the eyes of researchers and
    practitioners on what could be done with more time, money and the limited
    data available. The data sets developed as part of this update should be
    enhanced and used for future improvements.</para>

    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>

    <para>Section xxx <?oxy_custom_end ?>provides a summary the types of data
    used for flood estimation.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Climate Change</title>

    <para>ARR 1987 (Pilgrim,1987) while acknowledging climate change did not
    address climate change or non-stationarity or provide guidance on the
    inclusion of climate change impacts in flood estimation. One key aim of
    this edition was the incorporation of the best available information of
    climate change impacts on flooding.</para>

    <para>This edition of ARR funded research projects which investigated:How
    climate change will affect flooding and the factors influencing flooding;
    How to incorporate climate change into the investigation methodologies
    used by the engineering profession to estimate design floods;Updating of
    the methodology in Australian Rainfall and Runoff so that the outcomes
    from climate change research (eg. regional dynamic downscaling) can be
    incorporated easily into the investigation methodology as the science and
    results become available.</para>

    <para>The impacts of climate change on design flood estimation is
    discussed in detail in <emphasis role="bold"><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Section
    1.7<?oxy_custom_end ?>.</emphasis> More detail can be found in the
    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>ARR
    Climate Change Research Plan and ARR Project 1: Climate Change Synthesis
    report. <?oxy_custom_end ?></para>

    <section>
      <title>Climate change impacts on flooding</title>

      <para>Global warming has been observed over several decades, and has
      been linked to changes in the large-scale hydrological cycle including
      increasing atmospheric water vapour content; changing precipitation
      patterns, intensity and extremes; changes in soil moisture and runoff;
      and increasing melting of snow and ice (Bates et al., 2008).There is
      increasing evidence that human-induced climate change is changing
      precipitation extremes, and that extreme flooding globally has increased
      over the 20th century (Trenberth, 2011). There is confidence that these
      changes in the hydrological cycle will lead to increased variability in
      precipitation and increased frequency of flood events over many areas
      (IPCC 2007, Bates et al. 2008). Changes in climate will result in
      changes in the frequency, intensity, spatial extent, duration, and
      timing of extreme weather and climate events, and may lead to
      unprecedented extreme weather and climate events (IPCC, 2012).</para>

      <para>The major areas where climate change will impact flooding
      are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Design rainfall intensity-frequency-duration;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Storm type, frequency, and depth;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Rainfall spatial and temporal patterns;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Antecedent conditions;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Changes in sea level and;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The joint probability of storm surge and flood producing
          rainfall.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <section>
        <title>Climate Change Impacts on Rainfall</title>

        <para>Changes in extremes events, such as floods, can be linked to
        changes in the mean, variance, or shape of probability distributions,
        or all of these (IPCC, 2012). For example, climate change projections
        have shown that a relatively small shift in the distribution of
        precipitation may result in a large change in the frequency and
        magnitude of extreme precipitation events (Nicholls and Alexander,
        2007). Studies have shown that a change in the shape of the
        distribution of precipitation is likely to have a greater effect on
        the frequency of extremes than a shift in the mean precipitation
        (White, 2010; Groisman et al. 1999), and that climate change is most
        likely to increase climate variability, particularly affecting the
        extremes (Jones et al., 2012; Fowler and Ekstrom, 2009).</para>

        <para>A warming climate leads to an increase in the water holding
        capacity of the air, which causes an increase in the atmospheric water
        vapour that supplies storms, resulting in more intense precipitation.
        This effect is observed, even in areas where total precipitation is
        decreasing (Trenberth, 2011). Indeed, some of the largest impacts of
        climate change are likely to result from a shift in the frequency and
        strength of climatic extremes, including precipitation (White et al.,
        2010). It is likely that the frequency of heavy precipitation will
        increase by the end of the 21st century, particularly in the high
        latitudes and tropical regions and there is likely to be an increase
        in heavy rainfalls associated with tropical cyclones (IPCC,
        2012).</para>

        <para>There have been many studies globally that have found increases
        in the intensity or frequency of extreme precipitation events (Bates
        et al., 2008; Westra et al., 2013). It is likely that since the 1970s
        the frequency of heavy precipitation events has increased over most
        areas (Bates, et al. 2008). From 1950 to 2005, extreme daily rainfall
        intensity and frequency has increased in north-western and central
        Australia and over the western tablelands of New South Wales, but
        decreased in the south-east and south-west and along the central east
        coast (CSIRO, 2007). Projections analysed by CSIRO (2007) showed that
        an increase in daily precipitation intensity is likely under climate
        change. The study found that the highest 1% of daily rainfalls tends
        to increase in the north of Australia and decrease in the south, with
        widespread increases in summer and autumn, but not in the south in
        winter and spring when there is a strong decrease in mean
        precipitation (CSIRO 2007).</para>

        <para>The increases in precipitation are more evident in sub-daily
        rainfalls and major changes in the intensity and temporal patterns of
        sub-daily rainfalls can be expected by the end of the 21st century
        (Westra et al., 2013). In a study of downscaled outputs from climate
        models, Abbs and Rafter (2008) found that by 2070 the models projected
        an increase of an average of 40% in intensity for 24 and 72 hour
        events around the Queensland-New South Wales border, and an increase
        of more than 70% in the two hour rainfall events in the high terrain
        inland from the Gold Coast.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Antecedent Conditions</title>

        <para>Changes in the patterns of precipitation and in evaporation will
        lead to changes in antecedent conditions prior to flood events,
        affecting soil moisture and thus loss rates in the catchment (Bates
        et. al., 2008). Potential evaporation is projected to increase almost
        everywhere on a global scale due to an increase in the water-holding
        capacity of the atmosphere with higher temperatures combined with
        little projected change in relative humidity (Bates et al.
        2008).</para>

        <para>Projections of potential evapotranspiration over Australia show
        increases by 2030 and 2070. The largest projected increases are in the
        north and east, where the change by 2030 ranges from little change to
        a 6% increase, with the best estimate being a 2% increase. By 2070,
        the A1FI scenario gives increases of 2% to 10% in the south and west
        with a best estimate of around 6%, and a range of 6% to 16% in the
        north and east with a best estimate around 10%. (CSIRO, 2007).</para>

        <para>Projected decreases in rainfall over much of Australia combined
        with increases in evaporation may result in disproportionate decreases
        in runoff due to a disconnection between surface and groundwater, as
        was experienced in parts of Australia during the Millennium drought
        (CSIRO, 2012).</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Sea Level</title>

        <para>The relatively small rise in sea level that is seen in observed
        data over the past century has already caused a significant change in
        the frequency of extreme sea-level events, and associated flooding
        (Hunter, 2007). Studies of observed sea level data worldwide have
        shown that sea level rise is the predominant cause of increases in the
        frequency of extreme sea level events (IPCC, 2007; Hunter, 2007).
        There is high confidence that there has been an increase in the
        frequency of high coastal sea level events of a given magnitude, and
        that extreme flooding events due to sea level rise will increase
        significantly, dependent on location (Church et al. 2012). The likely
        range of global-mean sea level rise between the 1980 – 1999 and 2090 –
        2099 periods is given by IPCC (2007) as 0.18 – 0.59 m. There is high
        confidence that the global rate of sea level rise has increased
        between the mid-19th and the mid-20th centuries. The average rate was
        1.7 ± 0.5 mm/yr for the 20th century and 3.1 ± 0.7 mm/yr for 1993–2003
        (Bates et al., 2008). The observed rate of sea level rise in the
        Australian region from 1993 - 2011 has high spatial variability, with
        a maximum in the north and north-west coasts of Australia of 9mm/yr,
        and a rate of 2 to 4 mm/yr on the south-eastern and eastern Australian
        coastline (Church et al., 2012).</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <?oxy_insert_end ?>

  <section>
    <title>Dealing with Uncertainty</title>

    <para>Real content needs to be inserted h<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T212043+1100"?>ere.
    <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T212042+1100" content="ere."?></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>
