<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="b1_ch2-3" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Concepts</title>
    
    <para>This section needs to take the probability concepts introduced in the
        introduction and present them as the foundation of the probability of
        floods. Included in this discussion needs to be the assumptions implicitly
        and explicitly adopted to enable the approach. Also, the discussion of flood
        probability needs to be independent of hydrograph characteristic; in other
        words it needs to be applicable to any hydrograph characteristic.
        Nonetheless, it needs to highlight why flows are used predominately, i.e.
        the continuous flood probability model whereas level has a discontinuous
        flood probability model.</para>
    
    
    <section>
        <title>Definition of Flood Probability Model</title>
        
        <para>Joint probability question, influence of different factors (soil
            moisture, dam storage, tidal range)</para>
        
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Flood Risk Perspectives</title>
        <para>Ullamcorper hendrerit delenit duis eros, tation feugait ullamcorper sit. In augue consequat in, iusto tincidunt odio, qui vel amet iriuredolor te. Feugiat autem sed nisl at delenit commodo lobortis minim sit hendrerit tation enim accumsan enim nostrud in ex vel lobortis consequat? Feugiat eu facilisis quis in accumsan tation, ut at duis, feugait consequat, qui ut accumsan autem tation dolore autem. Feugiat ex magna wisi tation amet wisi, augue nulla et delenit, dolore ad te esse, feugait dignissim iriure, augue vulputate vel dolore. Ullamcorper eros veniam odio in ut at ullamcorper nostrud. Duis nulla diam facilisis nibh, vel ut ea hendrerit nulla dolore. Dolor sed wisi tincidunt consequat nostrud vero, duis euismod augue. Vel nisl vel aliquam vulputate ut veniam nulla? Ut diam crisare erat nulla iusto exerci blandit facilisi. Laoreet enim molestie vel feugait illum magna duis feugiat, blandit eum at sciurus tincidunt facilisi ullamcorper augue amet tation. Velit te ad qui augue ex nibh eum consequat augue commodo dolore consequatvel feugiat iriuredolor odio suscipit ad, accumsan at exerci enim. Sit ad consequat eros augue exerci, ad illum, volutpat esse facilisis esse ipsum consectetuer qui minim nulla feugiat.</para>
       
    </section>
</section>
