<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b1_ch2"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Fundamental Issues</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ling_fiona.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/thyer_mark.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/pilgrim_david.xml"/>
  </info>

  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>

      <td>1</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>

      <td>2</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>

      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>

      <td>Advanced draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>

      <td>N/A</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>

      <td>N/A</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>General</td>

      <td>Subject to final review and consistency check</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_trbrp">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>This chapter introduces important concepts of probability and
    statistics with respect to flood estimation, and defines the recommended
    terminology for these probability concepts. The chapter also discusses the
    difference between design and actual events, conversion of rainfall of a
    given probability to a flood of the same probability, risk-based design
    and dealing with uncertainty in flood estimates. Much of the text from the
    1987 edition of ARR is still relevant and has formed the basis for the
    information provided in some of following sections.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_n6pll">
    <title>Terminology</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_vt33jid">
      <title>Background</title>

      <para>Probability concepts are fundamental to design flood estimation
      and appropriate terminology is important for effective communication of
      design flood estimates. Terms commonly used in the past have included
      "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence interval</emphasis>", "<emphasis
      role="italic">return period</emphasis>", and various terms involving
      "<emphasis role="italic">probability</emphasis>". It is common for these
      terms to be used in a loose manner, and sometimes quite incorrectly.
      This has resulted in misinterpretation by the profession, the general
      community impacted by floods, and other stakeholders.</para>

      <para>In considering the terminology that should be used in this edition
      of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, the National Committee on Water
      Engineering's three major concerns were:</para>

      <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
          <para>Clarity of meaning;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Technical correctness; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Practicality and acceptability.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_xe7xl">
      <title>Clarity of Meaning</title>

      <para>Use of the terms "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence
      interval</emphasis>" and "<emphasis role="italic">return
      period</emphasis>" has been criticised as leading to confusion in the
      minds of some decision-makers and members of the public. Although the
      terms are simple superficially, they are misinterpreted regularly as
      implying that the associated event magnitude is only exceeded at regular
      intervals, and that they are referring to the expected elapsed time till
      the next exceedance. This misinterpretation of the terms used for
      expressing probabilities of flood magnitudes can be misleading and
      result in poor decisions.</para>

      <para>It is believed that irrespective of the terms used, it is critical
      that all stakeholders have a common interpretation of the terms.
      Furthermore, it is important that stakeholders understand that the terms
      refer to long term averages. This means, for a given climatic
      environment, that the probability of an event of a given magnitude being
      equalled or exceeded in a given period of time (for example, one year)
      is unchanged throughout the life of the structure or the drainage
      network. Furthermore, it is not uncommon for an event to occur for than
      once in a single year.</para>

      <para>Additionally, given the wet and dry phases that occur in many
      regions of Australia, these events are likely to be clustered in time.
      The occurrence of these wet and dry climatic phases highlight the
      misleading and inappropriate interpretation that flood events occur at
      regular intervals as implied by "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence
      interval</emphasis>" and "<emphasis role="italic">return
      period</emphasis>”.</para>

      <para>Flood events generally are random occurrences, and the period
      between exceedances of a given event magnitude usually is a random
      variate, the properties of which are assumed to be constant in time for
      a given location and climatic environment. The adopted terminology
      reflects this fundamental concept and is intended to convey a clear and
      precise interpretation.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_ijnsl">
      <title>Technical Correctness</title>

      <para>In view of the loose and frequently incorrect manner in which
      probability terms are often used, it was considered that Australian
      Rainfall and Runoff should adopt terminology that is technically
      correct, as far as this is possible and in harmony with other
      objectives. Additionally, even if this is not entirely popular with all
      practitioners, Engineers Australia has a responsibility to encourage and
      educate engineers regarding correct terminology.</para>

      <para>The two approaches used when describing probabilities of flood
      events in previous editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff
      were:</para>

      <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP) </emphasis>- the
          probability of an event being equalled or exceeded within a year.
          Typically the AEP is estimated by extracting the annual maximum in
          each year to produce an Annual Maxima Series (AMS); and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Average Recurrence Interval (ARI) </emphasis>- the
          average time period between occurrences equalling or exceeding a
          given value. Usually the ARI is derived from a Peak over Threshold
          series (PoTS) where every value over a chosen threshold is extracted
          from the period of record.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Details of AMS and PoTs and the background to these alternative
      techniques for extracting flood series from recorded data are presented
      in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>. Included in this discussion are the
      assumptions necessary for conversion of one probability terminology to
      the other using the Langbein formula (Langbein, 1949).</para>

      <para>Using the Langbein formula, in probability terms, there is little
      practical difference for events rarer than 10% AEP. Historically,
      however, there has been a reluctance to convert from the approach used
      for derivation of the design flood estimate. Furthermore, terminology
      was attached to particular design flood estimation techniques; for
      example, when AMS were used to derive design flood estimates, the
      resultant probability was expressed as an AEP while when a PoTS was used
      for the same purpose, the resultant probability was expressed as an
      ARI.</para>

      <para>In many situations, this distinction between an ARI and an AEP was
      imprecise as the design flood prediction methodology adopted did not
      explicitly note the use of either an AMS or a PoTS in the methodology.
      As a result, use of ARI and AEP was considered to be interchangeable.
      This interchangeable use often resulted in confusion.</para>

      <para>The National Committee on Water Engineering believes that within
      Australian Rainfall and Runoff a terminology should be used which, while
      being technically correct, is consistent with other uses. Furthermore,
      the terminology adopted should be easily understood both by the
      profession and by other stakeholders within the community.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_c6s8d">
      <title>Practicality and Acceptability</title>

      <para>The National Committee on Water Engineering is aware that while
      the terminology adopted must be technically correct it must also be
      relatively simple and suitable for use in practice. Terminology that
      meets this criterion will be accepted by the profession and by other
      stakeholders.</para>

      <para>The interaction of the profession with the community and the
      increased public participation in decision making means that terminology
      needs to be clear not only to the profession but also to the community
      and other stakeholders, other professions involved in flood management,
      and to the managers of flood-prone land. This need has resulted in a
      move away from the terminology adopted in the 1987 Edition of Australian
      Rainfall and Runoff towards a clear and unambiguous terminology
      supported by the National Committee on Water Engineering of Engineers
      Australia and the National Flood Risk Advisory Group (NFRAG, a reference
      group under the Australian and New Zealand Emergency Management
      Committee). All parties believe that terminology involving annual
      percentage probability best conveys the likelihood of flooding and is
      less open to misinterpretation by the public.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch1-3_s_aona4">
      <title>Adopted Terminology</title>

      <para>To achieve the desired clarity of meaning, technical correctness,
      practicality and acceptability, the National Committee on Water
      Engineering has decided to adopt the terms shown in <xref
      linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/> and the suggested frequency
      indicators.</para>

      <figure xml:id="arr_pref_term_table">
        <title>Australian Rainfall and Runoff Preferred Terminology</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1044.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Navy outline indicates preferred terminology. Shading indicates
      acceptable terminology which is depends on the typical use. For example
      in floodplain management 0.5% AEP might be used while in dam design this
      event would be described as a 1 in 200 AEP.</para>

      <para>As shown in the third column of <xref
      linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/>, the term Annual Exceedance Probability
      (AEP) expresses the probability of an event being equalled or exceeded
      in any year in percentage terms, for example, the 1% AEP design flood
      discharge. There will be situations where the use of percentage
      probability is not practicable; extreme flood probabilities associated
      with dam spillways are one example of a situation where percentage
      probability is not appropriate. In these cases, it is recommended that
      the probability be expressed as 1 in X AEP where 100/X would be the
      equivalent percentage probability.</para>

      <para>For events more frequent than 50% AEP, expressing frequency in
      terms of annual exceedance probability is not meaningful and misleading
      , as probability is constrained to a maximum value of 1.0 or 100%.
      Furthermore, where strong seasonality is experienced, a recurrence
      interval approach would also be misleading. An example of strong
      seasonality is where the rainfall occurs predominately during the Summer
      or Winter period and as a consequence flood flows are more likely to
      occur during that period. Accordingly, when strong seasonality exists,
      calculating a design flood flow with a 3 month recurrence interval is of
      limited value as the expectation of the time period between occurrences
      will not be consistent throughout the year. For example, a flow with the
      magnitude of a 3 month recurrence interval would be expected to occur or
      be exceeded 4 times a year; however, in situations where there is strong
      seasonality in the rainfall, all of the occurrences are likely to occur
      in the dominant season.</para>

      <para>Consequently, events more frequent than 50% AEP should be
      expressed as X Exceedances per Year (EY). For example, 2 EY is
      equivalent to a design event with a 6 month recurrence interval when
      there is no seasonality in flood occurrence.</para>

      <para>Different users of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, in general,
      will use different segments of the relationship between flood magnitude
      and exceedance probability. To reduce confusion, that may arise from
      switching between different terminologies, it is recommended that
      consistent terminology in accordance with one of the columns of <xref
      linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/> be used within an industry
      segment.</para>

      <para>These expressions of estimated frequencies relate directly to the
      particular time period for which data have been analysed and frequencies
      determined with no consideration given to the long term effects of
      climatic change. Nonetheless, the adopted terminology is considered to
      be equally applicable to both stationary and non-stationary climatic
      environments, as there is no requirement for the annual exceedance
      probabilities to be constant over time. Consequently, where flood
      characteristics are changing as result of long term climatic change, the
      AEP of a flood characteristic for a future time period may be different
      or, conversely, a flood characteristic magnitude corresponding to a
      given AEP may change.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_yjbxu">
    <title>Difference Between Design Events and Actual Events</title>

    <para>Much confusion has resulted from lack of recognition of the
    fundamental differences between these two types events and associated of
    flood estimation problems. Although the same mathematical procedures may
    be involved in both cases, the implications and assumptions involved, and
    the validity of application, are quite different. The emphasis in this
    document is largely on design floods.</para>

    <para>A design flood is a probabilistic or statistical estimate, being
    generally based on some form of probability analysis of flood or rainfall
    data. An Annual Exceedance Probability is attributed to the estimate. This
    applies not only to normal routine design, but also to probable maximum
    estimates, where no specific probability can be assigned but the intention
    is to obtain a design value with an extremely low probability of
    exceedance. In the flood estimation methods based on design rainfalls, the
    probability relationship between design rainfall events and design flood
    events is not a direct one. Occurrence of a rainfall eventwhen the
    catchment is wet might result in a very large flood, while occurrence of
    the same rainfall event when the catchment was dry might result in
    relatively little, or even no runoff. For the design situation, the
    combinations of different factors combining to produce a flood event are
    not known and must be assumed, often implicitly in the design values that
    are adopted.</para>

    <para>The approach to estimating an actual (or historic) flood from a
    particular rainfall event is quite different in concept and is of a
    deterministic nature. All causes and effects are directly related to the
    specific event under consideration. The actual antecedent conditions
    prevailing at the time of occurrence of the rain are directly reflected in
    the resulting flood and must be allowed for in its estimation. No real
    information on the probability of the on flood probability can be gained
    from consideration of a single actual flood event.</para>

    <para>Although the differences in these two types of events are often not
    recognised, they have three important practical consequences. The first is
    that a particular procedure might be might be appropriate for analysing
    actual flood events but quite unsuitable for probabilistic design flood
    events.</para>

    <para>The second concerns the manner in which values of parameters are
    derived from recorded data, and the manner in which designers regard these
    values and apply them. If actual floods are to be estimated, values for
    use in the calculations should be derived from calibration on individual
    observed events. If design floods are to be estimated, the values should
    be derived from statistical analyses of data from many observed
    floods.</para>

    <para>The third practical consequence concerns the manner in which
    parameters are viewed by designers and analysts. For example, design
    initial losses for bursts can be very different from event initial losses
    derived from actual events, yet practitioners still often compare them
    without understanding the differences.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_6y2kv">
    <title>Probability Concepts</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_vmhn8">
      <title>Probability Relationship Between Design Rainfall and Design Flood
      Characteristics</title>

      <para>In the flood frequency based design flood estimation approaches
      covered in Book 3, the probabilities of a specific event magnitude being
      equalled or exceeded are estimated directly for the flood characteristic
      of interest (e.g. peak flow or flood volume). However, for the catchment
      simulation and hydrograph estimation procedures covered in Books 4, 5
      and 7, the exceedance probability associated with design rainfall, as
      the primary probabilistic input to the design flood estimation
      procedure, needs to preserved in its transformation to a design flood.
      This concept is often referred to as AEP neutrality.</para>

      <para>However, each of the processes represented in a model that
      converts rainfall to runoff and forms a flood hydrograph at the point of
      interest introduces some joint probability, resulting in the fundamental
      problem that the true probability of the derived flood characteristic
      may be obscure, and its magnitude may be biased with respect to the true
      flood magnitude with the same probability as the design rainfall,
      especially at the low probabilities of interest in design.</para>

      <para>Since publication of ARR87 (Pilgrim,1987) there has been a steady
      shift towards methods that better account for the stochastic nature of
      how floods of different magnitude and exceedance probabilities are
      generated. Procedures of different complexity to deal with this
      fundamental issue are discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch3"/>.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_w5anx">
      <title>Choosing a Quantile Estimator</title>

      <para>The 1 in Y AEP quantile corresponds to the flood magnitude with
      annual probability of exceedance equal to 1/Y. Because the parameters of
      the flood frequency distribution have to be estimated from limited data,
      the true quantile is not known. Different quantile estimates are
      available depending on the application. These are described in <xref
      linkend="b3_ch2"/>.</para>

      <para>In cases where the interest is principally on the accurate
      estimation of the AEP that corresponds to a specified flood magnitude
      (e.g. the flood level at which a particular flood protection structure
      is expected to fail), an expected AEP (or expected probability) quantile
      should be used. The use of such a quantile ensures that, on average, its
      AEP equals the true value. In cases where the mean-squared-error in the
      flood magnitude is to be minimized for a given AEP, expected parameter
      quantiles should be used.</para>

      <para>The difference between these quantile estimates is typically not
      of significance when there is little or no extrapolation of the observed
      range of data, and especially if the skew is small. However, if
      extrapolation is required and high skews are involved, the difference
      can be appreciable. The methods in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/> describes
      how to estimates these quantiles.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_1t8xd">
      <title>Avoiding Inconsistencies in Procedures and Resolution</title>

      <para>The important step often overlooked by practitioners is mistakenly
      using an input or parameter that was derived a particular way and at a
      particular resolution in a manner that is different to how it was
      derived. This is particularly difficult to avoid with digital data sets
      compiled from different sources and resolutions. Historically problems
      have arisen when a method was derived from one scale map and used at a
      different scale.Without giving a clear recommendation (e.g. It is the
      responsibility of practitioners to ensure that procedures and design
      data applied in a particular application are appropriate for the nature
      and location of their specific design problem) this section is of not
      much use and can be left out.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_qgsui">
    <title>Risk-based Design</title>

    <para>Floods can cause significant impacts where they interact with the
    community and the supporting natural and built environment. However,
    flooding also has the potential to be the most manageable natural disaster
    as the likelihood and consequences of the full range of flood events can
    be understood, enabling risks to be assessed and where necessary managed.
    There is strong move from managing floods by a by simple standards
    approach, where a certain frequency of flooding is deemed acceptable, to
    risk-based approaches, where the consequence and probability of design
    capacity being exceeded are assessed explicitly. Risk and design flood
    estimation concepts are discussed in detail in <xref
    linkend="b1_ch5"/>.</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_whlxg">
      <title>Route Serviceability</title>

      <para>A particular aspect of risk based approaches is where total system
      risk is of main interest. With a railway or major road, flooding of any
      one of many stream crossings will cause closure of the route. The item
      of real interest is the probability of this closure, and not of failure
      at any particular site. This probability of closure will be much greater
      than that at an individual site. Closure of the route at any site may
      cause major disruption and economic losses. Upgrade works can be
      targeted at reducing the probability of closure.</para>

      <para>This problem is receiving increasing attention from transport
      managers and is discussed in detail in <xref linkend="b1_ch5"/>.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_acv2b">
    <title>The Importance of Data</title>

    <para>Data is fundamental to flood estimation. Data is needed to
    understand the processes involved in the formation of floods and to ensure
    that models are accurate and reflect the real world issues being analysed.
    Flood estimation primarily uses data that describes the rainfall,
    streamflow and water levels. The procedures and guidelines presented in
    ARR could not have been developed without historical data, and often the
    reliability of the methods presented depends on the extent of data that
    has been used in development.</para>

    <para>For the first time, ARR has been based completely on Australian data
    to better reflect Australia’s variable landscape, including a national
    database of extreme flood hazards. A major task of the current ARR update
    was assembling a national databases of rainfall and streamflow data for
    developing inputs and methodologies. ARR 1987 used 600 pluviographs
    rainfall gauge (measures the amount of rainfall which fell) with greater
    than 6 years data and 7500 daily rainfall gauges with over 30 years
    record. ARR 2016 uses almost 30 years of extra rainfall and streamflow
    data, including data from over 2200 pluviographs and over 8000 daily
    rainfall gauges. Over 900 streamflow gauges were analysed. Over 100, 000
    storm events were analysed. This data provides a valuable resource for the
    development of future methodologies.</para>

    <para>Major improvements have been made to design flood estimation methods
    but national databases will allow the use and parameterisation of more
    complex methods. Major advances will continue that will allow us to
    leverage the limited data we can afford to collect on the continent
    nation. Many projects have opened the eyes of researchers and
    practitioners on what could be done with more time, money and the still
    limited data available. The data sets developed as part of this update
    should be enhanced and applied to for future improvements.</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b1_ch4"/> provides a summary of the types of data
    used for flood estimation.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_vr72j">
    <title>Climate Change</title>

    <para>ARR 1987 (Pilgrim,1987) while acknowledging climate change did not
    address climate change or non-stationarity or provide guidance on the
    inclusion of climate change impacts in flood estimation. One key aim of
    this edition was the incorporation of the best available information of
    climate change impacts on flooding.</para>

    <para>This edition of ARR funded research projects which investigated the
    following aspects:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>How climate change will affect flooding and the factors
          influencing flooding;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>How to incorporate climate change into the investigation
          methodologies used by the engineering profession to estimate design
          floods;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Updating of the methodology in Australian Rainfall and Runoff
          so that the outcomes from climate change research (eg. regional
          dynamic downscaling) can be incorporated easily into the
          investigation methodology as the science and results become
          available.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>

    <para>The impacts of climate change on design flood estimation are
    discussed in detail in <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_lsfw7"/>.More detail can be
    found in the ARR Climate Change Research Plan and ARR Project 1: Climate
    Change Synthesis report.</para>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_470vz">
      <title>Climate change impacts on flooding</title>

      <para>Global warming has been observed over several decades, and has
      been linked to changes in the large-scale hydrological cycle including
      increasing atmospheric water vapour content; changing precipitation
      patterns, intensity and extremes; changes in soil moisture and runoff;
      and increasing melting of snow and ice (Bates et al., 2008).There is
      increasing evidence that human-induced climate change is changing
      precipitation extremes, and that extreme flooding globally has increased
      over the 20th century (Trenberth, 2011). There is confidence that these
      changes in the hydrological cycle will lead to increased variability in
      precipitation and increased frequency of flood events over many areas
      (IPCC 2007, Bates et al. 2008). Changes in climate will result in
      changes in the frequency, intensity, spatial extent, duration, and
      timing of extreme weather and climate events, and may lead to
      unprecedented extreme weather and climate events (IPCC, 2012).</para>

      <para>The major areas where climate change will impact flooding
      are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Design rainfall intensity-frequency-duration;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Storm type, frequency, and depth;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Rainfall spatial and temporal patterns;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Antecedent conditions;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Changes in sea level and;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The joint probability of storm surge and flood producing
          rainfall.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_n7o2c">
        <title>Climate Change Impacts on Rainfall</title>

        <para>Changes in extremes events, such as floods, can be linked to
        changes in the mean, variance, or shape of probability distributions,
        or all of these (IPCC, 2012). For example, climate change projections
        have shown that a relatively small shift in the distribution of
        precipitation may result in a large change in the frequency and
        magnitude of extreme precipitation events (Nicholls and Alexander,
        2007). Studies have shown that a change in the shape of the
        distribution of precipitation is likely to have a greater effect on
        the frequency of extremes than a shift in the mean precipitation
        (White, 2010; Groisman et al. 1999), and that climate change is most
        likely to increase climate variability, particularly affecting the
        extremes (Jones et al., 2012; Fowler and Ekstrom, 2009).</para>

        <para>A warming climate leads to an increase in the water holding
        capacity of the air, which causes an increase in the atmospheric water
        vapour that supplies storms, resulting in more intense precipitation.
        This effect is observed, even in areas where total precipitation is
        decreasing (Trenberth, 2011). Indeed, some of the largest impacts of
        climate change are likely to result from a shift in the frequency and
        strength of climatic extremes, including precipitation (White et al.,
        2010). It is likely that the frequency of heavy precipitation will
        increase by the end of the 21st century, particularly in the high
        latitudes and tropical regions and there is likely to be an increase
        in heavy rainfalls associated with tropical cyclones (IPCC,
        2012).</para>

        <para>There have been many studies globally that have found increases
        in the intensity or frequency of extreme precipitation events (Bates
        et al., 2008; Westra et al., 2013). It is likely that since the 1970s
        the frequency of heavy precipitation events has increased over most
        areas (Bates, et al. 2008). From 1950 to 2005, extreme daily rainfall
        intensity and frequency has increased in north-western and central
        Australia and over the western tablelands of New South Wales, but
        decreased in the south-east and south-west and along the central east
        coast (CSIRO, 2007). Projections analysed by CSIRO (2007) showed that
        an increase in daily precipitation intensity is likely under climate
        change. The study found that the highest 1% of daily rainfalls tends
        to increase in the north of Australia and decrease in the south, with
        widespread increases in summer and autumn, but not in the south in
        winter and spring when there is a strong decrease in mean
        precipitation (CSIRO 2007).</para>

        <para>The increases in precipitation are more evident in sub-daily
        rainfalls and major changes in the intensity and temporal patterns of
        sub-daily rainfalls can be expected by the end of the 21st century
        (Westra et al., 2013). In a study of downscaled outputs from climate
        models, Abbs and Rafter (2008) found that by 2070 the models projected
        an increase of an average of 40% in intensity for 24 and 72 hour
        events around the Queensland-New South Wales border, and an increase
        of more than 70% in the two hour rainfall events in the high terrain
        inland from the Gold Coast.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_czu0n">
        <title>Antecedent Conditions</title>

        <para>Changes in the patterns of precipitation and in evaporation will
        lead to changes in antecedent conditions prior to flood events,
        affecting soil moisture and thus loss rates in the catchment (Bates
        et. al., 2008). Potential evaporation is projected to increase almost
        everywhere on a global scale due to an increase in the water-holding
        capacity of the atmosphere with higher temperatures combined with
        little projected change in relative humidity (Bates et al.
        2008).</para>

        <para>Projections of potential evapotranspiration over Australia show
        increases by 2030 and 2070. The largest projected increases are in the
        north and east, where the change by 2030 ranges from little change to
        a 6% increase, with the best estimate being a 2% increase. By 2070,
        the A1FI scenario gives increases of 2% to 10% in the south and west
        with a best estimate of around 6%, and a range of 6% to 16% in the
        north and east with a best estimate around 10%. (CSIRO, 2007).</para>

        <para>Projected decreases in rainfall over much of Australia combined
        with increases in evaporation may result in disproportionate decreases
        in runoff due to a disconnection between surface and groundwater, as
        was experienced in parts of Australia during the Millennium drought
        (CSIRO, 2012).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_o0gf8">
        <title>Sea Level</title>

        <para>The relatively small rise in sea level that is seen in observed
        data over the past century has already caused a significant change in
        the frequency of extreme sea-level events, and associated flooding
        (Hunter, 2007). Studies of observed sea level data worldwide have
        shown that sea level rise is the predominant cause of increases in the
        frequency of extreme sea level events (IPCC, 2007; Hunter, 2007).
        There is high confidence that there has been an increase in the
        frequency of high coastal sea level events of a given magnitude, and
        that extreme flooding events due to sea level rise will increase
        significantly, dependent on location (Church et al. 2012). The likely
        range of global-mean sea level rise between the 1980 – 1999 and 2090 –
        2099 periods is given by IPCC (2007) as 0.18 – 0.59 m. There is high
        confidence that the global rate of sea level rise has increased
        between the mid-19th and the mid-20th centuries. The average rate was
        1.7 ± 0.5 mm/yr for the 20th century and 3.1 ± 0.7 mm/yr for 1993–2003
        (Bates et al., 2008). The observed rate of sea level rise in the
        Australian region from 1993 - 2011 has high spatial variability, with
        a maximum in the north and north-west coasts of Australia of 9mm/yr,
        and a rate of 2 to 4 mm/yr on the south-eastern and eastern Australian
        coastline (Church et al., 2012).</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_4vjbf">
    <title>Dealing with Uncertainty</title>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>This section provides an overview of the uncertainties in the design flood estimation.
        The specific aims are to </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>Identify the types of uncertainty in design flood
          estimation</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Motivate practitioners on the value of undertaking uncertainty analysis </para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Raise awareness of the various sources of uncertainty in common techniques for
          design flood estimates </para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para> </para>
    </section>
      <section>
        <title>Types of uncertainty in design flood
          estimation</title>
        <para>It is typical in current practise for design flood estimation to ignore the
          uncertainty in the estimates of the design flood. This is despite the considerable
          uncertainties that are introduced when undertaking a flood frequency analysis using short
          data records and extrapolating the fitted flood frequency distribution to estimate the 100
          year or 200 year flood. Similarly, when using a catchment modelling approach to obtain
          estimates of the design flood, the typical situation is that the catchment model is
          calibrated to a data from few selected rainfall-runoff events, and the calibrated model is
          then extrapolated using design rainfall estimates (which itself is an extrapolation of
          observed rainfall data) to provide estimates of 100 or 200 year flood. Both these type of
          approaches introduce significant uncertainties in estimates of the design flood.</para>
        <para>The causes of these uncertainties are that practitioners are required to (1) Use
          mathematical algorithms to represent the complexity of catchment processes that transform
          large rainfall into large flood events. (2) Calibrate and validate these algorithms using
          measurements of the catchment process that are highly uncertain. It is widely acknowledge
          that there is significant spatial variation in catchments and temporal and spatial
          variation in the antecedent catchment wetness and rainfall events that drive significant
          flood events. Practitioners, use hydrological models, which are simplified mathematical
          conceptualisations to represent these complex spatially and temporally distributed
          hydrological processes. These hydrological models are calibrated to measurements of data
          on variables such as rainfall, evaporation and river flow. It is widely acknowledged that
          these data can have significant measurement errors. Rainfall is spatial heterogeneous,
          however, typically there are only a small number rain gauges in a given catchment. River
          flow is based on river height measurements and a rating curve, which can be difficult to
          reliability estimate for large flood events. Typically, though these uncertainties are
          ignored in the design flood estimation process. </para>
        <para>Uncertainty analysis provides the tools with which to handle this uncertainty and
          incorporate it into the design flood estimates. To enable the use of uncertainty analysis
          tools, it is first important to distinguish two broad types of uncertainty: </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Aleatory (or inherent) uncertainty refers to uncertainty that arises through
              natural randomness or natural variability that we observe in nature. </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Epistemic (or knowledge-based) uncertainty refers to uncertainty that is
              associated with the state of knowledge of a physical system (our estimation of
              reality), our ability to measure it and the inaccuracies in our predictions of the
              physical system. </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>These definitions are consistent with the broad definitions provided by [Ang and Tang,
          2007] in wider context of general engineering and the specific context of flood risk by
          [Pappenberger and Beven, 2006]. The major differences between the two types of uncertainty
          is that epistemic uncertainty can be reduced, through advances in process understanding or
          improvement in measurement techniques, while aleatory uncertainty cannot be reduced, and
          therefore needs to be characterised. Both types of uncertainty can be characterised using
          tools of uncertainty analysis. [Ang and Tang, 2007] provide a wealth of examples of the
          two types of uncertainty in a general engineering context. </para>
        <para>In the context of design flood estimation, a simple example to understand the
          differences between these two types of uncertainty is to consider a an example of a flood
          frequency distribution, as shown in Figure 1, with probability limits on the design flood
          estimates over the range of AEP. </para>
        <para>An illustration of aleatory uncertainty is the natural variability in annual maximum
          floods which is due to the climate variability in extreme rainfall and antecedent soil
          moisture condition from year to year. This aleatory uncertainty influences the shape of
          the flood frequency distribution, and influences the values of 1% AEP design flood
          estimates. The aleatory uncertainty is why practitioners undertake a risk-based design
          approach to estimate the likelihood of flooding. At different catchments, the flood
          frequency distribution changes due to the natural variability in the climate and catchment
          processes, hence this is also of type aleatory uncertainty. </para>
        <para>An illustration of epistemic uncertainty is the uncertainty in the estimate of the
        design flood for a given AEP, e.g. in Figure 1, the design flood for a 1% AEP has an
        expected value of
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>X<?oxy_custom_end?>% and
        the 95% probability limits are +/-
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>X and
        Y<?oxy_custom_end?>. This uncertainty in the design flood estimate for a given AEP is
        primarily of type epistemic (or knowledge based) uncertainty. There is an opportunity to
        reduce this uncertainty, if there were longer flow records which would reduce the
        uncertainty in the parameters of the flood frequency distribution fitted to the annual
        maximum floods. Similarly, for catchment modelling, or if there was a better understanding
        on the catchment processes obtained through better data to calibrate and verify the
        catchment model, this would reduce the uncertainty in the flood estimates of the catchment
        model. </para>
      <figure>
        <title>Conceptual diagram illustrating the different types of uncertainty, aleatory and
          epistemic, in the context of design flood estimation</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1046.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
        <para>Despite the simplicity of the two illustrations of aleatory and epistemic uncertainty,
        given in the flood frequency distribution in Figure 1, there are occasions where the
        distinction between the two different types of uncertainty is not always clear. For example,
        the illustration of Figure 1 implies that as level of information increases and the
        epistemic uncertainty is reduced then “true” flood frequency distribution for a given
        catchment will emerge. There is practical limit on the level of information (data and/or
        process understanding) available on a given catchment hence the concept of a single “true”
        flood frequency distribution for a given catchment is likely to unobtainable. Hence the
        epistemic uncertainty given in Figure 1, will have a component of aleatory uncertainty.
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Similarly, provide an
        counter example, where aleatory uncertainty turns into epistemic uncertainty.
        <?oxy_custom_end?></para>
        <para>Mention that the concepts of aleatory and epistemic uncertainty are similar to
          concepts of flood likelihood and uncertainty from risk-based decision-making (cross
          ref)</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Motivation for incorporating uncertainty into design
          flood estimates</title>
        <para>There are a range of approaches for dealing with uncertainty, the simplest of which is
        to ignore it, to qualitative descriptions (highly uncertain) or relative rankings, (option 1
        is more uncertainty than option 2) i.e. to rigourous quantitative approaches which use
        uncertainty analysis techniques to characterise the individual sources of uncertainty, and
        use advanced techniques to estimate their impacts on the uncertainty in the design flood
        estimations (see
        cross-<?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T171613+1100" comment="Refer to approaches in other chapters. "?>ref<?oxy_comment_end?>
        for an overview of the various approaches). The greater the rigour in uncertainty analysis
        approach the more effort and resources is required. The reward for this greater effort is
        more informed decision making. </para>
        <para>An example of the potential benefits of incorporating uncertainty for more informed
          decision making is provided in Figure 2. Consider two different designs; design A and
          design B. The decision-maker needs to choose the design that reduces the flood magnitude
          for given catchment location. Design A has a higher value for the most likely estimate of
          the design flood, but has a lower uncertainty than design B. The differences in the
          uncertainty estimates could arise because design B is a more complicated design option
          than design A and requires the use of more complex flood modelling approach (e.g. fully
          distributed flood model) and there was a lack of spatial data in the catchment to
          calibrate the distributed model and hence parameter estimates had to be based on regional
          information. In contrast design A was based on flood modelling approach that was
          well-calibrated using high quality data that was readily available in the catchment. If
          the uncertainty is ignored then design B would be the preferred choice of the decision
          maker, because the most likely estimate of the flood magnitude is lower than design A. If
          the uncertainty in the flood magnitude incorporated than a decision-maker who is
          risk-averse may prefer to choose design A, because it the probability of a large magnitude
          flood with major/catastrophic consequence is lower than design B. This example illustrates
          how the uncertainty in the design flood estimates, when combined with risk attitude
          (risk-averse, risk-neutral, or risk-seeking) of the design-maker provides a more
          information on which to base the design choice </para>
      <figure>
        <title>Conceptual diagram illustrating the impact of uncertainty when comparing the
          estimates of the design flood from two different designs: Design A and Design B</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1047.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
        <para>From a practical and scientific perspective [Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] provide an
          overview of the common reasons for not undertaking uncertainty analysis for hydrological
          and hydraulic models and argue that these arguments are not tenable. A summary of the
          reasons provided by [Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] and their counter arguments are
          summarized as follows:</para>
        <para>1. <emphasis role="bold">Uncertainty analysis is not necessary given physically
          realistic models.</emphasis></para>
        <para>[Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] states there are a group of modellers who believe that
        their models are (or at least will be in the future) physically correct and thus parameter
        calibration or uncertainty analysis should not be necessary (or only minimal) if predictions
        are based on a true understanding of the physics of the system simulated. This position is
        difficult to justify considering published discussions of the modeling process in respect of
        the sources and impacts of uncertainties [see Beven, 1989, 2006; Oreskes et al.,
        <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T171645+1100" comment="Add own references"?>1994<?oxy_comment_end?>
        ]. It is argued that this group of modellers have too much faith in the model representation
        of physical laws or empirical equations. An alternative is a group of modellers who
        inherently accept uncertainties in the modeling process, at least as a result of errors and
        natural variability in time and space.</para>
        <para>2. <emphasis role="bold">Uncertainty analysis is not useful in understanding
          hydrological and hydraulic processes. </emphasis></para>
        <para>To be able to learn about how water flows through the landscape and the best model to
        represent this water flow requires the use of a
        <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T171457+1100" comment="Add refs to DK’s "?>hypothesis
        testing framework<?oxy_comment_end?> . In real applications, this hypothesis testing
        framework would evaluate different competing hypothesis (i.e. models) against the
        observations, and should explicitly consider the potential sources of uncertainty in
        applications to real systems to enable the results to be stated in a probabilistic rather
        than a deterministic manner. This would enable evaluation of whether the differences in
        model performance, can be reliability identified given the uncertainty in the predictions
        and observations.</para>
        <para>3. <emphasis role="bold">Uncertainty (probability) distributions cannot be understood
          by policy makers and the public.</emphasis></para>
        <para>[Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] cite several scientific studies that suggest decision
          makers actually want to get a feeling for the range of uncertainty and the risk of
          possible outcomes. Furthermore, policy makers derive decisions on a regular basis under
          severe uncertainties. If uncertainty is not communicated and there is a misunderstanding
          of the certainty of modeling results this can lead to a loss of credibility and trust in
          the model and the modelling process. </para>
        <para>However, it is acknowledge that there are a wide range of different perceptions of
          “risk” and “uncertainty” and that effort is required on the part of both pracitioners and
          policy-makers to work together to achieve a common understanding of uncertainty. </para>
        <para>4.<emphasis role="bold"> Uncertainty analysis cannot be incorporated into the
          decision-making process. </emphasis></para>
        <para>There are two supporting arguments to this reason (1) Decisions are binary; (2)
          Uncertainty bounds are too wide to be useful in decision making. [Pappenberger and Beven,
          2006] conclude there is no question that, for many environmental systems, a rigorous
          estimate of uncertainty leads to wide ranges of predictions. There are certainly cases in
          which the predictive uncertainty for outcomes of different scenarios is significantly
          larger than the differences between the expected values of those scenarios. This leads to
          the perception that decisions are difficult to make. To counter these arguments,
          [Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] present numerous examples from the literature on decision
          support systems and decision analysis which provide a range of methods for decision making
          under uncertainty based on assessments of the risk and costs of possible outcomes.
          Examples of decisions under uncertainty for flood frequency analysis are illustrated by
          [Wood and Rodríguez-Iturbe, 1975] and more recently by [Botto<emphasis role="italic"> et
            al.</emphasis>, 2014]. The key outcome from [Botto<emphasis role="italic"> et
            al.</emphasis>, 2014] was that incorporating uncertainty in estimating the design floods
          (by minimising the total expected costs) leads to substantial higher estimates of the
          design flood compared to standard approaches when uncertainty is ignored. This suggests
          incorporating uncertainty leads to reduce expected costs and highlights the benefits of
          incorporating uncertainty. </para>
        <para>5. <emphasis role="bold">Uncertainty analysis is too
          <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T171718+1100" comment="Needs to be shortened"?>subjective<?oxy_comment_end?></emphasis></para>
        <para>[Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] identify that in the application of uncertainty
          analysis methods, certain decisions must be made, some of which include an element of
          subjectivity, including the choice of probability distributions for data errors, prior
          distributions for parameter uncertainty or predictive errors. In principle, many of these
          assumptions can be checked as part of the analysis but it is common to find that not all
          assumptions can be fully justified or some assumptions cannot be checked, and hence this
          leads to the conclusion that predictions with uncertainty are too subjective.
          [Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] conclude that implies that any analysis which does not
          considering uncertainties in the modeling can be objective. This view is based on a
          misplaced faith in deterministic modeling in the light of the inevitable uncertainty in
          the modeling process (see also argument 1 above). Even a fully deterministic model run
          requires necessarily subjective assumptions about model inputs and boundary conditions and
          performance evaluation. The important issue is that the nature of the assumptions should
          be made explicit so that they can be assessed and discussed. Uncertainty analysis provides
          a set of tools to make these assumptions transparent and subject them to explicit
          scrutiny. </para>
        <para>6. <emphasis role="bold">Uncertainty analysis is too difficult to
        perform</emphasis></para>
        <para>[Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] note this is a common attitude amongst practitioners
        and is consequence of the need to spend more time and money on assessing the different
        potential sources of uncertainty in any particular application, coupled with a lack of clear
        guidance about which methods might be useful in different circumstances. They note that in
        general, uncertainty analysis is not too difficult to perform and provide list of relevant
        software that is available. Since, [Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] review, the research
        publications on uncertainty analysis in hydrological modelling has increased substantially,
        with many new tools/techniques and reviews available (see for example the recent review by
          [Uusitalo<emphasis role="italic"> et al.</emphasis>, 2015]. These tools will be reviewed
        as part of
        (<?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T171409+1100" comment="need to add"?>insert
        ref<?oxy_comment_end?>) to provide guidance for practitioners on which is applicable for
        different situations in the context of design flood estimation. The continued increases in
        computational power have reduced the computational costs of uncertainty analysis, which
        reduces the difficulty in undertaking uncertainty analysis. </para>
        <para>In summary, [Pappenberger and Beven, 2006] conclude that in the past many modeling and
        decision-making processes have ignored uncertainty analysis and it could be argued that
        under many circumstances it simply would not have mattered to the eventual outcome. However,
        they note that the arguments for uncertainty analysis
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>[after Morgan,
        1994<?oxy_custom_end?>] are compelling because (1) it makes the modeller think about the
        processes involved and the decisions based on our model results, (2) it makes predictions of
        different experts more comparable and leads to a transparent science, (3) it allows a more
        fundamental retrospective analysis and allows new or revised decisions to be based on the
        full understanding of the problem and not only a partial snapshot, and (4) decision makers
        and the public have the right to know all limitations in order to make up their own minds
        and lobby for their individual causes . </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Sources of uncertainty in context of design flood estimation</title>
        <para>The previous section outlined the practical advantages of undertaking uncertainty
          analysis. The first step of undertaking uncertainty analysis is to identify the various
          sources of uncertainty in the modelling processes (see section X for more detailed
          overview of these steps). To raise awareness of the various sources of uncertainty in the
          context of design flood estimation, this section will outline the various sources of
          uncertainty and identify how these sources of uncertainty manifest themselves in the two
          common techniques used for design flood estimation; the flood frequency analysis and
          catchment modelling approaches to design flood estimation. The primary drivers of each of
          the sources of uncertainty will then also be discussed. </para>
        <para>The various sources of uncertainty that are relevant to design flood estimation are
          outlined as follows: </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Predictive Uncertainty</emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Predictive uncertainty represents the total uncertainty in the predictions of
          interest, typically the estimates of the design flood. It is comprised of the various
          sources of uncertainty that are outlined below, including data uncertainty, parametric
          uncertainty, structural uncertainty, regionalisation uncertainty (if relevant) and deep
          uncertainty (if relevant). This total predictive uncertainty is what used as input to the
          decision making uncertainty framework, to provide reliable predictions. The magnitude of
          the total predictive uncertainty and the relative contribution of the various sources of
          uncertainty is of obvious interest. The magnitude provides an indication of the total
          uncertainty fo the predictions, while the relative contribution highlights which sources
          of uncertainty are the key contributors and which can be reduced. </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Data Uncertainty</emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Data uncertainty is a key source of predictive uncertainty. The more uncertain the
        data used to inform the methods used to estimate the peak flows, the more uncertainty in the
        predictions of the peak flows. The definition of “data” is a challenging one in the context
        of design flood estimation since in each step of the modelling process, the data used an
        input maybe based on the output of a prior modelling process, rather than actual
        measurements. Data uncertainty is dependent on the quality and number of measurements
        undertaken to inform that data.
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Need some examples of
        streamflow data and rainfall data uncertainty<?oxy_custom_end?></para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Parametric Uncertainty </emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Design flood estimates relay on using mathematical models to predict design floods.
          These models are estimated using time series of uncertain data with finite length. These
          limitations induce uncertainty in the estimates of these parameters, called parametric
          uncertainty. This parametric uncertainty would occur even if the mathematical model were
          exact. The magnitude of this parametric uncertainty, decreases as the length of the time
          series of data increases and increases when the uncertainty of the data increases. When
          time series are short and/or uncertainty in the data are high then parametric uncertainty
          can contribute significantly to total predictive uncertainty. </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Structural Uncertainty </emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Structural uncertainty refers to the uncertainty in the mathematical model used to
        provide the predictions of the peak flows. It is a consequence of the simplifying
        assumptions made in approximating the actual environmental system with a mathematical
        hypothesis [Renard<emphasis role="italic"> et al.</emphasis>, 2010]. The structural error of
        a hydrological model depends the model formulation, etc,.
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>need some examples of
        structural uncertainty <?oxy_custom_end?></para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Regionalisation Uncertainty </emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Regionalisation uncertainty refers to the uncertainty induced when there is a
        geographical migration of hydrological information from data rich location to a data-poor
        location. This is an extension of the concepts of regionalisation of hydrological model
        parameters, as outlined by [Buytaert and Beven, 2009]. In the context in of design flood
        estimation is refers to any information that is transferred from one site to another, and
        could include the parameters of the flood frequency distribution, the parameters of the
        runoff routing model, the loss model or the design rainfall used in the catchment modelling
        approach. Ii is a function of the predictive uncertainty of the original application of the
        model at the data-rich location (which is a dependent on the structural, parametric and data
        uncertainty at that data-rich site) and the regionalisation model used to transfer
        information from one site to another. Given there are large number of sources of uncertainty
        in regionalisation uncertainty, it can induce significant predictive uncertainty, when there
        is very limited at-site data.
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Need mention cases where
        regional information can reduce uncertainty <?oxy_custom_end?></para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Deep
              <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T171856+1100" comment="Look in Holger Maiers recent papers for a definition "?>Uncertainty<?oxy_comment_end?>
            </emphasis></para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Deep uncertainty refers to the sources of uncertainty that impact on the robustness of
        design but are difficult to assign apriori probabilities measures to. It acknowledges that
        practitioners and decision makers may not be able to enumerate all sources of uncertainty in
        a system nor their associated probabilities [Herman<emphasis role="italic"> et
          al.</emphasis>, 2014]. It is related to the emerging field of robust decision making,
        where it is assumed that future states of the world are deeply uncertainty and instead of
        assigning probabilities, it seeks to identify robust strategies which perform well across
        the range of plausible future states. In the context of design flood estimation, examples of
        deep uncertainty could include the effects of climate change, because the different
        scenarios used for future greenhouse gas emissions cannot be assigned probabilities, another
        example might be future landuse changes within a catchment, because it depends on variety of
        political, social and economic factors, which can be difficult to reliably assign
        probabilities. This source of uncertainty requires a different approach to the other
        sources, where scenario analysis is used to test the system and identify thresholds where
        significant failures occur. This approach has seen recent application in analysing water
        resources systems for long-term drought planning
        <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T171312+1100" comment="Need to add"?>(insert
        refs<?oxy_comment_end?>), however the application in flood design is limited. Given this is
        still a burgeoning area with significant research required, the approaches to treat this
        source of uncertainty will not be further considered in the scope of this uncertainty in
        ARR. </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title><anchor xml:id="_Ref415574763"/>Raising awareness of the sources of uncertainty in
          techniques used for design flood estimation </title>
      <para>In this section, it will be illustrated how to identify the sources of uncertainty for
        the two common techniques used for design flood estimation; flood frequency analysis and
        catchment modelling. The identification of the sources of uncertainty involves the following
        steps</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Identify the information required for each step of the methods</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Identify the potential sources of uncertainty in the information required for each
            of the steps</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>Uncertainty is related to the level of information (i.e. available of at-site data, its
        length and quality). For the purposes of this illustration, two different scenarios of
        available information will be considered (a) Using at-site data (b) No at-site data
        available, using regional information only. In practise, the level of information will be
        commonly be somewhere in between these two scenario, nonetheless these two scenarios provide
        convenient “use” case, to illustrate the identification of the sources of
        uncertainty.</para>
      <para>The relative contribution of each of these sources of uncertainty to the total
        predictive uncertainty is catchment specific, and depend on a range of factors (outlined
        below). Hence, to evaluate and determine the dominant source of uncertainty in a particular
        catchment requires a rigourous uncertainty analysis. Hence the following description will
        focus on describing the various source of uncertainty for each of the steps in both ffa and
        CM and identify the factors that will impact on the magnitude of that particular source. In
        any particular combination of information available means that one source could dominant the
        other. Hence in the following descriptions, each uncertainty source will not be described as
        low or high, rather the description will identify what increases or decreases the magnitude
        of the sources uncertainty. </para>
      <para>FFA</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Estimate flood frequency distribution (FFD) parameters</para>
            <orderedlist numeration = "loweralpha">
            <listitem>
              <para>Using at-site data</para>
            
          
        
      
      <para>Data uncertainty</para>
      <para>When using at-site streamflow data to estimate the FFD, the data uncertainty in this
        streamflow data is a source of uncertainty. The factors that effect the magnitude of this
        source of uncertainty are primarily the quality of the rating curve used to estimate the
        streamflow, the number of gaugings (and their quality), the degree of extrapolation of the
        rating, the stability of the rating curve, among others, insert refs to BARATIN</para>
      <para>Parametric Uncertainty</para>
      <para>As parameters of the FFD are estimated based on limited time series of data, this
        induces uncertainty in the parameters. This parametric uncertainty is determined by the
        length of data (uncertainty increases as the length decreases) and the quality of the data
        (parametric uncertainty increases as data uncertainty increases) </para>
      <para>Structural Uncertainty</para>
      <para>The source of structural uncertainty is the assumed form of the food frequency
        distribution probability model, i.e. log-normal, log pearson III etc. When calibrating to
        as-site data, this source of uncertainty can be checked by comparing against the observed
        data, to determine if the quality of the fit to observed data. </para>
            </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Using regional information without at-site data</para>
        
      
      <para>Data, Parametric, and Structural uncertainty</para>
      <para>When there is no at-site data, then regional information is used to inform the
        parameters and the choice of the probability model used for the flood frequency
        distribution. For this case, there data uncertainty is not a source of uncertainty, however
        the parametric uncertainty is higher than case (a), because no as-site data is available,
        and the structural uncertainty is also high than case (a) because no at-site data is
        available to evaluated if the chosen probability model for the flood frequency distribution
        is appropriate. </para>
      <para>Regionalisation Uncertainty</para>
      <para>When using regional information there is also regionalisation uncertainty because the
        parameters of the flood frequency has been transferred from another catchment. All the
        sources of uncertainty that contribute to the regionalisation uncertainty as described
        previously will be relevant to this source of uncertainty </para>
      
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
          <listitem>
          <para>Predicting design floods using FFA</para>
        
      
      <para>In this step 2 of predicting design floods using FFA, the data, parametric and
        structural uncertainty sources identified in step 1 will be present. A additional
        contributor to the structural uncertainty when predicting design floods with AEP beyond the
        range of the streamdata (eg. AEP of 1 in 100 year based on 30 years of streamflow data) is
        the assumption that the chosen probability model will provide a reliable estimate of design
        floods under extrapolation to the the AEP 1 in 100 year or 1 in 200 year flood. This
        additional source of structural uncertainty will be present, irrespective of case (a) or
        case (b) levels of information. A longer time series of at-site streamflow data, and hence a
        lower degree of extrapolation will decrease, but not eliminate, he magnitude of this source
        of uncertainty.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Catchment Modeling (CM) approach to estimating design
          floods</emphasis></para>
      <para>The catchment modelling approach to design flood estimation relies on estimates of the
        design rainfall, which is converted into effective rainfall using a loss model and then used
        as input into runoff-routing model (calibrated to a limited number of rainfall-runoff
        events) to simulated flow events and therefore provide estimates of the design flood. The
        steps of this approach are at (1) Estimate the parameters of runoff-routing model (2)
        Estimate the loss model parameters (3) Estimate the design rainfall and </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
        <para>Estimate runoff-routing model and loss model parameters</para>
      <para>The parameters for the runoff-routing model and the loss model are usually calibrated
        jointly using rainfall-runoff events in a given catchment. There are distinct components of
        the catchment modelling processes, however as their sources of uncertainty are similar, they
        will be discussed together. </para>
      <orderedlist numeration = "loweralpha">
        <listitem> 
        <para> Using at-site data</para>
      <para>Data Uncertainty </para>
      <para>Runoff-routing models (e.g. RORB) and loss models (e.g. required in the catchment
        modelling approach are typically calibrated to at-site rainfall-runoff event data. In this
        calibration step, the data uncertainty is the uncertainty in the streamflow data (discussed
        previously) and the additional uncertainty in the rainfall data, which as discussed
        previously, increases as the rainfall gauge density within the catchment decreases. </para>
      <para>Parametric Uncertainty</para>
      <para>The runoff-routing model loss model have parameters estimated through calibration to a
        limited number of rainfall-runoff events. This source of parametric uncertainty will
        decreases as the number of events decreases, and the consistency of the parameter estimates
        between events also increases. If the parameter estimates vary significantly between events,
        this will increase the parametric uncertainty</para>
      <para>Structural Uncertainty</para>
      <para>As the runoff routing model and the loss models represents a mathematical simplification
        of the actual catchment processes, will be a source of structural uncertainty. As the fit to
        the data used for calibration increases this source of uncertainty will decrease, but will
        not be eliminated. If the complexity of the runoff-routing model increases, e.g. move from
        lumped to a spatially distributed model, may potentially decreased the structural
        uncertainty, however, with a spatially distributed model the challenge becomes estimating
        the parameters over a spatial grid. Hence, if there is a lack of spatial streamflow and
        rainfall data to calibrate the model, than there is a potentially a shift from structural
        uncertainty to parametric uncertainty, which may results in no reduction the total
        predictive uncertainty.</para>
        </listitem> 
        <listitem>
          <para>Regional information only</para>
      <para>Data, Parametric, and Structural uncertainty</para>
      <para>Similar to FFA, when there is no at-site data, the regional information is used to
        inform the parameter estimates, and choice of runoff-routing and loss model. For this case,
        there is data uncertainty is not a source of uncertainty, however the parametric uncertainty
        is higher than case (a), because no as-site data is available, and the structural
        uncertainty is also high than case (a) because no at-site data is available to evaluated if
        the runoff-routing model or loss model is is appropriate.</para>
      <para>Regionalisation Uncertainty</para>
      <para>When using regional information there is also regionalisation uncertainty because the
        parameters of the runoff-routing model and loss model have been transferred from another
        catchment. All the sources of uncertainty that contribute to the regionalisation uncertainty
        as described previously will be relevant to this source of uncertainty, but they will apply
        both to the loss model and the runoff-routing model. In comparison to regionalisation of
        flood frequency distribution which is relatively well advanced
        <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151204T173319+1100" comment="Need to add. "?>(insert
        refs)<?oxy_comment_end?> , the regionalisation of runoff-routing models and loss models is
        still relatively unreliable (insert refs) and hence the regionalisation uncertainty of
        runoff-routing and loss models is likely to far larger than regionalisation of flood
        frequency distributions. </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <para>Estimating design rainfall and the temporal and spatial patterns</para>
      <para>In the majority of cases practitioners will use the design rainfall estimates provided
        by the Bureau of Meteorology, rather than undertake an IFD analysis of the observed rainfall
        data within a catchment, hence only the case when regional information is available will be
        considered in this description. There are many similarities to sources of uncertainty in the
        FFA, except the goal is to estimate extreme rainfall events rather than flow events. </para>
      <para>Data, Parametric, Structural and Regionalisation Uncertainty, </para>
      <para>The source of data uncertainty is rainfall gauge density and the length of rainfall data
        across Australia, is highly variable in different parts of Australia and with far lower
        gauge density and shorter records for subdaily rainfall data then daily. This can induce
        significant data uncertainty in the design rainfall estimates. Similar to FFA, a probability
        model is used to estimate the extreme rainfall events (e.g. AEP of 1 in 100 year) based on
        the limited rainfall data available. This probability model has parametric uncertainty,
        which increases as the length and quality of the rainfall data decreases. There is
        structural uncertainty in the choice of the probability model for extreme rainfall, and this
        is increased when the probability model is used to extrapolate to from shorter rainfall time
        series to extreme events. This is particular problematic for subdaily rainfall, because
        records are typically shorter than daily rainfall data. There is regionalisation uncertainty
        because the design rainfall estimates are regionalised to areas with limited gauged data. </para>
      <para>This design rainfall for an event is then disaggregated into a time series using
        temporal patterns, they have their own sources of data, parametric, structural and
        regionalisation uncertainty, because they are estimated based on rainfall data from outside
        the catchment of interest. If spatial patterns are used to distribute design rainfall
        spatially across a catchment, then they will similar sources of uncertainty. </para>
      <para>Considering the high spatial and temporal variability of rainfall process these
        uncertainties in design rainfall are unlikely to be small. </para>
      </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Predicting design floods using catchment models</para>
        
      
      <para>When a catchment modelling approaches is used to predict design floods, the data,
        parametric, structural and regionalistion uncertainty identified in steps 1-2 will be
        present. There are two sources of addition uncertainty, parameter uncertainty and structural
        uncertainty. These sources of uncertainty are because the runoff-routing and loss models in
        step 1 are calibrated on runoff events are then extrapolated to larger design flow events,
        e.g. 1 in 100 year AEP. The source of uncertainty is whether the parameters and model
        structural based on calibrations to (inevitable) smaller rainfall-runoff events can be
        applied to the larger design flow events.</para>
      <para>Total predictive uncertainty</para>
      <para>Table 1 provides a summary of the various sources of uncertainty for the two different
        techniques (flood frequency analysis versus catchment modelling) for design flood
        estimation. It can be seen that due to the larger number of components in the catchment
        modelling, there are a greater number of sources of uncertainty in this process, compared
        with flood frequency analysis. Typically when there are a larger number of sources of
        uncertainty the total predictive uncertainty is higher. Based on this analysis it can be
        concluded that catchment modelling is likely to have a higher total predictive uncertainty
        compared with flood frequency analysis. However, the relative magnitude of the total
        predictive uncertainty for the two different techniques would vary on a catchment basis. </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
        <para> </para>
          <table frame="void" width="1170">
        <caption>Summary table on sources of uncertainty in different techniques used for design
          flood estimation for different levels of information available</caption>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="17%"/>
        <col width="17%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2"><emphasis role="bold">Steps</emphasis></td>
            <td rowspan="2"><emphasis role="bold">Information available</emphasis></td>
            <td colspan="4"><emphasis role="bold">Sources of Uncertainty</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Data</emphasis></td>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Parametric</emphasis></td>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Regionalisation</emphasis></td>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Structural</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td colspan="6">Flood Frequency Analysis (FFA)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">1. Estimate FFA model parameters</td>
            <td>a. At-site data</td>
            <td>yes - streamflow</td>
            <td>yes</td>
            <td>No</td>
            <td>yes</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>b. Regional information only </td>
            <td>No</td>
            <td>yes – higher than case(a)</td>
            <td>yes</td>
            <td>yes – higher than case(a)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2. Predict design floods using FFA</td>
            <td>Based on step 1</td>
            <td>n/a - identified in step 1</td>
            <td>n/a - identified in step 1</td>
            <td>n/a - identified in step 1</td>
            <td>yes - in addition to step 1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td colspan="6">Catchment Modelling (CM)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">1. Estimate parameters for runoff-routing model and loss model </td>
            <td>a. At-site data</td>
            <td>yes – rainfall and streamflow</td>
            <td>yes</td>
            <td>No</td>
            <td>yes</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>b. Regional information only </td>
            <td>No</td>
            <td>yes – higher than case(a)</td>
            <td>yes</td>
            <td>yes – higher than case(a)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2. Estimate design rainfall and its temporal/spatial patterns</td>
            <td>Based on Bureau of Meteorology IFD</td>
            <td>yes – rainfall</td>
            <td>yes</td>
            <td>yes</td>
            <td>yes</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>3. Predict design floods using CM </td>
            <td>Based on steps 1-2</td>
            <td>n/a – identified in steps 1-2</td>
            <td>yes – in addition to steps 1-2</td>
            <td>n/a – identified in steps 1-2</td>
            <td>yes – in addition to steps 1-2</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Summary</title>
        <para>This overview of the uncertainty in design flood frequency estimation has identified
        the two different types of uncertainty in the context of design flood estimation, aleatory
        uncertainty (due to natural variability) and epistemic uncertainty (due to knowledge
        uncertainty). It then outlined the motivation for undertaking uncertainty analysis, which is
        to provide more informed and transparent information on the uncertainty in the design flood
        estimates to enable practitioners and design makers to make better judgements on the
        appropriate design. The major sources of uncertainty in the context of design flood
        estimation were then outlined, and include data (uncertainty in measurements), parametric
        uncertainty of the models used, structural uncertainty in the models mathematical
        representation of the physical process, regionalisation uncertainty when information is
        moved from data-rich to data-poor catchments, and the total predictive uncertainty, which is
        composed of the elements of the individual sources of uncertainty. To raise awareness of the
        sources of uncertainty in the different techniques used for design flood estimation were
        identified. The conclusion, was that comparing flood frequency analysis and catchment
        modelling, due to the larger number of components, the catchment modelling technique has a
        larger number of sources of uncertainty than flood frequency analysis, and hence this will
        likely lead to a higher predictive uncertainty. However, the magnitude of the total
        predictive uncertainty is catchment specific, depending the availability of data and
        knowledge of the processes that driver design flood events.  </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>References</title>
        <para>Ang, A., and W. Tang (2007), <emphasis role="italic">Probability Concepts in
            Engineering</emphasis>, 2nd edition ed., Wiley, United States of America.</para>
        <para>Botto, A., D. Ganora, F. Laio, and P. Claps (2014), Uncertainty compliant design flood
          estimation, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resour Res</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic"
            >50</emphasis>(5), 4242-4253, 10.1002/2013WR014981</para>
        <para>Buytaert, W., and K. Beven (2009), Regionalization as a learning process, <emphasis
            role="italic">Water Resour Res</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">45</emphasis>(11),
          n/a-n/a, 10.1029/2008WR007359</para>
        <para>Herman, J. D., H. B. Zeff, P. M. Reed, and G. W. Characklis (2014), Beyond optimality:
          Multistakeholder robustness tradeoffs for regional water portfolio planning under deep
          uncertainty, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resour Res</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic"
            >50</emphasis>(10), 7692-7713, 10.1002/2014WR015338</para>
        <para>Pappenberger, F., and K. J. Beven (2006), Ignorance is bliss: Or seven reasons not to
          use uncertainty analysis, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resour Res</emphasis>, <emphasis
            role="italic">42</emphasis>(5), 8, W05302</para>
        <para>10.1029/2005wr004820</para>
        <para>Renard, B., D. Kavetski, G. Kuczera, M. Thyer, and S. W. Franks (2010), Understanding
          predictive uncertainty in hydrologic modeling: The challenge of identifying input and
          structural errors, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resour. Res.</emphasis>, <emphasis
            role="italic">46</emphasis>(5), W05521, 10.1029/2009wr008328</para>
        <para>Uusitalo, L., A. Lehikoinen, I. Helle, and K. Myrberg (2015), An overview of methods
          to evaluate uncertainty of deterministic models in decision support, <emphasis
            role="italic">Environmental Modelling &amp; Software</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic"
            >63</emphasis>, 24-31, <link
            xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envsoft.2014.09.017"
            >http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envsoft.2014.09.017</link></para>
        <para>Wood, E. F., and I. Rodríguez-Iturbe (1975), Bayesian inference and decision making
          for extreme hydrologic events, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resour Res</emphasis>,
            <emphasis role="italic">11</emphasis>(4), 533-542, 10.1029/WR011i004p00533</para>
      </section>
     
    </section>


  <section xml:id="b1_ch2_s_u0c4v">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Abbs and Rafter (2008)</para>

    <para>Bates, B. C., Z. W. Kundzewicz, S. Wu, and J. P. Palutikof (2008):
    <emphasis role="italic">Climate Change and Water. Technical Paper of the
    Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, </emphasis>Rep., 210 pp, IPCC
    Secretariat, Geneva.</para>

    <para>Church, J.A., N.J.White, J.RHunter, K.L.McInnes (2012) <emphasis
    role="italic">Sea level. In A Marine Climate Change Impacts and Adaptation
    Report Card for Australia 2012 </emphasis>(Eds. E.S. Poloczanska, A.J.
    Hobday and A.J. Richardson). &lt;http://www.oceanclimatechange.org.au&gt;.
    ISBN: 978-0-643-10928-5</para>

    <para>CSIRO and Australian Bureau of Meteorology. (2007). <emphasis
    role="italic">Climate Change in Australia, CSIRO and Bureau of Meteorology
    Technical Report</emphasis>, 140 pp.
    www.climatechangeinaustralia.gov.au</para>

    <para>Fowler, H.J., and M.Ekstrom (2009): <emphasis
    role="italic">Multi-model ensemble estimates of climate change impacts on
    UK seasonal precipitation extremes</emphasis>, International Journal of
    Climatology, 29, 385-416.</para>

    <para>Groisman PY, Karl TR, Easterling DR, Knight RW, Jamason PF, Hennessy
    KJ, Suppiah R, Page CM, Wibig J, Fortuniak K, Razuvaev VN, Douglas A,
    Forland E and Zhai PM (1999): <emphasis role="italic">Changes in the
    probability of heavy precipitation: Important indicators of climatic
    change,</emphasis>Climatic Change, 42, 243–283.</para>

    <para>Hunter, J., (2007): Estimating sea-level extremes in a world of
    uncertain sea-level rise, 5th Flood Management Conference, Warrnambool,
    Australia, 9-12 October 2007.</para>

    <para>IPCC (2007): Climate Change 2007: Synthesis Report. Contribution of
    Working Groups I, II and III to the Fourth Assessment Report of the
    Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change [Core Writing Team, Pachauri,
    R.K and Reisinger, A. (eds.)]. IPCC, Geneva, Switzerland, 104 pp.</para>

    <para>IPCC (2012): <emphasis role="italic">Workshop Report of the
    Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Workshop on Socio-Economic
    Scenarios</emphasis> [Edenhofer, O., R. Pichs-Madruga, Y. Sokona, V.
    Barros, C.B. Field, T. Zwickel, S. Schloemer, K. Ebi, M. Mastrandrea, K.
    Mach, C. von Stechow (eds.)]. IPCC Working Group III Technical Support
    Unit, Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research, Potsdam Germany, pp.
    51.</para>

    <para>Jones et al. (2012)</para>

    <para>Langbein, W.B. (1949): Annual floods and the partial-duration flood
    series, Transactions, American Geophysical Union, Vol 30, No. 6, pp
    879-881</para>

    <para>Nicholls N and Alexander L (2007): <emphasis role="italic">Has the
    climate become more variable or extreme? Progress 1992</emphasis><emphasis
    role="italic">‑</emphasis><emphasis role="italic">2006</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">Progress in Physical Geography, </emphasis>31,
    77‑87.</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, DH (ed) (1987) Australian Rainfall and Runoff – A Guide to
    Flood Estimation, Institution of Engineers, Australia, Barton, ACT,
    1987.</para>

    <para>Trenberth KE (2011): <emphasis role="italic">Changes in
    precipitation with climate change</emphasis>. Clim Res 47:123–138.</para>

    <para>Westra, S., L.V. Alexander, F.W. Zwiers (2013): <emphasis
    role="italic">Global increasing trends in annual maximum daily
    precipitation</emphasis>. Journal of Climate, in press,
    doi:10.1175/JCLI-D-12-00502.1</para>

    <para>White C.J., Grose M.R., Corney S.P., Bennett J.C., Holz G.K.,
    Sanabria L.A., McInnes K.L., Cechet R.P., Gaynor S.M. and Bindoff N.L.
    (2010): <emphasis role="italic">Climate Futures for Tasmania: extreme
    events technical report</emphasis>, Antarctic Climate and Ecosystems
    Cooperative Research Centre, Hobart, Tasmania.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
