<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b9_ch3">
    <info><title>Philosophy of Urban Stormwater Management</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/coombes_peter.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/roso_steve.xml"/>

    </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td>Chapter Status</td>
      <td>Final</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>14/5/2019</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_zelwi">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Urban stormwater management is historically described as the hydraulic design of urban
      drainage networks that safely conveys stormwater runoff to receiving environments. The
      industry’s approach to urban water management in Australia has changed significantly since
      the establishment of centralised and separate water supply, stormwater and wastewater paradigm
      in the 1800s. </para>
    <para>Urban water management evolved over time to include waterways protection, mitigation of
      stormwater quality, use of Water Sensitive Urban Design (WSUD), Integrated Water Cycle
      Management (IWCM), Water Sensitive Cities (WSC), Integrated Water Management (IWM), and many
      other approaches. Although these approaches are relatively new, they have wide adoption and
      support in legislation and policies for water management throughout Australia. Similar changes
      in approach to urban stormwater management in other countries include Sustainable Urban
      Drainage Systems (SuDS) <citation>b9_c3_r48</citation> and Low Impact Design (LID)
        <citation>b9_c3_r49</citation>. Consequently, the approach to urban stormwater management
      includes water supply and is based on retention and conveyance of stormwater runoff to meet
      multi-purpose design objectives that enhance livability of urban areas, mitigate nuisance, and
      avoid damage to property and loss of life.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_69q9x">
    <title>The Journey from 1987 to 2016</title>
    <para>Australia has experienced considerable improvement in urban water management since the
      1800s, supported and underpinned by publications such as ARR <citation>b9_c3_r21</citation>.
      Stormwater drainage in Australia evolved from combined sewers that rapidly discharged the
      accumulated rubbish, sewage, sullage and stormwater from streets to waterways
        <citation>b9_c3_r32,b9_c3_r17</citation>. The impact on waterways and amenity of urban
      settlements drove the separation of sewage and stormwater infrastructure. Filling of swamps
      and development of contributing catchments to accommodate population growth resulted in
      frequent flooding of early settlements. Drainage solutions emerged to avoid stagnant water,
      local flooding and health impacts in urban areas. Nation building works  programs during
      economic depressions (for example in 1890 and 1920) and following wars provided large scale
      drainage infrastructure throughout Australia.</para>
    <para>The ARR 1987 guideline focused on collection and conveyance of peak stormwater flows in
      drainage networks. The guideline’s advice on hydrologic and hydraulic analysis was consistent
      with the emerging computer age and hand calculation while programmable calculator and computer
      methods were discussed. The increasing complexity of the different methods and an associated
      requirement for use of computers was highlighted.</para>
    <para>Use of statistical design rainfall bursts was recommended to calculate inflows to drainage
      networks and the Rational Method was described as the best known method for estimation of
      urban stormwater runoff. The main objective of urban drainage was to convey stormwater from
      streets and adjoining properties without nuisance from minor rain events, and to avoid
      property flooding and associated damage from major rain events (the minor/major design
      approach). </para>
    <para>In contrast to the introductory comments, urban drainage was presented as a prescriptive
      approach using pipes to convey minor flows, with streets, open space and trunk drains used to
      transport major flows. Trunk drainage was described to include designs for open channels,
      detention and retention basins to control peak discharge, and bridges. While urban stormwater
      management was presented and interpreted as a drainage approach, Chapter 14 in ARR 1987
      highlighted how urban drainage solutions should also:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>limit pollutants entering receiving waters;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>consider water conservation;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>integrate overall planning schemes;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>be based on measured or observed real system behaviour;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>be viewed in relation to the total urban system; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>maximise benefits to society.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Drainage solutions solely focused on developed catchment and were mostly designed by
      engineers. The simplicity of methods for estimating stormwater runoff implied accuracy and
      certainty of design performance for many users. Urban water management further evolved in the
      mid-1990s to cover protection of waterways, mitigation of urban stormwater quality, WSUD
        <citation>b9_c3_r27</citation>, IWM and IWCM <citation>b9_c3_r52</citation>  approaches.
      Nevertheless urban stormwater runoff creates complex impacts on urban stream ecosystems and
      receiving waterways <citation>b9_c3_r44,b9_c3_r40</citation>. Increases in runoff volumes and
      rates from urban areas (flow regimes) contribute to degradation of riparian ecosystems and
      promotes geomorphic changes within urban streams <citation>b9_c3_r45</citation>. Although
      these approaches are relatively new, they have subsequently gained widespread adoption and
      support throughout Australia. To support this evolution, Engineers Australia published
      'Australian Runoff Quality – A Guide To Water Sensitive Urban Design' in 2006
        <citation>b9_c3_r12</citation>.</para>
    <para>The acceptance of WSUD, IWCM and related approaches is manifested in three significant
      ways:</para>
    <para><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the development of benchmark projects (e.g; Lynbrook estate
              <citation>b9_c3_r18</citation>, Fig Tree Place <citation>b9_c3_r10</citation> and
            Little Stringy Bark Creek <citation>b9_c3_r46</citation>) that provided evidence that
            these new approaches were successful;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the creation of local policies and plans for integrated water management; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the adoption of policies for sustainable water management by state and federal
            governments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>Recent droughts, such as the 'millennium drought' also triggered many other
      changes in the urban water sector, largely associated with water conservation, harvesting,
      recycling and reuse <citation>b9_c3_r2</citation>.</para>
    <para>Urban areas are complex systems that are subject to dynamic interaction of economic,
      social, physical and environmental processes across time and space
        <citation>b9_c3_r51,b9_c4_r113,b9_c3_r50</citation>. Continuous intervention is required to
      renew urban economic, technical and social structures to maintain human welfare and protect
      ecosystem services <citation>b9_c3_r51,b9_c3_r53</citation>. Understanding these processes
      into the future also encounters the uncertainty created by non-stationary data that describes
      past processes. Design and analysis processes should include distributed approaches to account
      for the time based dynamics of essential data. The integrated nature of contemporary water
      management approaches is different to the objectives and design solutions envisaged in 1987.
      Urban water management is now required to consider multiple objectives (e.g. resilience,
      livability, sustainability and affordability) and the perspective of many disciplines.
      Advances in computing power, more available data and associated research also allows the
      analysis of increasingly complex systems to understand the trade-offs between multiple
      objectives <citation>b9_c3_r6</citation>. Design of urban water management seeks to integrate
      land and water planning. Use of more comprehensive datasets revealed a greater range of
      potential outcomes that needs understanding to develop integrated solutions.</para>
    <para>According to <citation>b9_c3_r1+1</citation>, the urban designer aims at managing the
      impact of urban stormwater runoff ‘at source’ and at multiple scales by retaining stormwater
      in landscapes and soil profiles, rainwater harvesting and disconnecting impervious surfaces
      from drainage networks <citation>b9_c3_r23</citation>. Consistent with the philosophy of
      source control and systems analysis, stormwater runoff is now seen as an opportunity and is
      valued as a resource <citation>b9_c3_r5,b9_c3_r20,b9_c3_r19</citation>. Modern design criteria
      may include analysis of the volumes, timing and frequency of stormwater runoff to determine
      peak flow rates, water quality and requirements to mimic natural flow regimes to protect
      waterway health <citation>b9_c3_r25</citation>.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_84gfv">
    <title>Evolving Opportunities and Challenges</title>
    <para>Urbanisation generates dramatic changes within the natural water cycle. Impervious
      surfaces and directly connected drainage infrastructure decreases evapotranspiration and
      infiltration to soil profiles. This increases the volume and frequency of stormwater runoff
      and reduces baseflows; which can create flooding and affect waterway health. Drainage
      strategies that are reliant on conveyance can transfer additional stormwater runoff and
      pollutant loads generated by urban areas to other locations. The different regional scale
      responses within a river basin and a linked urban catchment are presented in <xref
        linkend="b9_ch3_f_q5x14"/>. </para>
    <para>The impervious surfaces and hydraulically efficient infrastructure associated with urban
      catchments increases the magnitude and frequency of stormwater runoff whilse reducing the
      infiltration to soil profiles and subsequent baseflows in waterways. The accumulation of
      stormwater flows within urban catchments is highlighted. The first response at A is the
      (undisturbed) ecosystem upstream from urban impacts, the second response at B includes the
      impact of water extraction to supply the urban area (changed flow regime in rivers created by
      water supply) and the third response at C includes water discharges from the urban catchment
      (changed flow and water quality regime from both stormwater runoff and wastewater discharges)
      into the river basin.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b9_ch3_f_q5x14">
      <title>Schematic of Traditional Urban Catchments and Cumulative Stormwater Runoff
        Processes</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9017.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para><xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_q5x14"/> demonstrates analysis and solutions at point D at the
      bottom of urban catchments; it can exclude understanding of impacts within the urban catchment
      (sub-catchments a-h) and external impacts to the river basin at B and C. Traditional analysis
      of urban catchments is from the perspective of rapid discharge and accumulation of stormwater
      via drainage networks (in sub-catchments a-h) with flow and water quality management at the
      bottom of the urban catchment (D) using retarding basins, constructed wetlands, and stormwater
      harvesting. However, the benefits for flood protection, improved stormwater quality, and
      protection of the health of waterways from this approach do not occur within the urban
      catchment upstream of point D.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_q5x14"/> also highlights how distributed land uses (allotments or
      properties) produce hydrographs of stormwater runoff into the street drainage system. This
      system accumulates stormwater runoff from multiple inputs, creating progressively larger
      volumes of stormwater runoff, which ultimately flows into urban waterways or adjoining
      catchments <citation>b9_c3_r22</citation>. This process results in significant changes in
      volume and timing of stormwater discharge to downstream environments.</para>
    <para>There has been an emerging understanding that this issue can be solved by viewing urban
      stormwater as an opportunity to supplement urban water supplies and enhance the amenity of
      urban areas <citation>b9_c3_r20,b9_c3_r31,b9_c3_r28</citation>. This includes development of
      green infrastructure and microclimates that reduce urban heat island effects. Urban catchments
      with impervious surfaces are substantially more efficient than conventional water supply
      catchments in translating rainfall into surface runoff. Rainwater and stormwater harvesting
      can extend supplies from regional reservoirs and the restoration of environmental flows in
      rivers subject to extractions for water supply <citation>b9_c3_r33</citation>. These insights
      are consistent with earlier applied research by <citation>b9_c3_r54+1</citation> that both
      volumes and peak flows of stormwater runoff are required to design stormwater infrastructure,
      and the local property scale is the building block of cumulative rainfall runoff processes
        <citation>b5_c3_r31</citation>. Reducing urban stormwater runoff volumes via harvesting and
      retention in upstream catchments can also decrease stormwater driven peak discharges and
      surcharges in wastewater infrastructure <citation>b9_c3_r6</citation>.There has been an
      emerging understanding that this issue can be solved</para>
    <para>Changes in land use, climate, increased density of urban areas and decline in hydraulic
      capacity of aging drainage networks can result in local flooding and damage to property.
      Climate change is expected to reduce annual rainfall and generate more intense rainfall events
      in a warming climate <citation>b9_c3_r21,b9_c3_r30</citation>. This will intensify the
      challenges of providing secure water supplies and mitigating urban stormwater runoff. There
      may also be the need to replace stormwater conveyance networks installed during post-war urban
      redevelopment that are nearing the end of useful life. In this situation, the capacity of an
      aging network or increased runoff from increasing development density can be supplemented by
      source control measures and integrated solutions <citation>b9_c3_r3</citation>. Integrated
      solutions and flexible approaches to design can avoid costly replacement of existing
      infrastructure.</para>
    <para>Flood management issues for many urban areas are driven by runoff discharged towards
      waterways (overland flooding) rather than from flood flows originating at waterways (fluvial
      flooding). There is a need to consider more extensive range of stormwater runoff events, from
      frequent to rare or extreme and the associated impacts on urban environments
        <citation>b9_c3_r26</citation>. Management of these flood related impacts require integrated
      management of the full spectrum of flood events (<xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_5w01k"/>).</para>
    <figure xml:id="b9_ch3_f_5w01k">
      <title>The Full Spectrum of Flood Events (Adapted from
        <citation>b9_c3_r26+1</citation>)</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9019.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para><xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_5w01k"/> highlights the evolving methods of analysis, including
      continuous simulation and Monte Carlo simulation of full storm volumes that are likely to be
      required to account for the full spectrum of rainfall events as defined by Exceedance per Year
      (EY) or Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP). The definition of rain events is currently a mix
      of assumptions regarding frequency and magnitude that is clarified in this version of ARR to
      allow effective advice on design of stormwater management schemes. This includes development
      of green infrastructure and microclimates with reduction of urban heat island effects.</para>
    <para>Strategic use of water efficiency, rainwater, stormwater and wastewater at multiple scales
      can supplement the performance of centralised water supply systems to provide more sustainable
      and affordable outcomes <citation>b9_c3_r24</citation>. These integrated strategies diminish
      the requirement to transport water, stormwater and wastewater across regions with associated
      reductions in costs of extension, renewal and operation of infrastructure
        <citation>b9_c3_r6</citation>. This leads to decreased requirement to augment regional water
      supplies and long run economic benefits. These strategies also focus on restoring more natural
      flow regimes in waterways and they will be beneficial in reducing remedial works in waterways
      and will provide reduction in size or footprint of quality treatment measures
        <citation>b9_c3_r23</citation>.</para>
    <para>Current approaches to stormwater management include separate design processes and
      infrastructure for flooding, drainage and water quality. Jurisdictional and institutional
      boundary conditions are often imposed on analysis <citation>b9_c3_r4,b9_c3_r11</citation>.
      Integrated design includes solutions that meet multiple objectives, the catchment boundaries
      of each element and aims to avoid redundant infrastructure. Realisation of these benefits is
      dependent on integrated design approaches that account for changes in the timing and volumes
      of stormwater runoff, and respond to multiple objectives. Analysis of the economic benefits of
      integrated designs and drainage networks should be evaluated across an entire system from the
      perspective of whole of society. The methods and objectives for estimating urban stormwater
      runoff and the design of pipe drainage networks from 1987 do not include these additional
      considerations. </para>
    <para>A challenge to integrated solutions is presented by engineering and economic methods of
      estimating performance that are reliant on average assumptions and judgements as inputs to
      empirical methods of estimating performance. Consequently, optimum design based on average
      assumptions and model approximations may not represent the actual integrated response of a
      project.</para>
    <para>Educated empirical input assumptions and estimation processes can be reasonably
      approximated as generic processes for known historical and static problems
        <citation>b9_c3_r16,b9_c3_r26</citation>. However, these processes may not replicate
      performance of multiple solutions within a system. For example, with respect to intersection
      of local water cycle solutions with town planning processes and regional infrastructure and,
      therefore, cannot understand or value a system that changes runoff behaviour from the smallest
      distributed scales (from the ‘bottom up’) <citation>b9_c3_r1,b9_c3_r6,b5_c3_r31</citation>.
      For example, cumulative actions at the smallest scale, such as retaining stormwater in the
      soil profile on each property can produce significant changes in responses throughout urban
      systems as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_tqq1b"/>.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b9_ch3_f_tqq1b">
      <title>Cumulative Impacts of Distributed Management</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9018.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>It also follows that historical ‘top down’ design processes may not evaluate distributed
      processes because a small proportion of the available data may be simplified as whole of
      system average or fixed inputs (such as a runoff coefficient and average rainfall intensity).
      Thus, the signals of linked distributed performance (such as local volume management measures)
      in a system are smoothed or completely lost by partial use of data as averages and by the
      scale of analysis. Therefore, there is no direct mechanism to capture cascading changes in
      behaviours throughout a system. This can lead to competing objectives (For example: local
      versus regional), inappropriate solutions and information disparity such as provision of a
      wetland and retarding or detention basin downstream of an urban area when management is
      required within the urban area to protect urban amenity, stream health and avoid local
      flooding. This paradox can only be resolved through a broader analysis framework which
      recognises location based principles of proportionality and efficient intervention.</para>
    <para>For example, consider the connectivity of contemporary water cycle networks presented in
        <xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_g7d2g"/>.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b9_ch3_f_g7d2g">
      <title>Schematic of the Connectivity of Urban Water Networks</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9020.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para><xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_g7d2g"/> shows that an input, or extraction at any point α or β,
      or an increase in water storage in a reservoir,  at location A, will have some influence on
      flows and capacities at many other points in the system. These in turn, will translate into
      changes in performance and costs across the linked networks of infrastructure. Similarly,
      changes in behaviour (demand) at any point in the system will generate different linked
      impacts a, b and c on water, wastewater and stormwater networks respectively. Analysis and
      design of integrated solutions needs to account for the linked dynamic nature of the urban
      water cycle and demography. The inclusion of rainwater and stormwater harvesting, and
      wastewater reuse further increases the level of connectivity of urban water networks.</para>
    <para>The historical practice for estimation of stormwater runoff rates and the design of
      drainage (conveyance) infrastructure is based on a methodology where all inputs, other than
      rainfall, are fixed variables. The fixed values of the input variables are selected to ensure
      that the exceedance probability of stormwater runoff is similar to that of regional rainfall
      statistics. However, catchments that contain cascading integrated solutions involving
      retention, slow drainage, harvesting of stormwater and disconnection of impervious surfaces
      require enhanced design methods <citation>b9_c3_r16,b9_c3_r29,b9_c3_r7</citation>. These
      emerging methods for analysis and design of integrated solutions include the following
      considerations:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Long sequences of rainfall that include full volumes of storm events are required to
          generate probabilistic designs of integrated solutions;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Peak rainfall events may not generate peak stormwater runoff from projects with
          integrated solutions;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The frequency of peak rainfall may not be equal to the frequency of peak stormwater
          runoff from integrated solutions;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Stormwater runoff from urban catchments is influenced by land use planning, and the
          connectivity and sequencing of integrated solutions across scales;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The probability distribution of the parameters that influence the performance of the
          integrated solutions (for example human behaviour, rainfall and soil processes) and the
          ultimate stormwater runoff behaviour are unknown for each project;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Integrated solutions often meet multiple objectives (for example water supply,
          stormwater drainage, management of stormwater quality, provision of amenity and protection
          of waterways) and are dependent on linked interactions with surrounding infrastructure;
          and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>We should be mindful that the limitations of design processes are not always apparent
          and diligence is required to ensure that substantial problems are avoided. </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In this situation, continuous simulation using historical or synthetic sequences of
      rainfall in a Monte Carlo framework may be required to understand the probability of
      stormwater runoff and the design of infrastructure <citation>b9_c3_r16,b9_c3_r26</citation>.
      <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T170954+1100" comment="sentence doesnt make sense"?><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0" mid="1"?>There<?oxy_comment_end?>
      are approximately 20,000 daily rainfall records with sufficient continuous rainfall records
      (more than 3,500) to allow continuous simulation using real or synthetic continuous rainfall
      records<?oxy_custom_end mid="1"?>. Similarly, the designer can use ensembles of
      <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T171159+1100" comment="need to be clear here. we are not providing full storm patterns and this phrase is used throughout chapter "?>full
      volumes design storm event<?oxy_comment_end?> to test an integrated design
      solution.<?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T171419+1100" comment="not sure about reference to 1987. 1987 is now replaced. maybe reword
"?>
      Assumptions and methods of analysis imposed by approval authorities in accordance with ARR
      1987 can constrain the use of more appropriate analysis techniques required for better
      understanding the behaviour of integrated solutions.<?oxy_comment_end?> Similarly, a default
      requirement by approval authorities for
      <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T171506+1100" comment="this chapter uses &quot;drainage(conveyance)&quot; when the other chapters i have read use conveyance"?>drainage
      (conveyance) networks<?oxy_comment_end?> that are designed using peak storm bursts alone can
      limit the adoption of innovative and integrated solutions.</para>
    <para>A combination of event based estimation techniques, directly or indirectly, may not
      reliably produce probabilistic design of drainage, water quality, and water or wastewater
      infrastructure within integrated strategies. While use of best available event based design
      approximations are an accepted default or deemed to comply approach for design of
      infrastructure, there is a need for more advanced methods for design of integrated
      solutions.</para>
    <para>The absence of an integrated approach to design and planning in stormwater catchments may
      lead to missed opportunities and poor investment decisions, which ultimately results in higher
      costs with diminished social and environmental benefits <citation>b9_c3_r9</citation>.
      Estimation of stormwater runoff and design of drainage (conveyance) networks for mitigation of
      urban flooding needs to be enhanced to provide integration with water cycle management within
      a systems framework.</para>
    <para>The definition and purpose of minor or major drainage system is unclear in the context of
      modern approaches to water cycle management. Replacement of minor or major drainage
      descriptions with a definition of managing nuisance or disaster respectively, would provide a
      clearer focus on the relative importance of both concepts. To avoid nuisance, one may be too
      focused on a prescriptive drainage approach to the minor system. A well-designed major system
      to avoid disaster is likely to allow more opportunity for integrated solutions that will also
      mitigate nuisance. We also need to be cognisant that water supply and stormwater quality
      options can also assist in avoiding disaster and mitigating nuisance.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_34r7g">
    <title>Urban Flooding</title>
    <para>Urban flooding may include overland
      <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T212946+1100" comment="think was described different in chapter 2- check

Also do we want to use term fluvial"?>(pluvial<?oxy_comment_end?>)
      flooding and fluvial flooding (river and creek flows). This distinction can be important as
      the two types of flooding have different behaviours that may require particular analysis and
      management approaches.</para>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_b805k">
      <title>Overland Flooding</title>
      <para>Overland flooding is typically generated by short durations (minutes to hours) of
        intense rainfall on small catchments up to approximately 1 km<superscript>2</superscript>
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T213505+1100" comment="reference for this statement? 

"?>in<?oxy_comment_end?>
        area. This rainfall causes significant concentrations of surface runoff at low points and
        depressions throughout the urban topography. These concentrations of flows continue
        downslope and discharge into larger natural waterways with defined banks such as creeks,
        rivers or lakes where flows become fluvial in character.</para>
      <para>Overland flooding can be responsible for significant damage. Adequate major flow paths
        must be provided or retained to manage these events. A stormwater management strategy is
        required that includes systematic identification of overland flow paths and design practices
        that recognise and respond to overland flood risks. Simple design practices such as slightly
        elevating property and floor levels above the surrounding terrain can effectively eliminate
        most overland flood risks.</para>
      <para>Approaches to analysis have been developed in recent years to assist identification of
        overland flow paths that involve use of two dimensional
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T214455+1100" comment="check hydraulic book for hydraulic or hydrdynamic ?"?>hydrodynamic<?oxy_comment_end?>
        models where
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T214339+1100" comment="replace with histroic or observed "?>real<?oxy_comment_end?>
        and design rainfall events are applied throughout sub-catchments. These methods use digital
        terrain models of land profiles that are usually derived from LiDAR and aerial
        photogrammetry information. Hydrodynamic models can predict the accumulation of runoff
        across these surfaces and the generation of concentrated flows. Depth
        and<?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T214535+1100" comment="insert x or times
"?>
        velocity depth<?oxy_comment_end?> thresholds can be applied to model outputs and mapped
        spatially to allow identification of the most significant accumulation of flow. A map of a
        fluvial flow path prepared using a two dimensional
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T214612+1100" comment="used hydrodynamic for the rest of tthis paragraph"?>hydraulic
        <?oxy_comment_end?>model is presented in <xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_wpfl5"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch3_f_wpfl5">
        <title>Example Overland Flow Path Map Generated Using a Two Dimensional Model.</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9060.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>This modelling approach is complex and is undertaken by a designer with suitable
        experience to ensure reliable outcomes. However, successful application of this method can
        be efficient and reveal a range of important stormwater management issues, including
        overland flow paths. </para>
      <para>Approaches to analysis with less complexity may be more practical for smaller areas or
        simpler stormwater management strategies. This may involve the capture of detailed ground
        survey and inspection of the data by a suitably experienced designer to manually estimate
        the location of low points and likely flow paths. Simple hydrologic and hydraulic
        calculations (refer to <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>) could then be applied to estimate the depth
        and width of
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181108T215245+1100" comment="missing word?"?>stormwater<?oxy_comment_end?>
        at regular intervals throughout overland flow paths.</para>
      <para>Caution should always be employed when interpreting the mapping of results for
        stormwater flows and inundation as there may be significant uncertainties about the results
        caused by:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>obstructions to flow paths such as buildings and fences;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>rapidly changing flow conditions throughout a flow path;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>limitations in the accuracy of survey information; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>limited opportunity for calibration.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The application of two dimensional modelling approach produces results that reveal
        hydrologic uncertainty due to use of the hydraulic model to simulate the natural physical
        processes of stormwater flows. These results may be in contrast to empirical or statistical
        relationships between rainfall and runoff that are used to estimate stormwater runoff in
        some traditional hydrologic modelling software. </para>
      <para>Identification of overland flow paths allows development of stormwater management
        strategies. These may include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>mapping of flooding to promote public awareness of flood risks;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>education about flood risks;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>investigation of potential upgrades to stormwater management networks; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>building and development controls.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Flood warning emergency systems are usually inappropriate for overland flooding, as the
        potential warning times are too short. However, incorporation of overland flooding
        information with radar rainfall forecasts may assist in providing emergency management
        warnings.</para>
      <para>Building and development controls should include provisions that prevent the erection of
        new buildings within overland flow paths or set minimum floor levels that are deemed safe.
        Other building controls may also require measures that minimise potential blockage and
        obstruction to flows within effected building envelopes. Application of these controls to
        particular sites may require detailed site-based flood investigations to more accurately
        estimate flood levels and behaviours.</para>
      <para>A freeboard allowance above a calculated flood level is applied to determine the minimum
        level of infrastructure such as a habitable dwelling.
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T143105+1100" comment="cross reference to the national manual?"?>Freeboard
        <?oxy_comment_end?>is required to account for the uncertainties that are inherent in the
        calculation of flooding.
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T143016+1100" comment="typically use 0.5m. perhaps suggest this is for overland flow "?>A
        typical minimum value of 0.3 m above a flood surface is suggested.<?oxy_comment_end?>
        However, this value can be varied to account for local factors such as the sensitivity of
        specific infrastructure to flood damage and expected uncertainty in estimates of flood level
        estimates for a site. Uncertainty about flood levels are variable and dependent on many
        factors including the nature of the catchment and the cross-sectional
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T143211+1100" comment="profiles would typically be along not across the flow path
"?>profile
        across the flow path.<?oxy_comment_end?></para>
      <para>Freeboard should not be used to protect against measurable uncertainties for example
        risk of blockage and climate change. If these risks are a concern for the site then they
        should be explicitly incorporated into the basic flood level estimates before freeboard is
        applied.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_s7kzw">
      <title><?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T143720+1100" comment="not sure aboutt use of fluvial so mucch in this chapter. book 6, 7,8 etc do not refer to &quot;fluvial&quot; flooding 
"?>Fluvial
        <?oxy_comment_end?>Flooding (River and Creek Flooding)</title>
      <para>Fluvial flooding is often referred to as
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T143347+1100" comment="should this be riverine"?>river
        <?oxy_comment_end?>and creek flooding, and is generally caused by long durations (hours to
        days) of intense rainfall across large catchments. These catchments range in area from 1
          km<superscript>2</superscript> to many thousands of km<superscript>2</superscript>. Excess
        runoff from these catchments accumulates and is concentrated as flows in creeks, rivers and
        lakes that have natural features such as a main channel and defined banks.
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T143453+1100" comment="? should this sentence start with flood water "?>Stormwater
        escapes the main channel at locations where hydraulic capacity exceeded and caused
        inundation of surrounding land.<?oxy_comment_end?> This flooding can occur across vast areas
        of flat or low-lying terrain. The extent of flooding can be quite narrow and well defined at
        locations where the natural topography is incised. Fluvial flooding is generally easier to
        analyse than overland flooding because the channels are more readily identified and
        represented using computer models.</para>
      <para>This type of flooding is natural. However, careful urban planning is required to avoid
        substantial damage to infrastructure and property. Fluvial flooding is recognised as one of
        the most significant natural hazards in Australia that is responsible for a significant
        proportion of economic losses and damage to property. Therefore, fluvial flooding has been
        the target of significant government programs for mapping of flood hazards and
        implementation of measures that mitigate potential economic losses and damage to property. </para>
      <para>Fluvial flooding is a constraint to urban stormwater management that needs to be
        understood as it may heavily influence the type's solutions that are proposed. Numerical
        methods for the estimation of flood behaviour and identification of fluvial flood hazard are
        well established and tested. These methods are described in <xref linkend="book6"/>, <xref
          linkend="book7"/> and <xref linkend="book8"/>.</para>
      <para>The management of hazards created by fluvial flooding differs from overland flooding as
        the quantity of floodwaters can be much greater and therefore more difficult to control and
        contain using physical changes to the floodplain. It is often preferable and more cost
        effective to avoid these hazards using a process of careful urban planning. This is best
        achieved by the use of strategic plans and a suite of flood related building and development
        controls. </para>
      <para>Public flood awareness mapping, flood education, flood mitigation and flood warning
        emergency systems become more important where development has already occurred within parts
        of the floodplain subject to fluvial flooding. Catchments that generate fluvial flooding are
        often large and the lag between rainfall and runoff can be sufficient which increases the
        feasibility of flood warning and emergency management strategies.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_ybe0u">
      <title>The Overland and Fluvial Interface</title>
      <para>There is often an interface zone within catchments where both fluvial and overland flow
        paths may exist and differentiation between the two types of flowpaths becomes subjective.
        For example, a small gully drains through a town directly into a major creek as presented in
          <xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_zqrxe"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch3_f_zqrxe">
        <title>Example of Fluvial Flow Path with Interface with Overland Flow Path</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9061.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Analysis of stormwater management strategies at the interface zone requires first
        principles assessment of management techniques from the perspective of both overland and
        fluvial flooding. </para>
      <para>Both types of flooding can occur simultaneously. However, this is unlikely since the
        rainfall mechanisms that typically cause each type of flood are different. It is more likely
        that overland and fluvial flooding will occur at different times and possibly not during a
        single rainfall event. This complex behaviour can confuse attempts to
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T144253+1100" comment="to who"?>communicate
        flood risks<?oxy_comment_end?> and implement management strategies. Confusion also arises
        when insurance claims are made for loss and damage because the decision to pay a claim
        sometimes relies upon whether the flooding was overland or fluvial in nature. In addition,
        the insurance industry has begun to offer fluvial flood insurance cover, which may reduce
        this problem in future. Nevertheless, it is important for
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T144346+1100" comment="you have used practitioner here - should it be designer to match rest of book"?>practitioners<?oxy_comment_end?>
        to recognize the potential for both forms of flooding and carefully assess flood behaviour
        at each site and for each flood event from first principles.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_ov2xg">
    <title>Conveyance Systems</title>
    <para>A typical stormwater (drainage) conveyance system must convey a wide range of flows within
      a confined corridor of land (refer to <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>). At the same time the system
      must meet appropriate standards of flood safety and be delivered for low life-cycle cost. This
      challenge is best addressed through application of a design approach referred to as a ‘major
      and minor stormwater management system’.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A Major and Minor Stormwater Management System Has Two
        Parts:</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The minor system manages
          <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T150128+1100" comment="nuisance flooding"?>nuisance<?oxy_comment_end?>.
          This runoff is conveyed in a manner that maintains safety, minimises nuisance and damage
          to property. The infrastructure is also provided to avoid potential maintenance problems
          for example ponding and saturation of designated areas. Importantly, the minor system also
          includes volume management measures that aim to hold water within urban landscapes and
          sub-catchments (refer to <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>) – these solutions may include ponding
          of stormwater within a defined
          <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T150406+1100" comment="seems to contridict sentence before this"?>area<?oxy_comment_end?>.
          The minor system must withstand the effects of regular stormwater inundation.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A major system primarily intended to mitigate disaster. The major system typically
          includes overland flow paths on roads and through open space, and trunk conveyance
          infrastructure. This system conveys additional stormwater runoff produced
          during<?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T151336+1100" comment="arent these saying same thing"?>
          larger less probable and rarer<?oxy_comment_end?> storm events with the intent of managing
          the potential for flood disaster. Overland conveyance of stormwater
          from<?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T151411+1100" comment="please try and use rare or very rare terms to explain mangnitude"?>
          large<?oxy_comment_end?> events is potentially hazardous due to the velocity and depth of
          flows, and must be safely contained within a defined corridor of major system
          flows.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_p02c9">
      <title>Capacity to Manage Flooding</title>
      <para>The overall combined capacity of the major and minor drainage system to manage flooding
        or inundation needs to be established for each design. This capacity is normally expressed
        in terms of the exceedance probability of design rainfall, creating a flood that must be
        contained within the conveyance or drainage system. It is common practice to set the
        capacity of the major system at a similar exceedance probability as the flood event used for
        regional flood planning (e.g. 1% AEP discharge). </para>
      <para>However, there may be justification to deviate from this practice where a suitable risk
        assessment identifies the need. For example where the consequences of flooding at a
        particular location are high, it may be necessary to expand the overall system capacity to
        cater for more extreme events. This is not commonly required and this type of decision must
        have regard to the overall life-cycle cost and benefits that a larger capacity system may
        deliver. </para>
      <para>The threshold at which the capacity of the minor system is exceeded and the major system
        begins to convey runoff is also a matter for consideration at the design stage or for policy
        makers at the time when preparing local design standards for stormwater management. The
        capacity of minor system is typically established to manage stormwater events ranging from
        50% AEP to 5% AEP. Documentation of these standards can be found in drainage design
        guidelines prepared by local government and relevant state authorities. No single
        universally appropriate capacities of minor systems can be applied in practice. </para>
      <para>Some factors that may influence the balance between the capacity of major and minor
        systems are described in <xref linkend="b9_ch3_t_06he2"/>. These factors may generate a
        number of different capacity standards for minor systems that account for different
        locations and jurisdictions.</para>
      <para>
        <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch3_t_06he2">
          <caption>Factors Influencing the Balance between Capacities of Major and Minor Systems in
            Design</caption>
          <col width="20%"/>
          <col width="80%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Factor</th>
              <th>Description</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Land availability</td>
              <td>Sufficient land may be available for major systems to safely convey additional
                surface flows and reduce the proportion of flows conveyed by minor systems. The use
                of volume management and WSUD approaches can also change the proportion of flows
                assigned to minor and major systems.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Local rainfall patterns</td>
              <td>In some areas, such as tropical northern Australia, runoff generated by frequent
                storms may be too large to cost effectively convey using minor systems. Major flow
                paths will need to be expanded accordingly to manage a proportion of these
                flows.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Likely level of exposure to the major flow path hazard</td>
              <td>Major systems that are highly frequented by people or vehicles, for example in
                city streets or major motorways, involve greater exposure to floodwaters and
                corresponding risks. In these cases, it may be appropriate for a greater proportion
                of runoff to be conveyed in minor systems.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Physical and downstream constraints</td>
              <td>When new stormwater management systems are required for an existing urban area, it
                may be impractical or cost prohibitive to achieve an ideal capacity and compromise
                may be required.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Erosion</td>
              <td>Natural or otherwise unlined minor systems may be subject to erosion when flow
                durations and or velocities are too high. If volume management options (as discussed
                in <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>) are not available, then lowering the capacity of the
                minor systems and forcing a greater proportion of flow into the major system may be
                one way to manage these effects.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Blockage potential</td>
              <td>Where the capacity of minor systems is reduced by a likelihood of blockage with
                debris, resources should be directed towards safer and more durable surface flow
                paths within major systems.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Climate change</td>
              <td>The expected future increases in short duration rainfall intensities may require
                appropriate design responses to increase the capacity of minor systems or change the
                relationship with major systems to maintain current levels of service.</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_c1ne2">
      <title>Alignment and Configuration </title>
      <para>The characteristics of urban form including the layout of roads, location of urban
        parkland and topography will influence the alignment and configuration of stormwater
        management networks. It is difficult to modify the stormwater management network after
        installation. A design process should aim for a long service life. Concept planning for
        major and minor stormwater management systems should therefore be undertaken carefully as an
        early task in the design of new urban developments. </para>
      <para>The depth and velocity of flows along any proposed surface flow paths are considered
        when calculating the dimensions of stormwater conveyance corridors and must meet relevant
        standards for design, safety and maintenance. A design should also ensure that operation of
        a conveyance network during severe storms does not cause unexpected or catastrophic
        consequences (for example, an unintended diversion of flows into an adjoining catchment
        because of blockage or extreme events). </para>
      <para>Wherever possible the width of the land corridor set aside for stormwater management
        should be generous to improve the constructability of the system and reduce the costs of any
        future renewal and maintenance activities. Opportunities for co-location of stormwater
        management within urban parklands should be considered. The alignments of stormwater
        conveyance networks typically follow natural low points to minimise earthworks. However,
        some re-alignment away from the natural low points may occur to account for urban form and
        limit conflicts with other urban infrastructure. However, the design of conveyance networks
        should also consider minimising damage to existing ephemeral waterways.</para>
      <para>Alignments of major systems are often parallel to minor systems and should be continuous
        until intersection with a natural watercourse or receiving waters. The design should include
        adequate management to avoid nuisance or risks at crossings, for example roadways or
        footpaths. </para>
      <para>Configuration of stormwater management strategies (including conveyance networks) will
        depend on the land use within and alongside the selected overland flow paths (refer to <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5"/>). This configuration may also vary throughout a stormwater management
        solution. Some of the typical configurations deployed in Australian design practice are
        presented in <xref linkend="b9_ch3_f_xiam2"/>. The most common configuration (shown in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch3_f_xiam2"/>) comprises an underground conveyance (inlet structures and
        pipes) network (minor system) within surface flow paths on roads (major system).</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch3_f_xiam2">
        <title>Typical Configurations of Major Minor Conveyance Systems Deployed in Australian
          Practice</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20160525T104131+1000" comment="redraft"?>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9059.bmp"/>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The design of the major and minor systems should integrate smoothly with other urban
        infrastructure and manage impacts on natural environments. In particular, innovative design
        of urban parks can be used to achieve drainage objectives while also enhancing aesthetic and
        environmental outcomes. </para>
      <para>Innovative approaches to stormwater management strategies can reduce construction costs
        and requirement for land area. This opportunity should be given early consideration in the
        concept design phase from perspective of multi-disciplinary teams. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_arcmv">
      <title>Analysis</title>
      <para>Suitable hydrologic and hydraulic calculation methods, described in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch4"/>, <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/>,<?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T154249+1100" comment="should this refer to other books in ARR other than book9?"?>
        <?oxy_comment_end?>are used to estimate depths and velocities of stormwater flows with
        associated extents of flooding throughout major and minor systems, which facilitates the
        design of various components. The methods selected for analysis or design must be able to
        simulate the complexity of the stormwater management strategy. A design problem may include
        complex flow behaviours, for example parallel underground and surface flow paths, multiple
        inflows and the effects of storage and tail water conditions. </para>
      <para>These methods must have the capacity to predict the hydraulic performance of the overall
        system and of each different component within the system for example inlet structures, pipes
        and channels. Hydraulic performance must be assessed using a range of storm events and
        configurations. Ideally, a design should be challenged by ensembles of full volume storm
        events to determine the critical storm duration and shape for each AEP. </para>
      <para>The available software modelling tools can facilitate most of these complex
        calculations. However, emerging engineering practice and software tools aim to seamlessly
        handle the full range of linked hydrologic and hydraulic calculations required to account
        for surface flow behaviours throughout complex conveyance networks. These complex scenarios
        may require combinations of hydrologic models linked to hydraulic models with one
        dimensional conveyance network and two dimensional surface flows.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_g6vcu">
    <title>Stormwater Volume Management</title>
    <section>
      <title>Key Considerations</title>
      <para>The historical practice of designing urban stormwater management has traditionally
        focused on peak flows and conveyance. Design standards have evolved to require comprehensive
        management of hydrologic changes created by urbanisation. It is now recognized that volume
        and regimes of stormwater runoff need to be managed
        <citation>b9_c3_r50,b9_c3_r23</citation>. </para>
      <para>Typically, this is achieved through the design and installation of volume management
        facilities. Detailed aspects of these facilities are described in <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>,
        however at a philosophical level the questions that need consideration when developing a
        catchment-wide volume management strategy are: </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">What are the Volume Management Objectives for the
          Catchment?</emphasis></para>
      <para>Volume management objectives can include control of peak discharge, harvesting or
        infiltration of water and water quality treatment (refer to <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00002"
        />). These objectives are achieved using a volume management facility (either a single
        facility or a number of them) which can store and release runoff at different times, or even
        store runoff for later use. </para>
      <para>The impact on downstream floodplains and receiving waters must be determined by
        assessing the catchment–wide consequences of compounding peak flow and volume discharges
        (increases in runoff volume and peak discharges) from different sub-catchments, as well as
        increased duration of flows in ephemeral aquatic ecosystems. This impact assessment will
        then help inform a decision about the volume management objectives to be pursued.</para>
      <para><citation>b9_c3_r41+1</citation> suggest whilst undertaking these assessments, catchment
        managers should also consider whether to use an
        <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T175342+1100" comment="no complete patterns are provided by ARR at this stage. need to remove or provide some advice on how this is done"?>ensemble
        of complete storms <?oxy_comment_end?>with a storm burst of around the critical duration or
        a storm burst only to determine the benchmark condition(s). The decision of what design to
        adopt can be informed through identifying the level of risk the community is willing to
        accept within the catchment.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Should the Objectives be Achieved in Combined
          Facilities?</emphasis></para>
      <para>It is preferable to provide infrastructure that meets multiple objectives. Where
        multiple volume objectives are sought for the catchment, it is possible to design separate
        volume management facilities that each target only a single objective. </para>
      <para>For example, a facility might only manage peak discharge from a site for a single
        probability design flood event used for regional flood planning (e.g. 1% AEP). This might be
        achieved by storing a proportion of the hydrograph volume and releasing it later during the
        storm event through a constricted outlet. This is commonly called a detention basin or
        retarding basin.</para>
      <para>Separate facilities might be required to also meet other stormwater volume objectives
        for example a rainwater tank for harvesting and a bio-retention basin for water quality
        improvement.</para>
      <para>A more comprehensive facility might aim to achieve a peak discharge control objective
        alongside other volume objectives, by storing a proportion of the hydrograph volume and
        releasing it well after the storm event has finished, or even store it for later use (i.e.
        not released into the stormwater system at all). For example a constructed wetland (water
        quality) with an extended detention storage compartment above (peak discharge control),
        providing pre-treatment for a stormwater harvest facility (retention).</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">What is the Performance Level Sought?</emphasis></para>
      <para>For each facility and objective it is necessary to determine whether the facility must
        achieve a low or high level of performance. </para>
      <para>For example, it may be sufficient to retain the hydrologic conditions equivalent to a
        pre-developed condition, which might be considered a low level of performance. </para>
      <para>In some circumstances a higher level of performance might be required, for example, a
        return of hydrologic conditions back to a natural state.</para>
      <para>The performance level sought will be related to the sensitivity of the downstream
        receiving waterway and whether the local community aspires to achieve a high performance
        solution.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Where should Volume Management be Achieved in the
          Catchment?</emphasis></para>
      <para>In some circumstances, there is opportunity to make broad strategic decisions about the
        distribution of these facilities across a catchment. Some typical volume management
        strategies that can be followed include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>An ‘at source’ management strategy: this employs small facilities, widely
            distributed across the catchment, many of which will only service a small catchment or
            single property. Strategies of this type are most commonly part of a more comprehensive
            and integrated urban water strategy.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A ‘neighbourhood scale’ management strategy: this strategy employs larger facilities
            that are less widely distributed than lot scale facilities but servicing larger
            catchments. These facilities are normally publicly managed and co-located alongside a
            watercourse or drainage reserve at the interface between underground and surface
            conveyance paths.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A ‘regional scale’ management strategy: this strategy uses very large facilities
            that are located at the catchment outlet and service all properties in the watershed.
            These are normally publicly owned and co-located with major parkland. This is also
            referred to as an ‘end of pipe’ strategy.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">How does Existing Urban Development Influence the Volume
          Strategy?</emphasis></para>
      <para>Some typical types of urbanising catchments and their associated volume strategy
        considerations are:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Future growth areas</emphasis> where there is currently
            limited urban development (also commonly referred to as ‘Greenfields’ development). For
            these catchments the over-riding strategic objective commonly applied is to preserve the
            nature and amenity of their waterways in terms of hydrology (flow and channel geometry)
            and aquatic communities. This can be achieved using ‘source control’ measures applied
            throughout their contributing catchments. These measures include rainwater tanks,
            bio-retention facilities, ‘rain gardens’, infiltration trenches, ‘soakaways’ and access
            to aquifers where soil and geological conditions are favourable. </para>
          <para>Since there is often opportunity to forward plan in ‘greenfields’
            <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T202635+1100" comment="development - to be consistent with above para?"?>catchments<?oxy_comment_end?>
            there may also be opportunities for comprehensive ‘neighbourhood scale’ and ‘regional
            scale’ placement strategies.</para>
          <para>Every effort should be made in these catchments to encourage 'informal' drainage,
            green spaces and to disconnect as much impervious surface as possible. The criterion for
            successful design of these systems is keeping the volume discharged from each site the
            same after development as before, for design flood events. Use of these practices, is
            referred to by <citation>b9_c3_r1+1</citation> as a ‘regime-in-balance’ strategy. It is
            suggested that adoption of such a strategy can keep urban waterways operating as natural
            systems for many years before increased urbanisation might then require the introduction
            of rectification strategies such as increased channel lining. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Highly urbanised catchments</emphasis> where the strategic
            objective is often to minimise the need for further modification or upgrades to
            conveyance networks as development and re-development continues. For these catchments
            land availability may constrain opportunities for wide adoption of ‘neighbourhood scale’
            and ‘regional scale’ placement strategies. However volume management objectives can be
            achieved in a similar manner to a ‘greenfields’
            <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T203449+1100" comment="see above ccomment"?>catchment<?oxy_comment_end?>
            using ‘source control’ practices as re-development takes place. An additional
            opportunity, ‘roof gardens’, is provided by the presence of multi-storey and high-rise
            elements of this class of development. </para>
          <para>The objective for successful design of these systems is keeping the volume
            discharged from each site the same after development as before, for a design flood
            event. This objective is more difficult to achieve than in ‘greenfields’ catchments
            giving rise to the more common use of temporary on-site storages holding stormwater
            after flood peaks have passed. This problem can be solved by ‘slow release’,
            infiltration or harvesting to ensure storages are empty ahead of closely-spaced storm
            events. With such provisions in place, the supporting infrastructure can continue to
            operate successfully without enlargement.</para>
          <para>Prediction of Australia’s urban growth to mid-21st Century suggests that development
            within catchments of this type will provide the majority of new urbanisation.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Over-developed catchments
            </emphasis><?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T204023+1100" comment="change to be consistent with other dot pts
"?>are<?oxy_comment_end?>
            a particular case of highly urbanised catchments described above, and apply to many of
            our older, inner-city suburbs. These catchments are characterised by frequent episodes
            of flash flooding and resulting community disruption. </para>
          <para>The criterion for successful design of these systems is not just to match
            pre-development conditions but to go further and minimise the volume discharged from
            each site after re-development. This is referred to by <citation>b9_c3_r1+1</citation>
            as the ‘yield-minimum’ strategy. The nature of re-development in an already
            over-developed urban catchment is frequently large-scale, for example urban renewal
            projects. These lend themselves to complete re-organisation of local drainage
            infrastructure and, hence, opportunities for less discharge during the ‘design’ runoff
            events. Every component of re-development incorporated under the ‘yield-minimum’
            strategy moves the catchment in the direction of a balance between runoff being
            generated and infrastructure capacity. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Are There Other Constraints that may Influence the
          Strategy?</emphasis></para>
      <para>Catchment managers will also need to take into account the local landscape and soil
        conditions, which may limit the application of certain volume and quantity management
        solutions. For example, heavy clay soils may limit the application of infiltration based
        solutions, whereas sandy soils may promote such solutions. </para>
      <para>Other examples of constraints that may have strategic influence are:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>sensitive riparian vegetation communities</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>land ownership and development patterns, and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>different choices may be required depending on the nature of the catchment and the
            asset policies of the local stormwater authority.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Selecting a Strategy</title>
      <para>Once the above questions have been considered it might be appropriate to establish and
        document a catchment-wide strategy for stormwater volume management. Such a strategy should
        be used to assist with the design and assessment of individual volume management proposals. </para>
      <para>Typical catchment management strategies (as designed using bottom up or top down methods
        or other analyses) can include a number of different approaches which reflect the local
        authority’s commitment to WSUD principles, as well as commitment to restore overloaded
        systems to balance. </para>
      <para>Three examples of management strategies for catchment-wide volume management are
        provided by <citation>b9_c3_r1+1</citation>. These are consistent with the risk management
        framework discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch5"/> and are defined as follows: </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Yield-maximum:</emphasis> maximise the quantity of storm runoff
        captured at the end of the catchment and ensure that the floodwaters are contained within a
        defined floodplain. This strategy is most suitable for local authorities with a desire to
        have large centrally controlled systems, rather than distributed local solutions.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Regime-in-balance:</emphasis> maintain the harmonious and
        synergistic relationship that exists between continuing urban development and ‘acceptable’
        use of the floodplain for agricultural and amenity pursuits. This strategy is most suitable
        for catchment or sub-catchments where development has occurred or is likely to occur and
        will discharge to a nearly intact or sensitive receiving environment. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Yield-minimum:</emphasis> improve the performance of the urban
        flood control infrastructure through minimisation of stormwater discharge from each
        development site (including redevelopment sites). This strategy is most suitable for
        catchment or sub-catchments with already poorly controlled urban development with a history
        of flood damage and ecosystem deterioration. </para>
      <para>Large catchments, where urbanisation is actively occurring, and over an extended period,
        may contain precincts where a mix of these strategies might be appropriate. Notably, all
        strategies will benefit from urban planning that promotes rainfall infiltration, harvesting
        and retains natural hydrologic function.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_z2zeq">
    <title>Stormwater Offsets</title>
    <para>Tradeable permits or offset schemes are also known as market mechanisms and are
      established methods within the pollution control industry, in water markets and for management
      of nutrient or salinity loads in river basins. These processes commonly involve financial
      contributions paid by a landholder for provision of pollution control works at another
      location, construction of an alternative mitigation scheme instead of a conventional solution
      in the landholders development site, or the sale of a water licence from a landholder to
      another landholder at another location. </para>
    <para>Tradeable permits for pollution control are attractive as they provide opportunities for
      economic efficiency, flexibility and incentives for innovation
        <citation>b9_c3_r38,b9_c3_r37</citation>. The international experience with water pollution
      emission trading is not extensive but does include some successful examples
        <citation>b9_c3_r42</citation>. Trading of pollution abatement responsibilities can cause
      water quality to deteriorate at different times and rates in some parts of a catchment.
      Therefore designing a tradeable permit or offset scheme needs to take spatial, temporal and
      environmental equivalence effects into account. </para>
    <para>At the time of writing, Melbourne Water <citation>b9_c3_r39</citation> and Queensland
      Healthy Waterways <citation>b9_c3_r47</citation> (for example) operate stormwater quality
      offset schemes. These schemes involve a financial contribution paid by developers for
      stormwater management works to be undertaken in another location to meet catchment wide
      objectives for managing stormwater and protecting waterway health. These schemes respond to
      the assumption that regional stormwater management is more cost and time effective than
      distributed smaller scale solutions. These off-set schemes can be useful for urban areas
      subject to infill development that may have limited space for infrastructure.</para>
    <para>There are limited examples of trading or offset schemes for management of stormwater
      runoff volumes or peak flows. The
      <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181111T210159+1100" comment="where is this?"?>District
      of Columbia Water<?oxy_comment_end?> and Sewer Authority (for example:
        <citation>b9_c3_r36+1</citation>) provide an impervious area charge incentive program for
      customers to reduce effective impervious surfaces and, therefore, stormwater runoff on their
      properties which avoids regional works. Properties that use best management practices such as
      rain gardens, rainwater harvesting, green spaces and pervious paving are considered to reduce
      effective impervious surfaces and results in a reduced stormwater charge. Similarly, the
      historical on-site detention (OSD) strategies by the Upper Parramatta River Catchment Trust
      (for example: <citation>b9_c3_r43+1</citation>) offset the need for regional stormwater basins
      by use of detention storages (OSD) on properties. </para>
    <para>Use of formal stormwater off-set schemes to transfer local management of stormwater
      volumes and peak flows to regional facilities is not common, but these types of approaches are
      embodied in most developer contribution schemes for regional infrastructure. Stormwater
      off-set schemes for management of runoff volumes and peak flows should include the following
      key principles:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Transfer of stormwater management to another location should not negatively impact on
          surrounding local properties at any (legal) point of discharge</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The spatial, temporal and cumulative allocation of required treatment capacity must be
          defined using a catchment management strategy. It is unlikely that transfer of local
          stormwater management requirement to a downstream regional location will be a linear or
          average process</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A scheme must result in the desired and measurable changes in flow (and water quality)
          resulting from the infrastructure and stormwater strategies within the same
          catchment</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The funds obtained from stormwater off-sets must be tied to measurable deliverables in
          the catchment</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheme must provide for regional infrastructure in a reasonable time period that
          is consistent with the timing of upstream development.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The relative financial contributions from upstream developers must be proportional to
          their flow and pollutant loads that will be managed by the regional scheme</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheme must have the same life cycle or equivalent life cycle as the life cycle of
          the upstream development (e.g. short-term mitigation strategy, such as flow and erosion
          management, cannot be used for a long-term offset to a developed area stormwater
          management)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>If water quality is part of the scheme, consideration should be given to the
          bio-availability of pollutants removed through the different upstream and catchment wide
          management methods</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Clear ownership and rules about the off-set scheme should be established and risk
          should be mitigated through the adoption of appropriate ratios, and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The ongoing maintenance and renewal costs associated with the regional infrastructure
          must be allocated to ensure the performance of the scheme does not deteriorate over
          time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Stormwater off-set schemes that transfer management of stormwater volumes and peak flow to
      other locations have the potential for ecological impacts in local waterways or downstream
      receiving waters. The ultimate objectives of an off-set scheme should include performance
      targets that also consider secondary effects (such as impacts on local waterways) and
      monitoring strategies should be implemented to measure effects of strategies. </para>
    <para><citation>b9_c3_r34+1</citation> highlights that there is limited evidence of success of
      stormwater off-set schemes and formal monitoring strategies would provide an opportunity to
      more critically consider the evidence of how well schemes that have been implemented and their
      operation. It is also emphasized that achieving equivalence in stream biodiversity and
      ecological function is extremely difficult. </para>
    <para><citation>b9_c3_r35+1</citation> argue that stormwater off-sets should not result in
      avoided management of stormwater runoff. They emphasize the substantial challenge of
      adequately considering spatial, temporal and environmental influences of off-sets, and the
      importance of quantifying the spatial extent of stormwater impacts from the development in
      question. It is highlighted that unmitigated stormwater runoff from relatively small
      proportions of urban areas may propagate severe impacts a long way downstream which can render
      the practice of offsetting within a single catchment a difficult undertaking.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch3_s_h4vsi">
    <title>Acknowledgements</title>
    <para>This chapter benefited from the support and guidance provided by Mark Babister and
      Engineers Australia. The substantial contributions of the editorial panel of Andrew Allan,
      Andrew King, Stephen Frost, Mike Mouritz, Tony McAlister and Tony Webber in shaping this
      discussion are gratefully acknowledged. Additional review comments from James Ball, Bill Weeks
      and Christopher Walsh also assisted in clarifying the content of this paper.</para>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  

</chapter>



