<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b7_ch4" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
  xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  status="In Preparation">
 
 <info>
  <title>Catchment Representation in Model</title>
   
   <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>
   
   <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>
   
   <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
   
   <xi:include href="../../common/authors/testoni_isabelle.xml"/>
  
 </info> 
  
  <para>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Date last updated</td>
        <td>13/5/2019 </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
  </para>
  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Once a catchment modelling system has been conceptualised and modelling platforms have
      been selected it is necessary to represent the catchment and floodplain in the modelling
      platforms. This requires a series of important decisions where all the key features and
      previously identified processes need to be represented. Model selection may need to be revised
      once data collection and analysis is undertaken. This chapter outlines all the key steps in
      establishing a catchment modelling system. </para>
    <para>Schematisation of a catchment modelling system includes representing any physical
      properties of the catchment that affect the catchment’s flood response. The selection of a
      catchment modelling system (<xref linkend="b7_ch3"/>) will influence how the practitioner will
      schematise the catchment and its floodplain. Some catchment modelling systems are inherently
      easier to schematise certain key processes and features and therefore the ease of
      schematisation between different modelling platforms should be taken into account when
      selecting a modelling system. </para>
    <para> The guidance within this chapter is divided into generic catchment modelling systems and
      that specific to hydrologic model and hydraulic models for ease of use.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Adapting an Existing Model</title>
    <para>This is the most common mistake that practitioners and clients make. While it may be an
      easy choice from a time and budget perspective to choose to modify an existing model this
      often leads to a poorer representation of flood behaviour. Before making the choice to adopt
      an existing model consideration must be given to the original purpose of the model and how key
      processes relevant to the current design problem have been represented in the model.</para>
    <para>Typical problems include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The original model was calibrated for a range of frequent floods and is not suitable
          for very frequent floods (or vice versa);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>the model might represent the processes for the existing case but cannot be adapted
          easily for new scenarios (changed catchment and floodplain conditions) that need to be
          run; and </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para> The model is calibrated for rarer events and a different mechanism is dominant for
      smaller flows.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Data</title>
    <para>The amount of historic data and terrain information available for the development of a
      catchment modelling system has a large impact on the model establishment. <xref
        linkend="b1_ch4"/> provides a detailed discussion of the types of data available and issues
      that the practitioner should look out for when using the data. <xref linkend="b4_ch2"/>
      discusses the balance between data availability and model complexity.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch4_s_43001">
    <title>Key Features of a Catchment</title>
    <para>In the conceptualisation and model selection stage the key features of a catchment should
      have been identified along with key processes. When developing a catchment modelling system
      the practitioner needs to ensure that they key features are properly represented in the model.
      A list of possible key features are:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Landforms, vegetation and land use catchment areas influencing runoff response;
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Streams, stream network, floodplains and overflow paths;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Natural and man-made flow constraints;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Natural and man-made storages;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Roads and railway lines;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Weirs;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Flow structures including levees, bridges and culverts;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Levees;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Flow diversions;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pits and Pipe network;</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para> There are different ways of representing these key features within a modelling platform.
      Sometimes there are multiple options and it is important to select the method of
      representation that best suits the problem. Key features are identified so that most of the
      model effort is focused on them instead of other features that don’t have a material effect on
      flow behaviour.</para>
    <sidebar>
      <para>There is a temptation to spend modelling effort on those features that can be readily
        measured. Yet it is often that the features that are hard to measure and quantify have a
        significant effect on flood behaviour. For example in a large river model small culverts
        will have little effect on flood behaviour.</para>
    </sidebar>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Time step</title>
    <para>Time step is typically more of an issue with hydraulic modelling, however, it is also an
      issue for some hydrologic processes. For example the time step at which a loss model is
      applied can change the amount of rainfall excess. Too coarse a time step will mean that the
      runoff hydrograph will be too coarsely represented. Continuous simulation models often need to
      be run at a finer time step to capture important details for simulating floods. Most
      hydrological processes (unless spatially distributed) the time step it is not a problem and
      computationally is no longer a challenge. For two and three dimensional hydraulic models this
      can still be a computation time issue.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Boundaries between Models Elements and Platforms</title>
    <para>A key decision that has to be made is where the boundary is between modelling elements and
      platforms. The common example is between a hydrologic and hydraulic model. A model boundary
      usually means that there is no feedback between the modelling platforms. It is also important
      to understand at this point you could be using a very different modelling approach to
      represent the same process. </para>
    <sidebar>
      <para>A common problem is at the boundary between a hydrologic and hydraulic model. At the
        boundary care should be taken to ensure that there is no double routing of a flow
        hydrograph.</para>
    </sidebar>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Hydrologic Modelling</title>
    <para>As discussed in earlier chapters, the actual processes involved in converting rainfall
      inputs to a catchment into runoff and eventually a flood hydrograph are very complex, and they
      are represented in modelling platforms in a highly conceptualised form. The first decision to
      be made in representing a catchment is the level of spatial resolution to be adopted. At each
      level of resolution, from lumped models to fully distributed models further decisions then
      need to be made on how the key processes are to be represented in the model. In practice these
      decisions generally come down to selecting first an appropriate model platform and then
      possibly a particular model version.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Spatial Resolution </title>
      <para>The appropriate degree of spatial resolution to be adopted in a hydrologic catchment
        model depends on the following factors:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Catchment size</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Degree of spatial variation in catchment rainfall</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Variation in land use characteristics</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Presence of natural features or man-made structures that have a major influence on
            flood formation and need to be represented in the model</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Range of flood magnitudes to be simulated </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Requirement to estimate flood characteristics at internal points in the
            catchment</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <section>
        <title>Lumped Models</title>
      <para>In relatively small catchments there is often only limited spatial variation in rainfall
        and loss characteristics, and it is thus acceptable to treat the catchment as a homogeneous
        unit. In such situations, and when there is only interest on the flood hydrograph at the
        catchment outlet, a lumped model can give acceptable results. </para>
      <para>While lumped flood hydrograph estimation models have the advantage of simplicity, they
        are limited in their application to the following situations:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>catchments with relatively uniform spatial rainfall, loss and baseflow
            characteristics or where the variation of these characteristics between events is
            relatively minor, so that the derived unit hydrograph or other model parameters are
            applicable to a range of design events</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>catchments with no significant artificial storages (reservoirs or flood detention
            basins)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>applications that do not require extrapolation to the range of Very Frequent or Very
            Rare to Extreme floods.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>applications where a flood hydrograph is only required at the catchment outlet, as
            for the design of drainage structures on roads and railways</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>As lumped models do not represent the internal structure of the catchment explicitly and
        do not have direct links to physical catchment characteristics, they depend on the
        availability of observed flood hydrographs for their calibration. The scope for application
        to ungauged catchments is thus more limited.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Semi-distributed Models</title>
      <para>Semi-distributed models allow the spatial variation of inputs and key processes to be
        modelled explicitly. This is particularly important in large catchments and in catchments
        where the natural flooding characteristics have been significantly modified by various forms
        of development, including the construction of reservoirs, flood mitigation works and
        transport and drainage infrastructure.</para>
      <para>Most of the modelling platforms in common use in Australia belong to the group of
        semi-distributed models, owing to their flexibility and efficiency in representing the key
        factors that determine the flood formation under a broad range of catchment conditions. As
        explained in more detail in <xref linkend="b5_ch2"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch6"/>, the
        catchment is represented in the model through a network of nodes and links. </para>
      <para>It is important that the development of the network structure used in the model is
        guided by a good understanding of the key catchment features described in <xref
          linkend="b7_ch4_s_43001"/>. The catchment subdivision into model subareas should follow
        topographic features and match the degree of variation of the key influencing factors
        (spatial rainfall variability, soil and land use characteristics). The conceptualisation and
        level of detail in the representation of the flood producing and flood modifying processes
          (<xref linkend="b7_c4_s_462002"/>) should reflect their relative importance and their
        influence on the flood hydrograph outputs. </para>
      <para>In large catchments the distributed runoff inputs experience a large degree of smoothing
        as they are combined and routed progressively through the stream or channel network to the
        hydrograph output location. This means that recorded flow hydrographs at the catchment
        outlet will provide only limited information on the flow contributions from different parts
        of the catchment and the influence of individual catchment features. However, the role
        played by different catchment features in the formation of flood hydrographs can be expected
        change for different flood magnitudes, and this needs to be reflected in the catchment
        representation. </para>
      <para>Difficulties in calibrating a model to observed flood events of different magnitude
        should be taken as an indication of the changing role of processes, and the model
        representation thus needs to be adapted accordingly. In many cases a significant change
        occurs between floods that are mostly contained within the stream channel and floods in
        which floodplain storage plays an important role in the routing process. Large floodplain
        storage areas may need to be represented by special storage elements whose characteristics
        and parameters are determined from hydraulic calculations.</para>
      <para>For more detailed guidance on the representation of catchments in node-link type models
        users should consult the user manuals of specific modelling platforms. </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Distributed Models</title>
      <para>In the fully distributed or grid-based flood hydrograph estimation models the catchment
        is represented by a large number of grid cells, based on topographic data from a digital
        elevation model (DEM), supplemented by more detailed survey information on the drainage
        network and the flow controlling features of the catchment. The two-dimensional hydraulic
        modelling approach adopted in these models allows their application in quite complex flow
        situations, e.g. floodplain areas with ill-defined drainage networks or urban areas with
        many flow obstructions. </para>
      <para>In principle, distributed modelling allows the influence of spatial variability in
        rainfall inputs, runoff production and routing characteristics to be captured in more detail
        than in node-link type models. However, for this potential to be fully realised, the
        conceptualisation of the runoff producing processes has to be well matched to the scale of
        the basic model elements (grid cells) and has to reflect the change in processes as the
        cells are wetted up and the flow efficiency increases with flood magnitude. </para>
      <para>The capabilities and limitations of distributed (rainfall-on-grid) models are further
          discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_lgabf"/>. </para>
    </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_c4_s_462002">
      <title>Process Representation</title>
      <para>As explained in <xref linkend="b4_ch3"/>, all models applied in flood hydrograph
        simulation employ a highly conceptualised representation of the actual hydrologic processes
        involved in runoff production and routing of the runoff inputs from the different parts of
        the catchment to form hydrographs at points of interest. It has to be kept in mind that the
        adopted conceptualisations are intended for the the simulation of probability-based design
        flood events rather than actual flood events. The model should reflect the typical flood
        response of the catchment to be expected in future events but may not reproduce the full
        range of variability between actual flood events.</para>
      <para>In the event-based flood estimation methods, the influence of all the pre-event rainfall
        is only reflected in the initial catchment conditions (that determine initial loss), and in
        the delayed runoff contribution from baseflow which is modelled separately. The event
        rainfall is then divided into rainfall loss and rainfall excess which produces the surface
        runoff component that is modelled in detail. </para>
      <para>The detailed guidelines for modelling losses and baseflow are provided in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>, respectively. The different approaches
        for modelling the production of runoff hydrographs from model subareas and for routing these
        through the drainage network to points of interest are discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch6"
        />.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Hydraulic Model Establishment</title>
    <para>The text below is largely reproduced from <citation>b7_c2_r1+1</citation> which is focused
      on two dimensional modelling. Two dimensional models are used for the majority of problems
      because they provide spatial output showing the extent of flooding and flood characteristics.
      There is however a place for one dimensional models where a fast reliable computational model
      is required for flood forecasting or Monte Carlo modelling. More detail can be found in
        <citation>b7_c2_r1+1</citation>. </para>
    <section>
      <title>Model Extents</title>
      <para>The primary goal in selecting a model extent is to represent key processes within the
        area of interest without significant influences driving runoff-routing or hydraulic
        behaviour from areas outside the model extent. Key considerations include, but not limited
        to:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensuring that the model extent is sufficient to cover the likely inundation extent
            of the largest event to be modelled. The key here is that for the largest event to be
            modelled (typically the Probable Maximum Flood), the model extent does not artificially
            restrain water movement at its boundaries, and that the topographic data within the
            model extent also extends beyond the inundation areas. For a hydrologic model the model
            must cover the contributing area. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensure that boundary conditions are located sufficiently far away so as to not
            unduly influence results within the area of interest.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Minimise the inclusion of unnecessary (flood-free) areas, as this produces excessive
            results, impacts on computer memory requirements, increases model output file sizes and
            reduces efficiency.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>If the likely maximum extent of the inundated area is difficult to define (e.g. very
        flat terrain or dam break studies) defining the extent can be an iterative procedure. A
        recommendation is to always start with a large model area and then narrow the model domain
        based on feedback of model results, as this is far less problematic than the reverse
        process. Using a coarser grid/ mesh resolution to reduce run times during these earlier
        stages of the modelling process can be an effective and efficient approach, especially for
        large model areas. Run time is typically not an issue for hydrologic models other than
        distributed runoff-routing models. </para>
      
      
        <sidebar><title>Model Study Area vs Model Applicability Area </title><para>In most cases there is a difference between the model extent and the area that the
          model can be used to produce reliable results. Just because a model extends over a certain
          area does not mean reliable results can be extracted in all areas of the model. Often
          these fringe areas are modelled just so that the model boundary conditions are
          sufficientlyfar away from the study area.</para></sidebar>
      
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Boundary conditions</title>
    <para>Boundary conditions should be located a sufficient distance away from the location of
      interest so as not to influence the results. The practitioner must decide which type of
      boundary condition to apply.</para>
    <sidebar><title>Beware of direct rainfall boundary conditions and pre-wetting of catchment.</title>
      <para>When using direct rainfall water is applied to every grid cell so all calculation points
        are located on a boundary. A common problem is that the depression storage within the model
        which can be a combination of numerical and actual can be overlooked when applying
        losses.</para>
    </sidebar>
    <section>
      <title>Location of Boundary Conditions</title>
      <para>The location of the boundary conditions is of critical importance. In general,
        boundaries should be located as far away from the study area as is practicably achievable.
        Any boundary condition on a hydraulic model requires a description of the water level, flow
        rate and velocity, flow direction and water surface slope across the boundary. In most
        situations, these flow conditions are rarely available as input data time series.
        Consequently, a range of assumptions are made in the definition of these conditions. While
        some models provide the ability to specify these explicitly, most models have generic
        assumptions incorporated into the model system to facilitate the automatic calculations of
        the range of parameters required. </para>
      <para>As an example, the water level at a boundary condition is typically defined as a time
        series of recorded level. The other flow conditions are assumed or calculated based on the
        general assumptions or pre-defined conditions, such as an assumed flow direction across the
        boundary and assumed water surface slope. In this example, these assumptions, when combined
        with the water level time series, allow a discharge to be estimated across the
        boundary.</para>
      <para>The specification of these conditions on the boundary introduces errors into the model
        predictions. Over time, these errors propagate through the model domain and may eventually
        pass through the model domain and out through another boundary. In a well developed and
        tested model, these errors become dampened as they propagate through the model domain. If
        the boundary conditions are located remotely then the errors become insignificant at the
        area of interest.</para>
      <para> As an example, if a high flow rate is introduced through a topographic boundary
        condition that has small conveyance (restricted flow capacity) then high velocities and a
        significant velocity head results. This may cause large errors in the momentum flux into the
        system leading to errors in the flow patterns, water level and velocities downstream from
        the model boundary into the model domain. In this case, provided the boundary is located
        well away from the area of interest so that these effects have fully dissipated, the
        presence of these unrealistic flow patterns can be considered acceptable for the purposes of
        the investigation.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Type of Boundaries</title>
      <para>The types of boundary conditions that are applied are important in determining the
        results produced by the model. The boundary conditions can be defined into two broad
        categories of;</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>External boundary conditions; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Internal boundary conditions.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The most common boundary conditions applied in hydraulic models are external boundary
        conditions with a flow or discharge boundary defined along the upstream boundary of the
        model and a water level defined at the downstream external boundary. </para>
      <para>The boundary condition type can be described using one of the following for
        specifications:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flow time series specified which is distributed across the model boundary grid/mesh
            points;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Water level time series which is assumed to be constant across the model
            boundary;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flow and water level specified in combination as an input time series and
            distributed along the boundary;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flow or water level specified as a one dimensional line of values along the boundary
            for each time step; </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Transfer boundary where the water level, flow, velocity and water surface slope are
            provided from another model; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Rating curve along a model boundary (combination of water level and flow).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The combination of boundary types is important and must be considered in combination
        with the specification of initial conditions. In general, the boundary conditions for
        hydraulic models should be designed with upstream inflow or discharge boundaries and
        downstream water level boundaries. This ensures that any errors or uncertainties associated
        with initial conditions are “washed out” of the model. If other combinations of boundary
        conditions are used then the initial conditions will not necessarily be “washed out” of the
        model. The initial conditions will then significantly affect model simulation results and
        the results may not be reliable.</para>
      <section>
        <title>External Boundary Conditions</title>
        <para>The schematisation of the external boundary conditions can vary across the range of
          model types and even within specific modelling platforms. The schematisation of external
          boundary conditions is therefore highly dependent on the specific case and modelling
          platform being used and it would be inefficient to describe all types of boundary
          conditions in detail. However we can define some general principles for schematising
          boundary conditions that are important to consider.</para>
        <para>If general the practitioner should approach the schematisation of external model
          boundary conditions in a similar manner to how a boundary condition would be conceived for
          a physical model. The practitioner should consider the physical flow characteristics at
          the boundary in the real world and should attempt to schematise so as to minimise any
          artificial flow behaviour that is induced by the boundary condition. Issues that should be
          considered include:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Align the model grid to be normal to the boundary flow streamlines if
              possible;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Avoid rapid transitions in flow regime at the boundary;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Avoid placing the boundary where turbulent flows are likely to be crossing the
              boundary;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Minimise the wetting and drying on the boundary if the flooded boundary changes in
              width substantially during the simulation;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Ensure that the boundary condition does not restrict or expand the flow
              substantially at the boundary; and</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Preference for specifying an upstream inflow discharge boundary and a downstream
              water level (or rating curve) boundary in combination.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para> As discussed, the boundary conditions should be located as far from the area of
          interest as possible. This will minimise the possibility of boundary effects and errors
          influencing the model results within the study area. The specification of the boundary
          conditions will therefore have a significant influence on the grid/mesh resolution. In
          general, the boundary condition should be identified as the first task that is carried out
          when conceptualising and schematising a model.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Internal Boundary Conditions</title>
        <para>Internal boundary conditions are specified to control either the flow or the water
          level at grid/mesh element(s) within the model and not along the edge of the model grid.
          There are generally two types of internal boundary conditions:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Internal inflow points (sometimes called sources or sinks); and</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Internal flow or level controls.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>The primary issue in defining internal inflow boundary points is to ensure that the
          flow rate is compatible with the grid or mesh resolution. There should be sufficient
          conveyance into or out of the element(s) where the boundary condition is specified to
          allow the model to accept the flow without introducing significant disturbance to the
          natural flow streamlines. If a large flow is forced as a boundary through a relatively
          small cell element with limited flow area; the model will produce an excessively large
          velocity and water level gradient to achieve continuity with the flow volume. If this
          occurs then significant momentum can be artificially introduced to the model at this
          location which will then influence water levels and flow patterns for a relatively large
          distance away from the boundary cell.</para>
        <para> Internal control boundary conditions are a special form of boundary condition and are
          generally not recommended unless there is a strong compelling case for their use. An
          internal boundary condition will force the model to reproduce a predefined hydraulic
          behaviour within the model domain. The most common internal boundary condition is a forced
          rating curve at an internal cross-section of a one dimensional model. These boundary
          conditions are highly “reflective” and will introduce distortion and disturbance of the
          flow behaviour far from the actual boundary point. It is not recommended the use of this
          type of boundary for most catchment modelling applications.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Run Times and Computational Resources</title>
    <para>The availability and type of computational resources will impact directly upon the
      efficiency and timeliness of any project. The efficiency of a gridded model study will be
      greatest where model run times are less than 24 hours. The shorter the run time the greater
      the efficiency. However, depending upon the extent and resolution of the model and the length
      of the modelled events there may be situations in which run times may be in the order of
      several days. </para>
    <para>Excessively long run-times can introduce a significant bottle-neck in the study timeline
      and the decision to accept an excessively long model run time should be made carefully.
      Timeliness may be particularly affected during the calibration phase, where a large number of
      iterative simulations are necessary, mostly in series rather than parallel. With excessive run
      times the calibration essentially relies on the skill of the practitioner and their knowledge
      of likely calibration parameters.</para>
    <para> In addition, the total number of runs required can be an important consideration if there
      are many scenarios to be considered, such as different event durations and Annual Exceedance
      Probailities, development scenarios, blockage scenarios or scenarios to parameter sensitivity
      tests (refer to <xref linkend="b7_c7_s_pst001"/>). During the planning stage, the practitioner
      will need to consider the following factors to estimate the efficiency and timeliness of the
      study. </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The estimated length of time required to complete each run;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The number of calibration and design events to be simulated;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The number of computers/processors available;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The ability of the computers to undertake multiple runs in parallel or not; and
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The number of licenses available if proprietary software is to be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The type and availability of computational resources can provide a real practical
      constraint. It may limit the number of design runs that can be achieved, the length of event
      that can be simulated, or the achievable resolution of the model. Such limitations and the
      resulting implications need to be identified as soon as possible in the process.</para>
    <para>Consideration of run times can be particularly important for rural flood studies, or for
      studies involving continuous simulation of long flow periods. Such studies may require
      simulation of floods or flow sequences lasting several months. In these situations it may be
      appropriate to consider the use of a modelling package that can implement an adaptive
      timestep, using a longer timestep during periods of relatively steady flow conditions, which
      may significantly reduce computational run times. Adaptive timesteps are discussed further in
        <xref linkend="b7_ch4_s_ts003"/>.</para>
    <para>The fast run times of hydrologic models lend themselves to Monte Carlo modelling. However,
      run times of two dimensional hydraulic models are somewhat prohibitive at this point in time.
      Fast run times are possible one dimensional hydraulic models. One alternative is to Monte
      Carlo or Ensemble hydrologic models then apply a selection of events to the two dimensional
      hydraulic model. <xref linkend="b2_ch5"/> recommends running an ensemble of ten temporal
      patterns in a hydrologic model and the selecting the pattern closest to the average (flow or
      volume depending on the problem of interest) through a hydraulic model. </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Model Resolution </title>
    <para>All models represent different processes at different resolutions:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">One Dimensional Hydraulic Models </emphasis>
        - the resolution is based on the space between cross-sections; and </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Two Dimensional Hydraulic Models -</emphasis>
         it is a simple representation of the topography. </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Given other considerations such as run time it may not be possible to have the model
      resolution fine enough to represent the key features in the perfect detail. It is sometimes
      necessary to compromise on model resolution. For example, A levee is 30 m wide but chosen cell
      size is either 20 m or 40 m. Engineering judgement should be applied to decide which cell size
      should be used. An adjustment to the resolution of the model may be required in order to
      properly represent the flow behaviour.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch4_s_ts003">
    <title>Time Step</title>
    <para>The model simulation time step is dependent on the model grid/mesh resolution and the
      schematisation of features in the model. As a consequence, the impact of poor model
      schematisation can lead to inefficiently small time steps which in turn will produce excessive
      run times. The impact of excessive run times should not be underestimated and in practice it
      becomes impractical to calibrate and apply the model effectively.</para>
    <para>There are generally two choices for selecting a model time step which are:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>A fixed regular time step; or</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>An adaptive time step.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The fixed regular time step allows the practitioner to pre-determine the model run time
      and to set the saving step (in which model results are saved) as a regular multiple of the
      simulation time step. However, the time step will need to be set at the shortest time interval
      necessary for stability of the model during the most energetic or deepest flows during the
      simulation. This typically occurs for only a very short period of time during the peak of the
      flood hydrograph. Consequently the model simulation time is longer than is necessary as it is
      fixed for the entire simulation. However, the practitioner can be sure that the simulation
      will complete within predetermined run time.</para>
    <para>The adaptive time step allows the model to determine the appropriate time step necessary
      to maintain stability as defined by the Courant condition. The practitioner will typically set
      a maximum and minimum time step allowable. This allows the model to time step at relatively
      longer time steps when the flow is shallow or less energetic and shortens the time step during
      the peak of the flow event. In theory, this should allow the shortest run time for the
      simulation to be achieved whilst maintaining model stability. However, in practice the
      adaptive time step method can often lead to excessively long run times. This is due to the
      impact of a few minor locations in the model where short lived energetic fluctuations in the
      flow can lead to the minimum time step being selected for excessively long periods of
      time.</para>
    <para>Run times can also become excessive if the period that it takes for the flood wave to
      propagate through the model is very long. For example, simulations of large river systems or
      of flat terrain where the critical rainfall duration is long, will have propagation times in
      the order of days, if not weeks. However, small catchments with short critical durations may
      only have propagation times in the order of hours. Therefore, some idea of the likely
      propagation period is needed before finalising the model resolution and extent.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Save Step</title>
      <para>The model save step is an important issue to consider during the model schematisation
        process. As models (particularly hydraulic models and distributed models) will typically
        produce very large results files if all the results are saved, there is a requirement to
        select an appropriate saving step for the results. </para>
      <para>The model saving step needs to be sufficient short to be able to define the shape of the
        hydrograph in time. The model save step also needs to be sufficiently short to enable the
        observation of stability issues that may occur during the simulation. If a model is being
        saved at a longer time interval than a higher frequency oscillation in the model then it
        would not be easily identified and could be missed. It is important that the model is
        checked thoroughly by saving all time steps at specific points or at small regions in the
        model domain. This allows for the observation and checking of stability issues without the
        need to save the entire model at all time steps. It is generally impractical to save all
        results at all time steps in a 2D model and it will typically exceed the limitations of most
        computer storage and hardware to do so.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
</chapter>

