<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b7_ch3">
  
  <info>
  <title>Conceptualisation and Selection of a Catchment Modelling System</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/testoni_isabelle.xml"/>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>
    

  
  </info>

  <para>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td>Chapter Status</td>
        <td>Final</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Date last updated</td>
        <td>14/5/2019</td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
  </para>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch3_s_12bx2">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>A well thought out model conceptualisation and selection stage can result in significant
      project savings and the avoidance a lot of costly rework. While it is not possible to identify
      all potential issues, as learning experiences during a modelling project can identify issues
      and these can be addressed during this initial stage. This allows the limitations to be better
      understood and factored into decision making.</para>
    <para>The conceptualisation stage in the catchment modelling process can be broken down into a
      series of steps that lead to informed decision making: </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Defining the problem under consideration and output needs;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identifying the key process/es that must be modelled to understand and model the
          problem;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identifying the available data;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Selecting a level of modelling complexity that can be justified by the data available
          to calibrate or parameterise the modelling processes; and </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Selecting a modelling approach that matches these considerations with project
          constraints including, time, cost, model choices and modeller experience. </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch3_s_w52rm">
    <title>Factors for Consideration</title>
    <para>The most important step in developing a catchment modelling system is to properly identify
      the problem under consideration, the purpose of the modelling and required outputs. Modelling
      is used to predict the behaviour of complex systems under different scenarios and conditions.
      Modelling will generally have a specific purpose. The purpose of modelling may include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Floodplain studies – inclusive of flood studies all the way through to mitigation
          impact assessment. This may include defining flood behaviour for land use planning.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Flood Emergency Response – Model results can be used to enable emergency services to
          better prepare and respond to flood events by identifying potential flood hazard and
          planning evacuation routes. Model outputs can also enhance mapping outputs and improve
          flood intelligence for both responsible agencies and the community, leading to a reduction
          in flood impacts. Whilst not commonly used at present, it is possible that 2D models may
          be utilised more commonly for real-time flood warning in the future.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Urban drainage studies – in such applications the hydraulic model may also perform the
          routing functionality typically carried out by a hydrologic model. The 2D model provides
          the “major” drainage layer and interfaces also with the “minor” drainage system (i.e. pits
          and pipes) dynamically;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Dam Break assessments - Often a hyraulic model is used to route dam break hydrographs.
          2D models are well-suited to this application as the flowpaths resulting from a dam break
          are often unexpected or different to typical flowpaths;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Sizing of a spillway;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Land filling for development;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>In any environment in order to assess the flood impact due to development;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>In-bank river flow modelling in 1D or 2D. This may be carried out in 2D in order to
          provide flow velocity that varies over the cross-section or in 1D in which velocity will
          be averaged over the cross-section. This approach is often used in ecosystem/habitat
          assessment;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Wetland modelling - where routing paths are ill-defined and filling and draining
          processes are complex.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Lake or estuary studies – often at the lower end of river systems the floodplain
          interacts with a lake or estuary and subsequently ocean or lake dynamics become important
          (tide, storm surge, or seiching).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Water quality and sediment transport studies – these applications build on the
          two-dimensional hydrodynamics to provide information on water-dependent processes such as
          pollutant transport and river morphology.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Along with a specific purpose problems it is necessary to define the spatial extent and
      either the probability range of interest or parameter range. For example the spatial extents
      could be limited to just a dam, or a distance up and downstream. The following items should be
      defined at the start of the project: </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Spatial extent (note this might not be the same as the model extent);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Probability extent (e.g. 5% AEP to 1% AEP);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Parameter range;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Types of outputs (flow, volume, level, rate of rise, warning time). These may be
          presented as either:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Peak; </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Hydrograph; </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Spatial Map; and/or</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Animations. </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The required outputs may be specified by the client, in the study brief. </para>
    <para>While as part of the study a model of the entire catchment may be established typically a
      smaller specific location is the main focus of the study. If there are self-cancelling errors
      or bias in areas of the model not influencing the specific location of interest then the
      practitioner might not be concerned. </para>
    <para>An important step in the conceptualisation of the problem is determining the likely
      scenarios that will need to be run (<xref linkend="b7_ch3_s_6ckuu"/>). For example if a future
      development scenario is to be run with urbanisation then a hydrologic model will be required
      which allows a change in pervious to
      <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>impervious
      area.<?oxy_custom_end?></para>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch3_s_6ckuu">
      <title>Initial Scenario Identification</title>
      <para>Along with defining the problem under investigation identifying, the types of scenarios
        that are likely to be assessed will significantly improve modelling decisions. For some
        problems the practitioner will only need to identify existing conditions. However for many
        problems the practitioner will be required to build a catchment modelling system that is
        capable of assessing different scenarios. Scenarios are broadly divided into these
        categories: modelling of historic and future conditions, mitigation options and management
        options. Most scenarios will fall into these broad categories. Some typical scenarios
        include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Existing conditions;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Historic conditions;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Change in landuse (impacts or restoration to pre-development conditions to manage
            the impact of urbanisation);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Infrastructure (assessing and mitigation of the impact of a road and railway
            line);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Structural flood mitigation measures (such as dam and levees);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Future development scenarios; </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Change in dam operations;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Changed catchment conditions assessment;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Climate change; </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Parameter sensitivity tests; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ocean interaction.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para> If the project requires only the definition of flood behaviour under existing
        conditions then this step can be ignored and focus is on the identification of key processes
          (<xref linkend="b7_ch3_s_klmb9"/>). While in many situations, it will not be possible to
        identify all the scenarios at the conceptualisation stage that will need to be assessed, it
        is possible to identify the types of solutions, measures or works that are typically used to
        identify, mitigate or manage the problem. The ability to model scenarios is one of the
        powerful features of a catchment modelling system.</para>
      <sidebar>
        <title>What Has Been Defined So Far</title>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The Problem;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Likely Scenario (first pass); </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Spatial Extent (area of interest); </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Probability range or parameter range of interest</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </sidebar>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch3_s_klmb9">
    <title>Identify Key Processes, Inputs and Mechanisms</title>
    <para>The key processes and mechanisms in design flood estimation can include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Rainfall Models;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runoff generation;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Overland flow;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Hydrologic routing; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Hydraulic routing. </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The key processes in flood estimation have been defined in <xref linkend="book4"/>, <xref
        linkend="book5"/> and <xref linkend="book6"/>. The key design inputs have been defined in
        <xref linkend="book2"/>. </para>
    <para>It is important to decide which key processes have the most influence on the scenarios of
      interest. For example, if the scenario of interest is land use changes then the key processes
      are runoff generation from different landuse types, catchment response from different land use
      types, resistance to flow for different landuse types. Therefore the chosen modelling
      platforms and catchment modelling system must be able to model these processes and allow for
      changes to parameters representing these processes.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch3_s_r7wp8">
    <title>Data Availability and Model Complexity</title>
    <para>During the conceptualisation stage all data does not need to be collected. However an
      awareness of what data is or might be available will assist in the determination of which
      catchment modelling system should be used. Selecting the level of complexity of the model is a
      trade-off between data availability and predictive performance (<xref linkend="b7_ch3_f_n83q9"
      />). Typically there is not enough observed data. Time and budget constraints are usually best
      addressed by reducing model complexity and the extent to which data is used. </para>
    <figure xml:id="b7_ch3_f_n83q9">
      <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
      <title><?oxy_custom_end?>Conceptual Relationship between Data Availability, Model Complexity
        and Predictive Performance <citation>b4_c2_r13</citation></title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/4005.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>Consideration must also be given to the resolution of modelling required. For example for
      a large catchment coarse representation may be sufficient. Therefore large subareas in the
      hydrologic model and a relatively large grid in the two dimensional hydraulic model may be
      used. For complex studies fine scale detail may be important and small grid and subareas may
      be needed in order to represent the hydraulic controls and key features.</para>
    <sidebar>
      <title>What Has Been Defined So Far</title>
      <para>An assessment of the available data and what can be achieve with it must be made.
        Following this some compromising on how key processes are represented must be made. It is a
        non-linear process.</para>
    </sidebar>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch3_s_cc8kf">
    <title>Selecting Modelling Platform(s)</title>
    <para>With a firm understanding of the problem, the key processes and data availability it is
      now possible to select a preferred modelling platform/s. A single modelling platform may
      contain all the key processes, inputs and mechanisms required to solve the design problem.
      However, in many cases is it more desirable to combine a number of modelling platforms.
      Reasons that influence the choice of modelling platform include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Reliable regional/default parameters for ungauged catchments (refer to <xref
            linkend="b7_ch5"/>);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Different modelling platforms are able to model specific features;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Client preference;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Standardisation; </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Likely run time;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Anticipated resolution of the model and model outputs; and </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Ability to leverage existing modelling.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In many cases more than one modelling platform is often used. This is often the case where
      limited data is available as some modelling platforms are more suitable for ungauged
      catchments.</para>
    <para>The other key inputs that must be considered at this stage are the project timeline,
      budget, experience with, and availability of modelling platforms. There is a certain art to
      modelling and there is no substitute for experience with a particular modelling platform. On
      many projects it is not practical to develop a job specific model and it is necessary to
      select one or a set of existing modelling platforms. This has major impacts on cost and
      timing. Likewise, selecting a modelling platform that the practitioner is familiar with can
      have significant impacts on cost timing and the reliability of results. Typically leading to a
      better outcome. </para>
    <para>The advantages of selecting a platform that the practitioner is experienced with includes
      knowledge of appropriate parameter ranges, faster set up time, and knowledge of key
      features.</para>
    <sidebar>
      <title>Selection of the Hydraulic Model</title>
      <para>The selection of the appropriate type of hydraulic model is a critical decision in the
        application of catchment modelling systems process. In this step the physical system flow
        behaviour, which can commonly involve complex highly turbulent flows, must be reduced to an
        equation, or set of equations, describing the main characteristics of the flow. Here
        assumptions have to be made as to whether the flow can be considered as being
        one-dimensional (1D), two-dimensional (2D), or a combination of both, and whether the flow
        can be described as being steady (ie. constant with time), or unsteady (time-varying). In
        virtually all rural or urban floodplain modelling, vertical accelerations in the flow field
        are considered to be negligible and a hydrostatic pressure distribution is assumed, with
        computations and results based around a depth-averaged velocity. Further details are
        provided in <xref linkend="book6"/>, which outlines the governing equations utilised in
        hydraulic models. More detail on the application and selection of a hydraulic model is
        provided in Australian Rainfall and Runoff Supporting document – Two dimensional Modelling
        of Rural and Urban Floodplains <citation>b7_c2_r1</citation>.</para>
    </sidebar>
    <sidebar><title>What Has Been Defined So Far</title><para>A catchment modelling system has been chosen for the defined problem which makes the best use of available data. Consideration is given to model complexity and model representation of key processes. </para></sidebar>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
</chapter>
