<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b6_ch1" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         status = "In Preparation">
         
  <title>Introduction</title>
       <informaltable border="1">
              <tr>
                     <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Book</td>
                     <td>6</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Chapter</td>
                     <td>1</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Date</td>
                     <td>27/11/2015</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Content</td>
                     <td>In preparation</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Graphs and Figures</td>
                     <td>In preparation</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Examples</td>
                     <td>In preparation</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>General</td>
                     <td/>
              </tr>
       </informaltable>
       <section xml:id="b6_ch2_s_n640g">
              <title>Objectives and Scope</title>
              <para>Much of Australian Rainfall and Runoff is dedicated to the determination of peak
                     discharge, discharge hydrographs and flood volumes. This chapter deals with
                     translating these discharge estimates into flood levels, flow velocities and
                     the extent of flood inundation needed to determine flood damage and flood
                     hazard. The importance of the inter-relationship between hydrology and
                     hydraulics should not be under-estimated and there is often a blurring of the
                     boundaries between the two areas. For example, the flood routing used to obtain
                     a flow hydrograph and shallow flow surface runoff expressions are both founded
                     in hydraulic engineering principles. In recent approaches to urban flooding,
                     rainfall is a direct input to the hydraulic numerical grid hence forcing the
                     hydraulic model to deal with the hydrology and the hydraulics
                     simultaneously.</para>
              <para>The primary objective of this book is to provide a document which provides
                     background information to assist practicing engineers to carry out calculations
                     or hydraulic investigations related to free surface flows. The needs for such
                     calculations or investigations may be related to floods (inundation levels,
                     concentration of flows to endanger life, the power of flood flows to threaten
                     or impair structural integrity or even wash away structures, and bed level
                     scour), stormwater disposal, water supply distribution systems and sewerage
                     collection systems (the installation of new systems or augmentation of existing
                     systems).</para>
              <para>The present document concentrates on free surface flows. Textbooks are available
                     which cover the basics of open channel flow. The traditional texts in this area
                     are Henderson (1966) and Chow (1959) but more modern books include Chaudhry
                     (2007) and Sturm (2009). Pipe flow is covered in fluid mechanics textbooks like
                     Streeter and Wylie (1981) and Elgar <emphasis role="italic">et al.</emphasis>
                     (2008). There are numerous journals which publish research dealing with open
                     channel, pipe flow and river flood flows and these include the ASCE - Journal
                     of Hydraulic Engineering, IAHR - Journal of Hydraulic Research and the Journal
                     of Flood Risk Management. Those practicing and working in this area are
                     encouraged to keep abreast of new developments as this is an area that is
                     evolving with increases in computational power.</para>
       </section>

</chapter>
