<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="b5_ch5" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Losses</title>

  <info>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/hill_peter.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/thomson_rhys.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section version="5.0" xml:id="b5_ch5-3">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>This chapter provides advice on loss models and values for design
    flood estimation. It deals with the fundamental hydrologic question – how
    much rainfall becomes runoff? Design floods are typically derived either
    using flood frequency analysis or rainfall-based flood event models.
    Continuous simulation is covered in <xref linkend="b4_ch3"/> and the focus
    of this chapter is losses for event based design flood estimation.</para>

    <para>The loss is just one of the number of inputs to the design process
    (such as the critical storm duration, areal reduction factor, spatial
    pattern, temporal pattern, runoff routing model, model parameters and
    treatment of baseflow) that can affect the magnitude of the calculated
    design flood. These other inputs are discussed in other
    <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151123T103032+1100" comment="Which books?
"?>books<?oxy_comment_end ?>.</para>

    <para>This chapter is structured as follows:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_8u8o4"/> – discusses how loss processes
        are represented in different conceptual loss models, ranging from
        empirical models through to more complex process models</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_e5fbn"/> – discusses the selection of
        conceptual loss models and different approaches to estimating loss
        values</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/> – describes the estimation of
        effective impervious areas for urban catchments</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_dewgv"/> – summarise different sources
        of information on loss values for rural and urban catchments that can
        be used to help select values for design</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_h83ay"/> – discusses different
        approaches to characterising the distribution of loss values</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_d0jl5"/> – discusses a range of other considerations for
          selecting loss values for design flood estimation</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_8u8o4">
    <title>Conceptual Loss Models</title>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ncyi2">
      <title>Loss Processes</title>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_3ahpk">
        <title>Physical Processes</title>

        <para>Loss is defined as the precipitation that does not appear as
        direct runoff, and is attributed to the following key processes (refer
        to <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f1"/>):</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>interception by vegetation;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>infiltration into the soil;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>retention on the surface (depression storage); and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>transmission loss through the stream bed and banks.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f1">
          <title>Physical Processes which Contribute to Rainfall Loss</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5014.PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>More details on the runoff process are described in <xref
        linkend="book4"/>, while this section focuses on specific processes
        associated with estimation of losses.</para>

        <para>Runoff has generally been considered to consist of surface
        runoff produced by rainfall excess occurring at the ground surface
        when the rainfall intensity exceeds the infiltration capacity. This is
        known as Horton-type runoff, named after the <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151123T112911+1100" comment="Who?"?>father
        of infiltration theory<?oxy_comment_end ?>. An excellent review of
        infiltration theory and its application to practical hydrology is
        given by Fleming and Smiles (1975).</para>

        <para>Over the last twenty years the classical concept of storm runoff
        has been challenged as a result of observations on natural catchments
        during storm periods and many detailed studies of instrumented plots
        and small areas. Two alternative types of storm runoff mechanism have
        been proposed:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Saturated overland flow occurs when, on part of the
            catchment, the surface horizon of the soil becomes saturated as a
            result of either the build-up of a saturated zone above a soil
            horizon of lower hydraulic conductivity, or due to the rise of a
            shallow water table to the surface; and</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The other type of storm runoff is throughflow, which is
            water that infiltrates into the soil and percolates rapidly,
            largely through macropores such as cracks, root holes and worm and
            animal holes, and then moves laterally in a temporarily saturated
            zone above a layer of low hydraulic conductivity. It reaches the
            stream channel quickly and differs from other subsurface flow by
            the rapidity of its response and possibly by its relatively large
            magnitude.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Associated with the recognition of these two alternative types
        of storm runoff, is the concept that storm runoff may be generated
        from only a small part of many catchments. Additionally, this source
        area may vary in its extent from time to time, in different seasons
        and during the progress of a storm.</para>

        <para>There are no practical methods for estimating storm losses and
        runoff that would take explicit account of different runoff processes,
        partial and variable source areas and small-scale variations in
        characteristics. The various existing methods assume uniform or
        average conditions, not accounting non-homogeneity of the catchment.
        Though each model attempts to simplify the overall process by
        different degrees, however, it is important to understand the
        complexity of these physical processes when reviewing the different
        loss models that are available (refer <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_v24bb"/>).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_n65p4">
        <title>Urban Runoff</title>

        <para>Urban runoff, even at the allotment level, is complex, involving
        contributions from roofs, yards, adjacent road and pavement areas. The
        effective rainfall excess from the various areas is subject to
        significantly different infiltration regimes (Goyen &amp; O’Loughlin,
        1999a&amp;b) and these units are interconnected by complex and often
        transitory pathways (Riley &amp; Fanning, 1997). Further discussion on
        these complex processes is discussed in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_qbc9o">
        <title>Transmission Loss</title>

        <para>The estimation of transmission (or channel) losses may be
        required in systems where the volume along a reach is required.
        Stewart and Boughton (1983) identified that the processes contributing
        to transmission losses were water hole storage, infiltration,
        evaporation and bank storage.</para>

        <para>Majority of research on transmission losses for rural catchments
        was focused on long term losses relevant for water resource modelling
        and planning, rather than flood estimation. For example, there has
        been work done on gaining and losing river reaches within the Murray
        Darling Basin. Boughton (2015) explored transmission losses for 100
        catchments from the east-coast of Australia.</para>

        <para>The research on transmission losses tend to focus on specific
        reaches and hence the results are site specific. For very large arid
        catchments, transmission losses can be substantial, for example
        Knighton and Nanson (1994) found transmission losses of 75% for a
        reach of the Cooper Creek. However, for most design flood applications
        the channel losses will not be significant and can be combined with
        other processes that are implicitly covered by lumped conceptual
        models.</para>

        <para>Urban catchments may also be subject to transmission losses.
        While the losses identified for rural catchments are generally less
        pronounced in urban catchments, transmission losses can occur along
        the drainage system. This may include leakages and ageing
        infrastructure, particularly when the soil around the drainage system
        is highly permeable.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_v24bb">
      <title>Types of Loss Model</title>

      <para>For the purposes of this chapter, loss models are broken into
      three broad classes:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Empirical Models - designed to ensure depths of direct runoff
          and rainfall excess are in equilibrium. These types of models have
          minimal factors that would influence the values for an individual
          catchment.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Simple Models - attempt to quantify a portion of the processes
          in a simplified manner. These include, for example, Hortonian
          Infiltration models where all losses are assumed to relate to
          infiltration.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Process Models - attempt to represent the complex behaviour of
          losses within the catchment, and consider flow through the soil
          layers and over the catchment surface.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Given their complexities, process models have a large number of
      parameters that makes them difficult to apply to estimate design floods.
      In Australia, there is limited experience in applying process models for
      design flood estimation and therefore they are not covered in this
      section.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_9wr5k">
      <title>Empirical Models</title>

      <para>Empirical loss models focus less on the loss processes themselves,
      rather more on representing their effects in producing flows. Rainfall
      excess models typically fall within this category.</para>

      <para>In many of these models, the initial loss occurs in the beginning
      of the storm, prior to the commencement of surface runoff. It is assumed
      to be composed of interception losses, depression storage and
      infiltration before the soil surface is saturated; a continuing loss
      rate is then applied for the remainder of the storm. This model is
      consistent with the concept of runoff produced by infiltration excess,
      ie runoff occurs when the rainfall intensity exceeds the infiltration
      capacity of the soil.</para>

      <para>These models apply the losses directly to the rainfall,
      subtracting from the rainfall itself, to produce a rainfall excess that
      is subsequently applied to the hydrological model. This concept of
      rainfall excess is important, as it does not consider the changing
      catchment characteristics during the period of rainfall (compared with
      Simple and Process models).</para>

      <para>There is typically a wide range of initial loss values observed
      for a catchment (Rahman, et al, 2002; Phillips et al., 2014; Hill et al,
      2014a). This variability reflects the importance of antecedent
      conditions but uncertainties in the estimation of the timing and
      distribution of the catchment average rainfall also contribute to the
      range of values. This potential variability in the initial loss value is
      an important consideration, particularly in application of historical
      storms to hydrological models.</para>

      <para>A number of these models are described further below.</para>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_15kyp">
        <title>Initial Loss - Continuing Loss</title>

        <para>The continuing loss is the average loss rate throughout the
        remainder of the rainfall event after the initial losses are
        satisfied. Previous research and guidance suggests that constant loss
        rates are most applicable to large storm events, where a significant
        proportion of rainfall becomes runoff. <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_zi61a"/> provides an example of the application of a
        typical Initial Loss – Continuing Loss model.</para>

        <figure label="5040" xml:id="b5_ch5_f_zi61a">
          <title>Initial Loss – Constant Continuing Loss Model</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5040.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>Despite the simple conceptual nature of the <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151130T144521+1100" comment="should there be a glossary?
At least these terms need to be defined."?>IL/CL<?oxy_comment_end ?> model,
        there are a number of challenges in estimating continuing loss
        directly from recorded streamflow and rainfall.</para>

        <para>The continuing loss rate should not be based simply on a water
        balance of runoff volume less initial loss divided by the duration of
        the event. This will underestimate the loss rate; as illustrated in
        <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_zi61a"/> there will likely be timesteps in
        which the rainfall is less than the continuing loss rate (or even
        zero) and hence the full value is not taken up.</para>

        <para>Although not immediately apparent, the definition of CL also
        means that its magnitude is dependent on the timestep used in the
        analysis. This is because as the timestep reduces, there is an
        increased likelihood that there will be some timesteps in which the
        rainfall depth is less than the CL rate. Thus, to achieve the same
        volume of rainfall excess, the CL will typically need to be increased
        for shorter timesteps. This is discussed further in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_0rq6a"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_0mpxa">
        <title>Initial Loss – Proportional Loss</title>

        <para>The proportional loss models assume that a fixed proportion or
        percentage of the rainfall is lost at each time step, after the
        initial loss has been satisfied, which means that losses throughout
        the event may vary depending on the temporal patterns of rainfall. For
        simplicity, the proportional loss coefficient for a storm is usually
        taken as a constant.</para>

        <para><figure label="5041" xml:id="b5_ch5_f_6ak6p">
            <title>Initial Loss - Proportional Loss Model</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5041.PNG"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure></para>

        <para>Proportional loss models are consistent with runoff being
        generated by saturated overland flow. This assumes that runoff is
        generated from saturated portions of the catchment; this contributing
        area is expected to increase the duration and severity of the storm
        (Mein and O’Loughlin, 1991; Mag and Mein, 1994).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_d0sj6">
        <title>Variable Continuing Losses</title>

        <para>In the application of the constant continuing loss and
        proportional loss models, it has typically been assumed that the loss
        rates are a constant, after the initial loss is satisfied. However,
        based upon consideration of physical processes it might be expected
        that the loss rates should decrease throughout the event as the
        catchment becomes wetter and infiltration reduces and/or the size of
        source areas enlarges.</para>

        <para>For the IL/CL model this would suggest that the continuing loss
        should decrease as the event progresses and such a reduction with
        duration (as a surrogate for volume of infiltration) is observed from
        the empirical analysis of data by Ishak and Rahman (2006) and Ilahee
        and Imteaz (2009). The variation of continuing loss with event
        duration is discussed further in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_ty4k0"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ydmwv">
        <title>SCS Curve Number</title>

        <para>The SCS runoff curve number (CN) is widely used in the US as
        well as some countries in South-East Asia. Soils in the US are
        classified in four hydrologic groups (A, B, C, D) according to their
        infiltration rate. A CN is estimated from the hydrologic soil group,
        the treatment of the soil (effect of cultivated agricultural lands)
        and the hydrologic condition (the effect of vegetation density) to add
        more definition to the groupings (Boughton, 1989; Woodward et al.,
        2002; Van Mullem et al., 2002; and Ward et al., 2009).</para>

        <para>A number of studies such as Eastgate et al. (1979) and Rajendran
        et al. (1982) have applied the SCS to Australian soils. There is
        however a lack of information on how Australian soils are classified
        in the SCS hydrologic groups, which limits its application in
        Australia.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_k9w55">
        <title>Probability Distributed Storage Capacity Models</title>

        <para>Most conceptual loss models are lumped so that a similar
        parameter value is assumed over a catchment or sub-catchment. Moore
        (1985) introduced the concept of probability distributed models, which
        can be used to account for the spatial variability in runoff
        generation across a catchment. This variability can arise either
        from:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>differences in overall water storage capacity between
            sub-catchments (topography, soils, vegetation);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>spatial variation of water storage capacity within
            sub-catchments (potential loss distribution);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>stochastic variation of initial water storage status between
            events (different antecedent conditions); or</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>gradual variation in water storage status during an event
            (progressive wetting).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>These models are run in a continuous or semi-continuous fashion
        (updated during an event) and therefore can explicitly account for
        antecedent conditions, as well as for variation within an
        event.</para>

        <para>In general, the runoff mechanism in drier catchments is more
        likely to be controlled by infiltration rate whereas saturated excess
        is more likely to generate runoff for wetter catchments (Hill et al.,
        2013). The dominant mode of runoff production will depend on a range
        of factors including climate, soil, vegetation and topography. Those
        based on variable storage capacity reflect the subsurface saturation
        excess mechanism and include Xinanjiang (Ren-Jun et al., 1980), SWMOD
        (Stokes, 1989; Water and Rivers Commission, 2003) and the Revitalised
        Flood Hydrograph (ReFH) model in the UK (Kjeldsen et al, 2005).</para>

        <para>These models are based on the assumption that the catchment
        consists of many individual storage elements with a soil moisture
        capacity. The depth of water in each element increases with rainfall
        and decreases with evaporation. When rainfall exceeds the storage
        capacity, direct runoff is produced. The model assumes that the soil
        moisture is redistributed between the elements between rainfall
        events.</para>

        <para>The simplest form assumes a linear distribution of soil moisture
        in the catchment, from zero to its maximum capacity. This form of
        probability distributed model is incorporated in ReFH model in the UK.
        However, the above approach assumes that a portion of the catchment
        has zero storage capacity and hence there is no initial loss. Many
        catchments in arid and semi-arid areas exhibit a significant initial
        loss and therefore the conceptual model is extended such that the
        capacity varies between a minimum and maximum of the catchment. The
        simpler models assume that the capacities vary linearly while other
        models have introduced a shape parameter to describe the form of
        variation with capacity</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_681ox">
        <title>SWMOD</title>

        <para>Soil Water balance MODel (SWMOD) is developed by Stokes (1989)
        for the northern jarrah forest of Western Australia, where saturation
        excess overland flow is held to be the dominant runoff mechanism for
        storm events (Water and Rivers Commission, 2003). The model
        incorporates the ability of different landforms in the catchment to
        store water during the storm event. When the accumulated rainfall is
        greater than its infiltration capacity, the sub-catchment will
        generate saturation-excess overland flow. Infiltration capacity is
        assumed to vary within an area due only to soil depth.</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_g92zp">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>C</m:mi>

                <m:mi>f</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>C</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>max</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>−</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>C</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>max</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>C</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>min</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>×</m:mo>

              <m:msup>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                  <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                    <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                    <m:mi>b</m:mi>
                  </m:mfrac>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:msup>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where:</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic">Cf</emphasis> is the infiltration
        capacity at fraction <emphasis role="italic">F </emphasis>of the
        sub-catchment</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic">F</emphasis> is the fraction of the
        subcatchment</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic">b</emphasis> is the shape
        parameter</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic">C</emphasis>max is the maximum
        infiltration capacity</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic">C</emphasis>min is the minimum
        infiltration capacity</para>

        <para>The infiltration capacity is taken to mean the maximum depth of
        water that can be stored in the soil column. Where the accumulated
        rainfall is greater than the infiltration capacity that fraction of
        the sub-catchment will have saturation-excess overland flow.</para>

        <para>Large infiltrations ponds (10 to 15 m<superscript>2</superscript>) were used in
          conjunction with a ring infiltrometer and a well permeameter to determine the infiltration
          characteristics of a complex lateritic soil profile in the jarrah forest of Western
          Australia (Ruprecht &amp; Schofield, 1993). The logs from the construction of observation
          bores were able to characterise the shape of <emphasis role="italic">b</emphasis>
          parameter. Hill et al (2014b) outlines the application of SWMOD to 38 catchments across
          Australia.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ur1dn">
      <title>Simple Models</title>

      <para>In many loss models, the interception, depression storage and
      transmission losses are not directly accounted for, while the loss is
      treated as infiltration into the soil. The main factors affecting the
      soil infiltration process are the soil properties, antecedent moisture
      conditions, layered soils, rainfall intensity and surface sealing,
      vegetation cover and entrapment of air, and the soil slope and land use
      (Siriwardene et al. 2003). Simple models attempt to incorporate this
      infiltration into the soil through various models.</para>

      <para>Various representations to the complex equations for the water
      movement in the soil (such as Philip and Green-Ampt, Horton etc) are
      used to express the reduction of infiltration capacity with time
      (Maidment, 1992).</para>

      <para>Skukla et al. (2003) analysed ten infiltration models including
      Green-Ampt and Horton’s models, using double-ring infiltrometer tests
      and reported that the Horton’s model gave the best results for most land
      use conditions.</para>

      <para>Siriwardene et al (2003) undertook field infiltrometer tests at 21
      sites in eight Victorian urban catchments in order to estimate the
      infiltration parameters related to Horton’s infiltration model. They
      acknowledge the difficulty in selecting representative values for the
      infiltration parameters because of the 'significant variability with
      respect to soil type and land use in the catchment'.</para>

      <para>Mein and Goyen (1988) note that despite the obvious attraction of
      using Simple Models, 'the problem is to specify parameters (which relate
      to soil type) and initial conditions which are satisfactory for design
      use on a given catchment. In practice, the uncertainties of soil
      behaviour and the areal variability of soil properties do not justify
      the use of anything more than the simplest model'.</para>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ti9sw">
        <title>Horton Model</title>

        <para>Horton’s equation has been used and modified over the years to
        provide an estimate of losses due to infiltration into pervious
        surfaces. It is based on a diminishing continual loss, as described in
        <xref linkend="b5_ch5_e_r91ce"/> below.</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_r91ce">
          <m:math>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                <m:mi>t</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                <m:mi>c</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                    <m:mn>0</m:mn>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>c</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:msup>
                <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>k</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:msup>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where:</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> f<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis> is
        the infiltration capacity (mm/h)</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> f<subscript>c</subscript></emphasis> is
        the minimum or ultimate value of <emphasis
        role="italic">f<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis>(mm/h)</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> f<subscript>0</subscript></emphasis> is
        the maximum or initial value of <emphasis
        role="italic">f<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis> (mm/h)</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> k</emphasis> is a decay coefficient
        (per hour)</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> t</emphasis> is the time from the
        beginning of the storm (h)</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_q4tw1">
        <title>Green-Ampt</title>

        <para>The most commonly used approximate theory based infiltration
        model is the one developed by Green-Ampt (1911), which is an
        approximate model utilising Darcy’s law and is further discussed in
        Mein and Larson (1973), Chu (1978), Lee and Lim (1995) and King
        (2000).</para>

        <para>Williams (1994) describes a pilot study for nine Victorian
        catchments to determine if application of the Green-Ampt equation
        provides a superior results to simplified models, when applied at
        catchment scale. Although the Green-Ampt equation was successfully
        applied to each catchment, the results produced were not on average
        superior to those produced using the simple empirical models.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_77kg3">
        <title>Australian Representative Basin Model (ARBM)</title>

        <para>The Australian Representative Basin Model (ARBM) was developed
        with the aim to classify and select hydrologically diverse basins at a
        significant scale for resource development (Fleming, 1974; Mein &amp;
        McMahon; 1982). Furthermore, the model sought to increase the
        understanding of the hydrological processes in each basin.</para>

        <para>The ARBM is structured to represent the passage of water over
        and through the catchment, as illustrated in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_g5ett"/>. It is based on Chapman’s work (1968 &amp;
        1970), which originally sought to optimise certain parameters, while
        measuring others. However, developers Boyd et al began optimising all
        parameters as it was believed that measurements were difficult,
        uncertain, costly and impractical (Mein &amp; McMahon,1982).</para>

        <para>The model uses a deterministic mathematical model intended to
        represent physical processes and relationships between rainfall and
        runoff for the catchment. It operates in a continuous mode,
        considering both rainfall events and initial estimations of soil
        moisture conditions for each wetting event. This is done by simulating
        soil moisture depletion by evaporation between rainfall events
        (Fleming, 1974). It is expected that the parameters used would be
        related to physical catchment characteristics, therefore making the
        model applicable to any Australian gauged or ungauged
        catchment.</para>

        <para>Despite being developed, the optimised parameters have not
        exhibited uniqueness. Mein and McMahon (1982) however, do not believe
        that this particular model produces outcomes that are any different to
        other process models developed for the same purpose.</para>

        <figure label="5042" xml:id="b5_ch5_f_g5ett">
          <title>The model structure of the Australian Representative Basins
          model based on the work of Chapman (1968). Diagram obtained from
          Black and Aitken (1977) and Mein and McMahon (1982).</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5042.PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_iyrl7">
      <title>Process Methods</title>

      <para>Continuous simulation is covered in <xref linkend="b2_ch6"/> and
      therefore the following brief overview concentrates on the loss
      modelling aspects.</para>

      <para>These models typically estimate the losses from rainfall and the
      generation of streamflow by simulating the wetness and dryness of the
      catchment on a daily, hourly and occasionally sub-hourly basis.
      Continuous simulation eliminates the need to select representative
      values of loss, since the loss is explicitly included in the modelling.
      The focus of loss conceptualisation in continuous rainfall-runoff
      simulation models is less on the representation of the loss process,
      rather than on representing the effect on producing floods.</para>

      <para>The majority of continuous simulation applications are for flood
      forecasting, rather than for design flood estimation. The development of
      stochastic rainfall generation techniques has encouraged their
      application for design flood estimation (Boughton et al. 1999, Kuczera
      et al.. 2006).</para>

      <para>A number of Australian studies have applied a continuous
      simulation approach to estimate design floods and compared the results
      to those from flood frequency analysis such as Boughton and Hill (1997),
      Muncaster et al. (1999), Boughton et al. (1999) and Heneker et al.
      (2003). The reported applications of continuous simulation for design
      flood estimation have typically involved calibration against recorded
      data, however,to extend the use to ungauged catchments, it will require
      developing regional relationships for model
      parameters.<?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151130T145616+1100" comment="conclusion, generally arent yet suitable"?></para>

      <?oxy_comment_end ?>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_e5fbn">
    <title>Approach to Selection of Loss Model and Values</title>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_zwmz0">
      <title>Selection of loss model</title>

      <para>For real-time flood forecasting or calibration of a hydrologic
      model, the focus is on selection of models and parameter values that
      replicate the observed hydrograph. However, for design flood estimation,
      the objective is the derivation of unbiased estimates of specific
      characteristics of a design flood (typically the peak).</para>

      <para>Thus, the key objectives of loss models and their parameterisation
      for design flood estimation are to:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>close the volume balance in a probabilistic sense such that
          the volume of the design flood hydrograph for a given AEP should
          match the flood volume derived from frequency analysis of flood
          volumes;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>produce a realistic time distribution of runoff to allow the
          modelling of peak flow and hydrograph shape;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>reflect the effects of natural variability of runoff
          production for different events on the same catchment, to avoid
          probability bias in flood estimates; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>reflect the variation of runoff production with different
          catchment characteristics to enable application to ungauged
          catchments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_8u8o4"/>, there are a
      range of different conceptual loss models that were derived with
      different conceptualisation and varying degrees of complexity from
      simple lumped rainfall excess models to more detailed process
      models.</para>

      <para>The above objectives are important when selecting loss models for
      design flood estimation. It is therefore helpful to consider the
      following criteria when selecting a loss model for design flood
      estimation:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the model produces a temporal distribution of rainfall-excess
          that is consistent with the effect of the processes contributing to
          loss;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>suitable for extrapolation beyond calibration and is hence
          applicable to estimate floods over the required range of
          AEPs;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>inputs are consistent with readily available data;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>small number of parameters that need to be selected
          (preferably no more than 2);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>parameters have been linked to catchment characteristics, or
          it is considered reasonable that such a link could be established so
          that the parameters can be regionalised; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>have the potential to be easily incorporated into
          rainfall-runoff models.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Considerations of such issues have typically resulted in adoption
      of simple rainfall excess models.</para>

      <para>Dyer et al. (1994) compared the performance of the constant
      continuing loss and proportional loss models for 24 catchments using
      <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151124T142316+1100" comment="What does this stand for?"?>RORB<?oxy_comment_end ?>
      and found that the proportion loss model resulted in generally improved
      calibrations. This finding was supported by Hill et al. (1996), who
      calibrated RORB models for 11 Victorian catchments. However, analyses
      undertaken by Phillips et al. (2014) and Hill et al. (2014a), concluded
      that the results were inconclusive in regards to the best model. Even
      for catchments where one of the loss models was preferred for a majority
      of events, there were some events for which the alternate model was
      preferred. Similarly, there was no obvious relationship between the
      preference for a particular model and hydroclimatic or catchment
      characteristics that could explain the preference for a particular
      approach.</para>

      <para>A number of Australian studies have demonstrated that the IL/CL
      model is suitable for design flood estimation where in it can be used to
      estimate design flood estimates over a range of AEPs. However, it is
      often difficult to derive unbiased estimates of floods using the IL/PL
      model over a range of AEPs. Specifically, the IL/PL model has the
      potential to underestimate peak flows for events rarer than used in the
      derivation of the values; this suggests that PL should vary with the AEP
      of the event.</para>

      <para>Furthermore, studies that have analysed a large number of events
      and catchments such as Phillips et al. (2014) and Hill et al. (2014a)
      have found that there can be a large variation in PL values, which makes
      it difficult to recommend a representative value for design <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_s_w4y2w"/>.</para>

      <para>Given the difficulties in characterising how PL should vary with
      AEP, it is considered that the IL/CL model is the most suitable of these
      simple rainfall excess models for design flood estimation for both rural
      and urban catchments. Probability distributed loss models such as SWMOD
      demonstrate promise and should also be considered for rural catchments
      where there is reliable and consistent description of hydraulic
      properties of soils.</para>

      <para>If alternate loss models are to be adopted then they should be
      evaluated against the above criteria. An important consideration is how
      the loss model performs when extrapolated to events outside of the range
      of events used in deriving the loss values.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_wuhr9">
      <title>Design Rainfall Bursts v Complete Storms</title>

      <para>In selecting loss values for design flood estimation, it is
      important to consider the nature of the design rainfall information. The
      IFD data in <xref linkend="book2"/> is derived from the analysis of
      rainfalls for standard durations, rather than complete storms. In some
      cases, these events represent complete storms but also include cases of
      bursts of rainfalls within a much longer duration storm.</para>

      <para>The conceptual difference between the initial loss for a rainfall
      burst (ILb) and for a storm (ILs) is illustrated in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_f_i72qx"/>. The initial loss for the storm is assumed to
      be the depth of rainfall prior to the commencement of surface runoff.
      The initial loss for the burst however, is the portion of the storm
      initial loss, which occurs within the burst.</para>

      <figure label="5043" xml:id="b5_ch5_f_i72qx">
        <title>Distinction between Storm and Burst Initial Loss</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5043.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>If pre-burst rainfalls are included, then the design rainfalls
      will represent (near) complete design storms and therefore the storm
      losses can be directly applied without adjustment. The design values
      recommended in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_dewgv"/> are intended for
      application with complete storms and therefore, requires the pre-burst
      depths to be included.</para>

      <para>However, if design bursts, rather than complete storms, are used
      in design then the burst initial loss needs to be reduced to account for
      the pre-burst rainfall. For the same reason, the initial moisture
      content for storage capacity models (such as Horton and SWMOD) need to
      be increased to account for this pre-burst rainfall.</para>

      <para>This has implications for all design flood situations, but is
      particularly important for design situations where the outcome is
      sensitive to the flood volume, such as the design of retarding basins
      (Rigby &amp; Bannigan. 1996). The failure to recognise the rainfall
      prior to design rainfall bursts has the potential to significantly
      underestimate the design flood.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_b00h9">
      <title>Approaches to estimating loss values</title>

      <para>The most appropriate approach to estimating loss values will
      depend upon the objectives and required rigour of the study, and the
      quality and availability of at-site and regional flood data. The
      different approaches can be considered in the following broad
      classes:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Empirical analysis of at-site rainfall and streamflow
          records;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Information from regional analysis of data; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Reconciliation of design values with independent flood
          frequency estimates.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_70ifb">
        <title>At-site event data</title>

        <para>If there is long-term pluviograph and streamflow data available
        at the site of interest it may be possible to directly estimate loss
        values for a number of events. In order to undertake such an analysis
        the streamflow should be free of significant regulation or diversion
        and land use within the catchment should be stationary over the period
        of data being analysed.</para>

        <para>The events to be analysed should be selected carefully to ensure
        that the sample of events is not biased. The selection of high runoff
        events for loss derivation is likely to be biased towards wet
        antecedent conditions (ie. losses tend to be too low). Ideally, events
        should be selected on the basis of rainfall to remove this bias.
        However the selection and analysis of events by rainfall is
        problematic because it requires consideration of a representative
        duration of the rainfall and there may be little or no runoff
        generated from some intense bursts of rainfall if the antecedent
        conditions are dry.</para>

        <para>The main limitation of deriving losses directly from the
        analysis of recorded data is that they may not be compatible with the
        other design inputs and hence suitable for design flood estimation.
        That is, although the loss values may reflect the loss response
        observed for a number of events on the catchment, this does not
        guarantee that their application with other design inputs results in
        unbiased estimates of floods. For this reason, it is also desirable to
        reconcile design values with independent flood frequency estimates
        where possible (refer <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_pyitn"/>).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_t3hpv">
        <title>Regional Data</title>

        <para>Deriving loss values from an analysis from multiple catchments
        has the advantage that there is the opportunity to be more selective
        in selecting the data sets to be analysed and the larger sample allows
        the distribution of values to be explored. However the results from
        these regional analyses need to be transposed to the catchment of
        interest which relies on relationship being developed between the loss
        values and physical characteristics – a link which has generally
        proved to be elusive.</para>

        <para>As part of <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151124T162316+1100" comment="What is the exact name of this project. There is a different name used earlier. "?>ARR
        Revision Project #6<?oxy_comment_end ?>, loss values were estimated
        for a large number of urban (Phillips et al., 2014) and rural
        catchments (Hill et al., 2014a). These two studies represent the most
        comprehensive regional studies of losses covering Australia and hence
        the recommended loss values summarised in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_dewgv"/> are largely based upon these
        studies.</para>

        <para>As with the estimation of losses from a single site, their
        application with other design inputs does not guarantee unbiased
        estimates of floods and for this reason, it is therefore also
        desirable to reconcile design values with independent flood frequency
        estimates where possible (refer <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_pyitn"/>).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_pyitn">
        <title>Reconcile design values with independent flood frequency
        estimates</title>

        <para>Deriving loss values by comparison with flood frequency
        estimates has the advantage of producing design losses which are
        consistent with the other design parameters and the design objective
        of deriving peak flows of a given AEP. Indeed the use of design
        rainfalls to estimate design floods is in fact the sole objective of
        rainfall-based flood event modelling. The only difference between
        calibration of the model in this manner and its application is in the
        magnitude of the events being considered.</para>

        <para>The fundamental limitation of this approach is that all the
        uncertainty in the each of the design inputs (eg IFD, ARF, temporal
        patterns, spatial patterns), modelling (model conceptualisation and
        parameterisation) and the <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151130T150005+1100" comment="THis is all trbu FFa is a good method. refer to Book 4 where different methods are used"?>flood
        frequency analysis<?oxy_comment_end ?> (eg rating curve, choice and
        fitting of the distribution) is reflected in the resulting loss
        values. The loss simply becomes an error term to compensate for all of
        the uncertainty and biases in all other inputs. It is therefore not
        surprising that the values derived from such an approach (eg Walsh et
        al. 1991; Flavell &amp; Belstead, 1986) typically display a large
        range and relating such values to physical catchment characteristics
        (that should influence infiltration and interception) has proven
        intractable.</para>

        <para>A further limitation of such approach is that the resulting loss
        values are a function of the design flood estimation method itself and
        are therefore only suitable for application with the same set of
        inputs. For example, if new or alternate information is available on
        any of the inputs such as IFD, ARF then the analysis needs to be
        repeated. Thus, the values only work with a single combination of
        design inputs.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ohbe9">
        <title>Summary of Approaches</title>

        <para>The advantages and disadvantages of these different approaches
        are summarised in the table below. <table frame="all"
            xml:id="b5_ch5_t_vbguq">
            <title>Summary of Different approaches for estimating loss
            values</title>

            <tgroup cols="3">
              <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>

              <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

              <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>

              <thead>
                <row>
                  <entry><emphasis role="bold">Approach</emphasis></entry>

                  <entry><emphasis role="bold">Advantages</emphasis></entry>

                  <entry><emphasis
                  role="bold">Disadvantages</emphasis></entry>
                </row>
              </thead>

              <tbody>
                <row>
                  <entry>1. Empirical analysis of at-site rainfall and
                  streamflow records</entry>

                  <entry><itemizedlist>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Data is directly relevant to the location of
                        interest and explicitly accounts for the catchment
                        characteristics.</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></entry>

                  <entry><itemizedlist>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Only applicable where the catchment is free of
                        significant regulation and diversions and the land use
                        has been stationary</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Most catchments do not have a long period of
                        concurrent pluviograph and streamflow data</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Difficulty in selecting an unbiased sample of
                        events</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Does not guarantee that values result in
                        unbiased estimates of floods</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Small sample of events makes it difficult to
                        explore distribution of loss values</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>2. Regional information</entry>

                  <entry><itemizedlist>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Can be more selective in choice of data sets for
                        analysis</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Larger sample of events allows distribution of
                        values and relationships with characteristics to be
                        explored</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></entry>

                  <entry><itemizedlist>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Considerable effort required</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Difficulty in selecting an unbiased sample of
                        events</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Does not guarantee that values result in
                        unbiased estimates of floods</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Difficultly in linking loss values to rainfall
                        and catchment characteristics</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>3. Reconciliation of design values with independent
                  flood frequency estimates</entry>

                  <entry><itemizedlist>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Checks that, when combined with the other design
                        inputs, the loss values produce unbiased
                        estimates</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Loss values implicitly account for the nature of
                        the design rainfall; whether rainfall bursts or
                        complete storms</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></entry>

                  <entry><itemizedlist>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Unlikely to have a long-term stationary
                        streamflow record at the location of interest</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>If sufficient streamflow is not available,
                        reliance on estimates of regional flood frequency
                        analysis introduces additional uncertainty</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Different combination of loss values can result
                        in same flood estimates but has different impact when
                        applied outside of the magnitude used for
                        reconciliation</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>All of the uncertainty in the design process is
                        attributed to the loss which makes it difficult to
                        infer link with rainfall and catchment
                        characteristics</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Unlikely to have sufficient information to be
                        able to define distribution of loss values</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                </row>
              </tbody>
            </tgroup>
          </table></para>

        <para>If there is a long-term stationary streamflow record at the
        site, reconciliation of design values (Option 3) is preferable but if
        the distribution of loss values is required this will typically need
        to be inferred from previous studies (Option 2). In majority of cases,
        there will be insufficient streamflow data available at the site and
        therefore a combination of regional information (Option 2) and
        reconciliation of design values with regional flood frequency
        estimates (Option 3) will typically be the most appropriate
        approach.</para>

        <para>For urban catchments it is more difficult to obtain independent
        flood frequency estimates and therefore values will often need to be
        inferred from at-site data (Option 1) or values obtained from regional
        information (Option 2).</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2">
    <title>Losses in Urban Catchments</title>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_pzbvk">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_mx2fy">
        <title><?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151130T150145+1100" comment="the Effective Impervious Area (EIA) is a critical factor in assessing losses in urban catchments."?>Surface
        Types<?oxy_comment_end ?></title>

        <para>In estimating runoff from urban catchments, four separate types
        of surfaces are generally recognised and are referred to in this
        chapter as the following:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Directly Connected Areas, which consist of:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>impervious areas (e.g. roofs and paved areas) which
                  are directly connected to the drainage system – referred to
                  as Direct Connected Impervious Areas (DCIA).</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Indirectly Connected Areas, which consist of: <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>impervious areas which are not directly connected,
                  runoff from which flows over pervious surfaces before
                  reaching the drainage system (e.g. a roof that discharges
                  onto a lawn) – referred to as Indirectly Connected
                  Impervious Areas (ICIA).</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Pervious areas that interact with Indirectly Connected
                  Impervious Areas, such as nature strips, garden areas next
                  to paved patios, etc.</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Pervious areas consisting of parklands and bushland that do
            not interact with<?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151130T150223+1100" comment="Need to define total impervious area here"?>
            impervious areas.<?oxy_comment_end ?></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para><figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_w07xt">
            <title>Example of a Directly Connected Impervious Surface (Left)
            and an Indirectly Connected Impervious Surface (Right)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5044.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure></para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_cnp1s">
        <title>Challenges with Total Impervious Area</title>

        <para>Estimating the catchment imperviousness is an important step in
        urban rainfall runoff modelling, particularly given the sensitivity of
        simulated runoff to this parameter in many models (Alley &amp;
        Veenhuis, 1983). Traditionally, the Total Impervious Area (TIA) is
        used with the assumption that, neglecting depression losses, this area
        contributes fully to generating runoff. This is despite the research
        dating back to the 1970s, identifying the importance of the Effective
        Impervious Area (EIA) over the TIA (refer to Cherkaver, 1975; Beard
        and Shin Chang, 1979).</para>

        <para>Use of the TIA, which includes impervious areas with no direct
        connection to the drainage network, can result in the overestimation
        of urban runoff volumes and peak flows. Although definitions vary, the
        EIA is generally considered to be representative of the area of the
        catchment that generates a rapid runoff response in rainfall events.
        It incorporates the impervious area with a hydraulic connection to the
        drainage network (DCIA), plus a contribution comprising discharges
        from an impervious area onto a pervious area (ICIA), which rapidly
        saturates and acts in a similar manner to an impervious area. The EIA
        therefore provides a more realistic measure of the impervious area
        that generates runoff at the catchment outlet.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_qqflw">
        <title>Conceptualisation of Runoff Process</title>

        <para>As rainfall continues to fall, it would be expected that
        additional indirectly connected impervious areas would start to
        contribute to runoff. A simplified representation of this is shown in
        <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_fmz5c"/>. In this schematic, when the initial
        loss for the Indirectly Connected Area is saturated, the Indirectly
        Connected Area (comprising pervious and impervious areas) will start
        to contribute to the runoff. Similarly, once the initial loss of the
        pervious area is saturated, the pervious area will start to contribute
        to runoff.</para>

        <para>This conceptualisation was observed in Phillips et al (2014) by
        plotting cumulative runoff of the observed rainfall, the observed
        discharge, and the estimated runoff based on the calculated EIA
        estimate (<xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_jbird"/>). The deviation of the
        cumulative observed discharge form the calculated cumulative EIA
        discharge would suggest the point of Indirectly Connected Area
        contribution.</para>

        <para>It is noted that in Phillips et al (2014), the Indirectly
        Connected Area incorporated all residential components of the
        catchment outside of the EIA. Only areas such as large parklands,
        bushland areas etc were separated out of the analysis. This was
        following a detailed review of the behaviour, identifying only two
        discernible responses from within the urban components of a catchment.
        This approach is recommended.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_fmz5c">
          <title>Schematic of Rainfall Depth v Runoff, from Boyd et al
          (1993)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5045.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_jbird">
          <title>Cumulative Discharge Plot from Giralang (ACT), showing
          Cumulative Rainfall, Observed Runoff and Estimated EIA runoff
          (Phillips et al., 2014)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5046.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_oj30q">
      <title>Estimating EIA</title>

      <para>There are a number of methods for estimating EIA. These
      include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Regression analysis of streamflow and rainfall records, where
          sufficient data exists;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Adoption of typical EIA/TIA ratios, based on available
          literature;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>GIS Mapping of TIA areas.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>These are described in more detail below.</para>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_yu0rf">
        <title>Regression Analysis</title>

        <para>The EIA can be estimated using regression techniques on gauged
        urban catchments, where there are sufficient gauging records to do so.
        This method provides the most accurate method for estimating EIA for a
        specific catchment, as it does not require the extrapolation of
        relationships from other catchments.</para>

        <para>This method is done by comparing flow records with a
        representative rain gauge that is located within or very near the
        catchment. The key to this method is isolating the runoff that occurs
        only from the EIA, and not from the other impervious and pervious
        areas. A method for doing this is detailed in Phillips et al. (2014),
        with an overview of the general approach provided in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_9xa0f"/>. An example of the output of this kind of
        analysis is provided in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_rrohw"/>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_9xa0f">
          <title>Overview of Regression Analysis Approach</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5047.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>As identified in Phillip et al. (2014), the key requirements for
        this method are:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A sufficient gauging (both rainfall and flow) record to
            undertake the analysis. Phillips et al. (2014) adopted a 10 year
            record as a minimum, although the technique that was applied for
            the EIA estimation could potentially be used for much shorter
            records. Where shorter records are adopted, the data should also
            be checked to ensure that there are sufficient range of rainfall
            events in terms of magnitude, in order to create a reasonable
            regression.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The catchment must have an acceptable gauge rating. Further
            details on this are discussed in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>. It is
            noted that because of the technique to isolate EIA events, very
            large events are generally excluded due to the presence of
            pervious area runoff. In the absence of any detailed studies on
            this, a gauge that has an acceptable rating up to around an AEP of
            20% may provide a reasonable representation, as long as all events
            above the acceptable flow level of the gauge are excluded. It is
            important that engineering judgement is undertaken in reviewing
            the suitability of the data set.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A relatively small catchment area. A catchment area of 5 km²
            was used as a target catchment area for the Phillips et al. (2014)
            analysis, although there is no strict guide as to what is
            appropriate. Larger catchment areas result in a number of
            potential issues:</para>

            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Greater likelihood for influences of hydraulic controls,
                catchment storages etc. influencing the runoff;</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Greater difficulty in isolating the EIA runoff due to
                longer lag periods from upper catchment areas;</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>More potential for baseflow which will need to be
                excluded from the analysis;</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Spatial variation of rainfall becomes more important,
                and therefore more gauges should potentially be used in the
                analysis. This will require spatial averaging techniques for
                rainfall, as discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch4"/>.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A relatively stationary upstream catchment during the period
            of record (i.e. minimal changes in land-use, development intensity
            etc.).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>This process is analytically intensive and is unlikely to be
        applied in simple applications.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_rrohw">
          <title>Example Regression Analysis for Albany Drain Catchment in
          WA</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5048.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_3gs2s">
        <title>Adoption of Typical EIA/TIA Ratios</title>

        <para>Where appropriate flow gauging and rainfall data does not exist,
        an alternative method for estimating EIA is based on available
        research on similar catchments.</para>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_0nsjx">
          <title>Relevant Research</title>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">EIA/ TIA</emphasis></para>
          <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151130T150424+1100" comment="Total Impervious Area hasn&apos;t been defined and how to measure it"?>
          <para><?oxy_comment_end?>The EIA/ TIA ratio has been found in a number of studies (e.g.
            Phillips et al, 2014; Ball and Powell, 1998; Boyd et al., 1993) to be a good indicator,
            removing the variability of total imperviousness to create a measure that can be
            extrapolated to other catchments.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Australian Estimates</emphasis></para>
          <para>Phillips et al. (2014) analysed 8 separate catchments throughout Australia using the
            regression analysis discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_pzbvk"/>. These catchments
            spanned across all 8 states and territories. However, it is noted that there is only
            limited representation from the northern part of Australia, with only one catchment from
            Darwin in the Northern Territory included. This is a reflection of the general urban
            densities throughout Australia.</para>
          <para>This study identified that EIA is typically 55 to 65% of the TIA for most of the
            catchments identified. This range was recommended in the study in estimating the EIA for
            most Australian catchments. Based on a sensitivity analysis undertaken within Phillips
            et al. (2014) of some of the key assumptions, the estimates of EIA are expected to fall
            within +/- 5% to 10% of this estimated range.</para>
          <para>It is noted that one catchment from the ACT was identified to have a higher ratio of
            74% to 80%. It was theorised that this is likely due to the higher degree of connected
            surfaces (as discussed in Goyen (2000)), although there were insufficient additional
            catchments to confirm this hypothesis.</para>
          <para>The Phillips et al. (2014) study also estimated the DCIA using GIS methods, which
            primarily included road, roof and driveways (where these driveways drained to the
            street). It is noted that the road and roof area represents the majority of this area.
            The analysis suggested that the EIA was roughly in the range of 70 to 80% of this area,
            suggesting that not all of the roof and road area contributed to runoff.</para>
          <para>A summary of results from Phillips et al (2014) are presented in <xref
              linkend="b5_ch5_t_0jql6"/>.</para>
          <para>In order to derive the estimates of EIA/ TIA, Phillips et al (2014) used detailed
            mapping of different land-uses and aerial photography to estimate the TIA. This was
            undertaken by taking representative areas within the catchments, detailing the
            impervious areas, and then extrapolating this to the wider catchment based on land-use
            mapping which was also derived from aerial photography.</para>
          <para>
            <table frame="all" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_0jql6">
              <title>Summary of EIA Results</title>
              <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c6" colnum="6" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c7" colnum="7" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c8" colnum="8" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Catchment</entry>
                    <entry>Total Area (ha)</entry>
                    <entry>Urban Area<footnote>
                        <para>The urban area for these catchments was based on the residential
                          developed areas, excluding parklands, bushland etc.</para>
                      </footnote> (ha)</entry>
                    <entry>TIA (ha)</entry>
                    <entry>Urban TIA Fraction<footnote>
                        <para>The Urban TIA fraction is defined as the percentage of impervious area
                          in the urban area and was based on the desktop GIS method.</para>
                      </footnote></entry>
                    <entry>EIA/TIA</entry>
                    <entry>DCIA (GIS)/ TIA</entry>
                    <entry>EIA (Reg.) /DCIA(GIS)</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Albany Drain (WA)</entry>
                    <entry>8.2</entry>
                    <entry>8.2</entry>
                    <entry>2.9</entry>
                    <entry>35%</entry>
                    <entry>59%</entry>
                    <entry>83%</entry>
                    <entry>71%</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>McArthur Park (NT)</entry>
                    <entry>144</entry>
                    <entry>120</entry>
                    <entry>53.7</entry>
                    <entry>45%</entry>
                    <entry>66%</entry>
                    <entry>93%</entry>
                    <entry>70%</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Giralang (ACT)</entry>
                    <entry>91</entry>
                    <entry>61.8</entry>
                    <entry>28.4</entry>
                    <entry>46%</entry>
                    <entry>74 to 80%</entry>
                    <entry>95%</entry>
                    <entry>82%</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Parra Hills Drain (SA)</entry>
                    <entry>55.1</entry>
                    <entry>48.5</entry>
                    <entry>26.9</entry>
                    <entry>55%</entry>
                    <entry>56%</entry>
                    <entry>87%</entry>
                    <entry>64%</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Kinkora Road (VIC)</entry>
                    <entry>202</entry>
                    <entry>184</entry>
                    <entry>122</entry>
                    <entry>66%</entry>
                    <entry>59%</entry>
                    <entry>87%</entry>
                    <entry>68%</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Powells Creek (NSW)</entry>
                    <entry>232</entry>
                    <entry>223</entry>
                    <entry>152</entry>
                    <entry>68%</entry>
                    <entry>59 to 63%</entry>
                    <entry>81%</entry>
                    <entry>75%</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Ithaca Creek (Qld)<footnote xml:id="b5_ch5_fn_iehnds">
                        <para>Note that Ithaca (QLD) and Argyle St (Tas) were noted to be limited
                          due primarily to large pervious (bushland) areas in these catchments,
                          which influences the results</para>
                      </footnote></entry>
                    <entry>926</entry>
                    <entry>262</entry>
                    <entry>128</entry>
                    <entry>49%</entry>
                    <entry>55%</entry>
                    <entry>95%</entry>
                    <entry>58%</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Argyle Street (TAS)<footnoteref linkend="b5_ch5_fn_iehnds"/></entry>
                    <entry>1900</entry>
                    <entry>491</entry>
                    <entry>292</entry>
                    <entry>59%</entry>
                    <entry>63%</entry>
                    <entry>93%</entry>
                    <entry>68%</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table>
          </para>
          <para>Ball and Powell (1998) estimated the EIA for Powells Creek in NSW (also analysed by
            the Phillips et al., 2014 research). The analysis of rainfall and runoff data was
            undertaken by also comparing the antecedent moisture (AMC) in the catchment, based on
            rainfall in the days leading up to the storm event (refer <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_fkq1d"
            />). The analysis showed an EIA percentage of the total catchment area (not the TIA) of
            ranging from 35% to 44% depending on the AMC. Based on the TIA estimated in <xref
              linkend="b5_ch5_t_0jql6"/> for the same catchment, this represents an EIA/ TIA of
            around 53% to 67%, depending on the AMC. This range is very similar to that found under
            Phillips et al (2014), both for Powells Creek as well as for the wider catchments
            analysed. Similarly, Chiew and McMahon (1999) undertook an analysis of Powells Creek and
            found an EIA to total catchment area of around 40%.</para>
          <para>Zaman and Ball (1994) undertook a study on Salt Pan Creek in NSW (Southern Sydney).
            This study estimated the EIA using two alternative methods. The first looked at
            estimates using orthophoto maps and applying estimates of the EIA to different
            land-uses. The second analysed rainfall and runoff records to estimate the EIA. Both
            methods estimated an approximate EIA to Total Area of 39% to 41% of the total catchment
            area. However, it is noted in the description of this catchment that there are open
            space areas, making it difficult to directly compare this to other studies. Also, there
            was no clear description of the TIA to be able to provide a comparative EIA/TIA ratio.
            Chiew and McMahon (1999) by comparison estimated an EIA to Total Area of 27% for this
            catchment.</para>
          <para>Boyd, et al. (1993) analysed 26 catchments, 9 located within Australia (Sydney,
            Canberra and Melbourne), while the others were international (USA, Canada, UK, Japan and
            a number of European countries). This study undertook a similar analysis to that of
            Phillips et al (2014). A regression analysis was undertaken on the EIA/Total Area versus
            the TIA/Total Area and estimated that the EIA/ TIA ratio of around 74%. A summary of the
            results is provided in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_a"/>.</para>
          <para>One key thing to note from this study is that there were a number of catchments
            where the EIA was identified as being greater than the TIA. This is unlikely to be the
            case in reality, unless the pervious areas have little infiltration. This was not
            discussed in the paper, but it assumed that the TIA estimated based on aerial
            photography may not have been appropriate. The data from this study was re-analysed
            where EIA &gt; TIA catchments are excluded from the analysis, with the results shown in
              <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_ppc4n"/> (the Australian catchments are circled for
            reference). This was also mapped against Urban Area (ie excluding large pervious areas
            like bushland and parks), rather than Total Area, to normalise it with the Phillips et
            al (2014) study and exclude the effects of bushland etc. in the catchments. The
            re-analysed EIA/TIA ratio is 71%, which is close to the 55% to 65% range identified in
            Phillips et al. (2014).</para>
          <para>Dayaratne (2000), which is also referenced in O’Loughlin and Stack (2014), obtained
            relationships with housing density from modelling storms on 16 gauged residential
            catchments in four Victorian municipalities:</para>
          <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_iesq3">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                  <m:mi>DCIA</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>TA</m:mi>
                </m:mfrac>
                <m:mo>(%) =</m:mo>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>
                        <m:mi>0.85</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>hhd</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                      </m:msup>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>23.38</m:mo>
                      <m:mi>hhd</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>- 101.19</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msup>
                          <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:msup>
                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                        <m:mi>0.90</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
          <para/>
          <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_9ks3u">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                  <m:mi>ICIA</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>TA</m:mi>
                </m:mfrac>
                <m:mo>(%) =</m:mo>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>
                        <m:mi>0.04</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>hhd</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                      </m:msup>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>1.13</m:mo>
                      <m:mi>hhd</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>- 3.79</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msup>
                          <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:msup>
                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                        <m:mi>0.91</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
          <para>Where hhd = number of houses per hectare.</para>
          <para>It is important to note that this study was based on a range of 7 to 14 houses per
            hectare. Beyond this range, the equation has significant limitations, as demonstrated in
              <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_qj05h"/> (ie DCIA reduces with increasing households per
            hectare for households greater than around 15 per hectare. Also, DCIA reduces below 0%
            for less than 5 households per hectare). The Phillips et al. (2014) results are also
            shown on this graph for reference.</para>
          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_qj05h">
            <title>Representation of Dayaratne (2000) Relationship for DCIA</title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5049.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <para>A further review of just the Australian data from the Boyd, et al. (1993) study was
            compared with that of the Phillips et al. (2014) study. The results of this review are
            shown in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_tceg6"/> (and removing those catchments which overlap
            in both studies). The EIA/ Urban Area from this analysis is estimated to be around
            60%.</para>
          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_ppc4n">
            <title>Re-Analysis of Boyd, et al (1993) Data<footnote>
                <para>Australian catchments circled for reference</para>
              </footnote></title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5050.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_tceg6">
            <title>Australian data from Phillips et al (2014) and Boyd et al (1993)</title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5051.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">International Estimates</emphasis></para>
          <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_t_o0kcf"/> provides an overview of international literature on
            the estimation of EIA/TIA.</para>
          <para>The research by Alley and Veenhuis (1983) shows close correlation with the
            Australian studies for residential catchments (between 53% to 77%, refer <xref
              linkend="b5_ch5_t_o0kcf"/>). This study also incorporated commercial and industrial
            land-uses, indicating 94% and 77% respectively. As many of the studies have been
            undertaken in residential (or predominantly residential) areas, this provides a useful
            comparison for commercial and industrial land-uses.</para>
          <para>Alley and Veenhuis (1983) also derived a relationship between the TIA/TA ratio
            versus the EIA/TA ratio as a combination of all 19 catchments analysed. This equation is
            as follows:</para>
          <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_mfh5r">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                  <m:mi>EIA</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>TA</m:mi>
                </m:mfrac>
                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>0.15</m:mo>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                      <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                        <m:mi>TIA</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>EA</m:mi>
                      </m:mfrac>
                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>1.41</m:mi>
                  </m:msup>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
          <para>It is noted that when applying this relationship both the TIA/TA and EIA/TA should
            be expressed in terms of the percentage multiplied by 100.</para>
          <para>In the Boyd et al (1993) research, 23 of the 26 catchments were predominantly
            residential (although some had low rise apartments). Non-residential catchments included
            Sample Road (highway, industrial), Fort Lauderdale (large shopping mall) and Vika (city
            centre). Both Sample Road and Fort Lauderdale resulted in much higher EIA/TIA, with 74%
            and 98% respectively. With Fort Lauderdale being nearly completely impervious, this high
            value of EIA/ TIA would seem reasonable.</para>
          <para>Pompano Creek (USA) in the Boyd et al. (1993) data was identified as having limited
            pipe infrastructure, and where water flowed through grass swales prior to reaching this
            infrastructure. This may provide some basis for suggesting greater infiltration through
            WSUD style features, although there is insufficient data to draw any detailed
            conclusions.</para>
          <para>A compilation of the available data (where individual catchment data is available)
            is provided in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_iksnk"/>. Both the Alley &amp; Veenhuis (1983)
            (the equation for which was derived from data from Denver USA) and the USA/ Canada data
            from Boyd et al. (1993) generally align, and are generally higher than the European and
            Australian data. The reason for the difference unknown, and may come down to variations
            in methods as well as catchment characteristics and rainfall patterns.<table
              frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_pvzb6">
              <caption>Overview of International Literature on EIA/TIA</caption>
              <col width="20%"/>
              <col width="20%"/>
              <col width="20%"/>
              <col width="20%"/>
              <col width="20%"/>
              <thead>
                <tr>
                  <th>Country</th>
                  <th>Catchments</th>
                  <th>Authors</th>
                  <th>EIA/TIA</th>
                  <th>Comments</th>
                </tr>
              </thead>
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Finland</td>
                  <td>7</td>
                  <td>Melanen &amp; Laukkanen (1981)</td>
                  <td>75%</td>
                  <td>As quoted in Boyd, Bufill &amp; Knee (1993)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Denmark</td>
                  <td>6</td>
                  <td>Jensen (1990)</td>
                  <td>90%</td>
                  <td>As quoted in Boyd, Bufill &amp; Knee (1993)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>USA</td>
                  <td>2</td>
                  <td>Janke &amp; Wilson (2011)</td>
                  <td>32 to 33%</td>
                  <td>Both catchments around 50% impervious.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>USA</td>
                  <td>19</td>
                  <td>Alley and Veenhuis (1983)</td>
                  <td>56 to 94%</td>
                  <td>Analysis undertaken in Denver. See Table 4. Residential between 56% to
                    65%.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>USA, Canada, UK, France, Denmark, Sweden, Italy, Norway, Yukoslavia,
                    Japan</td>
                  <td>17</td>
                  <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
                  <td>Variable</td>
                  <td>Refer to <xref linkend="b5_ch5_t_hwjb5"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_ppc4n"
                    /></td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table></para>
          <para>
            <table xml:id="b5_ch5_t_o0kcf">
              <caption>EIA Results of Alley &amp; Veenhuis (1983) for 19 Catchments in Denver, as
                summarised in Shuster et al. (2005)</caption>
              <thead>
                <tr>
                  <th colspan="3"/>
                  <th colspan="2">Total Impervious Area (TIA) (%)</th>
                  <th colspan="3">Effective Impervious Area (EIA) (%)</th>
                  <th colspan="2">Effective impervious area/Total impervious area</th>
                </tr>
              </thead>
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Land Use</td>
                  <td>Lot size, in acres</td>
                  <td>Number of Basins<footnote>
                      <para>A total of 19 basins were used to derive these averages. However,
                        certain basins had more than one land use type, so that the sum number of
                        basins studied exceeds the sample set</para>
                    </footnote></td>
                  <td>Mean</td>
                  <td>Range</td>
                  <td>Mean</td>
                  <td>Range</td>
                  <td>Mean predicted using mean total impervious area<footnote>
                      <para><inlineequation>
                          <m:math display="inline">
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>EIA</m:mi>
                              <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>0.15</m:mo>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:msup>
                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                      <m:mi>TIA</m:mi>
                                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                    <m:mi>1.41</m:mi>
                                  </m:msup>
                                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                                  <m:mrow>
                                    <m:msup>
                                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>
                                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                                    </m:msup>
                                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                    <m:mi>0.98</m:mi>
                                  </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:math>
                        </inlineequation></para>
                    </footnote></td>
                  <td>Mean</td>
                  <td>Range</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td rowspan="3">Single-family residential</td>
                  <td>&lt; 1/4</td>
                  <td>12</td>
                  <td>39</td>
                  <td>30-49</td>
                  <td>23</td>
                  <td>18-32</td>
                  <td>26</td>
                  <td>0.66</td>
                  <td>0.52-0.66</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>1/4 - 1/2</td>
                  <td>2</td>
                  <td>26</td>
                  <td>22-31</td>
                  <td>15</td>
                  <td>11-19</td>
                  <td>15</td>
                  <td>0.56</td>
                  <td>0.52-0.61</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>1/2 - 1</td>
                  <td>2</td>
                  <td>15</td>
                  <td>13-16</td>
                  <td>8.5</td>
                  <td>7-10</td>
                  <td>6.8</td>
                  <td>0.58</td>
                  <td>0.54-0.62</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Multifamily residential</td>
                  <td>-</td>
                  <td>3</td>
                  <td>60</td>
                  <td>53-64</td>
                  <td>42</td>
                  <td>33-52</td>
                  <td>48</td>
                  <td>0.65</td>
                  <td>0.57-0.77</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Commercial</td>
                  <td>-</td>
                  <td>4</td>
                  <td>88</td>
                  <td>66-98</td>
                  <td>83</td>
                  <td>51-98</td>
                  <td>83</td>
                  <td>0.94</td>
                  <td>0.78-1.0</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Industrial</td>
                  <td>-</td>
                  <td>1</td>
                  <td>60</td>
                  <td>-</td>
                  <td>46</td>
                  <td/>
                  <td>48</td>
                  <td>0.77</td>
                  <td>-</td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table>
          </para>
          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_iksnk">
            <title>Compilation of Available EIA Data<footnote>
                <para>Australian data derived from Boyd et al (1993) and Phillips et al (2014). USA,
                  Canada and European data is from Boyd et al (1993). TA = Urban Area for Boyd et al
                  (1993) and Phillips et al (2014)</para>
                <para>The 50% and 70% lines provide the recommended ranges in <xref
                    linkend="b5_ch5_s_z692j"/></para>
              </footnote></title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5052.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_z692j">
          <title>Recommended Values</title>

          <para><emphasis role="bold">EIA/TIA</emphasis></para>

          <para>Based on the international literature, and in the absence of
          any local streamflow and rainfall data, an EIA/ TIA ratio of 50% to
          70% would appear to be appropriate for the large majority of urban
          catchments. Most values from the recent Phillips et al (2014) study
          fit within a more refined range of 55% to 65%, and this range could
          be used if the catchments are similar to those described in Phillips
          et al (2014) (primarily single lot residential).</para>

          <para>In choosing the value of EIA/ TIA, the following should be
          considered:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Whether the roof areas are connected to the stormwater
              infrastructure. Where this is not the case, it is likely to be
              on the lower end of the range; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>If the drainage infrastructure is piped or whether WSUD
              features (eg swales) are adopted. Some international studies
              would suggest that large lengths of drainage swales (rather than
              pipes) results in a lowering of EIA/TIA, although there is
              insufficient data to adequately characterise this effect.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>The following additional points should be noted in relation to
          the recommended range of values:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>This range has been adopted primarily from residential
              catchments, and generally catchments with TIA/ total area of
              between 30% to 70%. There are no Australian catchments in the
              literature identified with percentage impervious greater than
              70%;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>In one situation in Phillips et al (2014), a catchment in
              Canberra exhibited EIA/ TIA in the 74% to 80% range. It is
              possible that this catchment had a higher proportion of
              “connected” areas, although there is insufficient data to
              explore this further; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Results from US based catchments suggests that for highly
              impervious industrial and commercial areas, there is a higher
              level of connectivity, resulting in a much higher EIA/ TIA. In
              one catchment, nearly 100% EIA/ TIA was observed (although the
              total imperviousness was also around 100%). However, this was
              not observed in data from Europe, and the US data does not
              appear to correlate with European or Australian results. There
              are insufficient results from Australia with catchments with
              industrial/ commercial land-uses and high total imperviousness
              to compare with the international studies. However, it may be
              appropriate to adopt higher values for EIA/TIA for highly
              impervious industrial, commercial as well as metropolitan areas
              (ie total imperviousness greater than 80%).</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para><emphasis role="bold">Estimating the TIA</emphasis></para>

          <para>The above method estimates the EIA as a proportion of the TIA,
          and therefore needs a reasonable estimate of the TIA. Most of the
          research undertaken as summarised in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5_s_0nsjx"/> estimated the TIA based on a detailed
          analysis of aerial imagery. In most applications, this will be the
          most appropriate method for estimating TIA. Further discussion on
          the use of GIS and mapping methods to estimate TIA are provided in
          <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_ih2vd"/>.</para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ih2vd">
        <title>GIS/ Mapping Methods</title>

        <para>GIS methods use data such as aerial photography, drainage maps,
        land-use maps, cadastral information and terrain to derive estimates
        of TIA and EIA.</para>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_8zkda">
          <title>Overview of GIS Methods</title>

          <para>There are different approaches that can be undertaken with the
          use of GIS. Two different levels of analysis have been identified
          here:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Level 1 – undertake mapping of land-use areas within a
              catchment, and use references to derive the proportion of TIA
              based on these land-use types; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Level 2 – undertake detailed mapping of representative
              sub-areas within the catchment, and apply the estimated
              imperviousness from this mapping to the land-use maps from Level
              1 analysis.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>The Level 2 analysis provides a higher level of certainty, but
          requires additional work in undertaking the mapping.</para>

          <para>The following is a step by step process for a Level 2
          analysis:</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Undertake GIS mapping of key land-use areas in the
              catchment;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Identify small representative areas within the catchment
              that represent the different land-uses;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Undertake detailed mapping of these representative areas.
              Refer <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_bch38"/> for an example. Use this
              mapping to estimate the TIA for the sample area;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Apply the estimates from Step 3 to the land-use areas from
              Step 1, to identify the overall TIA within the catchment;
              and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Using this TIA estimate, the EIA can be estimated from the
              recommended ratio of EIA/ TIA from <xref
              linkend="b5_ch5_s_z692j"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>

          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_bch38">
            <title>Example Sample Area Analysis for Residential and Commercial
            Land Use for the Giralang Catchment (ACT)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5053.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_74iqk">
          <title>Estimating EIA based on GIS Estimate of TIA</title>

          <para>Based on the TIA estimates from either Level 1 or Level 2
          analysis, the EIA can be estimated based on the EIA/ TIA
          recommendations as identified in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5_s_z692j"/>.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_lbyvq">
          <title>Estimating EIA using GIS Estimate of DCIA</title>

          <para>A Level 2 GIS method will allow identification of different
          types of impervious areas, which can be identified as being
          potentially DCIA or ICIA. For example, the impervious areas can be
          broken into rooves, roads, driveways drainage to the street,
          footpaths etc. The key challenge in attempting to identify DCIA
          areas using these methods is that it relies on an interpretation of
          what is directly connected. Studies such as Phillips et al. (2014),
          Goyen (2000) and Ball &amp; Powell (1994) have shown that DCIA from
          these methods are generally over-estimates.</para>

          <para>Phillips et al. (2014) showed that the large majority of what
          was estimated to be DCIA using GIS mapping of the catchments
          analysed was road and roof area. The EIA calculated from regression
          analysis represented approximately 70% (+/-5%) of this area.
          However, it is noted that this general rule did not apply to all
          catchments. For example, Giralang (ACT) had a higher EIA/DCIA ratio
          of around 82%, although this is likely due to the higher degree of
          connected surfaces [as discussed in Goyen (2000) and also as
          evidenced by the higher EIA(regression)/TIA ratio of around
          78%].</para>

          <para>The outcomes of these studies effectively suggest that areas
          that are traditionally thought of DCIA (e.g. roof areas), are in
          fact not directly connected. This is likely due to a number of
          factors, such as transmission loss (e.g. cracks in stormwater
          pipes), poorly connected roof drainage, drainage swales along roads
          etc.</para>

          <para>The result is that the use of GIS methods to estimate DCIA and
          subsequently EIA can be problematic. In general, if GIS methods are
          to be used, then a reduction factor will be required in order to
          convert the estimated DCIA to the EIA.</para>

          <para>In the absence of other information or data, then a range of
          70% to 80% could be adopted in converting the GIS DCIA estimate to
          EIA.</para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_pfpia">
      <title>Additional Considerations</title>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_fkq1d">
        <title>Antecedent Conditions</title>

        <para>Antecedent conditions have the potential to influence the EIA.
        Ball and Powell (1994), analysing Powells Creek in NSW (Sydney),
        showed the EIA to total area ranged from around 35% for six days or
        greater of no rainfall preceding the storm, to around 44% for less
        than six days of no rainfall preceding the storm. However, other
        studies have not reported on this effect. In undertaking sensitivity
        testing on the EIA, Phillips et al. (2014) did not identify a clear
        influence of the antecedent rainfall on the EIA. The relative
        importance of antecedent conditions is discussed further in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_s79ar"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_0nadv">
        <title>Changes in Urban Density</title>

        <para>Changes in the urban development over time can alter the density
        of development. This has the potential to influence results of EIA
        estimates.</para>

        <para>For the regression analysis, as identified in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_yu0rf"/>, it is important that this be taken into
        account. Ideally a stationary catchment (i.e. limited or not change in
        density) for the period of the gauging record should be used to
        estimate the EIA.</para>

        <para>For GIS methods, consideration should be made on changes to the
        catchment since the date of the aerial photography. Where the aerial
        photography is older, it may no longer be representative of the
        existing development. Alternatively, for analysis of historical
        flooding, the aerial photography may not be representative of the
        development at that time.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_hzrku">
        <title>Water Sensitive Urban Design</title>

        <para>Water Sensitive Urban Design is common practice for most new
        development. WSUD principles would be expected to counteract, to some
        degree, the increase in imperviousness as a result of the
        development.</para>

        <para>The literature in estimating EIA/ TIA ratios is based on
        catchments with reasonably long flow gauge records (typically greater
        than 10 years), and with stationary catchment conditions (i.e. limited
        new development). WSUD has increased in prevalence in design over the
        last 10 years or so. As a result, it is unlikely that any of these
        catchments in the research incorporate a large proportion of WSUD
        features, and even if one or two did, there would be insufficient data
        to establish any trends.</para>

        <para>Therefore, while it is expected that WSUD may influence the
        estimate of EIA in catchments, there is insufficient data at this time
        to fully understand the impact.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_dewgv">
    <title>Regional Loss Information</title>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_3r5pa">
      <title>Introduction</title>

      <para><xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_e5fbn"/> describes the different
      approaches to selecting loss models and suitable parameter values for
      design flood estimation. In most cases there is insufficient data to
      undertake a detailed analysis of the data and therefore loss values
      should be inferred from consideration of regional information as well as
      reconciliation of design values with other independent flood estimates
      (such as at-site or regional flood frequency estimates). However, if
      losses are to be derived for the specific study of interest then the
      analysis should be cognisant of the issues discuss in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_s_e5fbn"/>.</para>

      <para>The recommendations in this chapter have been drawn largely from
      regional studies of loss values undertaken as part of ARR Project #6
      projects for both urban (Phillips et al., 2014) and rural catchments
      (Hill et al, 2014a &amp; 2015).</para>

      <para>These 2 studies concluded that the IL/CL model is typically the
      most suitable for design flood estimation and hence the recommendations
      in this chapter relate to this model. If other loss models are to be
      used for design then it is important that consideration is given to the
      requirements discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_zwmz0"/>.</para>

      <para>The loss values recommended in this chapter are intended for
      application to complete design storms. Thus the initial loss is denoted
      as ILs to indicate that it is applicable to a complete storm. However,
      if design bursts, rather than complete storms, are used in design then
      the burst initial loss needs to be reduced to account for the pre-burst
      rainfall <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_wuhr9"/>).</para>

      <para>Based upon the physical processes that are known to contribute to
      loss as discussed In <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_8u8o4"/>, it is clear that
      the loss values should vary with catchment and hydroclimatic
      characteristics, however a range of Australian studies have not been
      able to develop definitive links between these characteristics and loss
      values at the catchment scale.</para>

      <para>The values in this chapter have been derived from regional studies
      involving a large number of catchments with different characteristics.
      Although for most areas prediction equations have not been developed to
      allow the loss values to vary with catchment characteristics, it is
      considered reasonable to adjust the loss values based the particular
      characteristics of a catchment. Any departure from the regional values
      should be done giving consideration to the range of loss values obtained
      in the Project #6 reports and other studies and the implications on the
      design flood estimates.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_iu0fo">
      <title>Rural Catchments</title>

      <para>Although previous studies have struggled to develop relationships
      between loss values and catchment characteristics at the catchment
      scale, the results from ARR Project #6 demonstrated some regional
      consistency. This indicates that climate is the dominate drivers for
      loss values as it influences both vegetation and antecedent
      conditions.</para>

      <para>Loss guidance has been developed for the regions shown in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_f_blmxc"/>, which has been defined, considering climatic
      and biophysical factors and the availability of information on loss
      values. The regions are similar to the Natural Resource Management (NRM)
      clusters defined by the Australian Department of Environment<footnote>
          <para><link
          xlink:href="http://www.climatechangeinaustralia.gov.au/en/climate-projections/about/modelling-choices-and-methodology/regionalisation-schemes/">http://www.climatechangeinaustralia.gov.au/en/climate-projections/about/modelling-choices-and-methodology/regionalisation-schemes/</link></para>
        </footnote> . The definition of the rangelands varies across
      Australia, but reflects a mean annual rainfall of approximately 300 to
      400 mm.</para>

      <para>Thus, loss guidance is provided for the following regions:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>East coast</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Monsoonal North</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Murray Darling</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Pilbara</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Rangelands</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>South-central South Australia</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>South-east coast</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>South-western WA</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Wet tropic</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_blmxc">
        <title>Regions defined for recommending loss values</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5054.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The following sections summarise recommended median loss values
      for each region. The loss values have been drawn from the ARR Project #6
      (Hill et al., 2014a) and a number of other studies (Waugh, 1991; Hill et
      al., 1996; Ilahee, 2005; Rahman et al. 2002, El-Kafagee &amp; Rahman,
      2011; Loveridge, 2015). These studies have been selected on the basis
      that the loss values were derived directly from rainfall and streamflow
      analysis (rather than reconciliation of design flood estimates with
      flood frequency quantiles) to ensure that the values are independent of
      the design inputs used in their derivation. Furthermore, in each study
      the sample of events was selected based upon rainfall rather than
      streamflow (to avoid any bias towards wet antecedent conditions).</para>

      <para>The number of events analysed and the median loss values are
      summarised in Appendix A for each catchment. For some catchments,
      multiple studies have derived loss values and hence there are more than
      one value of median loss.</para>

      <para>For some studies, the CL was estimated as the volume of loss (less
      the ILs) divided by the duration of the event post the commencement of
      surface runoff. As discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_15kyp"/>, this
      will underestimate the CL as there are likely to be timesteps where
      rainfall is less than the CL rate. Values of CL from such studies were
      removed from the dataset and hence, there are less values of CL than ILs
      provided in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_a"/>.</para>

      <para>The recommended median values are summarised in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_f_q3fwf"/>. For each region, a typical value and a
      recommended range is specified based upon the observed range in median
      values from the various studies. The range is based upon notional
      quartiles such that the median value for half of catchments are expected
      to lie within this range.</para>

      <para>It is important to note that the range refers to the median for a
      particular catchment. It is expected that the loss for any particular
      event could lie well outside of this range. For many catchments, the
      storm initial loss for any particular event could range from nearly
      zero, if the storm occurs on a wet catchment, to more than 100 mm if
      there is little antecedent rainfall.<?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T142027+1100" comment="The values in this table (figure 17?) are for design. Actual storms may be quite different. Maybe put this data in a table."?></para>

      <?oxy_comment_end ?>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_q3fwf">
        <title>Recommended median loss values</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T142053+1100" comment="this will be the figure everyone will turn to"?>

            <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T142142+1100" comment="design - point out that the actual storms maybe different" mid="63"?>

            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5055.png"/>

            <?oxy_comment_end ?>

            <?oxy_comment_end mid="63"?>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The range reflects the variability in the median loss values
      observed from catchments in the region and the number of available
      catchments. For some regions such as south-central SA the range is quite
      tight because the median catchments from the 4 available catchments are
      consistent. Whereas for the wet tropics there is a significant variation
      between the values from the available catchments.</para>

      <para>Although it has not been possible to develop prediction equations
      relating the loss values to the range of catchment characteristics that
      should influence loss, it is reasonable to select values within the
      reported range which take account of how the characteristics of a
      particular catchment are likely to influence the loss values. For
      example for catchments with either very dense vegetation or high
      permeable soil, it would be expected that the loss values would be on
      the higher end of the range. Similarly, steep, rocky catchments would
      expected to have loss values on the lower end of the reported
      range.</para>

      <para>The following sections provide more discussion on the loss values
      for each of the regions.</para>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_6jpdz">
        <title>East <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T142329+1100" comment="THis information is good but it would be useful to have a guideance .... specific circumstances
not based necessarily on recorded data but developed from experience while doing this research."?>Coast<?oxy_comment_end ?></title>

        <para>Based upon 11 catchments, the typical median value of ILs is 40
        mm with a range of 30 to 50 mm. These values are higher than the
        South-east coast and the Murray Darling regions.</para>

        <para>The CL values are generally lower than other regions in
        Australia with a recommended value of 2.0 mm/h and a range of 1.5 to
        2.5 mm/h.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_00oli">
        <title>Monsoonal North</title>

        <para>For the Monsoonal North region, based upon 9 catchments, the
        typical median ILs is 30 mm with a range of 25 to 45 mm.</para>

        <para>Values for median CL were only available for 5 catchments and
        based upon this data a typical value of 6.0 mm/h and a range of 3.5
        and 9.0 mm/h are recommended. These values of continuing loss are some
        of the highest in Australia.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_1qtrm">
        <title>Murray Darling</title>

        <para>Based upon 14 catchments, the typical median value of ILs is 30
        mm with a range from 15 to 40 mm. Although the typical value is
        slightly higher than the south-east coast region, the range is
        similar.</para>

        <para>There is a wide range of CL values observed within the Murray
        Darling region. The recommended typical value of CL is 5.0 mm/h.
        However the uncertainty is reflected in the range from 2.5 to 7.0
        mm/h. These CL values are higher than other southern regions and are
        more aligned to the values for Rangelands and the Monsoonal North
        regions.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_e6omq">
        <title>Pilbara</title>

        <para>The median loss values in the Pilbara are some of the highest in
        Australia. There was only 1 catchment from the Pilbara included in the
        Hill et al (2014a) study and therefore the results were supplemented
        by data from Pearcey et al. (2014) who calibrated RORB models to 19
        catchments in the Pilbara region. Although the events in Pearcey et
        al. (2014) were selected on the basis of streamflow rather than
        rainfall (and hence potentially biased towards wet antecedent
        conditions), they support the high values of loss.</para>

        <para>For the Pilbara, Flavell and Belstead (1986) recommended IL
        values of approximately 40 to 50 mm and a CL of 5 mm/h. It should be
        noted that the loss values were derived from reconciling rainfall
        based estimates with flood frequency analysis and thus the IL reflects
        a burst initial loss and a higher initial loss would be expected if
        complete storms are adopted so the range of IL reported by Flavell and
        Belstead (1986) should be considered a lower limit of expected ILs
        values.</para>

        <para>The recommended typical median ILs is 60 mm with a range of 40
        to 80 mm. For the CL, the typical value is 6.0 mm/h with a range of
        4.0 to 8.0 mm/h.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_2uwi5">
        <title>Rangelands</title>

        <para>The rangelands are characterised by a lack of suitable
        catchments to estimate loss values and only one of the ARR Project 6
        catchments lay within the Rangelands region and the estimated losses
        were unexpectedly low. Thus the guidance has been based upon a number
        of other studies.</para>

        <para>Kemp and Wright (2014) noted high loss rates for the Gammon
        Ranges in mid-north South Australia. They attributed the high values
        to the runoff processes being dominated by the large amounts of
        storage within the gravel bed of the tributaries and main streams
        which absorbs a significant amount of runoff from the hillsides. Thus
        the initial loss represents loss in the tributaries and main stream in
        addition to that occurring within the catchment. This explanation is
        supported by observations in arid western New South Wales (Cordery et
        al. 1983b).</para>

        <para>Board et al (1989) estimated losses for the Emily Creek and Todd
        River catchments in central Australia by calibrating a RORB model to 3
        floods. The ILs varied from 10 to 60 mm and the CL varied from 1.5 to
        4.5 mm. It should be noted that the events were selected based upon
        the largest floods and hence the sample is likely to be biased to wet
        antecedent conditions which would indicate that the ILs values are
        likely to underestimate the median value.</para>

        <para>The recommended typical median ILs is 60 mm with a range of 40
        to 80 mm. For the CL, the typical value is 5.0 mm/h with a range of
        3.0 to 7.0 mm/h.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_w91t7">
        <title>South-central South Australia</title>

        <para>The median loss values for 4 catchments in the Mt Lofty Ranges
        from Hill et al. (2014a) were consistent. The recommended typical
        value of ILs is 20 mm with a range of range of 15 to 25 mm.</para>

        <para>The typical value of CL is 3.0 mm/h with a range of 2.5 to 3.5
        mm/h. In the absence of other data, these values are also recommended
        for the Eyre and York peninsulas.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_tay31">
        <title>South-east Coast</title>

        <para>Based upon 20 catchments in the south-east coast region, the
        typical median value of ILs is 25 mm with a range from 20 to 40 mm.
        For the GSAM region defined by the Bureau of Meteorology (which
        includes the South-east coast and the southern portion of the Murray
        Darling region) Hill et al. (2014a) related the ILs to the 2% 24 hour
        design rainfall intensity:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_st2zl">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>IL</m:mi>

                <m:mi>s</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>0.62</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>0.124</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msubsup>
                      <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>24h</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>2%</m:mi>
                    </m:msubsup>

                    <m:mo/>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msup>
                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:msup>

                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.65</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>SE</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>26%</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>N</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>15</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where:</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic">ILs</emphasis> is the storm Initial Loss
        (mm)</para>

        <para>is the 2% AEP 24-hour design rainfall depth from IFD2013 (mm)
        with a range of 113 to 369 mm.</para>

        <para>The CL values for the South-east coast region are lower than
        northern regions of Australia with a recommended typical value of 2.5
        mm/h with a range of 1.5 to 3.5 mm/h. The values are typically a
        little lower in Western Victoria with most catchments between 1 and 3
        mm/h.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_sgkgv">
        <title>South-western WA</title>

        <para>The runoff characteristics of much of south-west Western
        Australia are different from that found in many other parts of
        Australia. The highly permeable soils and large soil water storages of
        the south-west landforms means that the continuing loss rates tend to
        be high.</para>

        <para>The dominate contribution to runoff is believed to be saturated
        areas in the broad valley floors which represent a relatively small
        proportion of the total catchment. For catchments where runoff is
        predominately generated via this mechanism, then a storage capacity
        loss model such as SWMOD should be applied to estimate the rainfall
        excess (Refer <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_681ox"/>). For other catchments
        in south-west WA the IL/CL model is recommended.</para>

        <para>For ILs there is some regional consistency in the values. The
        typical value of ILs is 20 mm with a range of between 15 and 30
        mm.</para>

        <para>The CL is more variable with a typical median value of 3.5 mm/h
        but a range from 0.5 to 7.0 mm/h. The highest values are along the
        Darling Range scarp catchments where the median CL values were
        approximately 7 to 8 mm/h. Hill et al. (2014a) related the CL for
        South-west WA as a function of the design rainfall.</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_2rbdc">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>CL</m:mi>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>-10.7</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>0.159</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msubsup>
                      <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>12h</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>2%</m:mi>
                    </m:msubsup>

                    <m:mo/>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msup>
                          <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:msup>

                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>0.54</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>SE</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>38%</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where:</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic">CL</emphasis> is the Continuing Loss
        (mm/h)</para>

        <para>is the 2% AEP 12 hour design rainfall depth from IFD2013 (mm)
        with a range of 80 to 109 mm</para>

        <para>Over the range of design rainfalls for which the above
        relationship was developed the predicted CL varies from approximately
        2 to 7 mm/h.</para>

        <para>For South-west WA the rainfall and losses are markedly seasonal
        in nature and it should be noted that the 160 events analysed by Hill
        et al. (2014a) were biased towards the winter months with 70% of them
        occurring in May, June or July. Considerations for the selection of
        seasonal loss values is discussed in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_cyafo"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_54m9w">
        <title>Wet Tropic</title>

        <para>Based upon 10 catchments, the typical median value of ILs is 35
        mm with a range from 25 to 70 mm. The higher end of this range reflect
        some of the highest ILs values in Australia.</para>

        <para>The recommended typical value of CL is 4.0 mm/h. However, there
        were only values of CL available for 2 catchments and therefore this
        uncertainty is reflected in the wide range from 2.0 to 6.0
        mm/h.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_3w0mq">
      <title>Urban Catchments</title>

      <para>As identified, in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/>, the urban
      catchments have been conceptualised as EIA, Indirectly Connected Areas
      (a combination of Indirectly Connected Impervious and Pervious Areas)
      and Pervious Areas. The following provide guidance on the losses to
      apply to these areas.</para>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_89urz">
        <title>Losses for Effective Impervious Areas</title>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_gpuyp">
          <title>Research</title>

          <para>Phillips et al. (2014) estimated initial loss based on the EIA
          analysis undertaken (refer to <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_oj30q"/>),
          plotting the runoff volume against the rainfall volume. The
          intersection of the best fit line with the x-axis represents the
          initial loss on the EIA. Should data be available for a catchment,
          then this provides a way in which the initial loss can be
          estimated.</para>

          <para>The analysis in Phillips et al. (2014) had initial losses
          ranging from 1 to 3 mm across the country, with no real identifiable
          trend between the different regions (although the data was limited).
          A similar approach was undertaken by Kemp &amp; Lipp (1999), Ball
          &amp; Zaman (1994) and Chiew &amp; McMahon (1999), and these studies
          identified typical values in the order of 0 to 1mm</para>

          <para><?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T144303+1100" comment="incorrect reference"?>Bufill
          &amp; Boyd (1992)<?oxy_comment_end ?> analysed 16 catchments, 10
          within Australia and 6 international catchments. Their analysis
          identified initial loss by estimating the mean initial loss across
          all events for these catchments. It is important to note that this
          is a slightly different way of undertaking the analysis from
          Phillips et al (2014), and therefore can result in slightly
          different results. However, this study found that typical initial
          loss rates for the 10 catchments within Australia are around 0 to 1
          mm. These catchments were subsequently re-analysed using the EIA
          technique in Boyd et al (1993).</para>

          <para>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992) also analysed 6 international
          catchments, using the method noted above, and found an initial loss
          ranging from around 0.5 to 1 mm. Boyd et al (1993) had 17
          international catchments in their analysis, with initial loss values
          typically ranging from 0 to 1.3 mm, although two catchments in the
          US had 3.7 mm and 6.1 mm.</para>

          <para>A summary of the different initial loss estimates available
          for the different studies are provided in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5_a"/>. It is important to note that there is only one
          catchment from the northern parts of Australia (i.e. Monsoonal
          North, Wet Tropics, Pilbara) or the central portion of Australia
          (Rangelands). However, given the consistency of the estimates across
          the regions, and with international estimates, it is unlikely that
          the initial loss for EIA in these areas will be significantly
          different.</para>

          <para>All studies assumed that the ongoing losses on the EIA were
          effectively zero.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_gi420">
          <title>Recommended Loss Value for EIA</title>

          <para>It is recommended to adopt a storm initial loss of between 1
          to 2 mm for EIA. Continuing losses for EIA can be assumed to be
          zero.</para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_w2fu6">
        <title>Losses for Indirectly Connected Areas</title>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_6f3rm">
          <title>Initial Losses</title>

          <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis
          role="italic">Literature</emphasis></emphasis></para>

          <para>One of the key challenges in urban catchments is the lack of
          gauged urban catchments with reasonable records and relatively
          stable development. In addition to this, many rainfall events do not
          produce any Indirectly Connected Area runoff, which can make it
          difficult to obtain sufficient data to determine appropriate
          losses.</para>

          <para>Phillips et al. (2014) used the same catchments as those
          identified in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_oj30q"/> for EIA. In order to
          isolate events with flow generated from the Indirectly Connected
          Area, they selected events where the flow generated was 10% higher
          than the flow estimated by calculating the runoff from the EIA area
          alone. A number of other criteria were adopted. Further details on
          the storm event selection are identified in Phillips et al (2014). A
          summary of the number of events identified for each of the
          catchments is summarised in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_t_kei32"/>.</para>

          <para>Two catchments from the EIA analysis in Phillips et al (2014)
          were excluded:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Parra Hills (SA) – only a limited number of storms were
              identified. The number of storms was too small to provide any
              meaningful analysis of the losses.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Kinkora Road (VIC) – further analysis of the data
              suggested some unusual behaviour, with periods of runoff with no
              rainfall and vice versa for the selected events. This catchment
              was therefore not included in any further analysis.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_kei32">
            <caption>Total Storms identified for Analysis (Phillips et al,
            2014)</caption>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th/>

                <th>Giralang (ACT)</th>

                <th>Powells Creek (NSW)</th>

                <th>Albany Drain (WA)</th>

                <th>McArthur Park (NT)</th>

                <th>Argyle St (TAS)</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Total Identified Storms</td>

                <td>41</td>

                <td>14</td>

                <td>30</td>

                <td>20</td>

                <td>49</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>

          <para>One of the key challenges in the use of the urban data in
          Phillips et al (2014), and with many other studies, is that the
          length of record is relatively small. This, together with the
          filtering method, reduces the number of large storm events to
          estimate losses. <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_wmkow"/> shows the storm
          magnitude from the selected events from Phillips et al (2014), based
          on the 1987 ARR AEPs (storms not shown are less than 63% AEP or 1
          EY).</para>

          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_wmkow">
            <title>Storm Magnitude from Phillips et al (2014)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5056.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>Based on the selected storms, Phillips et al. (2014)
          identified that mean storm initial losses across the range of storms
          for the catchments analysed were generally in the range of 20 to 30
          mm, with the majority between 10 and 40 mm, and would appear fairly
          consistent across most of the catchments. A summary of the results
          is provided in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_wmkow"/>, providing an
          indication of the ranges. Phillips et al (2014) noted that the
          Argyle Street (TAS) was not well suited to the analysis that was
          undertaken, due to large pervious areas and bushland. As with the
          rural catchments, there is significant variation in the results,
          which is driven by numerous factors such as antecedent conditions
          and temporal pattern of the storm.</para>

          <para>The storms in Phillips et al. (2014) were real storms, and may
          differ to the design storm temporal patterns. Furthermore, the
          higher loss values may be skewed by rainfall events that occurred
          where low depths continued for a prolonged period of time at the
          start of the event. On this basis, the storm initial loss for design
          storms may be lower than the range estimated in Phillip et al.
          (2014).</para>

          <para>Boyd et al (1994) fitted a model for urban catchment runoff to
          3 catchments in Australia (all in ACT). This model conceptualised
          that the urban catchment was comprised of EIA, pervious area that
          contributed for small rainfall events (&lt;40 mm) and pervious areas
          that contributed for larger rainfall events (&gt;40mm). For the
          “small pervious” area, the study indicated initial losses of 0 to 4
          mm, while for the “large pervious” area, the study indicated 30 to
          50 mm. It is noted that in other studies the “small pervious” area
          is effectively lumped into the EIA (such as Phillips et al, 2014),
          so that the 30 to 50 mm initial loss would be generally consistent
          with the initial loss concept for the Indirectly Connected Area in
          this chapter. However, key challenges with the Boyd et al (1994)
          catchments is that they are low density (5 to 25% total impervious
          fraction), and the model applied effectively incorporates a
          proportional loss into the fraction of “small pervious” and “large
          pervious” areas.</para>

          <para>Kemp and Lipp (1999) analysed three catchments in South
          Australia. For the <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T144427+1100" comment="this reference to IDIA isn&apos;t consistent"?>Indirectly
          Connected Areas<?oxy_comment_end ?>, they were not able to identify
          any clear runoff events from these areas for these catchments. Based
          on the available research, this paper recommended 45 mm of initial
          loss be adopted for Adelaide, although this could go as high as 60
          mm. However, these estimates were identified as preliminary, and
          there was no runoff records to verify this. Interestingly, Phillips
          et al (2014) were also unable to identify sufficient events with
          runoff from the Indirectly Connected Area for South
          Australia.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_ff0ai">
            <title>Summary of Initial Losses for Urban Catchments (from
            Phillips et al, 2014)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5057.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis
          role="italic">Conceptualisation</emphasis></emphasis></para>

          <para>As per the conceptualisation in this chapter, the Indirectly
          Connected Area is composed of impervious and pervious areas
          interacting with each other. The pervious area would be expected to
          tend towards the rural losses, although will be modified due to
          urban pervious area modification (such as import of top-soil,
          differing vegetation etc). However, the impact of the impervious
          area would be expected to lessen the initial loss across the
          combined area.</para>

          <para>A comparison of the initial loss derived in the literature
          with the recommended ILs for Rural catchments is provided in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5_t_kewb3"/>. This table also provides the ratio of
          the Indirectly Connected Impervious Area over Indirectly Connected
          Area. Key points:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>The initial loss values are similar to the recommended
              rural loss values. Generally, the values are in the order of 60
              to 80% of the recommended median Rural ILs, although obviously
              there is significant scatter in both data sets;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>There is insufficient data to determine any appropriate
              relationships with ICIA/ICA with initial loss and its relation
              to the recommended median rural loss.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The catchments from Boyd et al (1994) have almost no ICIA,
              and the median values for ILs are in the range of the
              recommended median rural loss.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>There is insufficient data covering all regions as
              identified in the rural section.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_kewb3">
              <caption>Comparison of Initial Loss Literature Values with Rural
              Recommended Values</caption>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col/>

              <thead>
                <tr>
                  <th>Catchment</th>

                  <th>Region</th>

                  <th>Median ILs (mm)</th>

                  <th>Reference</th>

                  <th>Recommended Rural ILs (mm)</th>

                  <th>ICIA/ICA</th>
                </tr>
              </thead>

              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Giralang (ACT)</td>

                  <td>Murray Darling</td>

                  <td>17</td>

                  <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>

                  <td>30</td>

                  <td>9%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Powells Creek (NSW)</td>

                  <td>East Coast</td>

                  <td>24.5</td>

                  <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>

                  <td>40</td>

                  <td>43%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Albany Drain (WA)</td>

                  <td>South-West WA</td>

                  <td>18</td>

                  <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>

                  <td>20</td>

                  <td>18%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>McArthur Park (NT)</td>

                  <td>Monsoonal North</td>

                  <td>18.9</td>

                  <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>

                  <td>30</td>

                  <td>17%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Argyle Street (TAS)</td>

                  <td>South-East Coast</td>

                  <td>7.9</td>

                  <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>

                  <td>25</td>

                  <td>6%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Long Gully Creek (ACT)</td>

                  <td>Murray Darling</td>

                  <td>34</td>

                  <td>Boyd et al (1994)</td>

                  <td>30</td>

                  <td>0%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Mawson (ACT)</td>

                  <td>Murray Darling</td>

                  <td>49</td>

                  <td>Boyd et al (1994)</td>

                  <td>30</td>

                  <td>5%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Curtin (ACT)</td>

                  <td>Murray Darling</td>

                  <td>31</td>

                  <td>Boyd et al (1994)</td>

                  <td>30</td>

                  <td>0%</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>South Australia (3 catchments)</td>

                  <td>South-Central SA</td>

                  <td>45</td>

                  <td>Kemp &amp; Lipp (1999)</td>

                  <td>20</td>

                  <td/>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table></para>

          <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis
          role="italic">Recommendation</emphasis></emphasis></para>

          <para>Based on the limited available information, it is recommended
          that a median ILs of 60 to 80% of the recommended rural catchment
          ILs be adopted.</para>

          <para>It is noted that this may trend towards 100% as the proportion
          of impervious area in the Indirectly Connected Area reduces. Based
          on the data that is available, this might occur when the impervious
          area drops below 5% of the total Indirectly
          Connec<?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T144607+1100" comment="summary tble here showing IL for urban catchment"?>ted
          Area.<?oxy_comment_end ?></para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_oafoo">
          <title>Continuing Loss</title>

          <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis
          role="italic">Literature</emphasis></emphasis></para>

          <para>The constant continuing losses estimated in Phillips et al.
          (2014) ranged generally from 0 to 4 mm/h across the catchments.
          However, this excludes the catchment in Northern Territory which was
          influenced by the presence of a large detention basin that affected
          results. However, more recent analysis of this catchment with
          regards to timestep (see <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_7vxfa"/>), would
          suggest that for a 6 minute interval the CL estimate is 2.8 mm/h,
          which is within the range of the other catchments. Phillips et al
          (2014) also cautioned with the results of the Tasmanian catchment
          (Argyle Street), which is influenced by a large bushland area
          component, significantly larger than the urban area of the
          catchment.</para>

          <para>Both NSW and ACT had median constant continuing loss values in
          the order of 2.5 mm/h. WA exhibited higher continuing losses, with a
          median value close to 4mm/h.</para>

          <para>A comparison of the median continuing loss values with those
          of the recommended values for the Rural catchments is provided in
          <xref linkend="b5_ch5_t_ire3n"/>. It is difficult to draw any real
          conclusions based on the limited data set, other than to note that
          they are generally in the same range.</para>

          <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_ire3n">
              <caption>Urban Continuing Loss Values Compared with Rural
              Continuing Loss Values</caption>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <col width="20%"/>

              <thead>
                <tr>
                  <th rowspan="2">Catchment</th>

                  <th rowspan="2">Region</th>

                  <th colspan="2">Median CL(mm/h)</th>
                </tr>
              </thead>

              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <th>Phillips et al (2014)</th>

                  <th>Regional rural estimate from <xref
                  linkend="b5_ch5_s_iu0fo"/></th>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Giralang (ACT)</td>

                  <td>Murray Darling</td>

                  <td>2.5</td>

                  <td>5.0</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Powells Creek (NSW)</td>

                  <td>East Coast</td>

                  <td>2.6</td>

                  <td>2.0</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Albany Drain (WA)</td>

                  <td>South-West WA</td>

                  <td>3.8</td>

                  <td>3.5</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>McArthur Park (NT)</td>

                  <td>Monsoonal North</td>

                  <td>5.1</td>

                  <td>6.0</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Argyle Street (TAS)</td>

                  <td>South-East Coast</td>

                  <td>1.4</td>

                  <td>2.5</td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table></para>

          <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_dllpf">
            <title>Indirectly Connected Area Continuing Loss Estimates (from
            Phillips et al, 2014)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5058.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis
          role="italic">Recommendations</emphasis></emphasis></para>

          <para>In the absence of other data, the following is recommended
          where appropriate gauging data is not available:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>For the South-East Coast, East Coast and Murray Darling
              regions, a typical value of 2.5mm/h, with a range of 1 to 3
              mm/h, would be appropriate. The value should be adjusted based
              on engineering judgement and reviewing the catchment
              characteristics such as soil types, interaction of indirectly
              connected impervious areas with pervious areas etc.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>For other areas, adopt a range of 1 to 4 mm/h.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Similar to initial losses, where the impervious proportion
              of the indirectly connected area is very low, it may be
              appropriate to adopt the rural continuing losses. However, there
              is insufficient data to confirm this.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_yl2sx">
        <title>Losses for Urban Pervious Areas</title>

        <para>Urban pervious areas represent areas that do not interact
        directly with impervious areas (i.e. those not within the Indirectly
        Connected Area), such as pockets of bushland, parks, recreational
        ovals etc. Traditionally, practitioners have adopted similar loss
        values for these areas as for those they would adopt in rural
        areas.</para>

        <para>The challenge in the research for these areas is identifying the
        runoff component from these portions, which are typically dominated by
        runoff from impervious areas. However, there is nothing to say that
        these areas will behave the same as rural areas. Areas like parks and
        sporting fields are highly disturbed from their natural state, and
        therefore may exhibit very different characteristics. However, with
        little research and information available, the losses for the rural
        catchment provide the best estimate that is available at this
        time.</para>

        <para>Therefore, in the absence of better information, it is
        recommended to adopt the loss values for rural catchments from <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_iu0fo"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_w4y2w">
        <title>Alternative Loss Models for Indirectly Connected Areas</title>

        <para>As noted in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_3r5pa"/>, the recommended
        loss model for urban catchments is the IL/CL model, based on the
        results of Phillips et al (2014). However, it is also recognised that
        a number of other loss models have been and are in use in Australia.
        Furthermore, there is insufficient data to categorically identify one
        loss model over another as being preferred, and there are
        circumstances where specific loss models may suit a particular
        catchment well.</para>

        <para>Two alternative models that are commonly applied in urban
        environments are the proportional loss models and the Horton loss
        models. These two loss models are described in the following
        sections.</para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Initial Loss -
        Proportional Loss Model</emphasis></emphasis></para>

        <para>The initial loss proportional loss model is described in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_0mpxa"/>.</para>

        <para>The initial loss for the model should be adopted as per <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_w2fu6"/>.</para>

        <para>In addition to testing the IL/CL loss model, Phillips et al
        (2014) also tested the proportional loss model. A summary of the
        results from this assessment are provided in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_3jgyf"/>. As identified in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_w2fu6"/>, some care should be taken with the
        interpretation of the results from Tasmania (Argle Street) and
        Northern Territory (McArthur Park).</para>

        <para>The key challenge with the results of this analysis is that the
        results range from median proportional losses of around 45% through to
        80%. This makes it difficult to provide a general guidance for
        catchments.</para>

        <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_zwmz0"/>, the greatest
        challenge in applying the IL/PL model for design flood estimation is
        understanding how the proportional loss varies with AEP. Great care
        should therefore be exercised if the IL/PL is to be applied to events
        outside of the range of events used in the derivation of the values.
        For this reason it is generally not considered appropriate for
        estimating rare or extreme events (ie AEP &lt; 1%).</para>

        <para>Therefore, it is recommended that this method only be used where
        suitable data is available to calibrate the loss model, either for a
        specific catchment or for a similar catchment nearby. Alternatively,
        should more research become available this could assist in informing
        appropriate parameters for design.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_3jgyf">
          <title>Indirectly Connected Area Proportional Loss Estimates (from
          Phillips et al, 2014)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5059.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Horton Loss
        Model</emphasis></emphasis></para>

        <para>The Horton loss model is described in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_ti9sw"/>, with the equation below repeated for
        reference.</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_4o7rw">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                <m:mi>t</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>c</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>f</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>c</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>k</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msup>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where:</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> f<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis> is
        the infiltration capacity (mm/h)</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> f<subscript>c</subscript></emphasis> is
        the minimum or ultimate value of <emphasis
        role="italic">f<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis></para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> f<subscript>0</subscript></emphasis> is
        the maximum or initial value of <emphasis
        role="italic">f<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis> (mm/h)</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> k</emphasis> is a decay coefficient
        (per hour)</para>

        <para><emphasis role="italic"> t</emphasis> is the time from the
        beginning of the storm (h)</para>

        <para>This model is for pervious areas only. The hydrological models
        that use this model separate out the Indirectly Connected Impervious
        Areas from the Indirectly Connected Pervious Areas, treating the
        losses separately. An examples of this is ILSAX, as detailed in
        O’Loughlin and Stack (2014). O’Loughlin and Stack (2014) has been used
        as the key reference for this section of the chapter, and the
        parameters reported here are based on this reference.</para>

        <para>The Horton model assumes that the losses (or infiltration) of
        runoff decreases over the duration of the storm. The shape of this
        decay function is described by the k value, which is typically assumed
        to be 2 (h-1). The remaining parameters to describe the decay curve
        are the initial infiltration rate (f<subscript>0</subscript>) and the
        final infiltration rate (f<subscript>c</subscript>). These are defined
        by the soil characteristics. Soil classifications that are used are
        described in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_t_hf7ew"/>, which are based on
        numerous reference and reproduced from O’Loughlin and Stack
        (2014).</para>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_hf7ew">
            <caption>Soil Classifications in Horton Mode</caption>

            <col width="50%"/>

            <col width="50%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Soil Classification</th>

                <th>Description</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>A</td>

                <td>low runoff potential, high infiltration rates (consists of
                sand and gravel)</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>B</td>

                <td>moderate infiltration rates and moderately
                well-drained</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>C</td>

                <td>slow infiltration rates (may have layers that impede
                downward movement of water);</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>D</td>

                <td>high runoff potential, very slow infiltration rates
                (consists of clays with a permanent high water table and a
                high swelling potential).</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <para>In applying the model, a “starting point” is required for the
        analysis. This represents the infiltration rate at the start of the
        storm, which is based on the Antecedent Moisture Condition (AMC). The
        AMC can be categorised from <xref linkend="b5_ch5_t_kei85"/> (based on
        O’Loughlin and Stack, 2014).</para>

        <para>Using the soil classification and the AMC number, the Horton
        Loss Model parameters can be defined based on <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_3sj84"/>. The resulting loss models for the different
        classifications, together with the AMC numbers, are shown in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_ql0pw"/>.</para>

        <table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_kei85">
          <caption>Antecedent Moisture Condition Number</caption>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Number</th>

              <th>Description</th>

              <th>Total rainfall in 5 days preceding the storm (mm)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>1</td>

              <td>Completely Dry</td>

              <td>0</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>2</td>

              <td>Rather Dry</td>

              <td>0 to 12.5</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>3</td>

              <td>Rather wet</td>

              <td>12.5 to 25</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>4</td>

              <td>Over Saturated</td>

              <td>&gt; 25</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_3sj84">
            <caption>Horton Loss Model Parameters</caption>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th colspan="5">Soil Type</th>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <th/>

                <th>A</th>

                <th>B</th>

                <th>C</th>

                <th>D</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Initial Rate (f<subscript>0</subscript>) (mm/hr)</td>

                <td>250</td>

                <td>200</td>

                <td>125</td>

                <td>75</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Final rate (f<subscript>c</subscript>) (mm/hr)</td>

                <td>25</td>

                <td>13</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>3</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Shape Factor (k) (h<superscript>-1</superscript>)</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td colspan="5">Initial Infiltration Rates (mm/h) for
                AMCs</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>1</td>

                <td>250</td>

                <td>200</td>

                <td>125</td>

                <td>75</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>2</td>

                <td>162.3</td>

                <td>130.1</td>

                <td>33.7</td>

                <td>40.9</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>3</td>

                <td>83.6</td>

                <td>66.3</td>

                <td>33.7</td>

                <td>7.4</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>4</td>

                <td>33.1</td>

                <td>30.7</td>

                <td>6.6</td>

                <td>3.0</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_ql0pw">
          <title>Horton Loss Model with Different Soil Classifications &amp;
          AMC Numbers</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5060.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>O’Loughlin and Stack (2014) report that this method has been
        used in the calibration of a number of ILSAX models to gauged
        catchments. While no references are provided, it is anticipated that
        this calibration is for whole hydrological and hydraulic models, which
        includes a number of parameters not just isolated to losses.</para>

        <para>O’Loughlin and Stack (2014) report that Siriwardena, et al.
        (2003) compared the infiltration rates from with those measured with
        infiltrometers at eight urban gauged catchments in Victoria. These
        rates suggested slightly higher rates than those reported in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_3sj84"/>. However, the research only focused on the
        soils, and did not look at the other components that loss models are
        trying to represent (such as those identified in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_s_ncyi2"/>).</para>

        <para>More research is required to compare the effectiveness of this
        loss model in comparison to constant continuing loss
        model.<?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T144752+1100" comment="needs a summary to explain final recommendations"?></para>

        <?oxy_comment_end ?>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_h83ay">
    <title>Distribution of Loss Values</title>

    <para>The discussion in the previous sections concentrates on a single
    representative (median) value of loss. However, joint probability
    approaches to design flood estimation allow a distribution of loss values
    rather than simply some measure of central tendency (eg Goyen, 1983;
    Rahman et al. 2002; Nathan et al. 2003; Kuczera et al. 2006).</para>

    <para>The degree of variability in the loss values reflects both natural
    variability in the factors contributing to loss (initial state of
    catchment wetness, seasonal effects on vegetation) and impacts of error in
    rainfall and streamflow data. As long as these errors are of a random
    rather than systematic nature, they should not bias the estimated loss
    distribution.</para>

    <para>These approaches can be grouped into parametric and non-parametric
    and are discussed in the following sections.</para>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_h7de3">
      <title>Non Parametric Approaches</title>

      <para>Nathan et al. (2003) describes the derivation of a standardised
      loss distribution by standardising the values by the median for each
      catchment. The concept of how the location of the loss distribution
      changes but not its shape is discussed in Nathan et al. (2003) and is
      illustrated in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_5mt84"/>. Thus, if the median
      loss value can be determined, then these standardised distributions can
      be applied to estimate the distribution of losses for any given
      catchment.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_5mt84">
        <title>Schematic illustration of variation in location but not shape
        of initial loss distribution (Nathan et al. 2003).</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5061.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The standardised distributions of storm initial loss and
      continuing loss from Hill et al. (2014a) are shown in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_f_aome8"/> and the values presented in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_t_jh284"/>. These standardised loss distributions are
      remarkably consistent for the different regions across Australia, which
      demonstrates that while the magnitude of losses may vary between
      different regions, the shape of the distribution does not.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_aome8">
        <title>Regional average standardised loss distributions (Hill et al.,
        2014a)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5062.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_jh284">
          <caption>Standardised Loss Factors (Hill et al., 2014a)</caption>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Percentile</th>

              <th>Standardised IL<subscript>s</subscript></th>

              <th>Standardised CL</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>0</td>

              <td>3.19</td>

              <td>3.85</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>10</td>

              <td>2.26</td>

              <td>2.48</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>20</td>

              <td>1.71</td>

              <td>1.88</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>30</td>

              <td>1.20</td>

              <td>1.50</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>40</td>

              <td>1.00</td>

              <td>1.24</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>50</td>

              <td>0.85</td>

              <td>1.00</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>60</td>

              <td>0.68</td>

              <td>0.79</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>70</td>

              <td>0.53</td>

              <td>0.61</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>80</td>

              <td>0.39</td>

              <td>0.48</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>90</td>

              <td>0.14</td>

              <td>0.35</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>100</td>

              <td/>

              <td>0.15</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_mqbuu">
      <title>Parametric Approaches</title>

      <para>Typical parametric distributions can also be fitted to the sample
      of loss values derived for a catchment. Parametric distributions provide
      an efficient means of describing the distribution and help facilitate
      characterising uncertainty.</para>

      <para>A number of studies have investigated different candidate
      distributions for storm initial loss from samples of catchments from
      Victoria (Rahman et al., 2002), Queensland (Tularam &amp; Ilahee, 2007)
      and from around Australia (Hill et al., 2013). Based on these studies
      the four-parameter Beta distribution is recommended for its flexibility
      and because its parameters lend themselves readily to physical
      interpretation. The lower limit can be set to zero, thus reducing the
      number of parameters to 3.</para>

      <para>There has been comparatively less attention paid to the
      distribution of continuing loss. Based upon a case study of three
      catchments in Queensland, Ilahee and Rahman (2003) found that the
      continuing loss values could be approximated by an exponential function.
      Ishak and Rahman (2006) investigated the probabilistic nature of
      continuing loss for four Victorian catchments and none of the
      distributions fitted the observed the distribution satisfactory, however
      the four-parameter Beta distribution providing the best approximation.
      Hill et al (2013) investigated different distributions for 10 catchments
      from around Australia and concluded that the Gamma (two parameter)
      distribution was best. Given these different outcomes, further work is
      required before a preferred distribution for the continuing loss is
      recommended.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_gnpl8">
      <title>Correlation between Initial and Continuing Loss</title>

      <para>The limited number of studies that have explored the correlation
      between initial and continuing loss values have concluded that there is
      little systematic dependence between the two. This apparent lack of
      dependence may reflect reality (for example it might be supposed that
      variation in continuing loss rates may be more dependent upon rainfall
      intensity rather than antecedent conditions) or else it may reflect the
      difficulties of parameter estimation given the limitations of the
      conceptual model adopted.</para>

      <para>It is likely, however, that the observed variation in continuing
      loss between one event and the next is more due to the propagation of
      data errors in the analysis rather than differences in event processes.
      In applying joint probability approaches to design flood estimation, a
      number of authors have stochastically modelled the storm initial loss
      while keeping the continuing loss at a constant value.</para>

      <para>The correlation between loss parameter values requires further
      investigation. In addition to the correlation of loss values for
      individual events it would be useful to analyse the distribution of
      total loss.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_d0jl5">
    <title>Other Considerations for Selecting Loss Values</title>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_pks7r">
      <title>Variation of Loss with Event AEP</title>

      <para>The majority of Australian studies of losses at catchment scale
      have concluded that both ILs and CL do not vary systematically with the
      severity of the event; that is loss is independent of AEP.</para>

      <para><?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T142743+1100" comment="I think it is!"?><?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T142834+1100" comment="This is a common assumption. studies show it isnt so it may need more discussion. Possibly ok." mid="77"?>This
      conclusion is not surprising<?oxy_comment_end ?><?oxy_comment_end mid="77"?>
      because any potential variation of loss with rainfall severity is
      difficult to infer from the empirical analysis of data due to the lack
      of severe rainfall events in the recorded data. This is compounded where
      the storm severity is characterised as the AEP of the rainfall burst,
      whereas the loss values relate to the complete storm, and this
      discrepancy further hinders the identification of any trend with storm
      severity.</para>

      <para>The Australian studies that present loss values that vary with AEP
      tend to be those where the loss values are derived by verification
      against flood frequency quantiles. In such studies it is difficult to
      ascertain whether any variation in loss is meaningful or simply a
      reflection of the uncertainty in the flood frequency quantiles and the
      link to the adopted design inputs.</para>

      <para>The conclusions that there is no evidence to vary loss with
      magnitude is supported by the analysis of rainfall antecedent to extreme
      storms recorded over Southeast Australia which showed that the
      antecedent rainfall was not significantly greater than normal for the
      location and time of the year (Minty &amp; Meighen, 1999). The
      implication of this is that the storm initial losses for large and
      extreme storms should be similar to those of smaller, more frequent
      storms”.</para>

      <para>The recommendation is therefore to keep the ILs and CL values the
      same for AEPs unless there is specific evidence to suggest that there is
      a systematic variation of loss with AEP.</para>

      <para>It should be noted that the stores in a storage capacity loss
      models such as SWMOD fill up during event and hence the proportion of
      the catchment contributing to the loss increases throughout the event.
      The net effect of this is an initial loss (which represents the initial
      filling of the smallest store) following by a variable proportional
      loss. This proportional loss decreases throughout the event and also
      decreases for larger rainfall events.</para>

      <para>In considering how loss varies with event magnitude it is worth
      considering that extreme rainfalls may be associated with changed runoff
      behaviour from that observed for more frequent events with the stripping
      of vegetation cover.</para>

      <para><xref linkend="book8"/> discusses how continuing loss and
      proportional loss would be expected to vary with event magnitude. The
      interpretation of proportional loss as the unsaturated proportion of the
      catchment implies that with larger storm events the unsaturated
      proportion of the catchment is reducing and the proportional loss
      reduces. It is however difficult to extrapolate the rate of this
      reduction to extreme events and hence how proportional loss varies with
      event magnitude. However, continuing loss is expected to approach a
      limiting value for saturated catchment conditions which makes it more
      suitable for application in extreme flood estimation.</para>

      <para>For urban catchments, Phillips et al (2014) undertook an analysis
      of the correlation between the peak 1 hour intensity after the
      commencement of indirectly connected area runoff with the continuing
      loss that was estimated. That study found that for almost all
      catchments, there was no clear relationship between the two. The one
      exception to this was the Giralang (ACT) catchment, which showed a
      strong correlation with the 1 hour peak rainfall intensity after ICA
      runoff and the continuing loss estimate. The reasoning for this
      exception was not clear, although it was thought it could be due to the
      types of storms that fell on the Giralang catchment, which tended to be
      high intensity in the first hour after the Indirectly Connected Area
      runoff occurred.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_gie27">
        <title>Correlation between 1hr Peak Rainfall Intensity and Continuing
        Loss (left Giralang (ACT) and right Powells Creek (NSW)) (from
        Phillips et al, 2014)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5063.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ty4k0">
      <title>Reduction of CL for long events</title>

      <para>In the application of the IL-CL model it is typically assumed that
      the loss rates are a constant after the initial loss is satisfied.
      However for some very large rural catchments where the critical duration
      is multiple days, it has been noted that the CL reduces throughout the
      event. This is consistent with the expectation that the loss rates
      should decrease throughout the event as the catchment becomes wetter and
      infiltration reduces (as characterised in the Horton model – <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_s_ti9sw"/>) and/or the size of source areas
      enlarge.</para>

      <para>This reduction of continuing loss with duration has also been
      noted by studies which have analysed a large number of events for rural
      catchments (eg Ilahee &amp; Imteaz, 2009; Ishak &amp; Rahman,
      2006).</para>

      <para>Developing a relationship which explains the reduction in CL with
      duration or infiltrated volume is confounded by the uncertainty in the
      estimation of CL for specific events. There tends to be very large
      variation of CL for a particular catchment and a large proportion of
      this variability is simply likely to be due to uncertainties in the
      catchment average rainfall depths.</para>

      <para>Although potentially important for real-time applications, the
      potential decrease of CL with duration is not significant for most
      design applications because the critical duration is typically shorter
      than a day. For very large rural catchments where the critical duration
      can be multiple days then it would be reasonable to reduce the CL.
      Ideally this relationship with duration should be based upon analysis of
      at site data but can also be informed by theoretical infiltrations
      relationships such as Manley-Phillips Loss Model (Manley, 1974). Such an
      approach in included in the URBS rainfall-runoff model (Carroll,
      2012).</para>

      <para>For storage capacity loss models such as SWMOD, the moisture
      content is continuously updated throughout the event which results in a
      variable proportional loss. This reduction in proportional loss
      throughout the event may have advantages for modelling of large rural
      catchments.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_0rq6a">
      <title>Influence of timestep on the estimation of CL</title>

      <para>The definition of Storm Initial Loss as the rainfall depth before
      surface runoff is generated suggests that its estimation should not be
      sensitive to the timestep used in the analysis. Similarly, the
      Proportional Loss and storage capacity loss models such as SWMOD should
      also not be affected by the timestep.</para>

      <para>However, the definition of Continuing Loss as the threshold rate
      above which rainfall excess is generated, means that it is dependent
      upon the timestep. This is because as the timestep reduces there is an
      increased likelihood that there will be some timesteps in which the
      rainfall depth is less than the Continuing Loss rate threshold. Thus to
      achieve the same volume of rainfall excess the Continuing Loss will
      typically need to be increased for shorter timesteps.</para>

      <para>This is demonstrated in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_b09it"/> for an
      event at Currambene Creek at Falls Creek in NSW. If the modelling
      timestep is reduced from 1 hour to 5 minutes the continuing loss rate
      needs to increase from 4.5 to 7.2 mm/h to maintain the same volume of
      rainfall excess. This is because for 5 minutes there is a higher
      proportion of timesteps for which the rainfall depth is less than the
      threshold value.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_b09it">
        <title>Example of CL varying with modelling timestep (February 1977
        event at Currambene Creek at Falls Creek in NSW)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5064.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>This adjustment of CL is important if the timestep used in the
      derivation of the loss values is different from that used in design. It
      should therefore be noted that the timestep used in the derivation of
      the regional loss information presented in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_s_iu0fo"/> was 1 hour for the rural catchments and up to
      5 minutes for the urban catchments (refer <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Table
      12<?oxy_custom_end ?>). If a different timestep is to be adopted in
      design then the continuing loss should be adjusted accordingly.</para>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_zfef9">
        <title>Rural Catchments</title>

        <para>The relationship between CL and the timestep used in the
        analysis for rural catchments is shown in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_iyigu"/>. The factor relates the CL derived for a
        timestep less than 1 hour to that for a timestep of 1 hour. The
        information was based upon the analysis of a number of storms at
        different timesteps for 18 catchments across Australia. Further
        details are contained in Lang et al. (2015).</para>

        <para>The factor is a function of the rainfall depth with the
        adjustment factor increasing for smaller rainfall depth. For larger
        depths, it is more likely that the full CL value can be satisfied in
        each timestep which reduces the adjustment factor.</para>

        <para>This line of best fit can be used to relate continuing losses
        modelled at sub-hourly time steps to hourly values and vice versa. For
        example, if the average storm depth is approximately 200 mm and the
        timestep is reduced from 1 hour to 15 minutes then the continuing loss
        needs to be increased by 30%.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_iyigu">
          <title>Variation of CL with modelling timestep for rural
          catchments</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5065.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_7vxfa">
        <title>Urban Catchments</title>

        <para>Urban catchments differ from rural catchments in that generally
        shorter timestep rainfall data is used. This is in order to represent
        the fast response that typically occurs in urban catchments. The
        shorter timestep is required to represent the peak flow appropriately
        (although the runoff volume may be appropriate).</para>

        <para>The urban catchment data derived in Phillips et al (2014) was
        based on shorter timestep pluviometer data than the rural catchments.
        A summary of the data is provided in <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Table<?oxy_custom_end ?>
        12.</para>

        <para>This data was re-analysed comparing with 6 minute time
        intervals, which is similar to a large majority of the pluviometer
        data that is available in Australia, and typical of the duration that
        would be analysed in urban catchments. This re-analysis suggests that
        there are minimal changes to the CL loss estimates, and well within
        the error margins of the estimates.</para>

        <para>There are insufficient storms for the loss estimates to develop
        a similar graph to that for the rural catchment (i.e. <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_iyigu"/>). Instead, the different catchments were
        plotted against timestep, and are shown in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_nv4l0"/>. This graph shows the percentage change
        relative to the median CL estimate for 6 minute timestep. A
        recommended curve is also provided, based on the average of the values
        provided. The equation of this can be broadly approximated by:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_otcci">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mfrac>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>CL</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>CL</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>6min</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mfrac>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>0.2</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>1.35</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where t=time in minutes</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_nv4l0">
          <title>Relationships of Urban CL with Timestep</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5066.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_s79ar">
      <title>Antecedent Rainfall</title>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_8jchs">
        <title>Rural Catchments</title>

        <para>It would be expected that the initial loss, and potentially the
        CL, is negatively correlated with the antecedent rainfall. To avoid
        the arbitrary selection of the period over which to define the
        antecedent rainfall, the antecedent precipitation index (API) can be
        used as a measure of the initial wetness of a catchment. API is
        calculated by discounting the time series of daily rainfall prior to
        the event using an empirical decay factor and the basic equation is
        (Cordery, 1970):</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_6ykf3">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>API</m:mi>

                <m:mi>d</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>k</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>k</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                  </m:msup>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>...</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where <emphasis role="italic">k</emphasis> is an empirical decay
        factor less than unity and <emphasis role="italic">Pd</emphasis> is
        rainfall for day <emphasis role="italic">d</emphasis>. The value of
        <emphasis role="italic">k</emphasis> varies typically in the range of
        0.85 to 0.98 (Linsley et al., 1982) and Cordery (1970) found that the
        average value for Australian catchments was 0.92. The value of
        <emphasis role="italic">k</emphasis> is considered to vary seasonally
        and has been linked to the variation in potential evapotranspiration
        (Mein et al., 1995).</para>

        <para>Cordery (1970) then related the ILs to the API using a
        relationship of the form:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b5_ch5_e_p9xg1">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>IL</m:mi>

                <m:mi>s</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>IL</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>max</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:msup>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>N</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>API</m:mi>
                </m:msup>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>For some rural catchments the API explains a large proportion of
        the variance in ILs whereas for other catchments the loss values
        appear to be invariant with API. For example for the 38 rural
        catchments considered by Hill et al. (2014a) the r² between ILs and
        API varied from approximately zero to 0.70 (refer to <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5_f_by012"/>).</para>

        <para>The results of these studies would indicate that the variability
        of losses is driven by factors other than antecedent rainfall. However
        for some catchments is may be possible to derive strong relationships
        between ILs and measure of antecedent rainfall such as API. If such
        relationships do exist, they can help inform the absolute and seasonal
        distribution of ILs.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_by012">
          <title>Proportion of variance explained (r²) between Storm Initial
          Loss and API (Hill et al., 2014a)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5067.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_ogaxx">
        <title>Urban Catchments</title>

        <para>In residential areas garden watering may influence antecedent
        wetness particularly if several dry days occur (Woolmington &amp;
        Burgess, 1983; Boyd et al., 1994) and therefore measures of the
        preceding days rainfall (such as API) may not reflect the true
        antecedent conditions of the catchment.</para>

        <para>Phillips et al (2014) undertook an analysis of the antecedent
        rainfall in the days leading up to the storms used to estimate the
        initial loss. They compared the rainfall in 1, 3 and 7 days prior to
        the event with the initial loss and continuing loss estimates, and
        found no clear correlation between the two. Samples of this analysis
        are provided in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_1f5g6"/>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_1f5g6">
          <title>Plot of Antecedent Rainfall Versus Initial Loss for
          Indirectly Connected Area (from Phillips et al, 2014)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5068.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_cyafo">
      <title>Seasonality</title>

      <para>The discussion of losses in the preceding sections has
      concentrated on the median annual values. However, due to the seasonal
      variation in rainfall, evapotranspiration (and to a lesser extent
      vegetation) many regions in Australia are characterised by distinct
      seasonality in hydrology. The estimation of seasonal design inputs,
      including loss values, is required in cases where:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>there is a strong seasonal variation in the flood producing
          mechanisms which need to be accounted for in order to estimate the
          annual risk; or</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the risk is required to be assessed for a particular period
          within the year such as the flood risk during construction or
          upgrade of major infrastructure.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The loss parameters (both initial and continuing loss) can be
      influenced by antecedent moisture and therefore may display significant
      seasonal variation. This is likely to primarily reflect changes in
      antecedent moisture but vegetation change may also contribute in some
      locations.</para>

      <para>The different seasonality across Australia is demonstrated in
      <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_q69s5"/>. This shows the seasonal distribution
      of the 803 events analysed by Hill et al. (2014a) which were selected on
      the basis of rainfall. It is clear that in south-eastern Australia the
      events are reasonably distributed throughout the year, whereas the
      majority of events in Northern Australia occur in summer and south-west
      WA is dominated by the winter months.</para>

      <para>It is important to consider this seasonal variation when selecting
      losses for design flood estimation. In some cases the loss values may
      need to be adjusted to account for a bias in the sample and for some
      locations it may be necessary to explicitly incorporate the seasonality
      in the adopted losses and design flood estimation framework.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_q69s5">
        <title>Seasonal distribution of events analysed by Hill et al.
        (2014a)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5069.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The seasonality of the loss values is demonstrated in <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_f_jc2pn"/>. In south-eastern Australia the median losses
      are lowest in July and steadily increase until summer. For northern
      Australia the highest losses are at the beginning of the wet season and
      the losses are slightly lower for late summer and autumn. For south-west
      WA the highest median losses occur in Summer.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_jc2pn">
        <title>Seasonality of standardised storm initial loss values for
        different regions in Australia</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5071.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>In south-west WA, two different rainfall mechanisms have been
      identified which result in distinctly seasonal nature of rainfall and
      losses. The majority of events have been recorded in the winter seasons
      which are typically associated with lower losses, however the rarer
      events are more likely to occur in summer when there is typically higher
      losses. It is therefore important to recognise this in the selection of
      losses.</para>

      <para>This is highlighted by Pearce (2011) which developed seasonal
      runoff coefficients for south-west WA by generalising the results of the
      application of SWMOD to a number of catchments (refer to <xref
      linkend="b5_ch5_f_gr6ng"/>). The results show the important influence of
      the season and the proportion of the catchment cleared of vegetation
      (refer to <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_jlte0"/>).</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_gr6ng">
        <title>Regional runoff coefficient curves for south-west WA (Pearce,
        2011)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5072.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Another approach to deriving seasonal loss values is to verify the
      rainfall-based estimates from a rainfall runoff model to seasonal flood
      frequency quantiles. That is, adopt a similar approach as outlined in
      <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_pyitn"/> but on a seasonal, rather than annual,
      basis.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_jlte0">
      <title>Influence of vegetation</title>

      <para>The presence of vegetation is expected to increase interception
      and hence loss. However, a number of studies have failed to find a link
      between the proportion of the catchment vegetated and the loss values
      (eg Cordery and Pilgrim, 1983a). This is likely to be due to the
      uncertainties in estimating both loss values and representatives
      measures of interception from vegetation at the catchment scale.</para>

      <para>One exception to this is south-west WA where the losses have been
      directly linked to the proportion of the catchment cleared of native
      vegetation (Pearce, 2011).</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_xaye0">
      <title>Interaction with Routing Parameters</title>

      <para>Although it may not be readily apparent, there is an
      interdependency between the adopted conceptual loss model and the
      inferences regarding the routing characteristics of the catchment. This
      is because the different conceptual loss model result in different
      temporal distributions of loss and hence rainfall excess.</para>

      <para>The rainfall excess obtained from loss models where the excess is
      a proportion of the total rainfall in the timestep (such as IL/PL or
      SWMOD) will tend to result in a more temporally uniform (less peaky)
      rainfall excess when compared to IL/CL loss model in which a constant
      rate of loss is applied. This is because a greater volume of loss is
      extracted in the timesteps of greatest rainfall.</para>

      <para>This means that more attenuation is required for the rainfall
      excess resulting from the IL/CL loss models than those for the IL/PL or
      SWMOD.</para>

      <para>For example, ARR Project #6 (Hill et al. 2014a) considered the
      routing parameters for IL/CL and SWMOD for 38 catchments from across
      Australia and demonstrated that the adopted loss model affected the
      selection of the C0.8 value (non-dimensional routing parameter in RORB).
      With the C0.8 value for SWMOD being typically 75% of that for the IL/CL
      model (refer <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_nod6t"/>).</para>

      <para>Therefore, the routing parameters derived using one conceptual
      loss model are not necessarily applicable for an alternate loss model.
      This is important if different loss models are to be applied to flood
      models than those used in calibration.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b5_ch5_f_nod6t">
        <title>Comparison of adopted routing parameters for IL/CL and
        SWMOD</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5073.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_2waxp">
      <title>Influence of Snowpack</title>

      <para>There is only a relatively small proportion of Australia that
      experiences substantial snow cover, and even for these catchments this
      only occurs for a portion of the year. These catchments in parts of
      south-eastern Australia are typically above an elevation of
      approximately 1,500 mAHD. The presence of a snowpack influences the
      losses, runoff generation and routing characteristics of a catchment.
      With respect to losses, there is typically low losses for rain on the
      snowpack and therefore it can be assumed that there are low losses for
      the proportion of the catchment covered by snowpack. For example USACE
      (1998) adopts a continuing loss of 1 mm/h for rain on snowpack.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_slfbn">
      <title>Link to climate drivers and change</title>

      <para>There has been little research on the potential role that large
      scale climate drivers such as El Niño/Southern Oscillation (ENSO),
      Interdecadal Pacific Oscillation (IPO), Indian Ocean Dipole (IOD) and
      Southern Annular Mode (SAM) have on influencing antecedent rainfalls and
      hence loss rates.</para>

      <para>A number of studies have shown significant dependence of annual
      maxima floods in Eastern Australia on the Interdecadal Pacific
      Oscillation (IPO). However, the annual maxima precipitation does not
      exhibit a similar level of dependency on the IPO. Pui et al. (2009)
      hypothesize that the difference in flood characteristics as a function
      of the IPO is a result of catchment antecedent conditions prior to the
      rainfall event. From the analysis of 88 daily rainfall stations in
      Eastern Australia they found that the antecedent conditions prior to
      storm events varied significantly across the 2 IPO phases.</para>

      <para>The influence of these key climate drives on loss rates warrants
      further research.</para>

      <?oxy_comment_start author="ward" timestamp="20151201T143313+1100" comment="maybe the best summary would be an overall one here so people can immediately reference the conclusion (assuming they read the whole book earlier)"?>

      <para/>

      <?oxy_comment_end ?>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_s_vvufa">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Alley, W. M., and Veenhuis, J. E. (1983). ‘‘Effective impervious
    area in urban runoff modeling.’’ J. Hydraul. Eng., 109 no. 2,
    313–319.</para>

    <para>Ball, JE and Powell, M, (1998), Inference of catchment modelling
    system control parameters, Proc. UDM ‘98: Developments in Urban Drainage
    Modelling, London, UK, Vol. 1, pp 313-320.</para>

    <para>Black DC &amp; Aitken AP (1977). Simulation of the Urban Runoff
    Process, Australian Government Publishing Service, 75/82</para>

    <para>Beard, L.R., and Shin Chang. (1979). Urbanization impact on
    streamflow, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of the Hydraulics Division
    ASCE</emphasis>, 105, 647-59.</para>

    <para>Board, R.J. Barlow, F.T.H., Lawrence, J.R. (1989) Flood and Yield
    Estimation in the Arid Zone of the Northern Territory. Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symposium 1989. Christchurch NZ pp 367-371</para>

    <para>Boughton, W.C. (1989) A Review of the USDA SCS Curve Number Method.
    Australian Journal of Soil Research 1989 27 pp511-523</para>

    <para>Boughton, W.C. Hill, P.I., (1997) A Design Flood Estimation
    Procedure using Data Generation and a Daily Water Balance Model. CRC for
    Catchment Hydrology. Report 97/8.</para>

    <para>Boughton, WC; Muncaster, SH; Srikanthan, R; Weinmann, PE, Mein, RG.
    (1999) Continuous Simulation for Design Flood Estimation - a Workable
    Approach. Water 99: Joint Congress; 25th Hydrology &amp; Water Resources
    Symposium, 2nd International Conference on Water Resources &amp;
    Environment Research; Handbook and Proceedings; pp178-183.</para>

    <para>Boughton, W.C. (2015) Master recession analysis of transmission loss
    in some Australian streams [online]. Australian Journal of Water
    Resources, Vol. 19, No. 1, 2015: 43-51. Availability:
    &lt;http://search.informit.com.au/documentSummary;dn=283113495712822;res=IELENG&gt;
    ISSN: 1324-1583. [cited 06 Oct 15].</para>

    <para>Boyd, M.J., Bufill, M.C., Knee, R.M. (1993) Pervious and Impervious
    Runoff in urban catchments. Hydrological Sciences. 38, 6, December 1993.
    pp 463-478</para>

    <para>Boyd MJ, Bufill MC &amp; Knee RM (1994). <emphasis
    role="italic">Predicting Pervious and Impervious Storm Runoff from Urban
    Drainage Basins</emphasis>, Hydrological Sciences Journal, 39, 4,
    August.</para>

    <para>Carroll, D.G. (2012) URBS (Unified River Basin Simulator) A Rainfall
    Runoff Routing Model for Flood Forecasting and Design. Version 5.00 Dec,
    2012.</para>

    <para>Chapman, T.G. (1968) Catchment Parameters for a Deterministic
    Rainfall-Runoff Model in “Land Evaluation” (ed G.A. Stewart), Macmillan,
    Melbourne pp. 312-323</para>

    <para>Chapman, T.G. (1970). Optimisation of a rainfall-runoff model for an
    arid zone catchment, in Symposium on the results of research on
    representative and experimental basins, pp. 126-144, IASH Publ. No. 96,
    Wellington, New Zealand.</para>

    <para>Cherkaver, D. S. (1975). The hydrologic response of small watersheds
    to suburban development: Observations and modeling in urbanization and
    water quality control, in Whiple Jr. (Eds), <emphasis
    role="italic">Proceedings of the American Water Resources
    Association</emphasis> (pp. 110-119), Herndon,VA.</para>

    <para>Chiew, F.H.S, McMahon, T.A. (1999). Modelling Runoff and diffuse
    pollution loads in urban areas. Water Science Technology, 39(12),
    241-248.</para>

    <para>Chu, S.T. (1978) Infiltration during an Unsteady Rain. Water
    Resources Research. Vol 14 No. 3 pp461-466.</para>

    <para>Cordery, I., (1970) Antecedent Wetness for Design Flood Estimation,
    Civil Engineering Transaction, Institution of Engineers, Australia, 1970,
    Vol. CE12 No. 2, pp 181-184.</para>

    <para>Cordery, I., Pilgrim, D.H., (1983a) On the Lack of Dependence of
    Losses from Flood Runoff on Soil and Cover Characteristics, IAHS Pub. No.
    140, pp 187-195.</para>

    <para>Cordery, I., Pilgrim, D.H., Doran, D.G., (1983b) Some Hydrological
    Characteristics of Arid Western New South Wales. Hydrology and Resources
    Symposium. I.E.Aust. Nat. Conf. Pub. No. 83/13, pp 287-292.</para>

    <para>Dayaratne, S.T. (2000). Modelling of Urban Stormwater Drainage
    Systems using ILSAX, PhD Thesis, Victoria University of Technology,
    August.</para>

    <para>Dyer, B.G., Nathan, R.J., McMahon, T.A., O’Neill, I.C. (1994)
    Development of Regional Prediction Equations for the RORB Runoff Routing
    Model. CRC for Catchment Hydrology Report 94/1. March 1994.</para>

    <para>Eastgate, W.I., Swartz, G.L., Briggs, H.S., (1979) Estimation of
    Runoff Rates for Small Queensland Catchments, Department of Primary
    Industries, Queensland Technical Bulletin No. 15.</para>

    <para>El-Kafagee, M., &amp; Rahman, A., (2011). A study on initial and
    continuing losses for design flood estimation in New South Wales. In Chan,
    F., Marinova, D. and Anderssen, R.S. (eds) MODSIM2011, 19th International
    Congress on Modelling and Simulation, (pp. 3782 – 3787), Perth,
    Australia.</para>

    <para>Flavell, D.J., Belstead, B.S. (1986) Losses for Design Flood
    Estimation in Western Australia. Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium.
    Griffith University. 1986. pp 203 – 208.</para>

    <para>Fleming, P. M., (1974). The Australian Representatives Basins
    Programme, Journal of Hydrology, 13(1), 21-31.</para>

    <para>Fleming, P.M., Smiles, D.E. (1975) Infiltration of Water into Soil.
    In Chapman, T.G. and Dunin, F.X. eds. Prediction in Catchment Hydrology.
    Canberra. Australian Academy of Science. pp 83-110.</para>

    <para>Goyen, A.G. (1983) A Model to Statistically Derive Design Rainfall
    Losses Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium 1983: Preprints of Papers;
    pages: 220-225. Institution of Engineers, Australia, 1983. National
    conference publication no. 83/13.</para>

    <para>Goyen, A.G., O'Loughlin, G.G. (1999a) The Effects of Infiltration
    Spatial and Temporal Patterns on Urban Runoff. Water 99: Joint Congress;
    25th Hydrology &amp; Water Resources Symposium, 2nd International
    Conference on Water Resources &amp; Environment Research; Handbook and
    Proceedings; pages: 819-822.</para>

    <para>Goyen, A.G., O'Loughlin, G.G. (1999b) Examining the basic building
    blocks of urban runoff. Urban Storm Drainage - 8th International
    Proceedings. Sydney, 30 Aug.-3 Sept. 1999, Vol. 3, pp. 1382-1390</para>

    <para>Goyen, A.G. (2000) Spatial and Temporal Effects on Urban Rainfall /
    Runoff Modelling. PhD Thesis. University of Technology, Sydney. Faculty of
    Engineering.</para>

    <para>Green, R.E., Ampt, G.A. (1911) Studies on Soil Physics: 1. Flow of
    Air and Water through Soils. Journal of Agricultural Science Vol 4.
    pp1-24</para>

    <para>Heneker, T.M; Lambert, M.F. Kuczera, G. (2003) Overcoming the Joint
    Probability Problem Associated with Initial Loss Estimation in Design
    Flood Estimation. Australian Journal of Water Resources; Volume 7, Issue
    2; 2003; 101-109.</para>

    <para>Hill, P.I., Maheepala, U., Mein, R.G., (1996) Empirical Analysis of
    Data to Derive Losses: Methodology, Programs and Results. CRC for
    Catchment Hydrology Working Document 96/5.</para>

    <para>Hill, P.I., Graszkiewicz, Z., Sih, K., Rahman, A. (2013) Revision
    project 6: Loss models for catchment simulation. Stage 2 Report
    P6/S2/016A</para>

    <para>Hill, P.I., Graszkiewicz, Z., Taylor, M., Nathan, R.J. (2014a) ARR
    Revision Project 6 Loss models for catchment simulation. Stage 4 Analysis
    of rural catchments. May 2014.</para>

    <para>Hill, P.I. Graszkiewicz, Z., Nathan, R.J., Stephens, D.A., Pearce,
    L. (2014b) Testing the Suitability of a probability distributed storage
    capacity loss model for design flood estimation. 2014 Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symposium, Perth.</para>

    <para>Hill, P.I., Graszkiewicz, Z., Loveridge, M., Nathan, R.J., Scorah,
    M. (2015) Analysis of loss values for Australian rural catchments to
    underpin ARR guidance. Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium 2015.
    Hobart. 9-10 December 2015.</para>

    <para>Ilahee, M., Rahman, A., (2003) Investigation of Continuing Losses
    for Design Flood Estimation: A Case Study in Queensland. 28th
    International Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, 10 - 14 November
    2003,Wollongong, NSW. Vol1. pp191 – 197.</para>

    <para>Ilahee, M. (2005). <emphasis role="italic">Modelling Losses in Flood
    Estimation</emphasis>, A thesis submitted to the School of Urban
    Development Queensland University of Technology in partial fulfilment of
    the requirements for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy, March
    2005.</para>

    <para>Ilahee, M and Imteaz, M.A. (2009) Improved Continuing Losses
    Estimation Using Initial Loss-Continuing Loss Model for Medium Sized Rural
    Catchments. American J. of Engineering and Applied Sciences 2 (4):
    796-803, 2009</para>

    <para>Ishak, E., and Rahman, A. (2006) Investigation into Probabilistic
    Nature of Continuing Loss in Four Catchments in Victoria. In: 30th
    Hydrology &amp; Water Resources Symposium: Past, Present &amp; Future;
    pages: 432-437.</para>

    <para>Janke, B., Wilson, N. (2011). Development of techniques to quantify
    effective impervious cover</para>

    <para>(Centre for Transportation Studies Research Report). University of
    Minnesota, USA.</para>

    <para>Jensen, M. (1990) Rain-runoff parameters for six small gauged urban
    catchments. Nordic &amp;drol. 21, pp165-184.</para>

    <para>Kemp D.J. &amp; Lipp WR (1999). <emphasis role="italic">Predicting
    Stormwater Runoff in Adelaid – What do we Know?</emphasis>, Living with
    Water Seminar, The Hydrological Society of South Australia,
    Adelaide.</para>

    <para>Kemp, D.J., Wright, C. (2014) Flood Hydrology in an Arid Area –
    Findings from the Gammon Ranges Project. 2014 Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symposium, Perth. 24 - 27 February 2014. Pp 109-116</para>

    <para>King, K.W. (2000) Response of Green-Ampt Mein-Larsen Simulated
    Runoff Volumes to Temporally Aggregated Precipitation. Journal of the
    American Water Resources Association. Vol 36 No.4 pp 791-797</para>

    <para>Kjeldsen, T.R., Stewart, E.J., Packman, J.C., Folwell, S.S. and
    Bayliss, A.C. (2005) Revitalisation of the FSR/FEH rainfall-runoff method.
    Joint Defra/EA Flood and Coastal Erosion Risk Management R&amp;D
    Programme. R&amp;D Technical Report FD1913/TR</para>

    <para>Knighton, A.D., Nanson, G.C. (1994). Flow transmission along an arid
    zone anastomosing river, Cooper Creek, Australia. Hydrological Processes
    8: 137-154</para>

    <para>Kuczera, G.; Lambert, M.; Heneker, T.; Jennings, S.; Frost, A. and
    Coombes, P. (2006) Joint Probability and Design Storms at the Crossroads.
    Australian Journal of Water Resources; Volume 10, Issue 1; 2006;
    63-79.</para>

    <para>Lang, S.M., Hill, P.I. Scorah, M., Stephens, D.A. (2015) Defining
    and calculating continuing loss for flood estimation. 2015 Hydrology and
    Water Resources Symposium. Hobart.</para>

    <para>Lee, J., Lim, W.H. (1995) Green-Ampt Equation and the Soil Water
    Storage Depth in a Watershed Model. The Second International Symposium on
    Urban Stormwater Management. Melbourne Australia 11-13 July 1995. pp157
    -161</para>

    <para>Linsley, R.K., Kohler, M.A., Paulhus, J.L. (1982) Hydrology for
    Engineers. Third Edition McGraw-Hill Co</para>

    <para>Loveridge, M. (unpublished) Evaluation of Monte Carlo simulation for
    flood frequency curve derivation using an event-based rainfall-runoff
    model, Doctoral Thesis, University of Western Sydney</para>

    <para>Mag, V.S., Mein, R.G. (1994) A flood forecasting procedure which
    combines the RORB and TOPOG models", Hydrology and Water Resour, Symp,
    I.E. Nat. Conf. 94/15, pp.217-222,1994.</para>

    <para>Manley, R.E. (1974) Catchment Models for River Management, MSc
    Thesis, University of Birmingham.</para>

    <para>Maidment, D.R. (1992) Handbook of Hydrology. McGraw-Hill USA.</para>

    <para>Mein, R.G., Larson, C.L. (1973) Modeling Infiltration during a
    Steady Rain. Water Resources Research. Vol. 9. pp384-394.</para>

    <para>Mein, R. G. &amp; McMahon, T. A., (1982). <emphasis
    role="italic">Review of the role of process modelling in the Australian
    Representative Basins Program</emphasis>, (In Review of the Australian
    Representative Basin Program. Rep. Basin Ser. Rep. 4).</para>

    <para>Mein, R.G., Goyen, AG (1988) Urban Runoff. Transactions of the
    Institution of Engineers, Australia: Civil Engineering. v CE30, n 4,
    December 1988</para>

    <para>Mein, R.G., O’Loughlin, E.M. (1991) A New Approach to Flood
    Forecasting, Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Perth. I.E.Aust.
    Nat. Conf. Pub. No. 91/12, pp. 219-224.</para>

    <para>Mein, R.G., Nandakumar, N., Siriwardena, L. (1995) Estimation of
    Initial Loss from Soil Moisture Indices (Pilot Study) CRC for Catchment
    Hydrology Working Document 95/1.</para>

    <para>Melanen.M. &amp; Laukkanen.R. (1981) Dependence of runoff
    coefficient on area type and hydrological factors. Proceedings of 2nd
    International Conference on Urban Storm Drainage, edited B. C. Yen, Water
    Resources Publications, Littleton, Colorado, USA, 404-410.</para>

    <para>Moore, R.J. (1985) The probability-distributed principle and runoff
    production at point and</para>

    <para>basin scales. Hydrological Sciences Journal 30: 2, 273 — 297</para>

    <para>Muncaster, S.H., Weinmann, P.E. and Boughton, W.C. (1999). The
    representation of loss in continuous simulation models for design flood
    estimation. Water 99 Joint Congress, Brisbane 6-8 July 1999, Institution
    of Engineers, Australia, pp 184-189</para>

    <para>Nathan, R.J., Weinmann, P.E., Hill, P.I. (2003) Use of a Monte-Carlo
    Simulation to estimate the Expected Probability of Large to Extreme Floods
    28th International Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, 10 - 14
    November 2003,Wollongong, NSW. pp1.105 – 1.112</para>

    <para>O’Loughlin, G and Stack, B (2014). DRAINS User Manual,
    November.</para>

    <para>Pearce, L.J. (2011) Regional runoff coefficients for summer and
    winter design flood events in south-west Western Australia. 24th IAHR
    World Congress – Balance and Uncertainty. 26 June – 1 July 2011 Brisbane
    Australia.</para>

    <para>Pearcey, M., Pettett, S., Cheng, S., Knoesen, D. (2014) Estimation
    of RORB Kc parameter for ungauged catchments in the Pilbara Region of
    Western Australia. 2014 Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Perth. 24
    - 27 February 2014.</para>

    <para>Phillips, B., Goyen, A., Thomson, R., Pathiraja, S., Pomeroy, L.
    (2014) Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 6: Loss models for
    catchment simulation – Urban Losses Stage 2 Report. February 2014</para>

    <para>Pui, A., Lall, A., Sharma, A. (2009) How does the Interdecadal
    Pacific Oscillation affect Design Floods in Eastern Australia. H2009 –
    32nd Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium. November 2009.
    pp266-274</para>

    <para>Rahman, A.; Weinmann, P.E.; Mein, R.G. (2002) The Use of
    Probability-distributed Initial Losses in Design Flood Estimation.
    Australian Journal of Water Resources; Volume 6, Issue 1; 2002;
    17-29.</para>

    <para>Rajendran, R., Mein, R.G., Laurenson, E.M., (1982) A Spatial Model
    for the Prediction of Losses on Small Rural Catchments, Department of
    Civil Engineering, Monash University, Australian Water Resources Council
    Technical Paper No. 75, AGPS, Canberra.</para>

    <para>Ren-Jun., Z (1992) The Xinanjiang model applied in China. Journal of
    Hydrology. 135 pp 371 – 381</para>

    <para>Rigby, E.H., Bannigan, D.J. (1996) The Embedded Design Storm Concept
    - a Critical Review. In: Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium 1996:
    Water and the Environment; Preprints of Papers; pages: 453-459. National
    Conference Publication no. 96/05.</para>

    <para>Riley, S.J., Fanning, P.C. (1997) Spatial Patterns of Infiltration
    in Suburban Developments in the Hawkesbury-Nepean Catchment. Science and
    Technology in the Environmental Management of the Hawkesbury-Nepean
    Catchment. 10-11 July 1997. University of Western Sydney. Nepean.
    Institution of Engineers Australia. NCP 97/01.</para>

    <para>Ruprecht, J.K., Schofield, N.J. (1993) Infiltration characteristics
    of a complex lateritic soil profile. Hydrological Processes 7:
    87-97</para>

    <para>Shuster, W.D.; Bonta, J.; Thurston, H. Warnemuende; E.; Smith, D.R.
    (2005): Impacts of impervious surface on watershed hydrology: A review,
    Urban Water Journal, 2:4, 263-275</para>

    <para>Siriwardini, N.R., Cheung, B.P.M. and Perera, B.J.C. (2003)
    Estimation of Soil Infiltration Rates of Urban Catchments, 28th
    International Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Institution of
    Engineers, Australia, Wollongong</para>

    <para>Skukla, M.K. Lal, R., Unkefer, P. (2003) Experimental validation of
    infiltration models for different land use and soil management systems.
    Journal of Soil Science 168(3), pp178-191.</para>

    <para>Stewart, BJ and Boughton, WC. (1983) Transmission Losses in Natural
    Streambeds - a Review.: Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium 1983:
    Preprints of Papers; pages: 226-230. Institution of Engineers, Australia,
    1983</para>

    <para>Stokes, R.A. (1989) Calculation file for Soil Water Model – Concept
    and theoretical basis of soil water model for the south west of Western
    Australia. Unpublished Report. Water Authority of W.A. Water Resources
    Directorate.</para>

    <para>Tularam, G.A, and Ilahee, M. (2007) Initial loss estimates for
    tropical catchments of Australia. Environmental Impact Assessment Review
    27 (2007) 493–504</para>

    <para>USACE (1998) Runoff from Snowmelt. Engineering Manual 1110-2-1406 31
    March 1998.</para>

    <para>Van Mullem, J.A., D.E. Woodward, Hawkins, R.H., and A.T. Hjelmfelt,
    Jr. (2002) Runoff curve number method: beyond the handbook. In: Hydrologic
    Modeling for the 21st Century. Second Federal Interagency Hydrologic
    Modeling Conference, July 28 to August 1, Las Vegas, Nevada.</para>

    <para>Walsh, M.A., Pilgrim, D.H., Cordery, I., (1991) Initial Losses for
    Design Flood Estimation in New South Wales. International Hydrology and
    Water Resources Symposium, Perth, I.E.Aust. Nat. Conf. Pub. No. 91/19, pp.
    283-288.</para>

    <para>Ward, T.J., Hawkins, R.H., Van Mullem, J.A., Woodward. D.E. (2009)
    Curve Number Hydrology State of the Practice. American Society of Civil
    Engineers.</para>

    <para>Water and Rivers Commission (2003) SWMOD A rainfall loss model for
    calculating rainfall excess User Manual (Version 2.11). Prepared by
    Hydrology and Water Resources Branch Resource Science Division. September
    2003</para>

    <para>Waugh, A.S. (1991) Design Losses in Flood Estimation, International
    Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Perth. I.E.Aust. Nat. Conf. Pub.
    No. 91/19, pp. 629-630.</para>

    <para>William, J. (1994) Preliminary report on the use of the Green Ampt
    Infiltration Model for measuring surface runoff on rural catchments. CRC
    for Catchment Hydrology unpublished report 18 February 1994.</para>

    <para>Woodward, D.E., Hawkins, R.H., Quan, Q.D. (2002) Curve number
    method: origins, applications and limitations. Hydrologic Modeling for the
    21st Century. Second Federal Interagency Hydrologic Modeling Conference,
    July 28 to August 1, Las Vegas, Nevada.</para>

    <para>Woolmington, E., Burgess, J.S. (1983). Hedonistic water use and
    low-flow runoff in Australia's national capital. Urban Ecology 7(3):
    215-227</para>

    <para>Zaman, S; Ball, J.E. (1994) Simulation of small events in an urban
    catchment, Proc. 1994 Hydrology and Water Resources Conference – Water
    Down Under ’94. I.E.Aust. Adelaide, Australia, I.E.Aust. Nat. Conf. Pub.
    94/15 pp353 – 358.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch5_a">
    <title>Appendix</title>

    <table frame="void">
      <caption>Median loss values for rural catchments</caption>

      <col align="left" width="10%"/>

      <col align="left" width="10%"/>

      <col align="left" width="10%"/>

      <col align="left" width="10%"/>

      <col align="left" width="10%"/>

      <col align="right" width="10%"/>

      <col align="right" width="10%"/>

      <col align="right" width="10%"/>

      <col align="right" width="10%"/>

      <col align="left" width="10%"/>

      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">Region</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Method</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Gauge</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">River</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Name</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Area</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">N</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Median IL<subscript>s</subscript>
          (mm)</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Median CL (mm/h)</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Study</emphasis></th>
        </tr>
      </thead>

      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>141001</td>

          <td>South Maroochy</td>

          <td>Kiamba</td>

          <td>33</td>

          <td>22</td>

          <td>38</td>

          <td>2.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>141009</td>

          <td>North Maroochy</td>

          <td>Eumundi</td>

          <td>41</td>

          <td>23</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>2.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>201001</td>

          <td>Oxley River</td>

          <td>Eungella</td>

          <td>218</td>

          <td>53</td>

          <td>50</td>

          <td>2.6</td>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>203010</td>

          <td>Leycester River</td>

          <td>Rock Valley</td>

          <td>179</td>

          <td>48</td>

          <td>65</td>

          <td>0.3</td>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>204017</td>

          <td>Bielsdown Creek</td>

          <td>Dorrigo No.2 &amp; No.3</td>

          <td>82</td>

          <td>57</td>

          <td>50</td>

          <td>1.4</td>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>204025</td>

          <td>Orara River</td>

          <td>Karangi</td>

          <td>135</td>

          <td>37</td>

          <td>71</td>

          <td>4</td>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>208007</td>

          <td>Nowendoc River</td>

          <td>Nowendoc</td>

          <td>218</td>

          <td>37</td>

          <td>50</td>

          <td>2.3</td>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>210068</td>

          <td>Pokolbin Creek</td>

          <td>Pokolbin Site 3</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>36</td>

          <td>40</td>

          <td>2.0</td>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>211013</td>

          <td>Ourimbah Creek</td>

          <td>Upstream Weir</td>

          <td>83</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>40</td>

          <td>3.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>213200</td>

          <td>O'Hares Creek</td>

          <td>Wedderburn</td>

          <td>73</td>

          <td>22</td>

          <td>60</td>

          <td>1.6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>136108A</td>

          <td>Monal Creek</td>

          <td>Upper Monal</td>

          <td>92</td>

          <td>12</td>

          <td>13</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>141009A</td>

          <td>N. Maroochy River</td>

          <td>Eumundi</td>

          <td>38</td>

          <td>22</td>

          <td>42</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>142001A</td>

          <td>Caboolture</td>

          <td>Upper Caboolture</td>

          <td>94</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>50</td>

          <td>1.4</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>143110A</td>

          <td>Bremer River</td>

          <td>Adams Bridge</td>

          <td>125</td>

          <td>37</td>

          <td>39</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>145003B</td>

          <td>Logan River</td>

          <td>Forest Home</td>

          <td>175</td>

          <td>42</td>

          <td>31</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>145010A</td>

          <td>Running Creek</td>

          <td>5.8km Deickmans Bridge</td>

          <td>128</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>32</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>145011A</td>

          <td>Teviot Brook</td>

          <td>Croftby</td>

          <td>83</td>

          <td>37</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>145101D</td>

          <td>Albert River</td>

          <td>Lumeah Number 2</td>

          <td>169</td>

          <td>35</td>

          <td>44</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>809312</td>

          <td>Fletcher</td>

          <td>Frog Hollow</td>

          <td>30.6</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td>10.4</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>118003A</td>

          <td>Bohle River</td>

          <td>Hervey Range Road</td>

          <td>143</td>

          <td>24</td>

          <td>29</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>120014A</td>

          <td>Broughton River</td>

          <td>Oak Meadows</td>

          <td>182</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>18</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>120216A</td>

          <td>Broken</td>

          <td>Old Racecourse</td>

          <td>78</td>

          <td>34</td>

          <td>68</td>

          <td>6.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>916003A</td>

          <td>Moonlight Creek</td>

          <td>Alehvale</td>

          <td>127</td>

          <td>7</td>

          <td>29</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>917114A</td>

          <td>Routh Creek</td>

          <td>Beef Road</td>

          <td>81</td>

          <td>7</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>NT</td>

          <td>G8150151</td>

          <td>Celia</td>

          <td>U/S Darwin R Dam</td>

          <td>52</td>

          <td>15</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>5.4</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>NT</td>

          <td>G8170066</td>

          <td>Coomalie</td>

          <td>Stuart HWY</td>

          <td>82</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td>50</td>

          <td>8.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>NT</td>

          <td>G8170075</td>

          <td>Manton</td>

          <td>upstream Manton Dam</td>

          <td>29</td>

          <td>32</td>

          <td>42</td>

          <td>1.6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>403226</td>

          <td>Boggy Creek</td>

          <td>Angleside</td>

          <td>108</td>

          <td>33</td>

          <td>15</td>

          <td>3.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>404208</td>

          <td>Moonee Creek</td>

          <td>Lima</td>

          <td>91</td>

          <td>28</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>6.5</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>405229</td>

          <td>Wanalta Creek</td>

          <td>Wanalta</td>

          <td>108</td>

          <td>24</td>

          <td>31</td>

          <td>1.4</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>405257</td>

          <td>Snobs Creek</td>

          <td>Snobs Creek Hatchery</td>

          <td>51</td>

          <td>12</td>

          <td>8</td>

          <td>11</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>405261</td>

          <td>Spring Creek</td>

          <td>Fawcett</td>

          <td>60</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>27</td>

          <td>4.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>406208</td>

          <td>Campaspe River</td>

          <td>Ashborne</td>

          <td>33</td>

          <td>7</td>

          <td>48</td>

          <td>6.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>406216</td>

          <td>Axe Creek</td>

          <td>Sedgewick</td>

          <td>34</td>

          <td>12</td>

          <td>28</td>

          <td>6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>407258</td>

          <td>Myers Creek</td>

          <td>Myers Flat</td>

          <td>55</td>

          <td>9</td>

          <td>36</td>

          <td>2.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>ACT</td>

          <td>410736</td>

          <td>Orroral River</td>

          <td>Crossing</td>

          <td>90</td>

          <td>36</td>

          <td>18</td>

          <td>7.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>ACT</td>

          <td>410739</td>

          <td>Tidbinbilla Creek</td>

          <td>Mountain Creek</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>31</td>

          <td>10</td>

          <td>8.8</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>ACT</td>

          <td>410743</td>

          <td>Jerrabomberra Creek</td>

          <td>Four Mile Creek</td>

          <td>52</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>22</td>

          <td>2.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>ACT</td>

          <td>410751</td>

          <td>Ginninderra Creek</td>

          <td>u/s Barton Highway</td>

          <td>48</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>38</td>

          <td>6.5</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>411003</td>

          <td>Butmaroo Creek</td>

          <td>Butmaroo</td>

          <td>65</td>

          <td>21</td>

          <td>40</td>

          <td>2.6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Murray Darling</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>422321</td>

          <td>Spring</td>

          <td>Killarney</td>

          <td>32</td>

          <td>27</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td>5.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Pilbara</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>709007</td>

          <td>Harding</td>

          <td>Marmurrina Pool U-South</td>

          <td>49.4</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>60</td>

          <td>8.3</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Rangelands</td>

          <td>NT</td>

          <td>G0290240</td>

          <td>Tennant</td>

          <td>Old Telegraph Stn</td>

          <td>72.3</td>

          <td>24</td>

          <td>0</td>

          <td>5.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>602199</td>

          <td>Goodga River</td>

          <td>Black Cat</td>

          <td>49.2</td>

          <td>27</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td>4.8</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>603190</td>

          <td>Yates Flat Creek</td>

          <td>Woonanup</td>

          <td>53</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>27</td>

          <td>0.8</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>608002</td>

          <td>Carey Brook</td>

          <td>Staircase Rd</td>

          <td>30.3</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>3.8</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>609005</td>

          <td>Balgarup River</td>

          <td>Mandelup Pool</td>

          <td>82.4</td>

          <td>13</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>2.5</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>612004</td>

          <td>Hamilton River</td>

          <td>Worsley</td>

          <td>32.3</td>

          <td>13</td>

          <td>47</td>

          <td>3.3</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>613003</td>

          <td>Harvey</td>

          <td>Paganini Farm</td>

          <td>148</td>

          <td/>

          <td>16</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Waugh (1991)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>613013</td>

          <td>Bancell Creek</td>

          <td>Wagerup</td>

          <td>13</td>

          <td/>

          <td>11</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Waugh (1991)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>614003</td>

          <td>Marrinup Brook</td>

          <td>Brookdale Siding</td>

          <td>45.6</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>16</td>

          <td>7.3</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>614003</td>

          <td>Marrinup Brook</td>

          <td>Brookdale Siding</td>

          <td>46</td>

          <td/>

          <td>12</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Waugh (1991)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>614005</td>

          <td>Dirk Brook</td>

          <td>Kentish Farm</td>

          <td>36</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>14</td>

          <td>6.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>614005</td>

          <td>Dirk Brook</td>

          <td>Kentish Farm</td>

          <td>36</td>

          <td/>

          <td>15</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Waugh (1991)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>614016</td>

          <td>North Dandalup River</td>

          <td>Nth Dandalup Dam</td>

          <td>153</td>

          <td/>

          <td>20</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Waugh (1991)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>614047</td>

          <td>Davis Brook</td>

          <td>Murray Valley Plntn</td>

          <td>65.7</td>

          <td>18</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>8.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-west WA</td>

          <td>WA</td>

          <td>701006</td>

          <td>Buller River</td>

          <td>Buller</td>

          <td>33.9</td>

          <td>14</td>

          <td>32</td>

          <td>3.8</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-Central SA</td>

          <td>SA</td>

          <td>A5040523</td>

          <td>Sixth Creek</td>

          <td>Castambul</td>

          <td>44</td>

          <td>24</td>

          <td>15</td>

          <td>3.3</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-Central SA</td>

          <td>SA</td>

          <td>AW501500</td>

          <td>Hindmarsh River</td>

          <td>Hindmarsh Vy Res Offtake</td>

          <td>56</td>

          <td>33</td>

          <td>15</td>

          <td>3.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-Central SA</td>

          <td>SA</td>

          <td>AW502502</td>

          <td>Myponga River</td>

          <td>upstream Dam and Rd Br</td>

          <td>77</td>

          <td>15</td>

          <td>23</td>

          <td>2.6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-Central SA</td>

          <td>SA</td>

          <td>AW503506</td>

          <td>Echunga Creek</td>

          <td>upstream Mt Bold Res.</td>

          <td>34</td>

          <td>13</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>2.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>TAS</td>

          <td>2219</td>

          <td>Swan River</td>

          <td>upstream Hardings Falls</td>

          <td>38</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>40</td>

          <td>0.5</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>214003</td>

          <td>Macquarie Rivulet</td>

          <td>Albion Park</td>

          <td>35</td>

          <td>26</td>

          <td>69</td>

          <td>2.9</td>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>214003</td>

          <td>Macquarie Rivulet</td>

          <td>Albion Park</td>

          <td>35</td>

          <td>26</td>

          <td>69</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>216004</td>

          <td>Currambene Creek</td>

          <td>Falls Creek</td>

          <td>95</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>35</td>

          <td>3.9</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>NSW</td>

          <td>216004</td>

          <td>Currambene Creek</td>

          <td>Falls Creek</td>

          <td>95</td>

          <td>37</td>

          <td>37</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Loveridge (2015)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>224209</td>

          <td>Cobbannah Creek</td>

          <td>Bairnsdale</td>

          <td>106</td>

          <td>13</td>

          <td>52</td>

          <td>1.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>226222</td>

          <td>La Trobe River</td>

          <td>Near Noojee</td>

          <td>62</td>

          <td>7</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>3.4</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>227226</td>

          <td>Tarwin River East Branch</td>

          <td>Dumbalk Nth</td>

          <td>127</td>

          <td>5</td>

          <td>41</td>

          <td>1.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>227228</td>

          <td>Tarwin River East Branch</td>

          <td>Mirboo</td>

          <td>43</td>

          <td>5</td>

          <td>21</td>

          <td>3.6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>228217</td>

          <td>Toomuc Creek</td>

          <td>Pakenham</td>

          <td>42</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>24</td>

          <td>2.5</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>229106</td>

          <td>McMahons Creek</td>

          <td>Upstream Weir</td>

          <td>40</td>

          <td>21</td>

          <td>20</td>

          <td>3.7</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>231213</td>

          <td>Lerderderg River</td>

          <td>Sardine Creek</td>

          <td>153</td>

          <td>9</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td>1.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>231219</td>

          <td>Goodman Creek</td>

          <td>above Lerderderg Tunnel</td>

          <td>32</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>35</td>

          <td>2.4</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>233223</td>

          <td>Warrambine Creek</td>

          <td>Warrabine</td>

          <td>57</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>26</td>

          <td>1.5</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>235212</td>

          <td>Chapple Creek</td>

          <td>Chapple Value</td>

          <td>28</td>

          <td>23</td>

          <td>28</td>

          <td>2.6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>235219</td>

          <td>Aire River</td>

          <td>Wyelangta</td>

          <td>90</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>3</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>235219</td>

          <td>Aire River</td>

          <td>Wyelangta</td>

          <td>90</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>3</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>235229</td>

          <td>Ford River</td>

          <td>Glenaire</td>

          <td>56</td>

          <td>23</td>

          <td>21</td>

          <td>2.6</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>238231</td>

          <td>Glenelg River</td>

          <td>Big Cord</td>

          <td>57</td>

          <td>17</td>

          <td>24</td>

          <td>5.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (1996)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>South-east Coast</td>

          <td>VIC</td>

          <td>228206B</td>

          <td>Tarago River</td>

          <td>Neerim</td>

          <td>78</td>

          <td>22</td>

          <td>24</td>

          <td>3.9</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>125006</td>

          <td>Finch Hatton</td>

          <td>Dam Site</td>

          <td>36</td>

          <td>30</td>

          <td>23</td>

          <td>5.2</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>112003A</td>

          <td>N. Johnston River</td>

          <td>Glen Allyn</td>

          <td>173</td>

          <td>15</td>

          <td>34</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>114001A</td>

          <td>Murray River</td>

          <td>Upper Murray</td>

          <td>155</td>

          <td>23</td>

          <td>66</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>116008B</td>

          <td>Gowrie Creek</td>

          <td>Abergowrie</td>

          <td>124</td>

          <td>61</td>

          <td>22</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>116015A</td>

          <td>Blunder Creek</td>

          <td>Wooroora</td>

          <td>127</td>

          <td>48</td>

          <td>71</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>116017A</td>

          <td>Stone River</td>

          <td>Running Creek</td>

          <td>157</td>

          <td>55</td>

          <td>33</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>124002A</td>

          <td>St. Helens Creek</td>

          <td>Calen</td>

          <td>129</td>

          <td>11</td>

          <td>54</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>126003A</td>

          <td>Carmila</td>

          <td>Carmila</td>

          <td>82</td>

          <td>19</td>

          <td>70</td>

          <td>3.1</td>

          <td>Hill et al. (2014a)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>922101B</td>

          <td>Coen River</td>

          <td>Racecourse</td>

          <td>166</td>

          <td>59</td>

          <td>25</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Wet Tropics</td>

          <td>QLD</td>

          <td>926003A</td>

          <td>Bertie Creek</td>

          <td>Swordgrass Swamp</td>

          <td>130</td>

          <td>8</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td/>

          <td>Ilahee (2006)</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>

    <table frame="void" xml:id="b5_ch5_t_hwjb5">
      <caption>Summary of EIA Results from Boyd, et al (1993)</caption>

      <col align="left" width="14%"/>

      <col align="left" width="14%"/>

      <col align="right" width="14%"/>

      <col align="right" width="14%"/>

      <col align="right" width="14%"/>

      <col align="right" width="14%"/>

      <col align="right" width="14%"/>

      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">Catchment</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Country</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Area</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Impervious Fraction</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">EIA/TA</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">EIA/TIA</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Urban Area (%)</emphasis></th>
        </tr>
      </thead>

      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>Maroubra</td>

          <td>NSW, Australia</td>

          <td>57.3</td>

          <td>52%</td>

          <td>16%</td>

          <td>30%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Strathfield</td>

          <td>NSW, Australia</td>

          <td>234</td>

          <td>50%</td>

          <td>29%</td>

          <td>58%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Jamison Park</td>

          <td>NSW, Australia</td>

          <td>22.1</td>

          <td>36%</td>

          <td>21%</td>

          <td>58%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Fishers Ghost</td>

          <td>NSW, Australia</td>

          <td>226</td>

          <td>36%</td>

          <td>25%</td>

          <td>70%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Giralang</td>

          <td>ACT, Australia</td>

          <td>94</td>

          <td>25%</td>

          <td>35%</td>

          <td>140%</td>

          <td>85%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Long Gully</td>

          <td>ACT, Australia</td>

          <td>490</td>

          <td>5%</td>

          <td>6%</td>

          <td>118%</td>

          <td>16%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Mawson</td>

          <td>ACT, Australia</td>

          <td>445</td>

          <td>26%</td>

          <td>21%</td>

          <td>80%</td>

          <td>86%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Curtin</td>

          <td>ACT, Australia</td>

          <td>2690</td>

          <td>17%</td>

          <td>17%</td>

          <td>102%</td>

          <td>57%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Vine Street</td>

          <td>Vic, Australia</td>

          <td>70</td>

          <td>37%</td>

          <td>31%</td>

          <td>83%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Pompano Beach</td>

          <td>USA</td>

          <td>15.4</td>

          <td>44%</td>

          <td>7%</td>

          <td>16%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Sample Road</td>

          <td>USA</td>

          <td>23.5</td>

          <td>36%</td>

          <td>27%</td>

          <td>74%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Fort Lauderdale</td>

          <td>USA</td>

          <td>7.7</td>

          <td>98%</td>

          <td>96%</td>

          <td>98%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Kings Creek</td>

          <td>USA</td>

          <td>5.26</td>

          <td>71%</td>

          <td>75%</td>

          <td>106%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Gray Haven</td>

          <td>USA</td>

          <td>9.4</td>

          <td>52%</td>

          <td>48%</td>

          <td>93%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Malvern</td>

          <td>Canada</td>

          <td>23.3</td>

          <td>34%</td>

          <td>34%</td>

          <td>99%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>East York</td>

          <td>Canada</td>

          <td>155</td>

          <td>49%</td>

          <td>48%</td>

          <td>98%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Clifton Grove</td>

          <td>UK</td>

          <td>10.6</td>

          <td>40%</td>

          <td>24%</td>

          <td>60%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>St Marks Road</td>

          <td>UK</td>

          <td>10.3</td>

          <td>56%</td>

          <td>30%</td>

          <td>53%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Porsoberg</td>

          <td>Sweden</td>

          <td>13</td>

          <td>40%</td>

          <td>21%</td>

          <td>52%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Munkerisparken</td>

          <td>Denmark</td>

          <td>6.44</td>

          <td>46%</td>

          <td>35%</td>

          <td>76%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Livry Gargan</td>

          <td>France</td>

          <td>235.5</td>

          <td>33%</td>

          <td>17%</td>

          <td>53%</td>

          <td>78%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Miskole</td>

          <td>Hungary</td>

          <td>25.4</td>

          <td>15%</td>

          <td>13%</td>

          <td>89%</td>

          <td>52%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Luzzi</td>

          <td>Italy</td>

          <td>1.73</td>

          <td>85%</td>

          <td>58%</td>

          <td>68%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Vika</td>

          <td>Norway</td>

          <td>10.1</td>

          <td>97%</td>

          <td>65%</td>

          <td>67%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Miljakovic</td>

          <td>Yukoslavia</td>

          <td>25.5</td>

          <td>37%</td>

          <td>20%</td>

          <td>54%</td>

          <td>100%</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Kotta</td>

          <td>Japan</td>

          <td>1281</td>

          <td>23%</td>

          <td>32%</td>

          <td>137%</td>

          <td>84%</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>

    <table frame="void">
      <caption>EIA Initial Loss Estimates from Various Studies</caption>

      <col align="left" width="25%"/>

      <col align="left" width="25%"/>

      <col align="center" width="25%"/>

      <col align="left" width="25%"/>

      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">Catchment</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Region<footnote>
              <para>Regions defined in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_f_blmxc"/></para>
            </footnote></emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Initial Loss Estimate (mm)</emphasis></th>

          <th><emphasis role="bold">Reference</emphasis></th>
        </tr>
      </thead>

      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>Dee Why Creek (NSW)</td>

          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td>Chiew &amp; McMahon (1999)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td rowspan="2"><para>Fishers Ghost Ck (NSW)</para></td>

          <td rowspan="2">East Coast</td>

          <td>0.9</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Ithaca Creek (QLD)</td>

          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>2.8</td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td rowspan="2">Jamison Park (NSW)</td>

          <td rowspan="2">East Coast</td>

          <td>0.8</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td rowspan="2">Maroubra (NSW)</td>

          <td rowspan="2">East Coast</td>

          <td>0.3</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td rowspan="3">Powells Creek (NSW)</td>

          <td rowspan="3">East Coast</td>

          <td>2.6 to 2.9</td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0.7</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Upper Salt Pan Creek (NSW)</td>

          <td>East Coast</td>

          <td>0.8</td>

          <td>Ball &amp; Zaman (1994)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>McArthur Park (NT)</td>

          <td>Monsoonal North</td>

          <td>5.0<footnote>
              <para>Phillips et al (2014) notes that this catchment had a
              large detention basin that may have influenced results</para>
            </footnote></td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td rowspan="2">Curtin (ACT)</td>

          <td rowspan="2">Murray Basin</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td rowspan="3">Giralang (ACT)</td>

          <td rowspan="3">Murray Basin</td>

          <td>1.3 to 1.6</td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0.9</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>3.26</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Long Gully Creek (ACT)</td>

          <td rowspan="2">Murray Basin</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td/>

          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Mawson (ACT)</td>

          <td>Murray Basin</td>

          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Paddocks Catchment (SA)</td>

          <td>South Central SA</td>

          <td>1.3</td>

          <td>Kemp &amp; Limp (1999)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Parra Hills Drain (SA)</td>

          <td>South Central SA</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Argyle Street (TAS)</td>

          <td>South-East Coast</td>

          <td>0.9</td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Blackburn Lake (VIC)</td>

          <td>South-East Coast</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td>Chiew &amp; McMahon (1999)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Elster Creek (VIC)</td>

          <td>South-East Coast</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Kinkora Road (VIC)</td>

          <td>South-East Coast</td>

          <td>2.5</td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td rowspan="2">Vine Street (VIC)</td>

          <td rowspan="2">South-East Coast</td>

          <td>1</td>

          <td>Bufill &amp; Boyd (1992)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>0</td>

          <td>Boyd et al (1993)</td>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>Albany Drain (WA)</td>

          <td>South-West WA</td>

          <td>1.4</td>

          <td>Phillips et al (2014)</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </section>
</chapter>
