<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<chapter version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook>">

     
  <title/>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <section>
      <title>Background</title>

      <para>The safety of people in floods is of major concern in floodplain
      management. Analysis of the circumstances around individual flood
      fatalities, both in Australia and internationally, shows that most flood
      fatalities occur outside of buildings with people either wading or
      driving vehicles through floodwaters (French et al, 1983, Coates and
      Haynes, 2008). While floodplain management activities aim to reduce the
      risk of flooding, ongoing human activity in floods is largely
      unavoidable as significant areas of existing development and transport
      infrastructure in Australia remain flood prone.</para>

      <para>The best contemporary advice from emergency managers is that
      people should completely avoid entering floodwaters. Recent analysis of
      the Queensland floods in 2011 by the Queensland Commission for Children,
      Young People, and Child Guardian (CCYPCG, 2012) and the Queensland Fire
      and Rescue Service, 2012 has reinforced the conclusion that floodwaters
      are extremely dangerous to both people wading and driving vehicles of
      all types in floods.</para>

      <para>Irrespective of this advice, it is apparent that there are
      numerous circumstances and associated human behaviours during flood
      emergencies, which might cause people to either wade or drive into
      floodwaters. Once exposed to flood flows outdoors, the safety of people
      is compromised when flood flow forces exceed their ability to remain
      standing or when the vehicles they are travelling in become unstable by
      becoming buoyant or losing traction.</para>

      <para>It is incumbent on the floodplain management process to reduce the
      risk to life to as low as reasonably practicable. The responsibility for
      floodplain planning in Australia varies with jurisdiction, but generally
      falls to local government. Interpretation of flood data into the
      floodplain planning process is the responsibility of these various
      planning entities. Nationally, guidance for best practice in floodplain
      management is provided by the commonwealth government via the Emergency
      Management Australia publication “Managing the Floodplain: A Guide to
      best Practice in Floodplain Risk Management in Australia” (NFRAG, 2012).
      While NFRAG (2012) references The Engineers Australia “Australian
      Rainfall and Runoff Guidelines” (ARR) methods and techniques, ARR itself
      does not provide direct guidance for floodplain planning or
      management.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Defining Flood Risk (after NFRAG, 2012)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="444"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Fig%201-1%20NFRAG%20flood%20risk.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Use of this Report</title>

      <para>This report provides advice on the interpretation of flow
      behaviour as a flood hazard in respect of people and vehicle safety on
      floodplains. In this regard, the report is useful for the assessment of
      the consequences or impacts of flood when assessing aspects of flood
      risk, as illustrated in Figure 1 1.</para>

      <para>This report provides information to assist with the interpretation
      of flood data where floodwaters interact with people and vehicles. The
      specific scope of this report is to:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Prepare examples illustrating the assessment of hazard for
          people and vehicles using the information presented in the ARR
          revision Project 10 reports (Cox et al., 2010, Shand et al., 2011)
          prepared by WRL, UNSW; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Preparation of figures, suitable for inclusion in ARR that
          will provide information suitable for assessment of the hazard to
          people and vehicles during flood events.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Flood Hazard</title>

    <para>Hazard can be defined as a source of potential harm or a situation
    with potential to cause loss. In relation to floodplain management, the
    hazard is flooding which has the potential to cause damage or harm to the
    community. Flood hazard needs to be assessed by taking into account a
    range of factors. The usual starting point in a flood hazard assessment is
    to quantify the hazard provisionally by mapping the area inundated and the
    flow behaviour characteristics within the inundation area. The flow
    behaviour characteristics are typically parameterised by the flood depth
    (d) and velocity (v) which can be unified into a single hazard parameter
    by the product of the variables (v*d).</para>

    <para>Ultimately the flood hazard assessment needs to take into account a
    range of other social, economic and environmental factors, though these
    are often more difficult to quantify. Additional factors that can add to
    the provisional hazard and need consideration to ascertain the flood
    hazard beyond the provisional estimate are:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Effective warning time;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Rate of rise of floodwaters;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Duration of flooding;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Evacuation problems;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Isolation from flood free land;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Effective flood access;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Type of development; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Community flood awareness;</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section>
      <title>Flood Hazard Assessment</title>

      <section>
        <title>How is Provisional Flood Hazard Assessed?</title>

        <para>The baseline datasets that underpin floodplain risk management
        studies are typically developed using numerical floodplain models (see
        Figure 2 1). Contemporary flood plain models are usually a two
        dimensional (in plan), depth averaged representation of floodplain
        flows. The model outputs are typically maps of flood depth (see Figure
        2 1 b) and flood velocity (speed and direction), which can be
        interpreted into maps of flood surface level and flow (discharge)
        distribution across a floodplain. These maps are typically available
        as a time series of flow behaviour for the duration of a flood event,
        but presentation in reports is generally as enveloped maxima.</para>

        <para>The accuracy of the representation of flow behaviour in the
        model is reliant on the availability and accuracy of the input data,
        the availability of suitable calibration data for historical flood
        events for calibration and verification of the model and the skill of
        the model operator. Project 15 of ARR (EA 2012) provides best practice
        advice on the preparation of numerical models.</para>

        <para>Smith and Wasko (2012) completed a review of numerical flood
        modelling techniques in urban environments as part of the review of
        ARR. This study compared numerical model outputs against a calibrated
        physical model of part of the Merewether Heights floodplain in
        Newcastle, which was seriously affected by flash flooding in June
        2007. Smith and Wasko (2012) concluded that:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Correctly applied, numerical models provided an adequate
            representation of flood surface levels and flood inundation
            extents for setting Flood Planning Levels;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>When modelled at a suitable resolution, numerical models
            provided a reasonable representation of flow distributions through
            the floodplain;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Numerical models sometimes under-estimated flow velocities
            in complex urban environments including under-estimation of flow
            speeds between and around buildings;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Provisional flood hazard estimates (v*d) in urban
            environments could be underestimated by numerical models,
            particularly if the model spatial resolution was not
            adequate.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <figure>
          <title>Example of a Flood Study Depth Map (after Smith and Wasko,
          2012)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/11029-1.2%20With%20Houses_2.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>a) Physical model</para>

        <figure>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentwidth="294"
                         fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/1m_buildings%20as%20ds%20wall.bmp"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>b) Numerical Model – Depth Map</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Example of a Flood Study Depth Map (after Smith and Wasko,
        2012)</title>

        <para>Figure 2 2 compares provisional flood hazard (v*d) estimates at
        two model grid resolutions, 1 m and 10 m, for the Merewether model for
        the 2007 flood event. The figure shows that at the 1 m grid
        resolution, which best matched the flood velocity and flow
        distributions of the physical model (Figure 2 1a), the flood hazard
        estimates are significantly higher than at the 10 m grid
        resolution.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Comparison of Provisional Flood Hazard Estimates from
          Numerical Models at Differing Grid Resolutions (after Smith and
          Wasko, 2012)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentwidth="239"
                         fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/MIKE21_obstacles+eddyp1_1m.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>a) 1 m grid resolution</para>

        <figure>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentwidth="255"
                         fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/MIKE21_obstacles_10m.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>b) 10 m grid resolution</para>

        <para>An important conclusion of the Smith and Wasko (2012) study was
        that 2D numerical model outputs might require further interpretation
        in order to ensure that suitable, representative, flood behaviour
        information was being applied in planning and management
        decisions.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>People Stability</title>

      <para>The two recognised hydrodynamic mechanisms by which people may
      lose stability in flood flows include moment instability and friction
      instability (refer Figure 2 3). Cox et al. (2010) presents more
      comprehensive discussion, but in brief, moment (toppling) instability
      occurs when a moment induced by the oncoming flow exceeds the resisting
      moment generated by the weight of the body (Abt et al., 1989). This
      stability parameter is sensitive to the buoyancy of a person within a
      flow and to body positioning and weight distribution. Frictional
      (sliding) instability occurs when the drag force induced by the
      horizontal flow impacting on the legs and torso is larger than the
      frictional resistance between a person’s feet and the ground surface.
      This stability parameter is sensitive to weight and buoyancy, clothing
      type, footwear type and ground surface conditions.</para>

      <para>Additionally, loss of stability may also triggered by adverse
      conditions, which should be taken into account when assessing safety
      such as:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Bottom conditions</emphasis>: uneven,
          slippery, obstacles;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Flow conditions</emphasis>: floating
          debris, low temperature, poor visibility, unsteady flow and flow
          aeration;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Human subject</emphasis>: standing or
          moving, experience and training, clothing and footwear, physical
          attributes additional to height and mass including muscular
          development and/or other disability, psychological factors;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Other issues</emphasis>: strong wind,
          poor lighting, etc.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure>
        <title>Typical modes of Human Instability in Floods (after Cox et al,
        2010)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="380"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure2_Human%20Stability%20Failure%20Modes.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Determining safety criteria for people requires an understanding
      of the physical characteristics of the subjects along with the nature of
      the flow (Figure 2 3):</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The measure of physical attributes for human stability
          analysis is best represented by the parameter H.M (mkg), the product
          of subject height (H; m) and mass (M; kg) (Cox et al., 2010);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The measure of flow attributes for human stability analysis is
          D.V (m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)
          value, determined as the product of flow depth (D, m) and flow
          velocity (V, ms<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>While distinct relationships exist between a subject’s height and
      mass and the tolerable flow value, definition of general flood flow
      safety guidelines according to this relationship is not considered
      practical given the wide range in such characteristics within the
      population.</para>

      <para>In order to define safety limits, which are applicable for all
      persons, hazard regimes are defined based on H.M for representative
      demographics. Each classification is based on laboratory testing of
      subject stability within floodwaters. The following suggested
      classifications are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Adults, where H.M &gt; 50 mkg;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Children, where H.M = 25 to 50 mkg; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Infants and very young children, where H.M &lt; 25 mkg. (Cox
          et al., 2010)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Several hazard regimes are recommended based on D.V flow values
      for each H.M classification. The hazard regimes as suggested from
      laboratory testing of subject stability and response within variable
      flow conditions are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Low hazard zones where D.V &lt; 0.4
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          children and D.V &lt; 0.6
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          adults;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A Significant hazard zone for children exists where flow
          conditions are dangerous to most between D.V = 0.4 to 0.6
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Moderate hazard zone where conditions are dangerous for some
          adults and all children is defined between D.V = 0.6 to 0.8
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          adults. This is inferred to define the limiting working flow for
          experienced personnel such as trained rescue workers;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Significant hazard zone where flow conditions are dangerous to
          most adults and extremely dangerous for all children is suggested
          between flow values of D.V = 0.8 to 1.2
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>;
          and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Extreme hazard where flow conditions are dangerous to all
          people is suggested for D.V &gt; 1.2
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Recent research (Cox et al., 2010) concludes that self-evacuation
      of the most vulnerable people in the community (small children and the
      elderly) will be limited by relatively placid flow conditions. D.V as
      low as 0.4 m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>
      would prove problematic for those most vulnerable in the
      community.</para>

      <para>The hazard regimes for tolerable flow (D.V) as related to physical
      subject presence (H.M) are presented in Figure 2 4 and Table 1.</para>

      <table>
        <title>Flow Hazard Regimes for People (Cox et al, 2010)</title>

        <tgroup cols="4">
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>DV
              (m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</entry>

              <entry>Infants, small children (H.M ≤ 25) and frail/older
              persons</entry>

              <entry>Children (H.M = 25 to 50)</entry>

              <entry>Adults (H.M &gt; 50)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0</entry>

              <entry>Safe</entry>

              <entry>Safe</entry>

              <entry>Safe</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0 – 0.4</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Low Hazard</entry>

              <entry>Low Hazard</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.4 – 0.6</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Significant Hazard; Dangerous to most</entry>

              <entry>Low Hazard<superscript>1</superscript></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.6 – 0.8</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Moderate Hazard; Dangerous to
              some<superscript>2</superscript></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0.8 – 1.2</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Significant Hazard; Dangerous to
              most<superscript>3</superscript></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 1.2</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>

              <entry>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>

      <para><superscript>1</superscript>Stability uncompromised for persons
      within laboratory testing program at these flows (to maximum flow depth
      of 0.5 m for children and 1.2 m for adults and a maximum velocity of 3.0
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript> at shallow depths).</para>

      <para><superscript>2</superscript>Working limit for trained safety
      workers or experienced and well equipped persons (D.V &lt; 0.8
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para><superscript>3</superscript>Upper limit of stability observed
      during most investigations (D.V &gt; 1.2
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Safety Criteria for People in Variable Flow Conditions (After
        Cox et al, 2010)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%202.4.JPG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <section>
        <title>Physical considerations</title>

        <para>There is a lack of test data for infants and very young children
        as well as frail/older persons (Cox et al., 2004). These populations
        are unlikely to be safe in any flow regimes and as such, care is
        required in locating aged care and retirement villages as well as
        childcare centres and kindergartens.</para>

        <para>For physically and/or mentally disabled people, a similar
        intolerance criteria to the very young children and frail/older
        persons should be applied as subjects are considered vulnerable to all
        flow values. This is because while the H.M values may be similar to
        regular adults, they are clearly at a physical (e.g. muscular
        development, control of limbs) and/or psychological disadvantage
        (e.g., cognisant of the real/perceived danger, inability to cope with
        external stimulus).</para>

        <para>Emergency personnel tasked with carrying evacuees should be
        aware that the additional H.M gained by carrying a person is not
        necessarily a benefit to their stability. This was demonstrated in a
        particular laboratory test of human stability criteria, Jonkman and
        Penning-Rowsell (2008) who note that their test subject (a trained
        stuntman) considered balancing in the flowing water more difficult
        when carrying extra weight such as a child or elderly person.</para>

        <para>It should also be noted that while these criteria are based on
        experimental data for loss of stability for persons wading in
        floodwaters, it is also inherently dangerous to swim through
        floodwaters. Swimming through floodwaters should not be
        attempted.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Psychological/behavioural considerations</title>

        <para>A person’s ability to withstand flood flows is affected by their
        mental disposition, perception, specific training and
        experience.</para>

        <para>Where specific training has been undertaken or a subject has
        recent and relevant experience, personnel are able to tolerate
        situations of high D.V (Jonkman and Penning-Rowsell, 2008). A limiting
        working flow of D.V = 0.8
        m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> is
        suggested for experienced personnel such as trained rescue workers.
        These personnel should, where possible, be equipped for dangerous flow
        conditions with safety restraints, floatation aids and other safety
        apparatus, and be trained to cope with high D.V situations. It is
        trained emergency personnel who are likely to be instructing, driving
        and guiding evacuation paths, and consequently to whom the upper limit
        of safety design criteria is directed.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Vehicle stability</title>

      <para>The two recognised hydrodynamic mechanisms by which stability of
      vehicles is lost include buoyancy or floating and friction instability
      or sliding instability (refer Figure 2 5). More comprehensive discussion
      is presented within Shand et al. (2011) but briefly, vehicle floating
      instability occurs when the upward buoyancy force exceeds the downward
      force exerted by the vehicle mass. This instability is dominant in low
      velocity, high depth flows. Frictional or sliding instability occurs
      when the horizontal force exerted on one or more car panels is greater
      than the vertical restoring force, which is dependent on the vehicle
      mass, buoyancy and the friction between the car tyres and road
      surface.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Typical Modes of Vehicle Instability (after Shand et al,
        2011)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="476"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Typical%20modes%20of%20Vehicle%20Instability.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Note that in the context of this discussion friction instability
      is associated with slow moving or stationary cars as distinct to
      hydroplaning, which occurs when a vehicle at high speed encounters very
      shallow, evenly distributed water covering a road, typically a highway
      or freeway. Hydroplaning is not considered further within this
      report.</para>

      <para>Determining safety criteria for vehicles requires an understanding
      of the physical characteristics of the vehicle along with the nature of
      the flow (Figure 2 5).</para>

      <para>The measure of physical attributes for vehicle stability analysis
      is the vehicle classification as based on length (L, m), kerb weight (W,
      kg) and ground clearance (GC, m). Three vehicle classifications are
      suggested:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger: L &lt; 4.3 m, W &lt; 1250 kg, GC &lt; 0.12
          m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger: L &gt; 4.3 m, W &gt; 1250 kg, GC &gt; 0.12
          m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD: L &gt; 4.5 m, W &gt; 2000, GC &gt; 0.22 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The measure of flow attributes for vehicle stability analysis is
      D.V m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>,
      determined as the product of flow depth (D, m) and flow velocity (V,
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para>Limiting conditions exist for each classification based on
      laboratory testing of characteristic vehicles. The upper tolerable
      velocity for moving water is defined based on the frictional limits, and
      is a constant 3.0 ms<superscript>-1</superscript> for all vehicle
      classifications.</para>

      <para>The upper tolerable depths within still water are defined by the
      floating limits:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger vehicles: 0.3 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger vehicles: 0.4 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD vehicles: 0.5 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The upper tolerable depths within high velocity water (at 3.0
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript>) are defined by the frictional
      limits:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger vehicles: 0.1 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger vehicles: 0.15 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD vehicles: 0.2 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>While specifically equipped vehicles may remain stable in water of
      greater depths, the intention of the presented criteria is to focus on
      the more vulnerable of typical vehicle types in common use.</para>

      <para>Note that for all flow conditions in all vehicle classes, the
      proposed vehicle safety criteria remain below the moderate hazard
      criteria for adults (Cox et al., 2010). This ensures that adults
      occupying vehicles are, in principle, safe if exiting a vehicle in
      floodwaters with attributes within the specified hazard ranges.</para>

      <para>During flood events, the majority of flood deaths are vehicle
      related, more than half of all deaths during floods in the United States
      are vehicular-related (Gruntfest and Ripps, 2000). Regardless of how
      often people see the power of water in flash floods or are notified
      through community advertising that driving through high water is
      dangerous, there remain sections of the community who will continue with
      ‘business as usual’ irrespective of the flooding conditions (Gruntfest
      and Ripps, 2000).</para>

      <section>
        <title>Vehicle modernisation and scale</title>

        <para>A limiting aspect of the advice provided in this report is that
        vehicle stability data sets are limited to dated laboratory data
        (Shand et al., 2011). The properties of contemporary vehicles have
        significantly changed vehicle stability criteria through modified
        buoyancy properties (e.g. improve dust sealing), weight and ground
        clearance. These changes apply to all scales of vehicles from small
        passenger to large commercial vehicles.</para>

        <para>As a result, the hazard criteria provided in this report are
        identified as interim recommended limits based on interpretation of
        existing information. The criteria presented here are subject to
        change once acceptable data for modern vehicles becomes
        available.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Stability Criteria for Vehicles</title>

        <para>Stability criteria based on the best available information for
        stationary small passenger cars, large passenger cars and large 4WD
        vehicles in various flow situations are presented in Figure 2 6 and
        Table 2.</para>

        <table>
          <title>Interim Flow Hazard Regimes for Vehicles (Shand et al,
          2011)</title>

          <tgroup cols="8">
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Class of
                vehicle</emphasis></entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Length (m)</emphasis></entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Kerb Weight
                (kg)</emphasis></entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Ground clearance
                (m)</emphasis></entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Limiting still water
                depth<superscript>1</superscript></emphasis></entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Limiting high velocity flow
                depth<superscript>2</superscript></emphasis></entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Limiting
                velocity<superscript>3</superscript></emphasis></entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Equation of
                stability</emphasis></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Small
                passenger</emphasis></entry>

                <entry>&lt; 4.3</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 1250</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 0.12</entry>

                <entry>0.3</entry>

                <entry>0.1</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry>DV</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Large
                passenger</emphasis></entry>

                <entry>&gt; 4.3</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 1250</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 0.12</entry>

                <entry>0.4</entry>

                <entry>0.15</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry>DV</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Large 4WD</emphasis></entry>

                <entry>&gt; 4.5</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 2000</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 0.22</entry>

                <entry>0.5</entry>

                <entry>0.2</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry>DV</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>

        <para><superscript>1</superscript>At velocity = 0
        ms<superscript>-1</superscript>; <superscript>2</superscript>At
        velocity = 3.0
        ms<superscript>-1</superscript>;<superscript>3</superscript>At low
        depth.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Interim Safety Criteria for Vehicles in Variable Flow
          Conditions (After Shand et al, 2011)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentwidth="835"
                         fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%202.6.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>and et al (2011) concludes that the available datasets do not
        adequately account for the following factors and that more research
        may be needed in these areas:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Friction coefficients for contemporary vehicle tyres in
            flood flows;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Buoyancy changes in modern cars;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The effect of vehicle orientation to flow direction
            (including vehicle movement);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Information for additional categories including small and
            large commercial vehicles and emergency service vehicles;</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Hazard Assessment for Floodplain Management and Planning</title>

    <para>This section provides practical examples of the interpretation of
    flood hazard criteria for people and vehicle stability in a floodplain
    management context. The examples are not intended to be a comprehensive
    analysis of all possible circumstances, rather provide representative case
    studies, which illustrate the practical interpretation of flood hazard
    criteria in floodplain planning and management.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Example - Warehouse Car Park</title>

      <para>A large multinational retailer has identified an existing
      industrial area in an inner city suburb as a suitable site for
      re-development as a warehouse-style retail outlet. The site is gently
      sloping from the northwest to the southeast and, having been previously
      prepared for development, is clear of vegetation. An aging,
      concrete-lined channel runs along the eastern side of the site.</para>

      <para>The retailer has submitted a development application, illustrated
      in Figure 3 1, which conceptually has a warehouse building situated in
      the northeast corner of the site with the area between the building and
      the concrete-lined channel earmarked as a car park.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Schematic of Proposed Warehouse Development</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="335"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203-1%20Carpark%20Depth%20Map_cars.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The local council as the consent authority has identified a series
      of development constraints including flooding criteria. Amongst other
      criteria, the development must have:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>All retail floor space above the designated flood planning
          level defined as the 1% Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP) flood
          surface plus 500mm freeboard;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A flood free evacuation route for floods above the flood
          planning level; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>All car park areas compliant with ARR flood hazard criteria
          for vehicle stability;</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>As there was no existing flood study, following consultation with
      Council, the developer engaged an experienced flood consultant to
      undertake flood modelling of the site to estimate 1% AEP flood
      behaviour. Flood modelling of the site for the 1% AEP event completed
      using industry best practice guidance as provided by ARR reference “Two
      Dimensional Modelling in Urban and Rural Floodplains” (EA 2012)
      predicted that while the warehouse building met the flood planning
      criteria, the car park was inundated by floodwaters. Figure 3 2
      illustrates the extent of flood inundation for the existing site.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth Map – Existing Site</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="443"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203_2%20Carpark%20Depth%20Map_cars.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Interrogation of the flood model results to determine provisional
      flood hazard as the product of flood depth (D) multiplied by flood
      velocity (V) showed that the peak flood hazard (D.V) corresponded with
      the maximum inundation of the site at the peak of the flood hydrograph.
      Provisional flood hazard for the 1% AEP flood on the existing site as
      illustrated by Figure 3 3 showed that flooding in most of the area
      identified for car parking exceeds the ARR stability criteria for small
      cars defined in Table 2 and illustrated in Figure 2 6. In Figure 3 3
      areas coloured blue indicate locations where small cars are likely to
      resist being moved by flood flows, whereas areas coloured green through
      red indicate areas where small cars are very likely to be pushed across
      the floodplain by floodwaters, with the flow having the potential to
      move larger cars closer to the creek channel.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Existing Car Park</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="515"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203_3%20Carpark%20Hazard.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>As the concrete lined channel had low environmental value, Council
      was not opposed to the developer’s proposed adjustment of the channel
      flow conveyance capacity to reduce the proportion of overbank flow at
      the site. The developer, in consultation with the flood consultant ran a
      range of cut and fill scenarios through the flood model aimed at
      expanding the channel capacity while raising the relative ground level
      of the car park to the flood peak. Figure 3 4 shows the adjustment of
      the channel and overbank area through the car park on the longitudinal
      section identified as ‘A-A’ in Figure 3 1.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Comparison of Car Park Cross Sections (A-A)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="459"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Fig%203-4%20Cross%20Section.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>This section is representative of a balance between the minimum
      volume of earthworks to meet the car parking capacity criteria for the
      development. The car park area adjacent to section A-A was graded to
      meet the natural surface areas outside of the development site. Flood
      modelling for the revised site including the proposed earthworks is
      presented in Figure 3 5. The flood model results show that the site
      inundation area is significantly reduced.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth Map – Revised Carpark</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="449"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203_5%20Carpark%20Depth%20Map%20Fixed.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Importantly, analysis of the provisional flood hazard as presented
      in Figure 3 6 shows that flood hazard for the area designated as car
      park in the conceptual site design now meets the ARR flood stability
      criteria for small vehicles. It is now unlikely that cars inundated by
      floodwaters in the 1% AEP flood will be pushed across the floodplain and
      potentially into the channel creating a possible downstream blockage
      hazard.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Revised Car Park</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="527"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203_6%20Carpark%20Hazard%20Fixed.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Example - Detention Basin</title>

      <para>Council’s conditions of consent for a proposed retirement village
      development require that on-site detention be provided so that peak
      flows from the site in floods up to the 1% AEP event remain similar to
      existing local runoff conditions.</para>

      <para>The developer considers that a centralised detention basin on the
      site can be designed to have a dual use and integrated into the site
      grounds as a bowling green when not operating as a detention basin.
      Figure 3 7 illustrates the proposed design.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth - Proposed Flood Detention Basin</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="525"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203-7.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>As the catchment contributing runoff to the site is steep,
      Council’s flood expert considers that there is some risk in a dual
      purpose design for the basin due to flash flooding in prevailing
      thunderstorms. Council’s advice is that the developer engage a qualified
      flood expert to determine whether the basin meets the ARR hazard
      criteria for people safety.</para>

      <para>The basin design philosophy is that the local catchment stormwater
      will collect both overland flows and also surcharge from the pit and
      pipe stormwater system. If the basin capacity is exceeded, flows spill
      at a designated location and flow overland to the adjacent creek
      channel. Flows that remain in the basin discharge through a grated pit
      in the lowest location in the basin floor.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map - Proposed Flood Detention
        Basin</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="507"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203-8%20Basin%20Depth%20Map.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>An assessment of the provisional flood hazard (flood depth
      multiplied by the flood velocity) is presented in Figure 3 8. When
      compared to flood hazard criteria presented in Table 1 and Figure 2 4
      the provisional hazard meets the safety criteria for the elderly in most
      areas of the basin. This is because at full capacity, the basin is no
      greater than 0.5m deep. Analysis shows that a dangerous flood hazard is
      likely to occur near to the basin’s outlet pit when the basin begins to
      drain at full capacity.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Basin Overflow Spillway – Flood Depth</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="467"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203_9.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Further analysis of the full design presented in Figure 3 9 shows
      that when the basin capacity is exceeded overflows will cross a public
      footpath adjacent the creek reserve. Provisional flood hazard analysis
      of the overflow path presented in Figure 3 10 shows that the flood
      hazard in the flow path will exceed the people stability criteria for
      adults and be a dangerous hazard to passing pedestrians.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Basin Overflow Spillway</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="451"
                       fileref="file:/J:/Jobs/28060/Project_10/doc_figures/Figure%203_10%20Basin%20Spill%20Hazard.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>As a result of the analysis, Council consent criteria require
      signage to be placed in appropriate locations informing residents of the
      retirement village and the public passing the site on the public
      footpath of the dual purpose use of the basin and the danger of entering
      floodwaters when the basin is inundated. Further, Council’s consent
      criteria require that the developer upgrade the footpath to include a
      bridge of suitable span over the basin spillway flow path so that safe
      thoroughfare of the footpath can be maintained during flood
      conditions.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusions and Recommendations</title>

    <para>Recent flood events on the east coast of Australia in 2010 and 2011
    have highlighted that people continue to be exposed to dangerous and life
    threatening flow conditions in urban and rural floodplains. While
    floodplain management activities are continually decreasing the
    community’s exposure to floodwaters, ongoing human activity in floods is
    largely unavoidable while significant areas of existing development and
    transport infrastructure in Australia remain flood prone.</para>

    <para>This report has summarised and explained limitations of recent
    analysis of flood stability thresholds for pedestrians and vehicles in
    floodwaters. Proposed flood hazard criteria based on the stability of
    people and vehicles in flood flows as described by recent reports for
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff have been summarised.</para>

    <para>The presented floodplain management examples demonstrate the
    practical application of the criteria. While not exhaustive of all cases,
    the examples show how the criteria can be pragmatically applied to reduce
    the community’s exposure to flood danger.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Recommendations</title>

      <para>The flood hazard criteria provided in this report are interim as
      they are based on limited and dated information. This report should be
      updated immediately on the availability of improved vehicle stability
      criteria based on testing of contemporary vehicles. This being the case,
      users of this report should ensure that they are using the most up to
      date information.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Abt, S.R, Wittler, R.J, Taylor, A and Love, DJ. (1989). Human
    Stability in a High Flood Hazard Zone, <emphasis>Water Resources
    Bulletin</emphasis>, American Water Resources Association, 25 (4), pp
    881-890.</para>

    <para>Coates, L and Haynes, K (2008), Flash flood shelter-in-place vs.
    evacuation research: <emphasis>Flash flood fatalities within Australia,
    1950 – 2008</emphasis>. Report prepared for the New South Wales State
    Emergency Service.</para>

    <para>Cox, R.J., Yee, M. and Ball, J.E. (2004). Safety of People in
    Flooded Streets and Floodways. <emphasis>8th National Conference on
    Hydraulics in Water Engineering, Gold Coast.</emphasis> The Institution of
    Engineers, Australia.</para>

    <para>Cox, R J, Shand, T D and Blacka, M J (2010), “Appropriate Safety
    Criteria for People in Floods”, <emphasis>WRL Research Report
    240.</emphasis> Report for Institution of Engineers Australia, Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff Guidelines: Project 10. 22p.</para>

    <para>Engineers Australia, 2012. “Two Dimensional Modelling in Urban and
    Rural Floodplains”. Project 15, Mark Babister, editor.</para>

    <para>French J, Ing, R, Von Allmen, S and Wood, R (1983),
    <emphasis>“Mortality from Flash Floods: a Review of National Weather
    Service Reports, 1969-81.”</emphasis> Public Health Reports: Nov-Dec 1983,
    98(6), pp.584-588.</para>

    <para>Gruntfest, E, and Ripps, A (2000), Flash floods: warning and
    mitigation efforts and prospects. In: Parker, D.J. (Ed.), Floods, vol. 1.
    Routledge, London, pp. 377–390.</para>

    <para>Jonkman, S.N. and Penning-Rowsell, E. (2008). Human Instability in
    Flood Flows. Journal of the American Water Resources Association, Vol. 44,
    No. 4, pp 1 – 11.</para>

    <para>National Flood Risk Advisory Group (NFRAG), 2012. “Managing the
    Floodplain: A Guide to best Practice in Floodplain Risk Management in
    Australia”. Consultation Draft.</para>

    <para>Queensland Commission for Children, Young People, and Child Guardian
    (CCYPCG), 2012.
    https://www.fire.qld.gov.au/communitysafety/swiftwater/default.asp -
    accessed 11 August 2012</para>

    <para>Queensland Fire and Rescue Service, (QFRS) 2012
    https://www.fire.qld.gov.au/communitysafety/swiftwater/default.asp,
    accessed 11 August 2012.</para>

    <para>Shand, T D, Cox, R J, Blacka, M J and Smith G P (2011), “Appropriate
    Safety Criteria for Vehicles – Literature Review”. AR&amp;R Report Number:
    P10/S2/020. Report for Institution of Engineers Australia, Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff Guidelines: Project 10. ISBN 978-0-85825-948-5.</para>

    <para>Smith G P, and Wasko C D, (2012), <emphasis>Two Dimensional
    Simulations in Urban Areas: Representation of Buildings In 2d Numerical
    Flood Models.</emphasis> Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project
    15. Final Report, February 2012.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
