<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="b9_ch6" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
  xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
  xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" 
  xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
  xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" status="In Preparation">
  <info>
  <title>Modelling Approaches</title>
  
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/coombes_peter.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/roso_steve.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/> 
 </info>
  
  <para>The authors collaborated with Mikayla Ward and Sophia Buchanan to produce the Brownfield and
    Greenfield case studies.</para>
  
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T123738+1100"?>04<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T123736+1100" content="12"?>/<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T123740+1100"?>12<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T123739+1100" content="07"?>/<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T123741+1100" content="20"?>18
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Final<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T123729+1100"?>
        draft<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T123659+1100"?>No significant
        changes expected<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_7rxla">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Urban stormwater management responds to an increasing number of performance objectives
      including to mitigate property damage, avoid risks to human life, enhance the amenity of urban
      settlements<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T110044+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and protect surrounding environments (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3_s_84gfv"/> and <xref
        linkend="b9_ch5_s_j339y"/>). This involves consideration of the full spectrum of rain
      events<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T110429+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      from frequent to rare (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"
      />)<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T110433+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      from the perspective of flooding, water quality, provision of infrastructure, protection of
      environments<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T110604+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and enhancing amenity of urban areas. The assessment of urban stormwater behaviour,
      performance against objectives and associated design tasks, involves complex analytical
      problems that are better resolved using a computer-based model system.
      <?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T111325+1000" type="split"?></para>
    <para><?oxy_insert_end?>A computer model
      <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T111333+1000" content="typically "?>involves
      use of software or a complex spreadsheet. Compared with hand calculation, computer models
      permit rapid numerical calculation across large spatial and temporal domains, while
      facilitating testing of multiple suites of parameters and inputs (refer <xref
        linkend="b9_ch3_s_34r7g"/>). This in turn allows the model to be calibrated to best
      represent the real world conditions that are under assessment. Models can be a useful tool to
      assist our thinking, and can be readily documented and reviewed, ultimately leading to better
      assessments and design outcomes. </para>
    <para>Reliable estimates are nevertheless conditional upon best practice application of the
      computer model. It is important to remember that models are only tools to guide our thinking
      about design and management. The purpose of this chapter is to provide guidance on the
      selection and application of modelling approaches within urban catchments, having regard to
      the techniques described in other books of ARR. The chapter is structured as follows:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_2lxrp"/> describes tasks that are characteristic of urban
          modelling. </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_rfr2v"/> discusses current trends in urban modelling. This may
          assist with planning a long-term strategy for technology adoption,
          research<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T112431+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          and training. A general description of the types of computer models commonly applied in
          urban stormwater practice is provided as an aid for model selection.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_cj3nx"/> provides a framework for application of computer
          models to urban stormwater catchments. This discussion includes guidance for each segment
          of the catchment, from the watershed, through the urban stormwater network, and into the
          receiving waterway.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>This chapter is not intended to duplicate content in other chapters. Where relevant detail
      is available elsewhere, references to
      <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T112625+1000" content="these "?>other books
      and chapters are provided.</para>
    <para>In the context of this chapter, an ‘urban model’ can be defined as a conceptual or
      computer-based modelling system that performs hydrologic, hydraulic, water
      balance<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T112638+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      or water quality calculations, across a catchment significantly disturbed by urban development
      and associated infrastructure. This modelling system may operate across all the significant
      scales of urban areas from allotment to neighbourhood to precinct to region. Urban
      infrastructure of most direct relevance includes increased impervious surfaces, modification
      to natural conveyance areas (e.g. pits,
      pipes<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T112827+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and open
      channels)<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T112829+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and volume management infrastructure (e.g. rainwater tanks,
      bio<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T112834+1000" content="-"?>retention<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T112836+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and basins). </para>
    <para>Emerging urban stormwater analysis and solutions are based on a systems approach that
      incorporates multiple linked scales (<xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). The
        <citation>b9_c3_r49+1</citation> highlights that past practice of designing individual items
      of stormwater infrastructure at a single centralised scale has been inadequate for managing
      urban flooding and water quality in waterways. Stormwater management needs to be designed as a
      system that integrates structural and non-structural attributes of design with site
      characteristics and performance objectives.
      <?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T113418+1000" type="split"?></para>
    <para><?oxy_insert_end?>More recently, the USEPA established that green infrastructure solutions
      distributed at multiple scales throughout urban catchments partially disconnected impervious
      surfaces. They also contributed to improved stormwater quality and avoided flood damages
        <citation>b9_c6_r2</citation>. These insights are consistent with earlier Australian applied
      research finding that both the peak flows and volumes of stormwater runoff are required for
      the design of stormwater infrastructure <citation>b9_c3_r54</citation>, and the local scale
      was the basic building block of cumulative urban rainfall runoff processes
        <citation>b5_c3_r31</citation>.
      <?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T114434+1000" type="split"?></para>
    <para><?oxy_insert_end?>Many methods for modelling stormwater runoff are based on regional scale
      assumptions and processes. However, inclusion of local scale processes in analysis improves
      knowledge of within catchment outcomes and whole of catchment responses. </para>
    <para>It is suggested that a catchment with less than 10 percent impervious surfaces, or with
      less than 10 percent of the natural conveyance areas modified, would not be considered an
      ‘urban catchment’. In which case, the advice in this chapter may have less relevance. However,
      each catchment is different, some natural or rural catchments contain sub-catchments that are
      urbanised (for example, in semi-urban areas). The relevance of this chapter to a specific
      modelling investigation needs to be determined by the reader through application of judgement
      and experience. </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_2lxrp">
    <title>Urban Modelling Tasks</title>
    <para>Typical urban modelling tasks are introduced in this section to establish context for
      subsequent discussion. In particular this section focusses on those modelling tasks that are
      not typically required when modelling rural and natural catchments. This section should be
      read in conjunction with <xref linkend="book5"/>, <xref linkend="book6"/> and <xref
        linkend="book7"/> where the reader can find information about modelling tasks and
      assumptions that are common across all catchment types (i.e. urban, semi-rural,
      rural<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160548+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and natural).</para>
    <para>There are some important differences between modelling of urban catchments compared with
      modelling other types of catchments. Urban areas can include: </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>A larger proportion of impervious surfaces (refer <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_tojzw"
          />).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Stormwater conveyance infrastructure. This includes a network of inlet structures and
          non-natural flow paths that provide for greater concentrations and velocities of flow
          (refer <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_0k1v3"/>).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Numerous hydraulic structures. This includes infrastructure for waterway crossings,
          temporary storage of volume, water harvesting and treatment of runoff (refer <xref
            linkend="b9_ch6_s_9pjt4"/>, <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_y9jk6"/> and <xref
            linkend="b9_ch6_s_5envo"/>).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A greater variety of land uses at different scales with different connectivity to
          catchment outlets (refer <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_cj3nx"/>)</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>The density of land uses and associated infrastructure within an urban catchment also
      changes with time. The urban modelling process must therefore consider the information needs
      of the stakeholder and ensure the temporal scenarios being modelled are relevant.</para>
    <para>There are also differences relating to the availability and use of model input data.
      Modelling in urban areas has intensive requirements related to representation of urban form,
      land
      uses<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T120732+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and stormwater infrastructure.
      <?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T120741+1000"?>Therefore,
      <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T120745+1000" content="C"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T120746+1000"?>c<?oxy_insert_end?>ollection
      and collation of input data can
      <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T120749+1000" content="therefore "?>become
      a significant component of the overall urban modelling task (refer <xref
        linkend="b9_ch6_s_mxsz7"/>).</para>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_tojzw">
      <title>Impervious Surface Estimation</title>
      <para>One of the defining characteristics of an urban catchment is the presence of impervious
        surfaces such as roads, buildings,
        footpaths<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T121039+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and driveways. These surfaces have an associated reduced infiltration loss and decreased lag
        in hydrologic response in comparison to pervious surfaces (i.e. landscaping, lawns, open
        space) or natural catchments. <xref linkend="b4ch2_s_0hsvn"/> provides further discussion of
        the effects of impervious cover on runoff from urban areas.</para>
      <para>Hydrologic modelling of urban areas requires an estimate of the proportion of impervious
        surfaces across each catchment and sub-catchment to be modelled. As described in <xref
          linkend="book5"/>, there are two main types of impervious surfaces that exist within urban
        areas:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Impervious areas which are directly connected to the conveyance network or urban
            waterway – referred to as Directly Connected Impervious Areas (DCIA)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Impervious areas which are indirectly connected to the conveyance network, typically
            where impervious surface runoff flows over pervious surfaces before reaching the
            conveyance network (e.g. a roof that discharges onto a lawn). These are referred to as
            Indirectly Connected Impervious Areas (ICIA). Alternatively, the responses of these
            impervious surfaces are disconnected from sub-catchment outlets by volume management
            measures (refer <xref linkend="book4"/>). </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>These two configurations of impervious surfaces provide different hydrologic
        responses<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150305+1000" content=","?> with
        Directly Connected Impervious Areas contributing to runoff more quickly than Indirectly
        Connected Impervious Areas (refer <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_qqflw"/>). </para>
      <para>For large urban catchments, isolating the separate hydrologic effects of these two types
        of impervious surfaces is challenging. <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/> instead describes a
        concept referred to as Effective Impervious Area (EIA)
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150331+1000" content="which "?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150331+1000"?>that
        <?oxy_insert_end?>encompasses the combined hydrologic effect of both directly and indirectly
        connected impervious areas. The estimated EIA value for a catchment is calculated and then
        applied to hydrologic calculations using the adopted modelling software. </para>
      <para>The approach described in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/> involves estimation of EIA
        via linear regression of site stream flow gauge and rainfall data. In situations where there
        is insufficient available data to allow this technique to be used, the ratio of EIA to Total
        Impervious Area (TIA) has been established for a collection of gauged catchments that allows
        EIA to be estimated based on an estimate of TIA. (Refer <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_3gs2s"
        />).</para>
      <para>TIA is a measurable catchment feature
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150453+1000" content="which "?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150453+1000"?>that
        <?oxy_insert_end?>is typically estimated using GIS methods (refer <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5_s_ih2vd"/>). The selection of a technique for estimation of TIA will
        depend on catchment scale, data availability, accuracy requirements, and whether<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150607+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>the catchment scenario being investigated relates to an existing or future
        condition.</para>
      <para>From <xref linkend="book5"/> the recommended ratio of EIA/TIA for the majority of urban
        catchments sits within the range of 50%
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T160551+1100"?>and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T160551+1100" content="to"?>
        70%. For example, if the TIA for an urban catchment was measured to be say 55% then the EIA
        for that same catchment would be somewhere between 27.5% and 38.5% of the total catchment
        area.</para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        when the EIA approach is used, it is important that the characteristics of the catchment
        under investigation are compared to those of the catchments that have been used to establish
        the recommended EIA/TIA ratio. Different catchments have different stormwater management
        standards and land use patterns that may alter the overall degree of connectivity between
        impervious surfaces and the drainage network serving the catchment. Where there is higher
        connectivity,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150901+1000" content="then "?>the EIA is
        also expected to be higher.</para>
      <para>For some catchment investigations where there is strong connectivity between the
        impervious surfaces and the downstream drainage system<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150925+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T150926+1000" content="then "?>the
        measured TIA value may be the more suitable impervious surface value to be used for
        hydrologic modelling purposes.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161021+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> the analysis of a sealed carpark surface, where the entire
        impervious area is directly connected to surface inlets, is more appropriately undertaken
        using a TIA estimate. </para>
      <para>Also<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T151002+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        where the scale of the catchment is small, for example an individual parcel of land or a
        small development site, the use of TIA values in conjunction with a sub-catchment definition
        that reflects actual stormwater connectivity may be more appropriate. To avoid over
        estimation,
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162224+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162224+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
        should only use TIA for small scale catchments when they are satisfied that all the
        impervious flow is directly connected. The effect of any volume management infrastructure
        should also be explicitly reflected in these model simulations. </para>
      <para>Consideration also needs to be given to the overall need for accuracy when deriving
        estimates of impervious cover. The majority of techniques applied by
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162226+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162226+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
        typically under or over-estimate actual impervious cover by between 10 and 20
          percent<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T151250+1000" content="age "?><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T151701+1000" content="points "?><citation>b9_c6_r16</citation>. </para>
      <para>Predicted peak discharges and runoff volumes are sensitive to error in impervious cover
        when modelling low rainfall events with both event-based and continuous simulation models.
          <citation>b9_c6_r16+1</citation> observed that a difference in impervious surfaces of +/-
        10
        percent<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T160753+1100" content="age points"?>
        from actual conditions, can result in typical errors of 13% in peak discharge and 25% in
        runoff volume. These errors decrease in situations where rainfall depths are higher and
        infiltration losses less significant. </para>
      <para>It is also noted that where a catchment has significant impervious cover, the
        variability of runoff is reduced in comparison to a similar pervious catchment since
        infiltration losses have less influence.</para>
      <para>Additional discussion of configurations of impervious surfaces is provided in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_s_rhstb"
        /><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T151829+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
        Local observations or information about connectivity of impervious surfaces should be
        applied in models wherever possible.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_0k1v3">
      <title>Conveyance Infrastructure</title>
      <para>Urban areas typically contain a significant amount of stormwater conveyance
        infrastructure, including numerous stormwater inlet structures feeding a network of other
        conveyance infrastructure such as street gutters, pipes, open channels,
        roadways<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152054+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and overland flow paths through open spaces. These are linked together to form a continuous
        and distributed network from source to receiving waterway (refer <xref linkend="b9_ch5"
        />).</para>
      <para>While natural waterway conveyance is increasingly sought as a design objective for new
        urban areas, traditionally urban drainage systems have been designed to transfer runoff
        quickly and within a minimum corridor, often partly underground. This containment of flows
        within conduits that have artificial linings and unnatural slope leads to faster average
        flow velocity, greater volume, and significantly altered flood hydrographs compared to those
        from comparably sized rural and natural catchments.</para>
      <para>In order to accurately represent the hydrologic and hydraulic behaviour of an urban
        area, the influence of conveyance infrastructure on routing and flow behaviour should be
        included within the adopted urban flood model. For most
        applications<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160722+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the model should be capable of describing the effect of conveyance infrastructure on flow
        characteristics such as flow depth, velocity, direction, surface
        level<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152321+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and the hydraulic grade line showing hydraulic losses including their position and size.
        Other important information includes the split of flow between the minor and major flow
        path, maximum flow widths in gutters, maximum allowable flow velocity in pipes, the location
        and direction of any diversions and breakouts, and the extent of property inundation.</para>
      <para>The effect of conveyance infrastructure on these flood characteristics varies across the
        different types of urban flood models. </para>
      <para>Some models reflect the performance of conveyance infrastructure explicitly, which
        requires that the modeller input a detailed physical definition of conduits and their
        hydraulic characteristics. The typical data that must be collected and input to these models
        include:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Conduit type</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Cross-sectional dimensions (e.g. pipe diameter, channel width and depth,
            profile)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Length</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Slope, or sufficient elevation data to allow slope to be calculated using
            length</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Hydraulic parameters (e.g. mannings ‘n’, viscosity)</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>This information must be gathered for each
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160737+1000" content="and every "?>relevant
        piece of conveyance infrastructure that is part of the network being investigated. In some
        cases<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160745+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        this data may be readily accessible in an asset database. In other circumstances this data
        may require collection via ground survey. When data cannot be obtained due to inaccessible
        structures, assumptions regarding the network geometry may be required.</para>
      <para>A schematic representation of the overall conveyance network, including connectivity
        between inlets,
        conduits<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152512+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and junctions is then constructed within the model.</para>
      <para>These models can be data intensive, but they also have potential to provide detailed and
        accurate descriptions of flood behaviours. </para>
      <para>Depending on the type of user interface and pre-processor associated with the adopted
        model software, some of these data requirements may be automatically harvested from other
        raw input data.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161021+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> a
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161156+1100" content="3"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161203+1100"?>three
        d<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161207+1100" content="D"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161049+1100"?>imensional<?oxy_insert_end?>
        surface model may be used to establish roadside gutter profile and slope automatically. Even
        so, some information will be required such as in this case the plan position of the roadside
        gutter.</para>
      <para>For large urban areas, particularly those that have become densely developed over a long
        period of time, the task of collecting and collating all the dimensions of all conveyance
        infrastructure can be a major undertaking. Further complexity and effort arises since each
        inlet structure has a potential hydrologic sub-catchment that must be defined and input to
        the model. It is also possible that the size of the sub-catchment may change as flow rate
        increases. An exception is a
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100" content="rainfall on grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>
        model approach where sub-catchment definition may not be required, but even still,
        substantial effort is required to ensure each inlet structure is capturing a realistic
        amount of runoff.</para>
      <para>In some cases the burden of this infrastructure definition task can be reduced through
        use of simplified models and assumptions that do not explicitly model the performance of all
        conveyance infrastructure items.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> the capacity of underground drainage may be an assumed proportion
        of the total runoff hydrograph or in some cases totally ignored. This approach can be
        acceptable if the capacity of the underground system is small relative to the size of floods
        being investigated. In this case the model construction may instead focus on a more accurate
        definition of surface-based conveyance infrastructure and overland flow paths.</para>
      <para>Other models can provide flood estimates using an even more implicit description of
        conveyance infrastructure.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> rating curves and stage hydrographs may be used for selected
        locations in conjunction with run-off routing hydrologic estimates. In this case less
        physical data needs to be collected.</para>
      <para>Any decision to simplify the description of conveyance infrastructure within a model
        needs to be made recognising the accuracy requirements of the investigation and the risks
        associated with any limitations that may be introduced. It is important that the impacts of
        simplifying models and associated assumptions are fully understood. This is further
        discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_qz9hc"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_9pjt4">
      <title>Waterway Crossings</title>
      <para>Waterway crossings are urban infrastructure for the purpose of allowing access across a
        natural or man-made waterway. The most commonly encountered waterway crossings comprise of
        causeways, culverts and bridges that are constructed as part of a vehicular, rail or
        pedestrian transport system. </para>
      <para>Waterway crossings can have considerable hydraulic impact for floods within the range
        where the crossing structure causes the cross-sectional area of the waterway to be
        substantially reduced. In these circumstances additional energy is required to pass flow
        through and/or over the structure causing increased pressure head upstream of the crossing
        (afflux). Afflux is flow dependant and will change across the range of potential flood
        discharges. This afflux can cause a significant storage volume to be engaged upstream of
        embankments which can therefore also heavily influence downstream flood behaviour.</para>
      <para>A comprehensive description of hydraulic behaviour at waterway crossings and other
        hydraulic structures is found in <xref linkend="b6_ch3"/>.</para>
      <para>As well as causing afflux locally around the structure, the hydraulic behaviour
        associated with waterway crossings can also have an impact on:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Floodplain storage and hydrograph attenuation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tail water levels for upstream drainage</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Cross-catchment diversion of flow</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Bed scour and local stream morphology</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>These impacts are not necessarily confined to those that are in the immediate vicinity
        of the investigation site or study area and may impact areas upstream or downstream. A
        comprehensive urban flood investigation should therefore consider the impact of each
        existing or proposed waterway crossing in the catchment (and adjoining catchment in the case
        of cross-catchment diversion) and whether they could have an impact on local flood
        behaviour.</para>
      <para>Once the relevant waterway crossings have been identified, the urban modelling task is
        then to suitably define the crossing structure within the model. This will normally include
        the physical dimensions and shape of the waterway opening beneath the crossing deck and any
        obstruction caused by associated railings,
        embankments<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161241+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and utility services. Models may also assist with identifying locations where bed shear
        stress increases are likely and the design of scour protection measures (see <xref
          linkend="b6_ch3"/>).</para>
      <para>Consideration also needs to be given to blockage potential of the overall structure and
        which blockage scenarios may be required in order to fully describe potential flood
        behaviour. <xref linkend="b6_ch6"/> provides further detail regarding blockage
        considerations.</para>
      <para>As with conveyance infrastructure, some types of urban models may estimate the flood
        behaviour impacts of the waterway crossing in an implicit manner through use of rating
        curves and stage hydrographs. The impact of any such simplifications and assumptions on
        model accuracy needs to be considered when selecting an appropriate model platform for the
        investigation.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_y9jk6">
      <title>Volume Management Infrastructure</title>
      <para> Volume management infrastructure comprises of discrete facilities, primarily for the
        purpose of controlling peak discharge and volume. They can be located at almost any point
        within a drainage network and are linked by conveyance infrastructure and/or natural
        waterways. A comprehensive description of typical volume management infrastructure
        facilities is found in <xref linkend="b6_ch4"/>.</para>
      <para>The hydrologic and hydraulic impact of these facilities can be significant and will vary
        according to the design of the facility and size of the flood. For the urban modeller, the
        task associated with this infrastructure is the physical description and schematisation of
        the facility within the model. This will normally include:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Storage characteristics and how the volume stored varies with depth</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Outlet characteristics and how the outlet influence depth and volume of water stored
            in the facility</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>The way this model task is completed will depend on the type of model being used, but
        most commonly involves entering a form of definition table describing storage volume with
        depth along with details regarding the physical dimensions and elevations of the outlet
        structure.</para>
      <para>Depending on the intended purpose of the urban modelling task, consideration should also
        be given to antecedent conditions, whether the storage is partly utilised prior to the onset
        of the storm burst and whether there is potential for blockage of the outlet structure at
        some point in time and to what extent.</para>
      <para>The hydrologic and hydraulic impact of a volume management facility may be distant from
        its physical location (upstream or downstream). The modeller must consider inclusion of all
        volume management facilities that could potentially impact the investigation site. Also, as
        proposed storage volumes increase, the critical storm duration and pattern may
        correspondingly change, necessitating the inclusion of additional rainfall scenarios into
        the suite of model tests. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_5envo">
      <title>Water Quality Treatment Performance</title>
      <para>An increasingly common urban modelling task is the assessment of the water quality
        treatment performance associated with a water treatment facility such as those described in
          <xref linkend="b6_ch4"/>. </para>
      <para>The facilities that perform this function are often co-located or are an integral part
        of a volume management infrastructure facility. Where this is indeed the case then similar
        model inputs are required such as the basin storage and outlet characteristics.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        a different model platform may be necessary since the treatment process targets smaller
        storms and occurs over longer time periods.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161021+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> event-based hydrologic models may not be a suitable basis for
        these assessments. Instead a continuous simulation-based model would be more
        suitable.</para>
      <para>In addition, further information is required to define the treatment characteristics of
        the facility. These are mostly based on empirical relationships that simply associate the
        performance of the facility with its size or alternatively retention curves that relate
        inflow and outflow concentrations of pollutants. The pollutants of most interest are gross
        pollutants, nutrients (Total Nitrogen and Total Phosphorus), and Total Suspended
        Solids.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_mxsz7">
      <title>Data Collection and Collation</title>
      <para>A well organised data collection and collation process is essential in the modelling
        process. It not only ensures that the modelling is fit for purpose, but it documents the
        sources of data and how the data was interpreted and used in the model. Models often evolve
        as improvements are made or processes are changed to better represent different components.
        This task is much simpler if a good data management process has been used.
        <?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161407+1000" type="split"?></para>
      <para><?oxy_insert_end?>It is important that the data management system properly documents the
        source of the data, the
        format<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161401+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and the date of acquisition. <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/> provides comprehensive advice on the
        use of data. A key challenge in urban catchments is that many urban drainage components
        cannot be put directly into a model but need to be
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152625+1000" content="schematized"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152625+1000"?>schematised<?oxy_insert_end?>.
        Examples include converting a basin drawing into a stage storage table or representing a
        complex pit system. It is important that the data management system properly documents this
        process so the interpretation and
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152629+1000" content="schematization"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152629+1000"?>schematisation<?oxy_insert_end?>
        is properly documented and can be reviewed or refined<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161456+1000" content=" at a "?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161457+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>later<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161500+1000" content=" date"?>.
        While data can be classified in many
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161424+1000" content="different "?>ways,
        there are three broad types of data:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>model inputs such as rainfall and temporal patterns that change between
            events</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Model components such as pipes, storages, terrain information and land use
            data</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Observed data such as observed peak flood levels and flows</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>The digital age has changed many aspects of data collection with data often being easier
        to find but often the original data sources are unclear with merged data sets representing
        the largest part of this problem. This same problem exists in the model development process
        where many data sets are interpreted and merged. While most urban catchments are ungauged
        recent observed flood data can often be found on social media and older historical flood
        information can be found in scanned historical records and newspapers.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_rfr2v">
    <title>Model Selection</title>
    <para>There is a wide range of conceptual modelling approaches, software platforms and systems
      available to the urban designer. Each platform has different capabilities and strengths. It is
      not the role of
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161354+1100" content="Australian Rainfall and Runoff ARR"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161356+1100"?>this Guideline<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152654+1000"?>
      <?oxy_insert_end?>to recommend specific conceptual modelling approaches, software packages or
      prescribed flood estimation methods.
      <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      the guidance contained in this chapter does seek to classify the available options into
      categories and highlight the current strengths and weaknesses of each to support a decision on
      the adoption of an appropriate platform or estimation procedure for the task at hand. We are
      mindful that the science and practice of urban stormwater management will continue to
      evolve<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161520+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      and new models and data will become available. The guidance in this chapter should not be
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161426+1100" content="seen as"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161426+1100"?>perceived
      to be<?oxy_insert_end?> excluding new and innovative approaches.</para>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_f49r1">
      <title>Overall Trends in Urban Modelling</title>
      <para>The last 30 years has seen fundamental changes in the way urban stormwater assessment
        and design tasks are undertaken. It is reasonable to assume that similar change will occur
        over the next 30 years. Recognising that the decision to adopt a specific urban catchment
        model platform can have significant implications for personal research and training, this
        section provides introductory level discussion about these trends. It is expected this will
        support more informed choices related to adoption of a model platform, either for a specific
        investigation project or for a
        longer<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161603+1000" content=" "?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161603+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?>term
        strategic assessment program.</para>
      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_det6h">
        <title>Computing Power </title>
        <para>In response to the overall computing requirements of society, urban modelling
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162227+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162227+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
          now have access to faster computers with enormous numerical computation capability. This
          has arisen through improvements to computer processors
          (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152716+1000" content="CPU’s"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152716+1000"?>CPUs<?oxy_insert_end?>)
          including 64-bit computing and multi-core processing. More recently the use of graphics
          processing units
          (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152723+1000" content="GPU’s"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161511+1100"?>G<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161510+1100" content="C"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152723+1000"?>PU<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161451+1100" content="’"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152723+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>)
          has led to further substantial processing improvements. New opportunities are also arising
          with the advent of
          high<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161613+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161613+1000" content=" "?>performance
          computing services, including on the cloud. The transition from hand calculations to
          widespread availability of computing power to assist in designs is a major change in
          stormwater management practice since ARR 1987 (<xref linkend="b9_ch3_s_84gfv"/>). </para>
        <para>As these computing advances have occurred, urban modelling software platforms have
          been adapted to harness some of the available computational speed increases. This permits
          the modelling
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162228+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162228+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>
          to consider:</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Increasing the physical size of the model domain.
              <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
              example,<?oxy_insert_end?> model a larger urban catchment.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Increasing the spatial and temporal resolution of the model to allow for finer
              grained numerical calculations that account for location and connectivity of different
              land uses </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Longer time-series of rainfall</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A greater number of catchment scenarios</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Tighter integration of hydrologic and hydraulic computation</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>More model iterations to support improved calibration and sensitivity
              analysis</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Less conceptualisation and closer alignment to complex physical processes</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>It can be expected that computational capabilities will continue to increase into the
          future and that urban modelling software platforms will continue to be refined and
          improved to harness more of the available capacity. </para>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161640+1000" content="At the present time"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161640+1000"?>Currently,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          computing power is such that it is reasonable to expect that most urban hydrologic model
          simulations, even relatively complex ones, can be undertaken within seconds or minutes. It
          can therefore be assumed that pure hydrologic investigations are already unconstrained by
          computing power regardless of the choice of model platform.</para>
        <para>Computing power is still somewhat of a constraint for hydraulic simulations. Some of
          the more complex finer resolution or larger domain hydraulic model simulations can take
          hours or days per simulation. This may constrain the design of an urban hydraulic
          modelling investigation and also means that due care must be taken when selecting a
          hydraulic model platform. A hydraulic platform and method should be chosen that has
          computational efficiency to match the problem at hand. Models with very long run times
          should be carefully managed as they usually preclude comprehensive testing, checking or
          calibration. </para>
        <para>The future will permit very large multi-catchment spatial domains to be modelled at
          the finest level of temporal and spatial resolution necessary, with sufficient speed to
          allow simultaneous and exhaustive exploration of hydrologic and hydraulic
          scenarios.</para>
        <para>This trend may outpace our ability to improve the underlying science and gather
          sufficient quality input data, and to respond with more informed design and management
          solutions. Consideration will also need to be given to whether the ultimate outcomes of
          investigations are
          <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161742+1000" content="actually "?>improved
          by aggressively pursuing the full capabilities of available computing power. </para>
        <para>In other words, at some point in the future, further improvements to computing power
          may cease to provide any material value to urban modelling
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162229+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162229+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s.
          Substantial further research and data collection, for a range of urban catchment scales,
          is necessary to ensure theory is able to keep pace with computing power.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_9bitm">
        <title>Alignment to Physical Hydrologic and Hydraulic Processes </title>
        <para>The underlying methods that are applied using computer-based models have experienced a
          trend away from conceptual and simplified deterministic techniques to methods that more
          closely align with the actual physical processes that are occurring.</para>
        <para>Some examples of this trend are:</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A move away from isolated storm bursts with a single pattern, towards
              consideration of pre-burst rainfall and more complete storm bursts including an
              ensemble of equally likely but different temporal patterns. This leads to more robust
              design and resolves some of the issues that arise when trying to maintain probability
              neutrality between rainfall and flood (refer <xref linkend="book3"/> and <xref
                linkend="book5"/>). The future will see this trend continue with designs becoming
              increasingly based on complete storms and continuous recorded or synthetic rainfall
              sequences.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The use of direct rainfall, also referred to as
              ‘<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162015+1100" content="rain on grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>’
              approaches which attempts to explicitly resolve the accumulation of runoff
              progressively down the catchment, removing the need to pre-identify flow paths and
              sub-catchments. This is a useful way to ensure flow paths are not inadvertently
              omitted from an investigation. With further research and software development this
              approach may in time also eliminate the need for hydrologic models to undertake
              surface routing. At this stage
              <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="however"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161615+1100"?>h<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161611+1100" content="H"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000"?>owever,<?oxy_insert_end?>
              there is inadequate evidence that a direct rainfall approach should be relied upon for
              this purpose with many parameters being scale and approach dependent (refer <xref
                linkend="book5"/>).</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The hydraulic models applied in practice have increasingly changed from
              one-dimensional to two-dimensional representations of the floodplain surface. This
              allows a more realistic definition of potential flow paths which in turn improves the
              representation of flood behaviour (refer <xref linkend="book5"/> and <xref
                linkend="book7"/>). </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>With continuation of this trend it can be anticipated that model platforms will
          eventually converge on more accurate representations of rainfall runoff and flood
          processes, requiring different model inputs,
          parameters<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161802+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          and application techniques.
          Again<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161810+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          this will only occur with adequate research and software development effort and data
          collection for a range of urban catchment scales.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_o5lps">
        <title>Statistical Approaches</title>
        <para>There has been increasing awareness and understanding of the need to consider the
          joint probability of model assumptions and physical processes
            <citation>b9_c3_r16</citation>. This has given rise to techniques such as Monte-Carlo
          sampling and ensembles of rainfall patterns to reduce potential probability distortions
          and gain better appreciation of model uncertainty (<xref linkend="book3"/>). For simple
          urban models or where the design objectives have limited sensitivity to model results
          these approaches may not be warranted. </para>
        <para>These approaches should be considered where better appreciation of natural variability
          and uncertainty is required. This may include sensitive urban areas, a major waterway
          crossing, large flood mitigation proposal or hydrologic design of regional scale water
          quality infrastructure.</para>
        <para>Machine learning algorithms are also being used for the prediction of stream flow
          using statistical information drawn from historic rainfall and stream gauge data,
          providing an alternative approach to hydrologic modelling.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_y52zj">
        <title>Accumulation of Longer Periods of Recorded Data</title>
        <para>With the passage of time, longer periods of recorded data have become available to
          allow refinements of design rainfall,
          losses<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161830+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          and more informed model calibration (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_wfiku"/>). Over time this
          will allow a better understanding of model performance and uncertainty, particularly
          within those catchments where data has been recorded. There will be diminishing situations
          where models are left uncalibrated for the want of historic data.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_pdsnv">
        <title>The Internet and Spatial Information Systems </title>
        <para>Since the 1987 version of
          <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152800+1000" content="Australian Rainfall and Runoff"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152800+1000"?>ARR<?oxy_insert_end?>,
          the Internet has emerged to become a ubiquitous part of life. The internet provides urban
          modelling
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162230+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162230+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
          a new potentially more effective method for:</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>accessing and disseminating research, including international practice</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>gathering model input data </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>processing of simulations (using cloud processing technology)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>storing and communicating information arising from model investigations</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>Furthermore, modelling software platforms that have traditionally been tied to a
          single computer, are now able to be offered as internet-based services. Into the future
          other new applications will be found for the internet that cannot be fully anticipated at
          this time but will likely support further improvements in the application of urban
          models.</para>
        <para>In parallel to the Internet, an associated trend that has also emerged is a deeper
          interest and reliance on spatial information systems
          (<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161718+1100" content="or Geographical Information Systems ["?>GIS<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161701+1100" content="]"?>).
          These systems are used for the storage, handling and display of physical catchment data,
          catchment parameters and infrastructure data. </para>
        <para>Spatial information systems have become an important support technology for the
          application of urban models, with most platforms leveraging these tools for pre-processing
          and post-processing of data, storage of data, data display, data enhancement and the
          preparation of information products for stakeholders.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_p1qdr">
        <title>Information Needs of the End-User</title>
        <para>The information needs of the end user have become more complex. A greater number of
          aspects are of interest.
          <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
          example,<?oxy_insert_end?> the extent,
          depth<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161908+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          and level of floodwaters are now typically supplemented by velocity, combinations of
          velocity and depth (hazard), volume and timing. Enhanced datasets are also now prepared
          such as risk and planning controls. These results are often required at many additional
          locations distributed across urban catchments rather than at selected locations at the
          bottom of catchments. </para>
        <para>Urban modelling
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162231+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162231+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
          should consider how the model software platforms they use can be used to accommodate these
          growing information needs.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_vd8jb">
      <title>Types of Urban Models</title>
      <para>Notwithstanding the potential future trends in urban modelling described above, today’s
        industry
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162232+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162232+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
        already have a greater array of model platforms and estimation options than available in the
        past.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        each option differs in the quality of spatial representation they are capable of achieving,
        as well as the capability with which they can represent different physical flood processes.
        Accordingly<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161952+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        some models or methods may or may not be suitable for a specific urban modelling
        task.</para>
      <para>Some of the more common types of models and methods are listed in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_t_okqdg"
        /><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161827+1100" content=" below"?>. For
        each type, a generic classification of its capability is also provided. This is a snapshot
        in time of the capability of these models and will change with time. This classification is
        based on the examples in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_kby4c"/>. A subsequent section describes
        the performance of these models at different spatial scales.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_okqdg">
        <caption>Common Types of Urban Models</caption>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;11%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181204T131824+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="13%"/>
        <col width="14%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;12%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181204T131909+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="14%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181204T131829+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="12%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;11%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181204T132730+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="14%"/>
        <col width="28%"/>
        <col width="14%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th rowspan="1">Focus</th>
            <th rowspan="1">Urban Model Type</th>
            <th colspan="4">Estimation Capabilities (also refer <xref linkend="b9_ch3_t_06he2"
              />)</th>
            <th rowspan="1">
              <para>Example Model Platforms (where relevant)</para>
            </th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132703+1100"?>Runoff
              Generation and Surface
              Routing<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132703+1100" content="&lt;emphasis role=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Runoff Generation and Surface Routing&lt;/emphasis&gt;"?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132659+1100"?>Channel and
              Storage
              Routing<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132659+1100" content="&lt;emphasis role=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Channel and Storage Routing&lt;/emphasis&gt;"?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132656+1100"?>Structure
              Hydraulics<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132656+1100" content="&lt;emphasis role=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Structure Hydraulics&lt;/emphasis&gt;"?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132653+1100"?>Other specific
              capabilities or
              limitations<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T132653+1100" content="&lt;emphasis role=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Other specific capabilities or limitations&lt;/emphasis&gt;"?></td>
            <td/>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydrology</td>
            <td>Rational Method</td>
            <td>Limited</td>
            <td>None</td>
            <td>None</td>
            <td>Peak flow only – scalar quantity, single lumped catchment, requires ‘Time of
              Concentration’ assumption, only suitable for small catchments. It has best
              capabilities where there is no storage present.</td>
            <td>RATHGL, PCdrain</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydrology</td>
            <td>Time Area Method, Extended Rational Method</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>None</td>
            <td>None</td>
            <td>Suitable for small catchments only. Can be extended as a collection of linked
              sub-catchments.</td>
            <td>ILSAX, DRAINS</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydrology</td>
            <td>Runoff Routing</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Limited</td>
            <td>Full event hydrograph, empirically derived lag parameters, non-linear routing
              capabilities. Structure hydraulics can be moderately capable for discrete structures
              but not for continuous conveyance networks.</td>
            <td>RORB, RAFTS, WBNM, URBS, HEC-HMS</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydrology</td>
            <td>Continuous Simulation</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Limited</td>
            <td>Continuous multi-year runoff sequence, comprehensive infiltration loss models.
              Limited capability for rare to very rare floods unless utilised with replicates of
              conditioned synthetic continuous rainfall (such as DRIP)</td>
            <td>XP-RAFTS, MUSIC, PURRS, Systems Framework</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydrology and Hydraulics</td>
            <td>Hydrology coupled to 1D hydraulic model</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Not always emulating full capability of the underlying hydrologic model</td>
            <td>DRAINS,
              <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152934+1000" content="Pcdrain"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152934+1000"?>PC<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T161916+1100" content=" "?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152934+1000"?>drain<?oxy_insert_end?>,
              XP-SWMM</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydrology and Hydraulics</td>
            <td>
              <para>Direct Rainfall
                (‘<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162015+1100" content="Rain on Grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>’)</para>
            </td>
            <td>Limited</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Does not require pre-defined flow paths. Sensitive to topographic data
              pre-processing and surface roughness assumptions. Not suitable for ‘greenfield’
              subdivision drainage design.</td>
            <td>TUFLOW, MIKE21, SOBEK, ANUGA</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydrology and Hydraulics</td>
            <td>Runoff routing coupled to two-dimensional hydraulic model</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Requires pre-defined understanding of flow paths in order to establish initial
              model. Requires input and output procedure between two model software packages.</td>
            <td>RAFTS with MIKE21, WBNM with TUFLOW, XP STORM with TUFLOW, DRAINS with TUFLOW</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydraulics</td>
            <td>One-dimensional hydraulic model</td>
            <td>None</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Simple channel or pipe behaviour only. Limited where complex flood storages
              exist.</td>
            <td>HEC-RAS, MIKE11, SOBEK</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydraulics</td>
            <td>Two-dimensional hydraulic model</td>
            <td>None</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Complex flow behaviour including breakout and diversion. Flow transitions and
              hydraulic jumps. Principally surface flow. </td>
            <td>TUFLOW, SOBEK, ANUGA, MIKE21, HEC-RAS 2D, RMA, RiverFlow2D</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Hydraulics</td>
            <td>Pipe network models</td>
            <td>None</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Strong</td>
            <td>Specialist models for underground drainage networks, storage routing performance
              best where flow is contained within the minor system.</td>
            <td>SWMM, XP-STORM, DRAINS,
              <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152934+1000" content="PCdrain"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152934+1000"?>PC
              drain<?oxy_insert_end?>, MIKE URBAN</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Water Quality</td>
            <td>Water quality model</td>
            <td>Moderate</td>
            <td>Limited</td>
            <td>Limited</td>
            <td>
              <para>Additional capabilities related to pollutant generation and removal. Hydraulic
                capabilities can be extended by coupling to 1D hydraulic model.</para>
              <para>Runoff generation less suited to event-based flood estimates.</para>
            </td>
            <td>MUSIC, EPA-SWMM</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_kby4c">
        <caption>Generic Classification of Model Estimation Capability </caption>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Flood process</th>
            <th>Limited Capability</th>
            <th>Moderate Capability</th>
            <th>Moderate Capability</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para>Runoff generation and surface routing</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Average intensity or burst</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Cursory treatment of infiltration losses</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Surface characteristics not fully represented </para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>More complete storm</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Infiltration losses</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Surface characteristics partially represented </para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Full storm or rainfall sequence</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Infiltration losses</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Spatial distribution of rainfall</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Surface characteristics well represented (including surface wave speed)</para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para>Channel and storage routing</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Channel characteristics not represented </para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>No explicit calculation of flood storage and its attenuation effects</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Channel characteristics partially represented </para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Storage behaviour partially represented including attenuation effects and
                spatial influences</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Channel characteristics and flood wave speed well represented </para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Storage behaviour well described including complex hydraulic behaviour and
                attenuation effects</para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Structure hydraulics</td>
            <td>
              <para>Basic hydraulic structures only</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Rating tables</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Manning’s formula for open channels.</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Small range of hydraulic structures</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Basic topographic representation</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Wide range of hydraulic structures</para>
              <para> </para>
              <para>Resolves shallow water equations (1D or 2D or both)</para>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para>When selecting a particular model or technique, the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162233+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162233+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>
        should in the first instance look to match the estimation capabilities of the model, whether
        they be ‘limited’, ‘moderate’ or ‘strong’, with the nature of urban modelling problem that
        is being investigated. </para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> if channel routing and structure hydraulics are not aspects of
        the problem that need to be investigated, then the model selected need not have any
        capabilities in these areas. Equally, if it is expected that a particular problem will
        require significant capabilities in
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?>) runoff generation, then a model with ‘strong’ capabilities in
        this area should be considered.</para>
      <para>Where the estimation capabilities are identified in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_okqdg"/> as
        ‘limited’, significant caution must be adopted. As a minimum they should be applied by, or
        under the direct guidance of, a
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>
        who fully understands the limitations of these approaches. The tolerance for error in the
        results should be considered and if greater accuracy is required then an alternative more
        capable model platform applied.</para>
      <para>As
        always<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162148+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the level of experience of the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>
        is a significant factor. Someone with significant experience and familiarity with a specific
        model may be able to extend its capabilities to a level that achieves an acceptable level of
        estimation accuracy that is beyond its normal capabilities if deployed by an average or less
        advanced user.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_j6bj1">
      <title>Model Scale</title>
      <para> Urban models are constructed at different spatial scales depending on the size of the
        overall catchment to be analysed and the nature of the performance objectives being sought.
        Typically the smallest catchment a
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>
        will consider is that of a single small parcel of land with a single dwelling. The type of
        model assessments that are normally undertaken at this scale include model calculations to
        assist with design of internal drainage systems and small volume management facilities (e.g.
        rainwater tanks and OSD).</para>
      <para>At the other end of the spectrum of potential scale, an urban model may be constructed
        to represent all the stormwater catchments spanning an entire suburb or even a small city.
        These larger models are often used for the purpose of regional flood mapping, establishing
        flood levels for development purposes or the design of
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162213+1000" content="large scale"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162213+1000"?>large-scale<?oxy_insert_end?>
        stormwater and road crossing infrastructure. </para>
      <para>When evaluating which type of model to adopt for a particular urban modelling project,
        the spatial scale of interest is an important factor to consider since some particular
        models may not be capable of competently representing all the complexity that is encountered
        at the scale of interest.</para>
      <para>Consider four example spatial scales with each physical footprint increasing by an
        approximate order of magnitude as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_umoju"/> below.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_umoju">
        <caption> Typical Urban Model Scales</caption>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Lot</th>
            <th>Site</th>
            <th>Neighbourhood</th>
            <th>Precinct</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>A small parcel of land with 1 or 2 buildings. </td>
            <td>A large parcel of land with multiple buildings. Sometimes a small number of 'lots'
              combined.</td>
            <td>Many parcels of land each with at least one building. Many 'lots' and potentially
              some multi-building complexes.</td>
            <td>Hundreds of parcels of land each with at least one building. A large number of
              'lots' and multi-building complexes combined. Several neighbourhoods.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>e.g. single detached dwelling or duplex up to say 1,000m<superscript>2</superscript>
              in area</td>
            <td>e.g. large townhouse complex covering an area up to say 1 hectare</td>
            <td>e.g. a residential subdivision stage or a neighbourhood covering an area up to say
              10 hectares</td>
            <td>e.g. a small suburb covering an area of say 100 hectares</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para>As a model’s spatial scale increases from ‘lot’ through to ‘precinct’ the more likely
        that the catchment being modelled will contain a greater range of features of relevance to
        stormwater behaviour such as:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Public roads acting as overland flowpaths</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A larger variety of different land uses and associated connectivity</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Large capacity conveyance infrastructure</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Large basins and volume management infrastructure</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Urban waterways</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Urban waterway crossings</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>In conjunction with this increase in the number of stormwater features, it follows that
        the potential number of rainfall runoff processes encountered in a larger scale model will
        also increase. In this context flood generation processes include damaging floods as well as
        much smaller floods that are relevant to yield and water quality assessment. </para>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_npwo3"/> below provides a list of the flood generation processes
        encountered at each of the four spatial scales described above. This listing is
        non-exhaustive and only provided to demonstrate that there is a larger number of potential
        flood generation processes that can be expected to occur as spatial scale increases from
        ‘lot’ scale to ‘precinct’ scale (growing from approximately 8 to 32 in the example listing
        provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_npwo3"/>). </para>
      <para>Some degree of simplification of these flood generation processes normally occurs when
        preparing an urban flood model. The flood generation processes listed in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_t_npwo3"/> have
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152949+1000" content="differentlevels"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T152949+1000"?>different
        levels<?oxy_insert_end?> of importance and influence when trying to decide whether any
        simplifications are possible. Each process has been indicated in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_t_npwo3"/> by one of two different symbols as follows:</para>
      <informaltable frame="void">
        <col width="88%"/>
        <col width="12%"/>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="italic">A very important flood generation process. A model
                constructed at this scale should have the capability to competently address this
                flood process.</emphasis></td>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="italic">A flood generation process that is
                  less important. This process may be omitted or simplified if accuracy of model
                  estimates is not critical </emphasis></emphasis></td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </informaltable>
      <para>Further discussion regarding model simplification is included in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_s_qz9hc"/>.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_npwo3">
        <caption>Example Flood Generation Processes at Different Model Spatial Scales</caption>
        <col width="63%"/>
        <col width="7%"/>
        <col width="7%"/>
        <col width="15%"/>
        <col width="9%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Example Flood Generation Processes</th>
            <th>Lot</th>
            <th>Site</th>
            <th>Neighbourhood</th>
            <th>Precinct</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Overland flow routing across surface of lot</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of roof gutters and downpipes</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through internal underground drainage</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from impervious surfaces within lot (e.g. roof)</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from pervious surfaces within lot (e.g. garden)</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of internal underground drainage</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through temporary and/or permanent storage connected to dwelling (source
              control)</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Storage outlet behaviour including use of stored water for internal and external
              private demand (source control)</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Overland flow routing between multiple lots</td>
            <td/>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through open surface drains and driveways</td>
            <td/>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through inter-allotment drainage</td>
            <td/>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from impervious surfaces within common areas (e.g. common
              driveway)</td>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from pervious surfaces within common areas (e.g. landscape
              areas)</td>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of open surface drains and driveways</td>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of inter-allotment drainage</td>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Capacity of inlets to the internal underground system and potential bypass</td>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through temporary and/or permanent storage within common area (source
              control)</td>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Storage outlet behaviour including use of stored water for external demand within
              common areas (source control)</td>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Overland flow routing across the sub-catchment surface</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through roadside gutters and table drains</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>2</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through underground drainage and trunk drainage</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through major overland flow paths</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of roadside gutters and table drains</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from impervious surfaces (neighbourhood scale)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from pervious surfaces (neighbourhood scale)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Capacity of inlets to the road drainage system and potential bypass</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Capacity of inlets to the trunk underground drainage system and potential
              bypass</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of underground drainage and trunk drainage</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of major overland flow paths</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through temporary and/or permanent storage within public areas
              (neighbourhood control)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Storage outlet behaviour including use of stored water for external demand within
              public areas (neighbourhood control)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from impervious surfaces (precinct scale)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Runoff generation from pervious surfaces (precinct scale)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through large open channels and urban waterways</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Conveyance capacity of large open channels and urban waterways</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Performance of culverts and bridges including impact of blockage and diversion</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Routing through temporary and/or permanent storage within public areas (regional
              control)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Storage outlet behaviour including use of stored water for external demand within
              public areas (regional control)</td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para><emphasis role="italic"
          >2<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153042+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153040+1000" content=" -"?>
          Opportunity for model simplification (refer <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_28ypi"
        />)</emphasis></para>
      <para>Most model platforms have some limitations on which processes they
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162309+1000" content="are capable of representing"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162309+1000"?>can
        represent<?oxy_insert_end?>. A decision will be required at the commencement of model
        preparation as to whether the selected model and the available data are capable of achieving
        the required level of accuracy and reliability.</para>
      <para>As a result of the expected increase in the number of flood generation processes with
        scale, if a catchment investigation requires investigation across a large spatial scale,
        then the modeller can expect that a model or method with ‘strong’ estimation capabilities
        across multiple flood process areas will be necessary (refer <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_okqdg"
        /> and <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_kby4c"/>). </para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> the Rational Method, with ‘limited’ runoff generation and surface
        routing capabilities, is not likely to be suitable for a ‘precinct’ scale estimate of peak
        flow as it cannot adequately simulate the array of flood processes that are encountered,
        even in the
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162345+1000" content="most simple "?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162345+1000"?>simplest
        <?oxy_insert_end?>of catchments.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        it may be suitable at a ‘lot’ scale in circumstances where storage routing is not
        critical.</para>
      <para>If volume management infrastructure forms part of a solution, or if an understanding of
        potential impacts on downstream flooding are required, then a ‘strong’ hydrologic estimation
        method such as a runoff-routing model should be used. For most urban modelling at this point
        in time, a runoff-routing model coupled to a two-dimensional hydraulic model or pipe network
        model will provide the strongest estimation capabilities across a wide range of model
        scales. </para>
      <para>The resolution of model inputs and boundary conditions also needs to be considered.
        There is little value in developing a
        high<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162416+1000" content=" "?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162418+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?>resolution
        model with coarse lumped inflows or considering the performance of a complex system using a
        single temporal pattern. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_19hh2">
      <title>Flood Magnitude</title>
      <para>The capability of each type of model also varies with magnitude of the flood being
        considered. For the smallest of floods, including frequent storms and runoff events, the
        model’s capabilities should include consideration of infiltration losses including for some
        applications the recovery of soil moisture profiles during inter-event periods and base
        flow. The importance of this capability may change depending on the level of impervious
        cover within the catchment, becoming decreasingly important as impervious cover
        increases.</para>
      <para>These capabilities are principally the domain of runoff-routing and continuous
        simulation models. Other processes that effect total runoff volume such as harvesting and
        use of rainwater may also be important considerations for smaller flood magnitudes. <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_w760n"/> indicates the likely range of effectiveness for the different
        types of hydrologic models against flood magnitude on x-scale and model scale on
        y–scale.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_w760n">
        <title>Types of Urban Hydrologic Models and their Likely Application Range</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9098.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>As the magnitude of flooding that is of interest increases, different hydrologic model
        requirements emerge since the importance of antecedent soil moisture and rainfall diminish.
        Typically<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162449+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        runoff-routing models applied using discrete rainfall bursts or more complete storms would
        be used.</para>
      <para>For the companion hydraulic calculations during small floods, and where flooding is
        confined to the pipe network or a simple channel, a pipe network model and/or 1D channel
        hydraulic model will normally be adequate. Even some hydrologic model packages have the
        capability to undertake basic hydraulic calculations. </para>
      <para>For hydraulic calculations associated with large floods that exceed the normal capacity
        of a channel, or where substantial overland flows develop, a 2D hydraulic model may have
        more utility since the likelihood of complex flow patterns increases.</para>
      <para>Further detailed information regarding hydraulic models is included in <xref
          linkend="b6_ch4"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_mbm01">
      <title>Choosing a Model</title>
      <para>A stepwise process is suggested below to assist with identifying the types of models
        that may be suitable for a specific urban modelling problem. Consideration of each step in
        the flowchart shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_qny1q"/> will help to progressively reduce
        the number of candidate model types that may apply. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_qny1q">
        <title>Stepwise
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115720+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115719+1100" content="f"?>lowchart
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115727+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115727+1100" content="s"?>electing
          an
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115730+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115730+1100" content="u"?>rban
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115733+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115733+1100" content="s"?>tormwater
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115735+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115735+1100" content="m"?>odel</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9099.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Where there are multiple options arising from this process, the simplest model, capable
        of the necessary calculations should be favoured. Other model selection criteria include,
        availability of sufficient input data and parameter research, output data capabilities,
        availability of other required functionality (e.g. water quality calculation), cost, and
        user familiarity with the model. A hydraulic model involves a more explicit representation
        of flow routing and how storage is represented in the catchment.
        Generally<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162511+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        a hydraulic model will be required where there is a need to understand both flow and flood
        levels. One dimensional pipe and channel models only provide this information at key
        locations but are well suited to ‘greenfields’ subdivision design, while a two dimensional
        model provides a detailed spatial representation of surface stormwater processes and may be
        more suited to brownfields investigations.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_qz9hc">
      <title>Model Simplification</title>
      <para>In conjunction with selecting a type of model that has the necessary estimation
        capabilities and is well suited to the model scale of interest and associated smaller scale
        influences, consideration must also be given to the degree of model simplification that
        might be appropriate. </para>
      <para>When modelling at small spatial scales it is simpler to closely represent each flood
        process and its associated physical features and drainage connections explicitly. As spatial
        scale increases it is sometimes possible to adopt some model simplifications to manage data
        requirements and the general complexity of the modelling task.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> when building a ‘precinct’ scale model it may be possible to omit
        or simplify ‘lot’ scale processes.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models should not be simplified unless that consequences of spatial averaging, deterministic
        assumptions and judgements is well understood. Where simplification is undertaken, efforts
        should be made to fully understand the impacts of simplification and limits on validity of
        the model outputs.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> by comparison of results against a more detailed sub-model or
        results generated by an alternative model.</para>
      <para>Experience and careful judgement are required when choosing to omit or simplify those
        processes that are suggested as being less important. In
        general<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162523+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the omission or simplification of such a process should only occur when the investigation
        does not demand highly reliable estimates,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> for preliminary sizing of structures or where flood risks are
        low. <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_npwo3"/> indicates those flood generation processes that may be
        less important and therefore could be considered as an opportunity for simplification at
        each different spatial scale.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_28ypi">
      <title>Model Resolution</title>
      <para>Closely related to consideration of model simplification is the interrelated
        consideration of model resolution. Resolution can in this context have multiple aspects. </para>
      <para>Firstly there is spatial resolution of the model. For a hydrologic model this will
        relate to the minimum size of sub-catchments. For a hydraulic model this will relate to the
        density of sampling of the ground surface. </para>
      <para>The adopted spatial resolution of a model will govern the density of reporting locations
        i.e. where model results are output by the model software. It may also influence model
        accuracy. Through experience a modeller will develop an understanding of the optimum model
        spatial resolution for each type of model and to what degree spatial simplification can be
        tolerated.</para>
      <para>Then there is the temporal resolution of the model and the ability to extract output
        time series that are fit for purpose.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> the temporal resolution necessary for regional water supply
        planning may be lower than required for calculation of stormwater harvest yield from a small
        catchment. In this case a degree of temporal simplification to daily or monthly data may be
        acceptable for a regional water supply planning task.</para>
      <para>Again, through experience a modeller will develop an understanding of the optimum model
        temporal resolution and to what degree temporal simplification can be tolerated.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_cj3nx">
    <title>Application to Urban Modelling</title>
    <para>Stormwater management is subject to ongoing evolution and change. There has been
      substantial change to the practice and science of stormwater management since 1987 as
      discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>. This version of
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162654+1100" content="Australian Rainfall and Runoff"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162654+1100"?>ARR<?oxy_insert_end?>
      combines 30 years of additional data with evolving science and professional capability to
      accommodate changes in professional and community aspirations. This process has provided a
      range of new methods, data and resources that can assist the designer to address the local
      challenges of managing stormwater runoff in urban areas. </para>
    <para>Drainage networks (also discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>) are now considered to be
      part of more comprehensive stormwater management approaches (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162730+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162729+1100" content="see"?>
      <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>) that respond to multiple water cycle objectives including protecting
      waterways, mitigating flood risks, provision of water resources, managing the quality of
      stormwater runoff and enhancing the amenity of urban areas. These approaches respond to a need
      to manage urban water balances (discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch2"/>) and to also incorporate
      a range of storage measures (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162738+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162736+1100" content="see"?>
      <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>) that aim to manage flooding, stormwater quality and provide
      additional water resources. </para>
    <para>This section provides a framework for application of modelling approaches to urban
      stormwater catchments. The framework provides guidance for key segments of catchments from the
      behaviour of land uses within sub-catchments that flow to inlet structures, through urban
      stormwater networks, and into the receiving waterway. </para>
    <para>A range of approaches are now available to determine the configuration of measures in a
      linked stormwater management system than may include a conveyance network, volume management
      strategies and non-structural measures. These methods can range from simple procedures to
      detailed computer modelling. The application of new rainfall data and methods to modelling
      approaches is discussed with reference to the different approaches to the design of stormwater
      management measures and systems. </para>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_laai8">
      <title>Urban Modelling Frameworks</title>
      <para>An increasing range of modelling frameworks and approaches are available to urban
        designers (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162800+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162759+1100" content="see"?>
        <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_w760n"/>). The urban stormwater design process, as outlined in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5_s_h00bb"/> (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162755+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162752+1100" content="see"?>
        <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_2a26n"/>), should be modified to respond to the characteristics of a
        particular project. Selection of a modelling framework will depend on the purpose of the
        analysis, scale and complexity of the project, availability of data and the consequences of
        failure, and includes: </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Hydrological models that translate rainfall into stormwater runoff and evaluate
            behaviour of storages; </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Hydraulic models that evaluate or design the transfer of stormwater flows through
            networks of infrastructure and across land surfaces; </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Hydrology models that include simple pipe hydraulics or one dimensional hydraulic
            models;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Linked hydrology and hydraulic models that include detailed two dimensional surface
            flows with hydrodynamic conveyance networks;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100" content="Rainfall on grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>Rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>
            models;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Continuous simulation of rainfall runoff and physical processes to evaluate
            behaviour of integrated solutions and account for antecedent conditions, water quality
            and associated performance issues;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Approximate empirical relationships or peak runoff assumptions used to design and
            evaluate components of urban catchments. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>We should be mindful that all models are an approximation of reality that can be used to
        enhance our understanding about the likely stormwater behaviours for particular urban
        scenarios. The different hydrological and hydraulic models can be classified by their
        outputs of peak flowrates, hydrographs, flood depths or continuous sequences of stormwater
        runoff. These models can also be distinguished by the methods used to route rainfall runoff
        towards inlet structures in urban conveyance networks or stormwater volume management
        measures. Models can also be described by different spatial detail such as lumped,
        semi-distributed or distributed inputs (<xref linkend="b4ch2_f_lsm3n"/>, <xref
          linkend="b4ch2_s_pfupn"/>). Lumped catchment models approximate the behaviour of the
        catchment using single average inputs and assumptions. Semi-distributed models employ a
        range of sub-catchments with different attributes and assumptions. In contrast, spatially
        explicit details are included in distributed models – this detail may include the range of
        different land uses and properties in an urban model or a grid of equal size and shape used
        throughout the model. An emerging type of distributed hydrology and hydraulic model is the
        direct rainfall or
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162015+1100" content="rain on grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>
        methods (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162919+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162918+1100" content="see"?>
        <xref linkend="b6_ch4_s_9f1m8"/>). </para>
      <para>Empirical relationships can be utilised to determine peak flows from small catchments
        and are applied to the design of roof gutters,
        downpipes<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T162821+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and infrastructure to manage stormwater runoff from properties in accordance with standards
        such as AS/NZS 3500.3. These approximate methods include nominal “deemed to comply”
        infrastructure specifications or generally require information about catchment area and
        slope, and utilise assumed runoff coefficients, time of concentration and design rainfall
        intensity in a lumped catchment design process. </para>
      <para>The probabilistic or the urban Rational Method is a more detailed approximate method
        that is utilised to generate peak flowrates for use in the design of pipe networks within
        small properties and for small sub-catchments. This framework of analysis differs from
        simple empirical relationships by including equivalent or effective impervious areas,
        accumulation of flow rates and the areas of different land uses. The method uses rainfall
        intensity derived from Intensity Frequency Duration (IFD) data, assumed runoff coefficients
        and time of concentration to derive stormwater peak flows. </para>
      <para>The design approach associated with urban Rational Method is often based on lumped
        sub-catchment inputs to inlet structures which require the resolution of partial area
        effects on the timing of cumulative peak discharges throughout a conveyance network. A
        lumped sub-catchment process combines all land uses, including the area of pervious and
        impervious surfaces (full area), with an estimated time of concentration to derive peak
        flows at the outlet of a sub-catchment which is the inlet to a conveyance network. A partial
        area effect is,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161048+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> where the runoff from impervious surfaces (partial area) arrives
        at the outlet before runoff from pervious surfaces reach the outlet at less than the full
        area travel time. These methods may be used to analyse the capacity of individual pipes or
        peak flows from small catchments but cannot simulate actual flow behaviour throughout
        conveyance networks and urban stormwater management systems <citation>arr_1987</citation>. </para>
      <para>The simple nature of the urban Rational Method cannot account for the complexity of
        contemporary urban catchments and modern stormwater management approaches, the temporal and
        spatial variability of storm events, and variations in antecedent or between storm event
        processes. Approximate methods, such as Rational Method, should only be applied within a
        catchment where more detailed analysis of rainfall runoff observations have defined the
        parameters (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163110+1100"?>for
        eexample,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163108+1100" content="such as"?>
        runoff coefficient and time of concentration) for use in the method
          <citation>b8_c_r58,b2_c5_r40</citation>. <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        <citation>b5_c3_r31+1</citation> established that derivation of runoff parameters at the
        regional scale or bottom of a catchment may not necessarily describe local processes in
        sub-catchments. Local information is also needed to determine urban runoff parameters. </para>
      <para>Runoff or hydrograph routing methods are commonly associated with computer models that
        include internal processes that incorporate different land uses with separate pervious and
        impervious surfaces. The process includes depression storages and losses with lag times to
        generate separate hydrographs of runoff for each land surface. These runoff routing methods
        typically employ
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        rainfall inputs (<xref linkend="b4_ch3_s_y3noq"/>) of selected Annual Exceedance Probability
        (AEP) and duration of peak burst rainfall (see <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_9307w"/>). An
        objective of this process is to achieve probability neutrality between rainfall inputs and
        generated runoff for urban catchments. </para>
      <para>These runoff routing methods may utilise single or multiple design storms and associated
        temporal patterns to determine regimes of excess rainfall that is then routed through
        hydraulic models that range from simple pipe hydraulics to full two dimensional hydrodynamic
        processes. A key limitation of
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        modelling approaches is the need for assumptions about joint probability of antecedent
        conditions (such as soil moisture and available storage in volume management solutions) and
        the characteristics of storm events <citation>b9_c3_r16</citation>. In addition,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        methods have traditionally only simulated runoff from burst rainfall and have not considered
        that runoff is also generated by pre-burst and post burst rainfall (see <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_s_9307w"/>). The magnitude of rainfall runoff in urban catchment may be
        under-estimated by
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        processes unless pre-burst rainfall is also counted in rainfall
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models. </para>
      <para>The limitations of rainfall
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models, and dramatic increases in the capacity and utilisation of computers has fostered the
        use of continuous simulation (<xref linkend="b4_ch3_s_5wtrv"
        /><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163207+1100"?> and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163200+1100" content=";"?>
        <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>) models that can account for continuous physical, conceptual and
        statistical processes in urban catchments. These methods have traditionally utilised real or
        synthetically generated rainfall sequences to understand the yield from water supply
        catchments and the behaviour of water and wastewater distribution networks. These methods
        are also used to estimate the behaviour of stormwater quality solutions in urban catchments
          <citation>b9_c6_r9</citation>.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        continuous simulation can also be employed to account for the interactions between climate
        processes, human interventions or behaviours and stormwater runoff from urban catchments
          <citation>b9_c4_r173</citation>. Pluviograph rainfall records with intervals of less than
        an hour (often 6 minute intervals) are used in continuous simulation of rainfall runoff from
        urban catchments. </para>
      <para>The continuous simulation method involves simulation of a rainfall runoff model over a
        time period of sufficient length to account for all of the important interactions between
        rainfall and catchment processes to produce an urban flood frequency analysis. Sufficient
        lengths of observed rainfall are usually not available to provide adequate information about
        rare runoff events and synthetic rainfall sequences are often required for continuous
        simulation models (<xref linkend="b4_ch3_s_6xe8d"/>; <xref linkend="b2_ch6"/>, ). Use of
        continuous simulation with synthetic rainfall inputs may require calibration of the rainfall
        model and the continuous runoff routing model (<xref linkend="b4_ch3_s_77dp8"/>).
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        all models require calibration and verification. </para>
      <para>An alternative use of continuous simulation is to derive the probability distribution of
        initial conditions prior to storm events such soil moisture storage, and available storage
        in rainwater tanks and
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153122+1000" content="bio-retention"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153122+1000"?>bioretention<?oxy_insert_end?>
        facilities <citation>b9_c3_r8,b9_c2_r31</citation>. These probability distributions of
        initial conditions are then utilised in
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        runoff routing models to determine runoff from urban catchments. Note that these types of
        probabilistic inputs are associated with complete storm events and will need to be applied
        in
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models using complete storm events or combinations of pre-burst and burst rainfall. </para>
      <para>Direct rainfall or
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162015+1100" content="rain on grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models combine hydrological and hydraulic processes to generate rainfall runoff and
        hydraulic routing in a single model. Rainfall is applied to each grid in a two dimensional
        hydraulic model to generate overland flows and discharges in conduits (<xref
          linkend="b6_ch4_s_9f1m8"/>). This method can provide more realistic representation of
        catchment storages and surface runoff processes including cross catchment flows. A fine grid
        of good quality topographic, losses and roughness data is required, and topography
        information will need to be edited to include key infrastructure such as street gutters,
        hydraulic structure, conveyance networks and road crowns <citation>b9_c6_r21</citation>.
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162015+1100" content="Rain on grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>Rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models should be calibrated to local historical spatial flood levels or flow data. Use of
        regional rainfall runoff parameters is not suitable for direct rainfall methods that are
        driven by local processes. </para>
      <para>There may also be a need to vary roughness parameters (such as
        Manning<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163344+1100"?>'<?oxy_insert_end?>s
        n) with flow depth
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for example,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163359+1100" content=":"?>
        <citation>b9_c6_r20+1</citation>; <citation>b9_c6_r12+1</citation>;
          <citation>b9_c6_r13+1</citation>) and carefully assign loss parameters in each grid
          <citation>b4_c2_r2</citation>. The results at local and sub-catchment scales may be
        unexpected as all flow paths are identified. The method is subject to a range of potential
        challenges including mathematical instabilities, unrealistic flows and large errors created
        by losses, variable roughness, long runtimes and shallow flow depths. These powerful direct
        rain methods are subject to ongoing research and model results should be interpreted with
        caution. It is imperative that
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162235+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
        check that catchment response with an alternative model and volume of runoff is consistent
        with loss model used (see <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_4i8gc"/>). If a rainfall excess model is
        used this represents the volume of runoff that appears at the catchment outlet not rainfall
        applied to the model so depression storage needs to factored into losses. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_9307w">
      <title>Choice of Rainfall</title>
      <para>Most hydrology and hydraulic models require rainfall inputs to estimate stormwater
        runoff and associated flood responses. The investigations underpinning the 2016 version of
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163456+1100" content="Australian Rainfall and Runoff"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163456+1100"?>ARR<?oxy_insert_end?>
        incorporated 30 years of additional data and science (<xref linkend="b2_ch1"/>) to develop
        improved design rainfall frameworks. There was also a need to incorporate climate change
        processes into design rainfall frameworks (<xref linkend="b2_ch2_s_3"/>). Design rainfalls
        are simpler and different to real or observed rainfall. More advanced design rainfalls that
        assume storm bursts and spatial uniform temporal patterns cannot capture that actual
        variability of observed rainfall. This insight motivated a change in practice from simple
        average rainfall intensity or single rainfall burst approaches to ensemble and Monte Carlo
        methods to better capture the natural variability of rainfall. </para>
      <para>The design of stormwater infrastructure and understanding of runoff for urban areas
        involves decisions at multiple scales. This insight can be combined with ensembles of design
        rainfall patterns to determine the appropriate rainfall inputs as shown
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for
        example<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163517+1100" content=","?>)
        by the Box and Whisker plot of peak runoff (discharge) to the catchment outlet in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_qdfwc"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_qdfwc">
        <title>Example of a Box and Whisker
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115800+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115759+1100" content="p"?>lot
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115802+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115802+1100" content="p"?>eak
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115805+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115804+1100" content="s"?>tormwater
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115808+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115808+1100" content="r"?>unoff
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115810+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115810+1100" content="u"?>tilised
          to
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115813+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115813+1100" content="s"?>elect
          the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115817+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115817+1100" content="c"?>ritical
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115821+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115820+1100" content="s"?>torm
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115823+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115822+1100" content="b"?>urst
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115825+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115825+1100" content="e"?>nsemble
          and
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115827+1100"?>O<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115827+1100" content="o"?>ther
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115832+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115832+1100" content="d"?>esign
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115836+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115835+1100" content="i"?>nformation</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9100.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_qdfwc"/> indicates highest average and median peak discharge is
        generated by the ensemble of 10 storm bursts of 25 minute duration at the catchment outlet.
        A small number of higher values of peak runoff also occur in the 45 minute (maximum value)
        and 120 minute (far outlier value) durations which could be used to test the potential
        maximum hazard of surface flows. Conveyance infrastructure within the catchment should be
        designed using ensembles of storms with durations up to and including 25 minutes to account
        for impacts of smaller duration storms upstream of the outlet. Different design ensembles
        may apply in situations that incorporate within catchment storage solutions and at different
        locations in the urban catchment.</para>
      <para>This improved approach to design rainfall inputs to models is particularly important for
        urban catchments that are significantly different to rural catchments because they generate
        runoff from majority of rainfall as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_bo594"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_bo594">
        <title>Rainfall
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115900+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115900+1100" content="r"?>unoff
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115858+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115857+1100" content="p"?>rocesses
          in
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115855+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115854+1100" content="u"?>rban
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115849+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115848+1100" content="c"?>atchments</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9101.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_bo594"/> demonstrates that urban runoff can be generated by
        pre-burst, burst and post-burst proportions of complete storms (entire storm event). There
        are many different configurations of pre-burst, burst and post-burst rainfall in real
        rainfall events that should be considered in analysis of urban hydrology. Urban designs
        based on a single burst pattern of rainfall or peak rainfall assumptions can overlook
        substantial runoff rates and volumes which may adversely impact on the performance of inlet
        structures in conveyance networks, volume management measures, roads and overland flow paths
          <citation>b9_c5_r1</citation>. </para>
      <para>A range of updated rainfall products are available from the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 Data Hub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?>, including new spatially distributed
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163750+1100" content="Intensity Frequency Duration data ("?>IFD<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163753+1100" content=")"?>,
        Areal Reduction factors (ARF), design temporal patterns for burst rainfall,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T163048+1000" content="hydrological losses"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T163048+1000"?>hydrological
        losses,<?oxy_insert_end?> and pre-burst rainfall – as summarised in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_t_f182x"/>. </para>
      <para>
        <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_f182x">
          <caption>Summary of
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163821+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163820+1100" content="u"?>pdated
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163825+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163824+1100" content="d"?>esign
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163828+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163827+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163832+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163830+1100" content="p"?>rocesses</caption>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Input</th>
              <th>ARR 1987</th>
              <th>Pre Update </th>
              <th>ARR 2016</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>IFD</td>
              <td>Paper maps</td>
              <td>BoM web page</td>
              <td>
                <para>Updated BoM web page. </para>
                <para><xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>ARF</td>
              <td>Figure 2.7 from US data</td>
              <td>FORGE work (except NSW)</td>
              <td>
                <para>New equations derived using Australian data. </para>
                <para><xref linkend="b2_ch4"/>.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Temporal patterns</td>
              <td>Single temporal pattern of design burst rainfall based on
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163850+1100" content="a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163851+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?>verage
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163854+1100" content="v"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163855+1100"?>V<?oxy_insert_end?>ariability
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163858+1100" content="m"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163858+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?>ethod
                (AVM)</td>
              <td>
                <para>AVM, filtered for embedded burst</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Ensemble of real storms. </para>
                <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5"/>.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Spatial pattern</td>
              <td>Centroid</td>
              <td>Spatially distributed IFD</td>
              <td>Spatially distributed IFD</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Climate change</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
              <td>
                <para>Factors available from<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164012+1100"?>
                  <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/> and<?oxy_insert_end?>
                  the<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163914+1100"?>
                  ARR<?oxy_insert_end?> Data<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163916+1100"?>
                  <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163917+1100" content="h"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163918+1100"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?>ub<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164116+1100"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164125+1100" content="&lt;para&gt;&lt;xref linkend=&quot;b1_ch6&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/para&gt;"?>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Losses</td>
              <td>State based advice, sometimes based on data</td>
              <td>Calibrated in the hydrologic Model.</td>
              <td>
                <para>Calibrated losses. Uncalibrated models use losses available from
                    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164052+1100"?><xref
                    linkend="b5_ch3"/> and <?oxy_insert_end?>the
                  <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163924+1100"?>ARR
                  D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163926+1100" content="d"?>ata<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163928+1100"?>
                  H<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163928+1100" content="h"?>ub. </para>
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164103+1100" content="&lt;para&gt;&lt;xref linkend=&quot;b5_ch3&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/para&gt;"?>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Pre burst </td>
              <td>Allegedly incorporated into advice</td>
              <td>mixed</td>
              <td>Estimates provided on
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100" content="Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100"?>Data
                Hub<?oxy_insert_end?>. Use 60 minute pre-burst rainfall with burst rainfall
                ensembles of durations less than 60 minutes</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </para>
      <para>The different rainfall inputs to hydrology and hydraulic models are discussed in <xref
          linkend="book2"/>. The updated IFD design rainfall data is available from the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?>. Derivation of the IFD data using the additional rainfall records
        is outlined in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s4_0"/> and the application of the updated IFD design
        rainfalls is presented in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s9_0"/>. </para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164350+1100" content="Areal Reduction Factors ("?>ARF<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164352+1100" content=")"?>
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164407+1100"?>are<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164406+1100" content="is"?>
        available from the ARR
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164411+1100" content="2016 "?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100" content="Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100"?>Data
        Hub<?oxy_insert_end?> and is discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch4"/>. Design rainfalls
        (<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164438+1100" content="such as "?>IFD)
        only apply at a point in a catchment. When estimates of rainfall runoff are required for
        catchments with areas greater than 10 km<superscript>2</superscript>, the design rainfall
        intensities at a point are not representative of the areal average rainfall intensity for
        the entire catchment. The ARF is the ratio between the design values of areal average
        rainfall and point rainfall, for same duration and Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP).
        Application of ARF is outlined in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_q7liu"/>.</para>
      <para>Most runoff routing methods utilise design temporal patterns to determine the timing of
        rainfall falling on catchment and generate hydrographs of runoff. The traditional use of a
        single average temporal pattern has been found to be inadequate for hydrological analysis
        due to the variability of natural rainfall patterns (<xref linkend="b2_ch5"/>) and of the
        characteristics of urban catchments (<xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). The application of design
        temporal patterns as outlined in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_16"/>. Ensembles of design temporal
        patterns that are more likely to capture these natural and human variabilities are available
        from the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?>. It is noted that two different ensemble patterns are provided,
        point rainfall patterns for catchments with areas up to 75 km<superscript>2</superscript>
        and areal rainfall patterns for catchments with areas greater than 75
          km<superscript>2</superscript>. </para>
      <para>Climate change has the potential to alter the frequency and severity of rainfall events,
        storm surge and floods by altering rainfall IFD relationships, rainfall temporal patterns,
        continuous rainfall sequences, antecedent conditions and baseflow regimes (<xref
          linkend="b1_ch6"/>; <xref linkend="b2_ch2_s_3"/>). Interim climate change factors are
        presented as changes in average temperature and associated percentage increases in rainfall
        intensity for selected global climate models (GCM) in the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?>. These values should be applied in the context of the risk
        decision tree processes provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_g9sbm"/>. These interim values
        are subject to continuing research and evolving science. </para>
      <para>The
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?> provides regional rural losses for complete storms and pre-burst
        rainfall. In urban areas, the median values of local losses should be utilised wherever
        possible. The average initial losses from urban impervious surfaces is less than 1 mm (<xref
          linkend="b4ch2_s_0hsvn"/>) and ranges from 1 mm to 4 mm for urban effective impervious
        areas (<xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/>). In most cases, storm burst loss is equal to median
        storm loss less pre-burst rainfall. </para>
      <para>Rural and regional loss assumptions should not be a default assumption for urban areas
        and a hierarchy for selecting urban losses is highlighted as follows:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use local losses based on GIS investigations, local knowledge and observations.
            Losses derived at a regional scale are not local
            losses<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153205+1000" content=" -"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153205+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?>
            use local losses in small scale models. Note that a well-constructed model with adequate
            spatial scale should account for effective impervious area and connectivity
            effects</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Regional losses (<xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_dewgv"
            />): Impervious area losses: IL: &lt;1 mm, CL: 0 mm/hr; Effective Impervious Area: IL:
            1-2 mm, CL: 0 mm/hr; Pervious area ≈ rural losses</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Rural losses: Urban losses are some proportion of rural losses</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>Continuous simulation of rainfall runoff processes is aided by the increased
        availability of continuous (also known as pluviograph or instantaneous) rainfall from the
        Australian Bureau of Meteorology (BOM).
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        as discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_laai8"/>, longer synthetic continuous rainfall
        records are usually required to understand the impacts of rarer runoff events. Development
        and availability of synthetic continuous rainfall sequences are discussed in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch6"/>. Additional discussion of synthetic continuous rainfall records that
        incorporate regional layers (surfaces) of spatial observed climate observations is also
        provided by <citation>b9_c4_r173+1</citation> and
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115415+1100"?><citation>b9_c6_r200+1</citation><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115408+1100" content="Coombes and Barry (2018)"?>.
        ARR 2016 also provides software to generate multi-site continuous synthetic rainfall
        (Multi-site Rainfall Simulator) at
        arr.ga.gov.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164745+1100"?>au<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164744+1100" content="org"?>. </para>
      <para>Radar rainfall (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164755+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164754+1100" content="see"?>
        <citation>b9_c6_r3+1</citation>) can be used to interpolate between point rainfall
        observations for use in hydrology and 2D hydraulic models. There have been many studies that
        have developed methods to correct errors in radar rainfall but some residual errors are
        intrinsic to radar rainfall that should be resolved by spatial and temporal comparison to
        point rainfall observations.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_rhstb">
      <title>Runoff
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115444+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115443+1100" content="f"?>rom
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115441+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115441+1100" content="p"?>roperties</title>
      <para>Stormwater runoff from roofs and properties, at the lot scale, is the basic building
        block of urban stormwater catchment behaviour
        (<citation>b5_c3_r30,b9_c6_r17</citation><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163616+1100"?> and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163615+1100" content=";"?>
        <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). Runoff from properties involves a complex interaction of roofs,
        yards, paved areas, gardens, and adjoining roads and footpaths as shown for a residential
        property in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_4txi2"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_4txi2">
        <title>Stormwater
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120204+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120204+1100" content="r"?>unoff
          from
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120207+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120206+1100" content="r"?>oofs
          and
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120209+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120209+1100" content="p"?>roperties
          –
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120212+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120211+1100" content="l"?>ot
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120215+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120215+1100" content="s"?>cale
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120219+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120219+1100" content="e"?>ffects</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9102.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_4txi2"/> demonstrates the pathways of stormwater runoff from
        different surfaces within a property. These runoff processes are dominated by directly
        connected impervious surfaces, indirectly connected surfaces and pervious surfaces. Rain
        falling on impervious roof surfaces flow into roof gutter storages which discharge via
        downpipes into pipes connected to the street gutter or pipe network. Runoff from impervious
        driveway surfaces and adjacent road surfaces discharge to street gutters. These impervious
        surfaces facilitate highly efficient translation of rainfall into runoff, are subject to
        small depression storage losses, and are mostly directly connected to street gutters. Rain
        falling on pervious yard areas is partially retained in depression storages and infiltrates
        into soil profiles prior to generation of runoff from residual rainfall. These types of
        pervious surfaces are relatively inefficient at generating runoff and are often indirectly
        connected to street gutters or pipe networks. Urban properties can also include impervious
        areas that discharge stormwater to pervious surfaces or storages
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T163627+1100" content=";"?>
        rainwater tanks, onsite detention and raingardens) that partially disconnect these surfaces
        from street gutters. </para>
      <para>Runoff from impervious surfaces may also arrive at street gutters more rapidly than
        runoff from pervious surfaces. In many situations, pervious surfaces may not generate runoff
        for frequent rainfall events. These runoff behaviours are influenced by the configuration of
        property assets (including building form), topography and stormwater management measures. In
        situations where allotments slope away from roads, runoff from roofs and impervious surfaces
        may be directed to an inter-allotment conveyance (easement drainage) network. Local
        authorities will often specify locations of stormwater discharges from properties – this is
        known as a legal discharge point. Subsoil drains are sometimes used on properties to lower
        water tables around buildings or in waterlogged areas and discharge stormwater from
        properties. </para>
      <para>Property scale influences are fundamental to urban stormwater runoff.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        there has been limited testing at this scale <citation>b9_c6_r17</citation>, and designs of
        roof and property drainage are not clearly defined <citation>b9_c6_r11</citation>. A major
        challenge for simulation of urban stormwater runoff is the behaviour of individual
        properties and accumulation of these property behaviours throughout urban catchments
          (<citation>b5_c3_r31,b9_c5_r2</citation>; <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). The cumulative
        impacts of properties on the behaviour of catchments are defined by the timing, volume and
        rate of stormwater runoff from each property. The runoff behaviour of properties can also be
        altered by a range of onsite stormwater management approaches including disconnection of
        roof downpipes from street gutters, raingardens, landscaping, rainwater tanks, infiltration
        measures, onsite detention and green spaces (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164905+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164904+1100" content="See"?>
        <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>). Local authorities can apply
        restrictions on the flowrate, quantity and quality of stormwater that discharges from a
        property to encourage onsite management of stormwater to avoid or reduce downstream impacts
          <citation>b9_c6_r4,b9_c6_r15,b9_c2_r61,b9_c6_r8</citation>. </para>
      <para>Calibration or verification of urban stormwater modelling frameworks at the catchment
        scale does not imply that the sub-catchment or local behaviours in models are also correctly
        described <citation>b5_c3_r30,b9_c6_r17,b9_c3_r16,b9_c5_r2</citation>. Attention to local
        detail in stormwater design is required to ensure that potentially overlooked local
        processes do not generate local failures or excessive infrastructure or unexpected
        downstream consequences. The problems generated by approximated local behaviours can become
        worse in areas subject to increasing urban density and infill development.
          <citation>b9_c6_r10+1</citation>,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161048+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> found that increases in urban density of 18% generated 16%
        increase in runoff volumes and a 300% increase in expected flood damages for 20% AEP storm
        events. </para>
      <para>Simple methods for design of roof gutters, downpipes and property drainage are provided
        in Australian Standards
        (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164937+1100"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164936+1100" content="such as"?>
        AS/NZS 3500.3), by suppliers of roofing materials, government authorities and the Plumbing
        Code of Australia. These approaches include nominal and general methods. Nominal methods
        apply to single dwellings on properties with land areas up to 1,000
          m<superscript>2</superscript> by providing “deemed to comply” specifications of
        infrastructure (configuration, minimum pipe sizes, depth of cover over pipes and slopes). </para>
      <para>Design calculations are provided for more complex land uses and larger properties. These
        guidelines highlight the need to avoid ponding against buildings, flows into buildings and
        management of overland flows from adjoining properties. Large residential, commercial and
        industrial properties and
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153305+1000" content="carparks"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153305+1000"?>car
        parks<?oxy_insert_end?> include more complex and dendritic stormwater management systems as
        shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_lb3w0"/>
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for
        example<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164957+1100" content=","?>). </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_lb3w0">
        <title>Stormwater
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165005+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165005+1100" content="m"?>anagement
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165008+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165008+1100" content="s"?>ystem
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165011+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165011+1100" content="l"?>arger
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165015+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165014+1100" content="p"?>roperties
          with
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165018+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165018+1100" content="c"?>omplex
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165021+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165020+1100" content="l"?>and
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165023+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165023+1100" content="u"?>ses</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9103.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_lb3w0"/> shows that stormwater management schemes within
        properties may combine multiple pathways of stormwater runoff from different surfaces that
        have variable levels of connection to the street gutter or inlet pit in the street
        conveyance network. The performance of these networks may be affected by in-pipe attenuation
        effects, volume management measures, and substantial variations in the timing and magnitude
        of runoff to sub-catchment outlets. These outflows from properties are surface flows, or
        direct inflows to pipe networks in streets or inter-allotment conveyance networks.</para>
      <para>Approximate or general design methods are based in rules derived from simple Rational
        Method assumptions and utilise catchment areas (roofs, paved surfaces and gardens),
        proportions of imperviousness, slopes, assumed times of concentration with associated
        average rainfall intensities and runoff coefficients to generate maximum or peak flow rates.
        A five minute time of concentration and associated rainfall intensity was commonly assumed
        in design processes for roof and property drainage. Performance standards for roofs have
        been defined by choice of rainfall intensity of a 5% AEP for roof gutters and of a 1% AEP
        for box gutters. Design of conveyance networks within properties aim to avoid surcharges and
        overland flows for 1 EY in low density areas and up to 5% AEP for important land uses (such
        as hospitals and aged care facilities) that may be vulnerable to greater risk or
        inconvenience. The volume, pattern and timing of stormwater runoff are not considered in
        these approaches which may lead to under-performance of stormwater management measures
        included unexpected surface flows on properties. </para>
      <para>Field measurements suggest that travel time to street gutters from residential
        properties is two minutes or less
          <citation>b9_c6_r17<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115222+1100"?>,
          b9_c6_r201<?oxy_insert_end?></citation><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115246+1100" content=" Coombes 2002)"?>.
        The assumption of five minute time of concentration in ARR87 was based on the lowest
        available time interval of IFD rainfall at the time. Revised
        IFDs<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165342+1100" content=" are"?>
        available from the <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165305+1100" content="ARR 2016 Datahub (data.arr-software.org)"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165305+1100"?>BoM<?oxy_insert_end?>
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165340+1100" content="that "?>provide
        values for rainfall intensity that commence at a one minute duration which permits use of
        finer detail in design and to account for shorter flow times to outlets. Observations by
          <citation>b9_c6_r17+1</citation>, <citation>b5_c3_r31+1</citation> and
          <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115305+1100" content="Coombes (2002)"?><?oxy_custom_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T115305+1100"?><citation>b9_c6_r201+1</citation><?oxy_insert_end?>
        indicate that initial losses from roof gutter systems range from 0 mm to 1 mm and continuing
        losses range from 0% for metal roofs to 20% for dry tile roofs. Average depression storage
        losses of impervious surfaces can range from 1 mm to 10 mm and average losses from pervious
        surfaces range from 2 mm to 20 mm. </para>
      <para><citation>b5_c3_r29+1</citation> highlighted that spatial and temporal patterns of
        rainfall losses and their magnitude have significant impacts on peak stormwater runoff.
        Larger scale and more general estimates of losses are provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>.
        Wherever possible, local information on losses should be incorporated in analysis of
        stormwater runoff and associated designs of infrastructure.</para>
      <para>More detailed hydrograph routing methods may be required for larger properties with
        complex land uses to design infrastructure for given performance standards, and to
        understand the behaviour of the stormwater management system. The need to manage inflows of
        groundwater and surface runoff to basements on some properties will also require volume
        based analysis to understand the extent of flooding and to design pump out infrastructure.
          <citation>b9_c6_r1+1</citation> provides a range of simple methods for including volumes
        in the small scale design processes that are known as “regime in balance” and accounting for
        “emptying times” of storages.</para>
      <para>Stormwater management strategies for larger or more complex properties should be
        designed or analysed using
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        hydrograph routing methods that utilise storm burst patterns and pre-burst rainfall as
        inputs. The pre-burst rainfall, rainfall intensities and patterns of storm bursts for a
        given location can be downloaded from the ARR<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165401+1100"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100" content="2016 Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100"?>Data
        Hub<?oxy_insert_end?> (data.arr-software.org) and included in models of stormwater runoff.
        These rainfall inputs are provided in most proprietary software packages. </para>
      <para>This modelling process includes details of different surfaces within sub-catchments that
        influence stormwater runoff to inlet structures within the property stormwater management
        network. The analysis should include the characteristics of pervious and impervious surfaces
        – such as initial and continuing losses, sub-catchment areas, slopes and details of overland
        flow paths. This approach is similar to the design and analysis process for public
        stormwater conveyance (street drainage) networks. </para>
      <para>Use of ensembles of storm burst rainfall will ensure that the stormwater management
        system for a property is tested by a range of equally likely storm patterns and volumes of
        rainfall. This will permit a more complete understanding of potential surface flow paths
        within the property and in the adjacent street gutter, and the impacts on downstream
        infrastructure.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        use of complete storms or inclusion of pre-burst rainfall with the burst rainfall patterns
        will assist with defining the likely magnitude of overland flow behaviours at the property.
        Initial losses in the analysis may need to be set to zero if the magnitude of pre-burst
        rainfall is greater than the capacity of depression storages on the property. At some
        locations, the residual pre-burst rainfall may also contribute to additional runoff and
        overland flows within the property. These approaches can be combined in a range of computer
        modelling packages. </para>
      <para>The ability of peak flow or
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models to describe runoff behaviours are limited in situations where the joint probability
        of antecedent conditions and storm events is not well defined (See <xref
          linkend="b4_ch3_s_5wtrv"/>) and there are continuous responses to complete storm events.
        These limitations apply to stormwater strategies that include volume storage measures,
        rainwater or stormwater harvesting, and water quality solutions. </para>
      <para>In these situations, continuous simulation using real local rainfall or synthetic
        rainfall sequences can be utilised to test the continuous interactions between key
        components of the stormwater management. The results from continuous simulation can be
        directly interrogated to understand key performance criteria such as annual average
        reduction in water demand, stormwater runoff and nitrogen loads created by rainwater
        harvesting and raingardens. Alternatively, continuous simulation can provide distributions
        of available storage in volume management measures (such as rainwater tanks, infiltration
        measures and
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153352+1000" content="bio-retention"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153352+1000"?>bioretention<?oxy_insert_end?>
        devices) or soil profiles prior to storm events versus frequency of storm events that can be
        used in
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        analysis <citation>b9_c4_r114,b9_c2_r31</citation> as shown,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161048+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ct2xs"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_ct2xs">
        <title>Example
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120250+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120250+1100" content="d"?>istribution
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120257+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120257+1100" content="a"?>vailable
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120300+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120259+1100" content="s"?>torage
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120302+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120301+1100" content="p"?>rior
          to
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120304+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120304+1100" content="s"?>torm
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120306+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120306+1100" content="e"?>vents
          versus
          <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153403+1000" content="a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153405+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?>nnual
          <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153406+1000" content="e"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153406+1000"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?>xceedance
          <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153407+1000" content="p"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153408+1000"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?>robability
          (AEP) of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120313+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120311+1100" content="s"?>torm
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120315+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120315+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9104.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ct2xs"/>
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?>) demonstrates the average retention storage available in
        rainwater tank (capacity of 5 m<superscript>3</superscript> collecting runoff from a 100
          m<superscript>2</superscript> roof area and supplying household indoor and outdoor uses)
        prior to storm events of a given AEP that was derived using continuous simulation. This type
        of information can be used in
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models to determine stormwater peak flows and runoff volumes. These results will vary
        significantly with different land uses, building form and throughout Australia. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_4i8gc">
      <title>Sub-<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165437+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165437+1100" content="c"?>atchment
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165435+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165434+1100" content="r"?>unoff
        to
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165440+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165440+1100" content="i"?>nlet
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165442+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165442+1100" content="s"?>tructures</title>
      <para>Sub-catchments define an urban area that discharges stormwater runoff to an inlet
        structure within a stormwater management network. There is further discussion of conveyance
        networks in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_seut7"/> to <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_h00bb"/> and of
        inlet structures in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_wtcce"/>. The configuration and characteristics
        of the urban area within a sub-catchment will define the hydrological response that produces
        stormwater inflows to a stormwater network. These surface flows define the performance of an
        inlet structure as inflows to a conveyance network and as surface bypass flows. An example
        of a simple urban sub-catchment is provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ypdw2"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_ypdw2">
        <title>Example of a
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165446+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165446+1100" content="s"?>imple
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165450+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165448+1100" content="u"?>rban
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165452+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165452+1100" content="s"?>tormwater
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165455+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165454+1100" content="s"?>ub-<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165457+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165456+1100" content="c"?>atchment</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9105.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ypdw2"/> highlights that an urban sub-catchment may contain a
        range of different land uses, including
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for
        example<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165505+1100" content=","?>)
        unit and detached residential dwellings on properties, a park and part of a road. These land
        uses incorporate different surfaces, including roofs, paved areas (impervious), garden and
        grassed areas (pervious) that produce different regimes of stormwater runoff. </para>
      <para>The behaviour of the sub-catchment surfaces can be estimated using lumped catchment
        approximations which are based on sub-catchment area, the total proportion of imperviousness
        (TIA) and a travel time (or time of concentration) for a critical rainfall duration to the
        inlet structure (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165526+1100"?>refer <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165525+1100" content="see"?>
        <xref linkend="b5_ch2_s_002"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_wtcce"/>).
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161021+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> a sub-catchment area of 4,250 m<superscript>2</superscript> with
        an impervious proportion of 56% and time of concentration which depends on rainfall
        intensity, slope and distance to inlet structure. In the absence of other data, these types
        of approximations could be used in simple calculations or in computer models.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        it is preferable to construct analysis of urban sub-catchments using local details which can
        be sourced from site inspection, survey plans and inquiry using
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165536+1100" content="Geographical Information Systems ("?>GIS<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165538+1100" content=")"?>. </para>
      <para>Impervious or pervious surfaces can be directly connected or disconnected to inlet
        structures in conveyance networks. These surfaces may be also distant from the inlet
        structure or near the inlet. Thus the level of connectedness and distance of impervious
        areas from inlet structures should also be considered in analysis of stormwater runoff in
        urban areas. In addition, the analysis should account for surfaces that discharge to inlets
        via rapid conveyance mechanisms, such as street gutters, and for other surfaces that may
        discharge to inlets via slower conveyance processes such as across pervious surfaces (green
        spaces) or via storages. </para>
      <para>An urban sub-catchment often includes depression storages, and a mosaic of different
        surfaces, runoff rates, storages and cumulative connectivity. The order of actions in the
        connectivity of different types of surfaces with storages to the inlet can dramatically
        change travel times and peak flows. Roofs may discharge via pipes to street gutters that
        facilitate rapid transfer of runoff volume to inlets. Runoff from road surfaces to the
        gutter may arrive at a similar or earlier time (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165607+1100"?>refer<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165606+1100" content="see"?>
        <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ypdw2"/>). </para>
      <para>It is unlikely that lumped catchment approximations will provide reliable estimates of
        stormwater runoff from urban sub-catchments that include a range of different land uses and
        catchment storages with variable connectivity to inlets. Use of lumped catchment with TIA
        approximations may generate over-estimations of stormwater peak flows. Distributed methods
        of analysis may be more appropriate for ungauged catchments, where there are storages within
        catchments or for analysis using more robust runoff routing in computer models. </para>
      <para>Urban sub-catchments include directly connected impervious areas (DCIA), indirectly
        connected impervious areas (IDCIA) and pervious areas as described in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/>. Limited regional investigations suggest that a combination of
        these effects produced effective impervious areas (EIA) which are
        55%<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153435+1000" content=" -"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153435+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?>
        65% of the TIA of urban sub-catchments. Estimates of indirectly connected areas are further
        impacted by interactions between impervious and pervious areas, by storage in sub-catchments
        with Water Sensitive Urban Design (WSUD) measures and are influenced by antecedent soil
        moisture conditions (AMC). </para>
      <para>Other impervious surfaces may discharge via driveways to the street gutter which
        produces a different time for stormwater runoff to reach the inlet structure. Pervious
        surfaces also discharge to the street gutter, partially via impervious surfaces, to the
        inlet. Thus the timing of the arrival of runoff volumes to the inlet is dependent on these
        many different configurations and characteristics within the sub-catchment. So the
        performance of the inlet structure and the magnitude of surface bypass flows are
        dramatically affected by these considerations. These complex processes can be better
        described by semi-distributed (link-node) and distributed (grid) computer models (<xref
          linkend="b5_ch2_s_009"/>; <xref linkend="b6_ch4_s_v3f40"/>) that explicitly combine these
        details with pre-burst rainfall and ensembles on burst rainfall patterns. </para>
      <para>Regional analysis of a small number of urban catchments provides estimated initial
        losses of 1 – 3 mm for EIA and 20 – 30 mm for indirectly connected areas in sub-catchments
          (<xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_dewgv"/>). Estimated median continuing losses were 2.5 mm/hour in
        South East Australia and 1 – 4 mm/hour elsewhere. These
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        regional values should only be used in the absence of local data. It is essential that
        assumptions about losses in stormwater models are based on assessment of local conditions.
        The magnitude of losses is also impacted by antecedent moisture conditions (AMC) which is
        altered by garden watering in urban areas and by available storage in volume management
        measures throughout the sub-catchment. It is unlikely that
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        models can fully account for these effects. Sensitivity checks, Monte Carlo processes and
        continuous simulation can be utilised to include the variation in AMC and available storage
        within urban sub-catchments. </para>
      <para>Urban drainage was historically designed using peak flows derived using peak rainfall
        intensity or peak rainfall bursts in accordance with the assumption that peak flowrates only
        affect conveyance infrastructure. Many urban drainage networks are operating below
        anticipated service levels due to a range of impacts including increased density of urban
        areas. Analysis by <citation>b2_c5_r40+1</citation> indicates that the absence of stormwater
        runoff volumes in design processes based on peak runoff assumptions may partially explain
        under-performance of some urban drainage networks. The performance of inlet structures and
        therefore drainage networks can also be affected by the volume of stormwater arriving at the
        structure, variations in rainfall temporal patterns and by pre-burst rainfall that was not
        included in the design process. The uncounted volumes of stormwater runoff in peak flow and
        storm burst assumptions can become additional and unexpected overland or bypass flows in
        urban systems. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_ooqab">
      <title>From the Inlet to the Outlet</title>
      <para>Rainfall runoff from sub-catchments accumulates as inflows to conveyance networks or as
        surface flows throughout urban catchments that discharge towards an outlet (<xref
          linkend="b9_ch5"/>). A network of conveyance infrastructure may incorporate pipes, open
        channels, roadways and open space. These networks often include water quality, volume
        management and flow control infrastructure (see <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>) that are
        incorporated in sub-catchment scale processes (such as source and neighbourhood controls:
        see <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_s4eek"/>) or as regional controls at the outlet.</para>
      <para>Analysis and design of stormwater management and flooding in urban areas was
        historically based on separate hydrology and hydraulic processes, and is focused at the
        network scale. A key objective of these processes was determination of flows in conveyance
        infrastructure such as pipes and open channels to avoid surcharges and bypass flows at
        inlets (see <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_wtcce"/>) to avoid nuisance, property damage and risk to
        life (see <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_j339y"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch8"/>). These urban
        conveyance networks include significant surface flows, usually along roads and through open
        spaces, from sub-catchments into and throughout conveyance networks. These flows from
        sub-catchments to inlets and within conveyance networks were determined as a hydrological
        process as an input to hydraulic models of conveyance networks (see <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5_s_iy2cb"/>and <xref linkend="b5_ch2"/>).</para>
      <para>The conveyance network is a framework of sub-catchment inputs. Urban stormwater design
        typically employed pipe network hydraulic models that utilise peak inflows or hydrographs as
        inputs (see <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_bfuec"/>). More advanced one dimensional models were
        also available that can be applied to simulation of conveyance networks (see <xref
          linkend="b6_ch4_s_utkoe"/>; <xref linkend="b5_ch6"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>). </para>
      <para>Overland or surface flows are a key consideration in analysis and design of urban
        stormwater management infrastructure. The dominant urban hydraulic response to rare rainfall
        events (such as 1% AEP) is often overland flows on roads and across open space. Emerging
        methods of analysis and design of urban stormwater involve combined hydrology and hydraulic
        models to better understand surface flows throughout urban catchments. These methods include
        coupled one and two dimensional models, and direct rainfall (rain on grid) models. <xref
          linkend="b6_ch4_s_v3f40"/>, and <citation>b4_c2_r2+1</citation> provide detailed
        discussion about these approaches. </para>
      <para>The flowrates, depth and area of surface flows in urban catchments are highly sensitive
        to different temporal patterns and volumes of rainfall <citation>b4_c2_r2</citation>.
        Similarly, <citation>b9_c3_r54+1</citation>, <citation>b5_c3_r31+1</citation> and
          <citation>b2_c5_r40+1</citation> found that the performance of conveyance infrastructure
        also varies with temporal patterns and volumes of rainfall. It is recommended that ensembles
        of ten temporal patterns of design rainfall are used for investigation of the hydrology and
        hydraulic processes in urban areas. The separation of hydrologic and hydraulic routing is
        often blurred in analysis of urban areas which fosters complicated decisions around the use
        of hydrologic inputs and their interaction with hydraulic models. An overview of the
        difference approaches to rainfall inputs provided by ARR 2016 is compared to ARR 1987
        approach in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_qf2b0"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_qf2b0">
        <title>Changes in
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165642+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165642+1100" content="d"?>esign
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165645+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165645+1100" content="m"?>odelling
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165648+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165647+1100" content="t"?>echniques
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165651+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165650+1100" content="u"?>rban
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165652+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165652+1100" content="a"?>reas</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9106.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_qf2b0"/> highlights that ARR 2016 provides ensembles of 10
        temporal patterns for each region that is a departure from the single event process
        supported by ARR 1987. These rainfall inputs can be used in hydrology and hydraulic
        modelling as required for different design and assessment tasks (see <xref linkend="b2_ch4"
        /> for further detail). The rapid assessment approach is not recommended for design of urban
        conveyance networks and the Monte Carlo processes can be used in special cases. It is
        expected that rainfall ensembles in hydrologic simulations, and in hydrologic and hydraulic
        simulations would be commonly utilised in urban conveyance networks. The process of using
        rainfall ensembles in hydrology is outlined in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_d4u19"/>. </para>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_d4u19"/> shows that the inputs to analysis of the conveyance
        network include
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165714+1100" content="Intensity Frequency Duration ("?>IFD<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165716+1100" content=")"?>
        information from the BOM, ensembles of rainfall temporal patterns, regional losses,
        pre-burst rainfall and Areal reduction factors from the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 Data Hub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?>. Wherever possible, local losses derived in accordance with <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_s_rhstb"/>and <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_4i8gc"/> should be used in
        preference to regional losses for urban areas. These inputs are used in a hydrology model to
        generate ensembles of peak flows throughout the urban catchment for various storm durations
        and the required quantiles or AEPs of storm events Mean peak flows are derived for key
        locations in the catchment and the rainfall temporal pattern that produces peak flows
        closest to the mean peak flows are utilised in the hydraulic model. This approach may be
        better suited to models with longer run times as considerable time can be expended
        determining critical durations in both hydrology and hydraulic models. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_d4u19">
        <title>Design
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165740+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165740+1100" content="p"?>rocess
          that
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165743+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165742+1100" content="u"?>tilises
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165744+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165744+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165746+1100" content="e"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165746+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?>nsembles
          in
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165750+1100" content="h"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165759+1100"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?>ydrology
          to
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165802+1100" content="s"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165802+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?>elect
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165804+1100"?>the
          R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165804+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165807+1100" content="p"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165809+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?>attern
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165817+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165817+1100" content="c"?>losest
          to
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165819+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165819+1100" content="m"?>ean
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165821+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165821+1100" content="p"?>eak
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165824+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165823+1100" content="f"?>lows
          for use in
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165828+1100"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165827+1100" content="h"?>ydraulic
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165830+1100" content="a"?>nalysis</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9107.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The processes outlined in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_d4u19"/> produce a single estimate of
        flood depth for each selected quantile or AEP. It is important to highlight that the
        critical rainfall duration and temporal pattern estimated using the hydrology model is
        likely to be different to the critical rainfall and temporal pattern relevant to the
        hydraulic simulations. These differences between critical hydrology and hydraulic inputs can
        have substantial impacts on the design of infrastructure and understanding of surface flows. </para>
      <para>In situations where the hydraulic impacts of the design processes are significant,
        rainfall ensembles can be used in the hydrologic and hydraulic simulations as outlined in
          <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_97wfi"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_97wfi">
        <title>Design
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120356+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120356+1100" content="p"?>rocess
          that
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120359+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120358+1100" content="u"?>tilises
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120401+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120401+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120404+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120403+1100" content="e"?>nsembles
          in
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120406+1100"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120406+1100" content="h"?>ydrology
          and
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120408+1100"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120408+1100" content="h"?>ydraulic
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120411+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120410+1100" content="s"?>imulations
          to
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120414+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120413+1100" content="s"?>elect
          the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120416+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120416+1100" content="m"?>ean
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120419+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120418+1100" content="p"?>attern
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120425+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120425+1100" content="a"?>nalysis
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120428+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120428+1100" content="f"?>looding</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9108.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_97wfi"/> outlines that process for utilising ensembles of
        rainfall patterns in hydrology and hydraulic models. This process is better suited to
        situations where there are shorter model run times, critical flooding considerations and for
        coupled hydrology and hydraulic models. The processes outlined in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_d4u19"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_97wfi"/> may also need to be
        applied to understand critical rainfall durations and patterns at key internal locations
        within catchments.</para>
      <para>A brownfield case study based on the Woolloomooloo catchment in Sydney demonstrates the
        use of ensemble temporal patterns of rainfall and effects on the performance of hydraulic
        models used for design or assessment of conveyance networks (see
          <citation>b9_c6_r18+1</citation>). The catchment area is approximately 1.6
          km<superscript>2</superscript> and has been heavily urbanised with limited open spaces or
        pervious areas. The catchment is also characterized by undulating terrain and contains known
        depression storages. The catchment drains to the harbour through a pit and pipe network,
        with the streets acting as overland flow paths (<xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_gywfk"/>).</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_gywfk">
        <title>The Woolloomooloo
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120438+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120438+1100" content="c"?>atchment
          in Sydney</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9109.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>ARR 2016 supports a number of modelling techniques and <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_okqdg"/>
        and <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_kby4c"/> provide guidance on selection of modelling approaches.
        Use of coupled 1D/2D and direct rain models were necessary to understand within catchment
        surface flows and flooding. The potentially short model run times and need to understand
        local flooding supports use of rainfall ensembles in both hydrology and hydraulics models.
        This study combined a well-known hydrology model with a popular 2D and 1D hydraulic model
        that relies on second order finite-difference schemes to simulate the hydrodynamics of
        floodplains and waterways. </para>
      <para>This case study discusses three modelling options that were designed to account for
        within catchment overland flows and flooding:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use of a hydrology model to generate overland flows from small sub-catchments for
            use in a coupled 1D/2D hydraulic model. Individual properties, roofs and small area land
            surfaces were assigned as sub-catchments (see <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_rhstb"/>) in the
            hydrologic model to capture the rainfall concentration phase of stormwater runoff into
            the hydraulic model. This approach is necessary to understand within catchment
            flooding.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A concentrated direct rainfall model where rainfall is applied to polygons of
            different land surfaces separated by perviousness and connectivity to the hydraulic
            1D/2D model. These concentrated land surfaces also account for rainfall losses.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Direct
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100" content="rainfall on grid"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162125+1100"?>rainfall-on-grid<?oxy_insert_end?>
            where rainfall, after accounting for initial and continuing losses, was applied to all
            active grid cells. A fixed grid of 2m<superscript>2</superscript> was employed in the
            hydraulic model.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Direct rainfall methods are known to trap volumes of rainfall in depressions and in
        areas with high roughness throughout 2D hydraulic models. The value of a carefully
        constructed direct rainfall model is the ability to identify sub-catchment flow paths,
        contributing areas and storage.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the modeller must ensure that catchment storages or initial losses are not doubled counted
        in simulations by the addition of regional loss assumptions. Given that there is a paucity
        of research into the accuracy of direct rainfall models, it is recommended that results of
        direct rainfall methods are compared with traditional methods by examination of the
        characteristics of hydrograph produced by both methods<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120545+1100"?>
        <citation>b4_c2_r2</citation><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120528+1100" content=" (Babister and Barton, 2012)"?>.
        A suitable method of representing buildings and good quality topography data is also
        required to produce accurate urban stormwater runoff behaviours. A mass balance or volume
        error check is also recommended.</para>
      <para>The historical process of determining rainfall loss parameters using ARR 1987
        assumptions, including soil type and antecedent moisture content parameters (AMC) from the
        ILSAX model, is provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_940mx"/> for comparison.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_940mx">
        <caption>ARR 1987
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120631+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120631+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120635+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120634+1100" content="l"?>oss
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120649+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120638+1100" content="p"?>arameters</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Paved Area Depression Storage (Initial Loss)</emphasis></td>
            <td>1.0 mm</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Grassed Area Depression Storage (Initial Loss)</emphasis></td>
            <td>5.0 mm</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">SOIL TYPE</emphasis></td>
            <td>3</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td colspan="2"><emphasis role="bold">Slow infiltration rates. This parameter, in
                conjunction with the AMC, determines the continuing loss</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">AMC</emphasis></td>
            <td>3</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Description</emphasis></td>
            <td>Rather wet</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Total Rainfall in 5 Days Preceding the Storm</emphasis></td>
            <td>12.5 to 25mm</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para>ARR 2016 provides a range of up-to-date parameters for use in analysis. The catchment is
        located within the East Coast South temporal pattern region. Temporal patterns for the East
        Coast South region and Intensity Frequency Duration (IFD) rainfall depths were downloaded
        from the ARR
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100" content="2016 Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100"?>Data
        Hub<?oxy_insert_end?> website. This information is combined to construct ensembles of 10
        rainfall patterns for the required flood quantiles (AEP). We focus on 1% AEP storm events
        for this case study. The initial and continuing storm losses of 28 mm and 1.6 mm/hour for
        rural areas, and median pre-burst rainfall of 1.1 mm associated with a one hour 1% AEP storm
        event can also be downloaded from the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100" content="Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?>.</para>
      <para>It is recommended that varied rainfall losses are applied to different types of surfaces
        in the catchment. These surfaces include urban pervious areas such as parks, and impervious
        areas such as roads, median strips and building roofs. The identified impervious areas were
        split up into Effective Impervious Area (EIA) and Indirectly Connected Impervious Area
        (ICIA). </para>
      <para>Effective Impervious Area represents the portion of a catchment area that has an
        impervious response. Due to the highly urbanised nature of the catchment this portion was
        identified as 75% of the total impervious area. The remaining area that is not classified as
        Effective Impervious Area is Indirectly Connected Impervious Area (25%). Building roofs were
        identified separately as Indirectly Connected Impervious Area as the down pipes were not
        assumed to directly discharge into the storm water pipes. The information from the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100" content="Datahub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164240+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?> is modified by loss values for urban catchments that are provided
        in <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/> and in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_s_rhstb"/> as summarised in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_t_eubj1"/>.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_eubj1">
        <caption>ARR 2016
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120657+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120657+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120700+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120659+1100" content="l"?>oss
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120702+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120702+1100" content="p"?>arameters
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120705+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120705+1100" content="u"?>rban
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120708+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120708+1100" content="a"?>reas</caption>
        <col width="33%"/>
        <col width="33%"/>
        <col width="33%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Urban Area</emphasis></th>
            <th>Storm Initial Loss (mm)</th>
            <th>Continuing Loss (mm/hr)</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Effective Impervious Area</td>
            <td>1 – 2 mm</td>
            <td>0 </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Indirectly Connected Area</td>
            <td>60 to 80% of rural catchment losses</td>
            <td>
              <para>For south eastern Australia, a typical value of 2.5mm/h, with a range of 1 to 3
                mm/h, would be appropriate. This value should be adjusted based on engineering
                judgement and reviewing the catchment characteristics such as soil types,
                interaction of indirectly connected impervious areas with pervious areas.</para>
              <para>For other areas, adopt a range of 1 to 4 mm/h.</para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Urban Pervious Area</td>
            <td colspan="2">Traditionally,
              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162223+1100" content="practitioner"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T162223+1100"?>designer<?oxy_insert_end?>s
              have adopted similar loss values for these areas as for those they would adopt in
              rural areas.</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para>In
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000" content="event based"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T155601+1000"?>event-based<?oxy_insert_end?>
        modelling approaches, it is important to subtract pre-burst rainfall from local losses
        associated with impervious and pervious surfaces as follows:</para>
      <para>Burst initial loss = storm initial losses – pre-burst rainfall (for Burst Loss ≥
        0)</para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161021+1000"?>For
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> the burst initial loss for effective impervious area is 1.5 – 1.1
        = 0.4 mm. The adopted burst losses for the urban surfaces are presented in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_t_rxgjp"/>. Note that in a situation where pre-burst rainfall is greater
        than the storm initial losses, the residual pre-burst rainfall should be included in the
        analysis.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_rxgjp">
        <caption>Adopted ARR 2016
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120716+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120716+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120720+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120719+1100" content="l"?>oss
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120723+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120723+1100" content="p"?>arameters</caption>
        <col width="33%"/>
        <col width="33%"/>
        <col width="33%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Urban Surface</th>
            <th>Burst Initial Loss (mm)</th>
            <th>Continuing Loss (mm/hr)</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Effective Impervious Area</td>
            <td>0.4</td>
            <td>0</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Indirectly Connected Area</td>
            <td>16.1</td>
            <td>1.6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Urban Pervious Area</td>
            <td>26.9</td>
            <td>1.6</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para>Hydraulic and associated flood behaviour is influenced by the hydraulic resistance due
        to topography and urban form. The selection of appropriate roughness coefficients is
        critical to the success of this approach (see <xref linkend="b6_ch4"/>). Depth varying
        Manning’s “n” roughness parameters were selected for each land use to account for shallow
        overland flow depths across urban surfaces. Some hydraulic modelling packages provide this
        capability in accordance with emerging research into depth varying roughness
        (<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000"?>for example,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T165939+1100" content=":"?>
        <citation>b9_c6_r20,b9_c6_r12,b9_c6_r13</citation>). </para>
      <para>Analysis of the performance of urban conveyance networks is critically dependent on
        potential blockage of inlet structures (<xref linkend="b6_ch6"/>; <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5_s_wtcce"/>) and the need to address safety design criteria (see <xref
          linkend="b9_ch8"/>; <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_h00bb"/>). Assessment of potential blockage of
        inlet structures should also consider data from local authorities about maintenance programs
        and local flooding <citation>b9_c6_r19</citation>. The assumed blockage factors for inlet
        pits subject to runoff from 1% AEP rainfall events were derived from <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5_s_wtcce"/>, from local government historical records, and maintenance
        programs (see <xref linkend="b6_ch6_t_2fnk8"/>), from <citation>b9_c6_r19+1</citation> and
        are presented in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_mngrm"/>.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_mngrm">
        <caption>Assumed
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120745+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120744+1100" content="c"?>apacity
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120741+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120740+1100" content="i"?>nlet
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120738+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120738+1100" content="p"?>its
          for 1% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120732+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120732+1100" content="r"?>ain
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120734+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120734+1100" content="e"?>vents</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th colspan="2">Sag Inlet Pit</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Kerb Inlet</emphasis></td>
            <td>80%</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Grated Inlet</emphasis></td>
            <td>50%</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Combination</emphasis></td>
            <td>Assume Grate 100% blocked</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td colspan="2"><emphasis role="bold">On-grade Inlet Pit</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Kerb Inlet</emphasis></td>
            <td>80%</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Grated Inlet</emphasis></td>
            <td>60%</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Combination</emphasis></td>
            <td>90%</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para> The critical rainfall duration for the catchment was derived using the ensembles of
        rainfall temporal patterns in the combined hydrology and 2D hydraulic model to reveal the
        highest mean and median flood elevations at key locations as shown for in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_yhgjo"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_yhgjo">
        <title>Use of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120758+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120757+1100" content="e"?>nsembles
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120802+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120802+1100" content="s"?>torm
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120805+1100" content="b"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120809+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?>ursts
          (1% AEP) in the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120813+1100"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120813+1100" content="h"?>ydraulic
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120816+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120816+1100" content="m"?>odel
          to
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120819+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120818+1100" content="s"?>elect
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120822+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120822+1100" content="c"?>ritical
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120825+1100" content="d"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120832+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?>uration</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9110.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_yhgjo"/> reveals that the use of ensembles of rainfall in the
        hydraulic model indicates that different critical rainfall durations apply throughout the
        catchment. The results from <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_yhgjo"/> were used with consideration of
        the characteristics of the catchment to select the critical storm duration of 60 minutes.
        The impact on stormwater runoff from using the single storm burst pattern from ARR 1987 is
        compared to use of an ensemble of ten storm burst patterns (1% AEP) from ARR 2016 for part
        of the Wooloomooloo catchment in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_mb2m4"/>. This graph presents ten
        hydrographs of stormwater runoff in the trunk drainage system at Bourke Street confluence. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_mb2m4">
        <title>Example of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120856+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120855+1100" content="r"?>unoff
          from ARR 1987
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120859+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120858+1100" content="s"?>ingle
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120901+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120901+1100" content="s"?>torm
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120903+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120903+1100" content="b"?>urst
          and ARR 2016
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120907+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120907+1100" content="e"?>nsembles
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120910+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120909+1100" content="s"?>torm
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120913+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120913+1100" content="b"?>ursts
          (1% AEP)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9111.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_mb2m4"/> demonstrates that a single pattern of burst rainfall
        from ARR 1987 produces a different hydrograph shape, volume and peak runoff at the catchment
        outlet to the ensemble of storm burst patterns from ARR 2016. This difference is driven by
        the 30 years of additional data and science available to ARR 2016 that has allowed the
        derivations of more spatially relevant rainfall and temporal patterns. The variability of
        the equally likely storm burst patterns from the ARR 2016 ensembles facilitates testing of
        catchment characteristics for generation of maximum runoff. </para>
      <para>The direct rainfall method applies rainfall directly to all grid cells and the scale of
        routing is at every 2 m by 2 m grid cell. In this approach the depth of flow is shallow and
        rainfall can get stuck on the model grid. To maintain the area of rainfall applied to the
        grid, the buildings were nulled (removed) from the actual grid and rainfall was scaled up to
        account for the lost building areas. </para>
      <para>The concentrated direct rainfall method applied rainfall to polygons of different local
        surfaces such as buildings and parks. This process permits the specification of the area,
        initial and continuing losses that are applied to each land use polygon. Separate attributes
        are applied to roofs to account for the different connectivity to concentrated stormwater
        flows. </para>
      <para>A manual volume check should be undertaken on all direct rainfall model configurations.
        The volume of water leaving the model through the downstream boundary should be equal to the
        amount of water that was applied (via direct rainfall and inflows across external
        boundaries), less losses and storages within the model. The upper portion of the catchment
        (area of 52.8 Ha) was assessed to maximize the volume of water that drains from the
        catchment at the last time step. The characteristics of the upper catchment are shown in
          <xref linkend="b9_ch6_t_nvmut"/>.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch6_t_nvmut">
        <caption>Characteristics of the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120929+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120929+1100" content="u"?>pper
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120932+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120931+1100" content="c"?>atchment
          used in the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120935+1100"?>V<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120934+1100" content="v"?>olume
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120938+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120938+1100" content="c"?>heck</caption>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Type</th>
            <th>Catchment Area (m<superscript>2</superscript>)</th>
            <th>IL (mm</th>
            <th>CL (mm/hr)</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">100% Pervious</emphasis></td>
            <td>22,508</td>
            <td>26.9</td>
            <td>1.6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">100% Impervious</emphasis></td>
            <td>102,607</td>
            <td>0.4</td>
            <td>0.0</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">EIA</emphasis></td>
            <td>133,909</td>
            <td>0.4</td>
            <td>0.0</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">ICIA</emphasis></td>
            <td>34,549</td>
            <td>16.14</td>
            <td>1.6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">ICIA (Buildings)</emphasis></td>
            <td>234,630</td>
            <td>16.14</td>
            <td>1.6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">AVERAGE LOSS</emphasis></td>
            <td/>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">11.4</emphasis></td>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">0.9</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">TOTAL (m<superscript>2</superscript>)</emphasis></td>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">528,202</emphasis></td>
            <td/>
            <td/>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para>The model run was extended to allow all stormwater to drain from the catchment by
        extrapolating the outflow curve towards zero. Inflow volume was calculated as the cumulative
        depth of rainfall less initial and continuing losses multiplied by the area of the
        catchment. Flows extracted from the hydraulic model 1D results can also be converted into
        volumes. A flow line along the upstream catchment divide together with outflow boundaries
        were used in the 2D hydraulic model to also account for the volume of overland flows leaving
        the catchment. These results can be presented as a cumulative depth graph or as a pie chart
        (see <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_jngvl"/>) </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_jngvl">
        <title>Upper
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120949+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120949+1100" content="c"?>atchment
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120952+1100"?>V<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120951+1100" content="v"?>olume
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120954+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120953+1100" content="c"?>heck
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120957+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120956+1100" content="d"?>irect
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121004+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T120959+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121008+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121007+1100" content="m"?>odel
          (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121016+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121015+1100" content="p"?>rior
          to
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121018+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121018+1100" content="c"?>orrections)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9112.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_jngvl"/> shows 5,750 m<superscript>3</superscript> (14%) of
        rainfall was retained in the model (11 mm) which is described as the volume balance. An
        acceptable error or additional retention of stormwater is less than 5% which indicates a
        need to reduce initial losses used in the direct rain model. Accounting for volumes of
        depression storage in the catchment topography by decreasing initial rainfall losses will
        increase in overall pipe and overland outflows. These results indicate that the catchment
        topography includes depression storages that capture 23.1 mm of rainfall. The results from
        coupled hydrology and 1D/2D hydraulic model with traditional loss assumptions revealed
        rainfall losses of 24.3 mm. The concentrated direct rainfall and direct rainfall methods can
        also be evaluated using sensitivity testing of initial conditions as follows:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>No accounting for rainfall lost to depression storage; </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Accounting for depression storage loss by reducing the initial loss. Apply direct
            rainfall with initial loss, less the average depth on grid;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Accounting for depression storage using a restart file, which reapplied the
            conditions from the last time step to the model. Direct rainfall applied with the
            initial conditions adopted from the final time step of the initial simulation.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The outflow depths in the standard direct rainfall simulations changed from 52 mm to 61
        mm by using a restart file and in the standard direct rainfall simulations changed from 52
        mm to 56 mm by reducing the assumed initial losses in the models.</para>
      <para>The hydrograph outputs of overland flows at selected locations (see <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_gywfk"/>) at Riley Street near the park (top pane) and at Crown Street
        North (bottom pane) are shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_7eekx"/>. It is clear that overland
        flow is under-represented in the uncorrected direct rainfall models as compared to
        traditional coupled 1D/2D models. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_7eekx">
        <title>Comparison of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121043+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121043+1100" content="t"?>reatment
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121046+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121046+1100" content="i"?>nitial
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121049+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121049+1100" content="c"?>onditions
          in
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121052+1100"?>O<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121052+1100" content="o"?>verland
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121055+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121055+1100" content="f"?>lows
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121057+1100"?>G<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121057+1100" content="g"?>enerated
          by
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121101+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121101+1100" content="c"?>oupled
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121104+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121103+1100" content="d"?>irect
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121107+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121106+1100" content="r"?>ainfall
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121110+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121110+1100" content="m"?>odels
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121113+1100"?>N<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121112+1100" content="n"?>ear
          the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121115+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121115+1100" content="t"?>op
          of the
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121122+1100" content="c"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121125+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?>atchment
          (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121129+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121128+1100" content="t"?>op
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121132+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121132+1100" content="p"?>ane:
          Riley
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121136+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121136+1100" content="s"?>treet)
          and
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121147+1100"?>N<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121146+1100" content="n"?>ear
          the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121151+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121151+1100" content="b"?>ottom
          of the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121156+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121154+1100" content="c"?>atchment</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9113.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_7eekx"/> demonstrates that the uncorrected direct rainfall
        models produce variable under-estimation of surface flows, as compared to a traditional
        coupled 1D/2D model, that is dependent on location and attributes of sub-catchments.
        Techniques that account for depression storage or pre-wetting of the catchment surfaces
        using restart files can improve the comparative performance of direct rain models.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the residual differences in surface flows highlight that 2D models and in particular direct
        rainfall models should also be verified using historical records of local flood depths.
        Surface flows are a significant proportion of the responses from urban catchment as shown in
          <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ioya3"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_ioya3">
        <title>Outflow
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121210+1100"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121209+1100" content="h"?>ydrographs
          for the Woolloomooloo <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121217+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121214+1100" content="c"?>atchment<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121222+1100" content="s"?>
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121226+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121225+1100" content="s"?>howing
          the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121229+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121229+1100" content="s"?>ignificance
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121231+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121231+1100" content="s"?>urface
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121234+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121234+1100" content="f"?>lows</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9114.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>This case study demonstrates practical application of the ARR 2016 ensemble temporal
        patterns on an urban catchment that is dominated by overland flow. The pattern that best
        represents the mean response has been selected based on flood elevation rather than flow. It
        is clear from the results of this analysis that a volume check of direct rainfall approaches
        should be undertaken in accordance with recommendations of <citation>b4_c2_r2+1</citation>
        and the results should be verified using historical records of spatial flooding. A
        significant amount the rainfall excess is not generating runoff because rainfall is trapped
        on the terrain grid. This trapped rainfall excess represents an effective overestimation of
        the catchment loses with associated underestimation of surface flow and should be factored
        into the losses so that the correct amount of rainfall excess is generated. This can be
        carried out by either pre-wetting parts of the catchment or adjusting the assumed initial
        losses or a combination of both.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_boid6">
      <title>Downstream</title>
      <para>Outflows from urban sub-catchments and conveyance networks interact with regional
        storage controls and water quality measures (see <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/> and <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5"/>), discharge to urban waterways (See <xref linkend="b9_ch2"/>and <xref
          linkend="b9_ch3"/>) and to receiving waters such as estuaries, rivers, bays and oceans.
        The methods outlined in <xref linkend="b6_ch5"/> may need to be applied to interactions of
        rainfall and storm surge processes in estuaries, bays and oceans to account for combined
        impacts on urban flooding. </para>
      <para>The complexity of urban areas also fosters the need to consider the joint probability of
        the different factors such intersection of urban runoff with regional flows in rivers or
        water levels in regional storages and water quality measures, which may be correlated or
        independent of each other. Methods to account for joint probability are provided in <xref
          linkend="b4_ch4"/>. The urban designer should also consider climate change impacts on
        urban flooding as outlined in <xref linkend="b8_s_8n655"/> of <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/>. </para>
      <para>The connectivity between design of urban conveyance and a volume management facility,
        setting the rural base case for design targets, application of climate change and assessment
        of downstream impacts on a sensitive waterways is combined in a greenfield example
          <citation>b9_c6_r200</citation>
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121250+1100" content="(Coombes et al.,, 2018)"?>.
        This conceptual design example is located near Ballarat in Victoria and includes an
        objective of no increase in peak flows in the downstream natural waterway to mitigate
        impacts of the urban development on erosion of the stream. The pre-development catchment is
        shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_f4kqg"/> and the proposed development is presented in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_7k83y"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_f4kqg">
        <title>Catchment prior to development</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9115.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_7k83y">
        <title>Developed
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121406+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121405+1100" content="c"?>atchment</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9116.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>An estimate of pre-development peak flows was required to set the design peak flow
        targets for the proposed urban development. The Regional Flood Frequency Estimator (RFFE)
        from the ARR Data Hub was utilised to estimate rural peak flows with uncertainty as shown in
          <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_suywh"/> which is based on gauged flows from multiple regional
        gauges (<xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_1ukfg"/>). The use and limitations of the RFFE is described
        in <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>. Whilst the example catchment size is less than the currently
        recommended minimum and the RFFE is subject to improvement, this process provides a good
        starting point for defining the rural flow target. The rural flows from the RFFE might also
        be combined with statistical analysis of observed flows in a nearby catchment using FLIKE
        (see <xref linkend="b3_ch2_s9"/>) to improve regional flow estimates. These improved
        regional peak flow results from the nearby catchment can be used to calibrate a hydrology
        model and the parameters transferred to the design catchment as explained by
          <citation>b9_c6_r6+1</citation>. <citation>b9_c6_r14+1</citation>,
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161040+1000" content="for example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161048+1000"?>for
        example,<?oxy_insert_end?> outline methods of transferring parameters from gauged catchments
        to ungauged catchments. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_suywh">
        <title>Estimated
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121416+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121416+1100" content="r"?>ural
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121418+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121418+1100" content="p"?>eak
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121421+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121420+1100" content="f"?>lows
          using the RFFE</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9117.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_1ukfg">
        <title>Regional
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121430+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121430+1100" content="f"?>low
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121432+1100"?>G<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121432+1100" content="g"?>auges
          used in the RFFE
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121435+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121435+1100" content="e"?>stimate
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121438+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121437+1100" content="r"?>ural
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121442+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121440+1100" content="p"?>eak
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121445+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121445+1100" content="f"?>lows</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9118.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The next step in the design process involved selecting the project location in the ARR
        Data Hub and downloading hydrology and rainfall information, including local design rainfall
        IFD and ensembles of temporal patterns. Most proprietary models will download this
        information and set up the ensembles of rainfall inputs. Estimated regional rural losses for
        initial losses (IL) of 25 mm and continuing losses (CL) of 4.3 mm/hr were also downloaded
        from the ARR Data Hub. </para>
      <para>A model with combined hydrology and hydraulic capacity was used with initial estimates
        of IL = 25 mm and CL = 4.3 mm/hr, design burst rainfall ensembles and pre-burst rainfall to
        estimate local rural losses that were calibrated to rural flows sourced from the RFFE as
        shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_zcahc"/>. The critical duration was found to be 1.5 hours
        as defined by highest mean peak flows for 50%, 10% and 1% AEP events as shown in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_jxn9x"/>, <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_3c9mh"/> and <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_d66aj"/>. Median pre-burst rainfall for 90 minute storm durations were
        also selected from the ARR Data Hub for 50% AEP: 4.1 mm; 10% AEP: 3.3 mm and 1% AEP: 1.1 mm.
        The pre-burst rainfall was included in the hydrology model and spread over the hour prior to
        burst rainfall and the calibration processes aimed to find values of IL and CL that produced
        simulated rural peak flows that were similar to RFFE peak flows for the 10% AEP events. This
        process enabled an estimate of local rural initial losses of 16 mm and continuing loss of 5
        mm/hr for an assumed Mannings roughness coefficient (n = 0.075).</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_zcahc">
        <title>Calibration of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121457+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121457+1100" content="r"?>ural
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121506+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121506+1100" content="f"?>lows
          to RFFE
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121510+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121509+1100" content="f"?>low
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121513+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121512+1100" content="e"?>stimates</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9119.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_jxn9x">
        <title>Pre-<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121531+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121530+1100" content="d"?>evelopment
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121535+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121534+1100" content="p"?>eaks
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121538+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121538+1100" content="f"?>lows
          for 50% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121542+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121541+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9120.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_3c9mh">
        <title>Pre-<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121552+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121552+1100" content="d"?>evelopment <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121554+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121554+1100" content="p"?>eak<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121626+1100" content="s"?>
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121603+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121602+1100" content="f"?>lows
          for 10% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121605+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121605+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9121.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_d66aj">
        <title>Pre-<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121617+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121617+1100" content="d"?>evelopment
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121620+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121619+1100" content="p"?>eak<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121649+1100" content="s"?>
          flows for 1% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121654+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121652+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9122.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The mean maximum pre-development peak flows for the 50%, 10% and 1% AEP were found to be
        0.011 m3/s, 0.14 m3/s and 0.45 m3/s respectively. These values were used as the peak flow
        targets for the urban development. The altered land surfaces (impervious and pervious areas
        of roads and properties) associated with the urban development was included in the hydrology
        model. The loss values for the urban catchment from <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/> and <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_s_rhstb"/> were assigned as follows:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Effective Impervious Area: IL =1.5 mm, CL = 0 mm/hr</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Pervious Area = rural losses</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>Indirectly connected impervious area assumptions were not required because the spatial
        detail of land uses with associated connectivity were included in the hydrology/hydraulics
        model. The hydrology of the urban catchment was simulated for all design rainfall ensembles
        to determine a critical duration of 10 minutes for the 10% AEP flows relevant to the design
        of pit and pipe conveyance infrastructure (see <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>). These simulations
        were completed prior to design of infrastructure to determine the relevant critical duration
        and design storm for use in the design process. Pre-burst rainfall for a one hour duration
        was selected from the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 Data Hub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?> (50% AEP: 2.2 mm, 10% AEP: 2.2 mm, 1% AEP: 0.8 mm) for use with
        the 10 minute duration design rainfall ensembles relevant to the design of the pit and pipe
        conveyance infrastructure. The pre-burst rainfall was distributed across an hour prior to
        the burst rainfall. </para>
      <para>The hydrographs from the simulation using ensembles of 10% AEP design burst rainfall
        with pre-burst rainfall was examined to select the design storm closest to mean peak flow
        for design of conveyance infrastructure as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_aa9ua"/>. Urban
        peak flows from all design rainfall durations for 50%, 10% and 1% AEP events are presented
        in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_2nppt"/>, <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ezqni"/> and <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_vseye"/> respectively. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_aa9ua">
        <title>Selection of the 10% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121706+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121705+1100" content="d"?>esign
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121708+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121708+1100" content="s"?>torm
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121711+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121710+1100" content="p"?>reliminary
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121714+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121713+1100" content="i"?>nfrastructure
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121716+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121716+1100" content="d"?>esign</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9123.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_2nppt">
        <title>Development <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121726+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121726+1100" content="p"?>eak<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121728+1100" content="s"?>
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121730+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121730+1100" content="f"?>lows
          for 50% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121733+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121732+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9124.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_ezqni">
        <title>Development
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121741+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121740+1100" content="p"?>eaks
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121745+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121744+1100" content="f"?>lows
          for 10% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121748+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121748+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9125.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_vseye">
        <title>Development <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121839+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121838+1100" content="p"?>eak<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121833+1100" content="s"?>
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121837+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121835+1100" content="f"?>lows
          for 1% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121830+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121829+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9126.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The preliminary design of the conveyance network (<xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>) shown in
          <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_v7xdn"/> was sized using storm 7 (<xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_aa9ua"
        />) for the 10% AEP event with a design pre-burst rainfall of 2.2 mm. Inlet pit
        relationships from <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_wtcce"/> were applied to the design process. Pit
        inlet capacities for on grade pits (<xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_2vdnh"/>) and sag pits (<xref
          linkend="b9_ch5_e_33eks"/> to <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_97bt4"/>) were derived using <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5_s_b5ju4"/>. Design blockage of on grade and sag pits was derived from
          <xref linkend="b9_ch5_t_x2nkl"/> and pit energy losses were defined using <xref
          linkend="b9_ch5_s_3wuje"/>. </para>
      <para>A hydrology/hydraulics model was use to sized pipes in the conveyance network with
        objectives of maintaining 150 mm freeboard to grates of inlet pits and less than two metre
        flow width on roads. The design of the conveyance network was then checked using ensembles
        for 10% AEP design storm events with pre-burst rainfall for 10, 15, 20 and 30 minute
        durations. </para>
      <para>The safety of surface flows were also checked by simulating the performance of the
        conveyance network using design rainfall ensembles for 1% AEP burst events with pre-burst
        rainfall for 10, 15, 20 and 30 minute durations. In accordance with <xref
          linkend="b9_ch3_s_34r7g"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_fm486"/> (also see <xref
          linkend="b7_ch6"
        />)<?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153504+1000" content=" ,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T153504+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the design aimed to limit surface water depths to less than 200 mm and less than 50 mm at
        road crowns. These objectives also included limiting depth velocity product to less than 0.4
        and aimed for freeboard to floor levels of greater than 300 mm. </para>
      <para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_v7xdn">
          <title>Overview of the
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121800+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121759+1100" content="p"?>lanned
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121802+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121801+1100" content="c"?>onveyance
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121806+1100"?>N<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121805+1100" content="n"?>etwork
            in the
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121813+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121813+1100" content="u"?>rban
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121816+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121816+1100" content="d"?>evelopment</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9127.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>A storage basin was then designed to manage flooding and impacts on downstream waterway
        (see <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>) by mitigating the 50%, 10%, 1% AEP peak flows to meet the
        rural target defined above. Storage volume and outflow arrangements were utilised to achieve
        this as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_h0w50"/>. The design of the basin included a
        freeboard of 300 mm from 1% AEP maximum depth and an emergency spillway designed for full
        blockage of 1% AEP rainfall events (See <xref linkend="b6_ch6"/> for blockage
        discussions).</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_h0w50">
        <title>Overview of the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121851+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121851+1100" content="p"?>lanned
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121854+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121853+1100" content="s"?>torage
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121857+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121856+1100" content="b"?>asin
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121859+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121859+1100" content="b"?>elow
          the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121904+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121902+1100" content="u"?>rban
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121907+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121906+1100" content="d"?>evelopment</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9128.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>A trial basin design was undertaken using the hydrology/hydraulics models and ensembles
        of 1.5 hour duration design rainfall with pre-burst rainfall. The design of the basin was
        then tested and modified using ensembles of design rainfall with pre-burst rainfall for all
        durations to ensure the rural peak flow targets were met and the maximum basin depth was not
        exceeded. The final results for peak flows discharging from the development via the basin
        are shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_6zky4"/>, <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_ptibi"/> and <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_367go"/> for 50%, 10% and 1% AEP rainfall events. Water levels in the
        basin for all 1% AEP rainfall durations are provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_fy6ha"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_6zky4">
        <title>Peak flows from the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121919+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121918+1100" content="b"?>asin
          for 50% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121921+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121921+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9129.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_ptibi">
        <title>Peak
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121942+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121942+1100" content="f"?>lows
          from the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121938+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121937+1100" content="b"?>asin
          for 10% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121935+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121930+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9130.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_367go">
        <title>Peak
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121950+1100" content="f"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121952+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?>lows
          from the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121955+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121955+1100" content="b"?>asin
          for 1% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121957+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T121957+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9131.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_fy6ha">
        <title>Peak
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122006+1100"?>W<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122005+1100" content="w"?>ater
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122008+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122008+1100" content="l"?>evels
          the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122012+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122011+1100" content="b"?>asin
          for 1% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122015+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122014+1100" content="e"?>vents</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9132.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_6zky4"/> to <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_367go"/> show that the mean
        peak flows from the basin were less than the rural flows with critical durations ranging
        from one to three hours. A one hour critical duration of peak water levels in the basin was
        also observed from the analysis (see <xref linkend="b9_ch6_f_fy6ha"/>). These result
        highlight that critical durations of stormwater runoff can vary throughout catchments and
        across different types of the infrastructure. </para>
      <para>The design of the conveyance and storage infrastructure was evaluated for climate change
        impacts using the methods outlined in <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/> and <xref
          linkend="b8_s_8n655"/>. A design life for the infrastructure and consequence level for
        climate change impacts was selected. A design life of 100 years was assumed for the basin
        with medium consequences of failure due to impacts on the waterway and surrounding rural
        properties.</para>
      <para>This assessment was utilised to extract data from
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100" content="ARR 2016 Data Hub"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181203T164539+1100"?>ARR
        Data Hub<?oxy_insert_end?> for the RCP 8.5 value for 2090 which indicated an expected 16.1%
        increase in peak rainfall. This expected increase in peak flows was used to alter the
        relevant design rainfall ensembles and the hydrology/hydraulic model was rerun to test the
        impact of climate change on peak water levels in the basin and on roads. Designers should
        also utilise emerging research to incorporate that most up to date climate change
        assessments.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161014+1000" content="For example,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T161021+1000"?>For example,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        <citation>b1_c6_r5+1</citation> outline greater potential for increased rainfall intensities
        in urban areas. </para>
      <para>The impact of applying the expected 2090 climate change effects on design rainfall on
        peak water levels in the basin and at a critical location on the road is shown in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6_f_9lvvw"/>. Increases in peak water depths are experienced in the basin
        and on the road. The increased runoff into the basin is managed by the emergency spillway
        and peak water levels are acceptable.
        <?oxy_delete author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160407+1000" content="However,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180922T160426+1000"?>However,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        peak water levels on the road exceed the design objectives and the designer should highlight
        this situation to the consent authority for further consideration.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9_ch6_f_9lvvw">
        <title>Peak
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122029+1100"?>W<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122028+1100" content="w"?>ater
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122033+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122032+1100" content="l"?>evels
          in the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122036+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122036+1100" content="b"?>asin
          and on
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122038+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122038+1100" content="r"?>oads
          for 1% AEP
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122041+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122041+1100" content="e"?>vents
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122044+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122043+1100" content="s"?>ubject
          to<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122047+1100"?>
          C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122046+1100" content=" c"?>limate
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122052+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181204T122052+1100" content="c"?>hange</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9133.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
</chapter>



<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>
