<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" version="5.0" xml:id="b9_ch6"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Safety Design Criteria</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/smith_grantley.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/cox_ron.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>The safety of people in floods is of major concern in floodplain
    management for both rural and urban areas. Consideration of the
    circumstances for individual flood fatalities, both in Australia and
    internationally, indicates that many flood fatalities occur outside of
    buildings with people either wading or driving vehicles through
    floodwaters (French et al, 1983, Coates and Haynes, 2008). Further, recent
    analysis of the Queensland floods in 2011 by the Queensland Commission for
    Children, Young People, and Child Guardian (CCYPCG, 2012) and the
    Queensland Fire and Rescue Service, 2012 has reinforced the conclusion
    that floodwaters are extremely dangerous to both people wading and driving
    vehicles of all types in floods. While floodplain management activities
    aim to reduce the risk arising from flooding events, ongoing human
    activity during flood events is largely unavoidable, as significant areas
    of existing development and transport infrastructure in Australia remain
    within flood prone regions.</para>

    <para>It is apparent that there are numerous circumstances and associated
    human behaviours during flood emergencies, which result in people either
    wading or driving into floodwaters. Once exposed to flood flows, safety of
    the people involved is compromised when flood flow forces exceed their
    ability to remain standing or when the vehicles they are travelling in
    become unstable by becoming buoyant or losing traction.</para>

    <para>Sound floodplain management and emergency planning requires
    identification of the location, timing and duration of potentially
    hazardous floodplain areas for design flood conditions. The intention of
    this chapter of Australian Rainfall and Runoff is to provide background
    information and guidance on the application of approaches for prediction
    of those locations; additional background information can be obtained from
    Cox et al. (2010) and Shand et al. (2011). Note that while guidance is
    provided on predicting the risk, it is the role of the relevant floodplain
    management authority to define the acceptability or otherwise of the
    predicted risk.</para>

    <para>A detailed discussion of risk with respect to floodplain management
    is presented in Chapter 5 Book 1 of Australian Rainfall and Runoff.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Flood Hazard</title>

    <section>
      <title>General Introduction</title>

      <para>In terms of floodplain management, hazard can be defined as a
      source of potential harm or a situation with potential to result in
      loss. Hence, the primary hazard is the result of a flood event that has
      the potential to cause damage or harm to the community. Associated with
      the hazard is the probability of its occurrence.</para>

      <para>There are a number of factors to be considered where assessing the
      hazard associated with floods. The usual starting point is to predict
      the flood characteristics and particularly the flow characteristics of
      the inundated areas of the floodplain. The main characteristics of
      interest typically are the flow depth and the flow velocity. In
      addition, the assessment of the flood hazard needs to consider a range
      of other social, economic and environmental factors, though these are
      often more difficult to quantify.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Flood Hazard Assessment</title>

      <para>The base data that underpins assessment of floodplain risk
      typically comprises the flow characteristics (the flow depth and
      velocity) in the flood-affected areas of the catchment. A common
      approach to obtaining this information is the analysis of predictions
      obtained from catchment numerical modelling systems although physical
      models of the flood affected area may be used. More information on the
      application of catchment modelling systems is presented in Books 4 to 7
      of Australian Rainfall and Runoff.</para>

      <para>The data used for assessment of the floodplain hazard are
      presented commonly as maps of flood depth (see <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.1"/>) and flood velocity (speed and direction).
      Typically, these maps are shown as an envelope of maxima; a time series
      of flow behaviour, however, is an alternative presentation
      format.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.1">
        <title>Example of a Flood Study Depth Map (after Smith and Wasko,
        2012)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="384"
                       fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.1.bmp"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Smith and Wasko (2012) investigated the effects of alternative
      grid resolutions on prediction of the flood hazard. The predicted flood
      hazard (computed as D.V – flood depth times flood velocity) for two
      model grid resolutions, namely 1m and 10m, for the 2007 flood event at
      Merewether, NSW are shown in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.2"/>. Comparing
      the predicted flood hazard estimates, it can be seen that those derived
      using the 1m grid are higher than those obtained with the 10m grid.
      Furthermore, Smith and Wasko (2012) report that the predicted velocity
      and depth characteristics for the 1m grid more closely replicated those
      obtained from a physical model of the same area.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.2">
        <title>Comparison of Provisional Flood Hazard Estimates from Numerical
        Models at Differing Grid Resolutions (after Smith and Wasko,
        2012)</title>

        <para>a) 1 m grid resolution b) 10 m grid resolution</para>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%"
                       fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.2.jpg" scalefit="1"
                       width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>An important conclusion of Smith and Wasko (2012) was that
      predictions from 2D numerical hydrodynamic models require further
      interpretation in order to ensure that suitable, representative flood
      behaviour information was obtained for application in planning and
      management decisions.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>People Stability</title>

      <para>The two recognised hydrodynamic mechanisms by which people may
      lose stability in flood flows are <emphasis>moment instability
      </emphasis>and <emphasis>friction instability</emphasis> (<xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.3"/>). A summary description of these mechanisms is
      provided here based on the comprehensive discussion of the topic
      presented in ox <emphasis>et al</emphasis>. (2010).</para>

      <para>In brief, moment (toppling) instability occurs when a moment
      induced by the oncoming flow exceeds the resisting moment generated by
      the weight of the body (Abt <emphasis>et al.</emphasis>, 1989). This
      stability parameter is sensitive to the buoyancy of a person within the
      flow and to body positioning and weight distribution.</para>

      <para>Frictional (sliding) instability occurs when the drag force
      induced by the horizontal flow impacting on a person’s legs and torso is
      larger than the frictional resistance between a person’s feet and the
      ground surface. This stability parameter is sensitive to weight and
      buoyancy, clothing type, footwear type and ground surface
      conditions.</para>

      <para>Additionally, loss of stability may also be triggered by adverse
      conditions, which should be taken into account when assessing safety
      such as:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Bottom conditions:</emphasis> uneven,
          slippery, obstacles;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Flow conditions:</emphasis> floating
          debris, low temperature, poor visibility, unsteady flow and flow
          aeration;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Human subject:</emphasis> standing or
          moving, experience and training, clothing and footwear, physical
          attributes additional to height and mass including muscular
          development and/or other disability, psychological factors;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Other issues:</emphasis> strong wind,
          poor lighting, etc.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.3">
        <title>Typical modes of Human Instability in Floods (after Cox et al,
        2010)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="294"
                       fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.3.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Determining safety criteria for people requires an understanding
      of the physical characteristics of the subjects along with the nature of
      the flow. The best measure of physical attributes for human stability is
      the parameter H.M (mkg), the product of subject height (H; m) and mass
      (M; kg) (Cox et al., 2010). The measure of flow attributes is the
      parameter D.V
      (m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>), the
      product of flow depth (D, m) and flow velocity (V,
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para>While distinct relationships exist between a subject’s height and
      mass and the tolerable flow value, definition of general flood flow
      safety guidelines according to this relationship is not considered
      practical given the wide range in such characteristics within the
      population.</para>

      <para>In order to define safety limits, which are applicable for all
      persons, hazard regimes are defined based on H.M for representative
      population demographics. Each classification is based on laboratory
      testing of subject stability within floodwaters. The following suggested
      classifications, after Cox et al., 2010) are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Adults, where H.M &gt; 50 mkg;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Children, where H.M is between 25 and 50 mkg; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Infants and very young children, where H.M &lt; 25 mkg.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Several hazard regimes are recommended based on D.V flow values
      for each H.M classification. The hazard regimes, as suggested from
      laboratory testing of subject stability and response within variable
      flow conditions, are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Low hazard zones where D.V &lt; 0.4
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          children and D.V &lt; 0.6
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          adults;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A Significant hazard zone for children exists where flow
          conditions are dangerous to most between D.V = 0.4 to 0.6
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Moderate hazard zone where conditions are dangerous for some
          adults and all children is defined between D.V = 0.6 to 0.8
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          adults. This is inferred to define the limiting working flow for
          experienced personnel such as trained rescue workers;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Significant hazard zone where flow conditions are dangerous to
          most adults and extremely dangerous for all children is suggested
          between flow values of D.V = 0.8 to 1.2
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>;
          and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Extreme hazard where flow conditions are dangerous to all
          people is suggested for D.V &gt; 1.2
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Cox <emphasis>et al.,</emphasis> 2010 concluded that
      self-evacuation of the most vulnerable people in the community
      (typically small children, and the elderly) is limited to relatively
      placid flow conditions. Furthermore, a D.V as low as 0.4
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> would prove
      problematic for people in this category, i.e. the more vulnerable in the
      community.</para>

      <para>These hazard regimes for tolerable flow conditions (D.V) as
      related to the individual’s physical characteristics (H.M) are presented
      in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.4"/> and <xref
      linkend="table_9.6.1"/>.</para>

      <table frame="box" rules="all" xml:id="table_9.6.1">
        <caption>Flow Hazard Regimes for People (Cox et al, 2010)</caption>

        <thead>
          <tr align="center">
            <th>DV
            (m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</th>

            <th>Children (H.M = 25 to 50)<superscript>1</superscript></th>

            <th>Adults (H.M &gt; 50)</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <th>0</th>

            <td>Safe</td>

            <td>Safe</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0 - 0.4</th>

            <td>Low Hazard if depth &lt; 0.5m and velocity &lt; 3m/s otherwise
            Extreme Hazard</td>

            <td rowspan="2">Low Hazard if depth &lt; 1.2m and velocity &lt;
            3m/s otherwise Extreme Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0.4 - 0.6</th>

            <td>Significant Hazard; Dangerous to most if depth &lt; 0.5m and
            velocity &lt; 3m/s otherwise Extreme Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0.6 - 0.8</th>

            <td rowspan="3">Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</td>

            <td>Moderate Hazard; Dangerous to some<superscript>2</superscript>
            if depth &lt; 1.2m and velocity &lt; 3m/s otherwise Extreme
            Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0.8 - 1.2</th>

            <td>Significant Hazard; Dangerous to
            most<superscript>3</superscript> if depth &lt; 1.2m and velocity
            &lt; 3m/s otherwise Extreme Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>&gt; 1.2</th>

            <td>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Maximum depth stability limit of 0.5 m for
      children and 1.2 m</emphasis> for adults under good condition. <emphasis
      role="bold">Maximum velocity stability limit of 3.0
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript> </emphasis>for both adults and
      children.</para>

      <para><superscript>1</superscript>More vulnerable community members such
      as infants and the elderly should avoid exposure to floodwater. Flood
      flows are considered extremely hazardous to these community members
      under all conditions</para>

      <para><superscript>2</superscript>Working limit for trained safety
      workers or experienced and well equipped persons (D.V &lt; 0.8
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para><superscript>3</superscript>Upper limit of stability observed
      during most investigations (D.V &gt; 1.2
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.4">
        <title>Safety Criteria for People in Variable Flow Conditions (After
        Cox et al, 2010)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.4.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <section>
        <title>Physical considerations</title>

        <para>There is a lack of test data for infants and very young children
        as well as frail/older persons (Cox et al., 2004). These populations
        are unlikely to be safe in any flow regimes and as such, care is
        required in locating aged care and retirement villages as well as
        childcare centres and kindergartens.</para>

        <para>For physically and/or mentally disabled people, similar
        intolerance criteria to the very young children and frail/older
        persons should be applied as subjects are considered vulnerable to all
        flow values. This is because while the H.M values may be similar to
        regular adults, they are clearly at a physical (e.g. muscular
        development, control of limbs) and/or psychological disadvantage (e.g.
        cognisant of the real/perceived danger, inability to cope with
        external stimulus).</para>

        <para>Emergency personnel tasked with carrying evacuees should be
        aware that the additional H.M gained by carrying a person is not
        necessarily a benefit to their stability. This was demonstrated in a
        particular laboratory test of human stability criteria, Jonkman and
        Penning-Rowsell (2008), who note that their test subject (a trained
        stuntman) considered balancing in the flowing water more difficult
        when carrying extra weight such as a child or elderly person.</para>

        <para>It should also be noted that while these criteria are based on
        experimental data for loss of stability for persons wading in
        floodwaters, it is also inherently dangerous to swim through
        floodwaters. Swimming through floodwaters should not be
        attempted.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Psychological/behavioural considerations</title>

        <para>A person’s ability to withstand flood flows is affected by their
        mental disposition, perception, specific training and
        experience.</para>

        <para>Where specific training has been undertaken or a subject has
        recent and relevant experience, personnel are able to tolerate
        situations of high D.V (Jonkman and Penning-Rowsell, 2008). A limiting
        working flow of D.V = 0.8
        m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> is
        suggested for experienced personnel such as trained rescue workers.
        These personnel should, where possible, be equipped for dangerous flow
        conditions with safety restraints, floatation aids and other safety
        apparatus, and be trained to cope with high D.V situations. It is
        trained emergency personnel who are likely to be instructing, driving
        and guiding evacuation paths, and consequently to whom the upper limit
        of safety design criteria is directed.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Vehicle stability</title>

      <para>The two recognised hydrodynamic mechanisms by which stability of
      vehicles is lost include <emphasis>buoyancy</emphasis> or
      <emphasis>floating</emphasis> and <emphasis>friction instability or
      sliding instability</emphasis> (refer <xref linkend="figure_9.6.5"/>).
      More comprehensive discussion is presented within Shand <emphasis>et
      al</emphasis>. (2011) but briefly, vehicle floating instability occurs
      when the upward buoyancy force exceeds the downward force exerted by the
      vehicle mass. This instability is dominant in low velocity, high depth
      flows. Frictional or sliding instability occurs when the horizontal
      force exerted on one or more car panels is greater than the vertical
      restoring force, which is dependent on the vehicle mass, buoyancy and
      the friction between the car tyres and road surface.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.5">
        <title>Typical Modes of Vehicle Instability (after Shand et al,
        2011)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="414"
                       fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.5.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Note that in the context of this discussion <emphasis>friction
      instability</emphasis> is associated with slow moving or stationary cars
      as distinct to <emphasis>hydroplaning</emphasis>, which occurs when a
      vehicle at high speed encounters very shallow, evenly distributed water
      covering a road, typically a highway or freeway. Hydroplaning is not
      considered further within this report.</para>

      <para>Determining safety criteria for vehicles requires an understanding
      of the physical characteristics of the vehicle along with the nature of
      the flow.</para>

      <para>The measure of physical attributes for vehicle stability analysis
      is the vehicle classification as based on length (L, m), kerb weight (W,
      kg) and ground clearance (GC, m). Three vehicle classifications are
      suggested:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger: L &lt; 4.3 m, W &lt; 1250 kg, GC &lt; 0.12
          m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger: L &gt; 4.3 m, W &gt; 1250 kg, GC &gt; 0.12
          m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD: L &gt; 4.5 m, W &gt; 2000 kg, GC &gt; 0.22 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The measure of flow attributes for vehicle stability analysis is
      D.V m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>,
      determined as the product of flow depth (D, m) and flow velocity (V,
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para>Limiting conditions exist for each classification based on limited
      laboratory testing of characteristic vehicles. The upper tolerable
      velocity for moving water is defined based on the frictional limits, and
      is a constant 3.0 ms<superscript>-1</superscript> for all vehicle
      classifications.</para>

      <para>The upper tolerable depths within still water are defined by the
      floating limits:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger vehicles: 0.3 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger vehicles: 0.4 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD vehicles: 0.5 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The upper tolerable depths within high velocity water (at 3.0
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript>) are defined by the frictional
      limits:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger vehicles: 0.1 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger vehicles: 0.15 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD vehicles: 0.2 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>While specifically equipped vehicles may remain stable in water of
      greater depths, the intention of the presented criteria is to focus on
      the more vulnerable of typical vehicle types in common use.</para>

      <para>Note that for all flow conditions in all vehicle classes,
      <emphasis>the proposed vehicle safety criteria remain below the moderate
      hazard criteria for adults</emphasis> (Cox <emphasis>et al.</emphasis>,
      2010). This ensures that adults occupying vehicles are, in principle,
      safe if exiting a vehicle in floodwaters with attributes within the
      specified hazard ranges.</para>

      <para>During flood events, the majority of flood deaths are vehicle
      related, more than half of all deaths during floods in the United States
      are vehicular-related (Gruntfest and Ripps, 2000). Regardless of how
      often people see the power of water in flash floods or are notified
      through community advertising that driving through high water is
      dangerous, there remain sections of the community who will continue with
      ‘business as usual’ irrespective of the flooding conditions (Gruntfest
      and Ripps, 2000).</para>

      <section>
        <title>Vehicle modernisation and scale</title>

        <para>A limiting aspect of the advice provided in this report is that
        vehicle stability data sets are limited to dated laboratory data
        (Shand <emphasis>et al.</emphasis>, 2011). The properties of
        contemporary vehicles have significantly changed vehicle stability
        criteria through modified buoyancy properties (e.g. improve dust
        sealing), weight and ground clearance. These changes apply to all
        scales of vehicles from small passenger to large commercial
        vehicles.</para>

        <para>As a result, the hazard criteria provided in this report are
        identified as interim recommended limits based on interpretation of
        existing information. The criteria presented here are subject to
        change once acceptable data for modern vehicles becomes
        available.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Stability Criteria for Vehicles</title>

        <para>Stability criteria based on the best available information for
        stationary small passenger cars, large passenger cars and large 4WD
        vehicles in various flow situations are presented in <xref
        linkend="figure_9.6.6"/> and <xref linkend="table_9.6.2"/>.</para>

        <table xml:id="table_9.6.2">
          <title>Interim Flow Hazard Regimes for Vehicles (Shand et al,
          2011)</title>

          <tgroup cols="8">
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Class of vehicle</entry>

                <entry>Length (m)</entry>

                <entry>Kerb Weight (kg)</entry>

                <entry>Ground clearance (m)</entry>

                <entry>Limiting still water
                depth<superscript>1</superscript></entry>

                <entry>Limiting high velocity flow
                depth<superscript>2</superscript></entry>

                <entry>Limiting velocity<superscript>3</superscript></entry>

                <entry>Equation of stability</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Small passenger</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 4.3</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 1250</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 0.12</entry>

                <entry>0.3</entry>

                <entry>0.1</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry><emphasis>DV</emphasis> ≤ 0.3</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Large passenger</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 4.3</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 1250</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 0.12</entry>

                <entry>0.4</entry>

                <entry>0.15</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry><emphasis>DV</emphasis> ≤ 0.45</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Large 4WD</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 4.5</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 2000</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 0.22</entry>

                <entry>0.5</entry>

                <entry>0.2</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry><emphasis>DV</emphasis> ≤ 0.6</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>

        <para><superscript>1</superscript>At velocity = 0
        ms<superscript>-1</superscript>; <superscript>2</superscript>At
        velocity = 3.0 ms<superscript>-1</superscript>;
        <superscript>3</superscript>At low depth</para>

        <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.6">
          <title>Interim Safety Criteria for Vehicles in Variable Flow
          Conditions (After Shand et al, 2011)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.6.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>Shand <emphasis>et al</emphasis> (2011) concludes that the
        available datasets do not adequately account for the following factors
        and that more research is needed in these areas:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Friction coefficients for contemporary vehicle tyres in
            flood flows;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Buoyancy changes in modern cars;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The effect of vehicle orientation to flow direction
            (including vehicle movement);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Information for additional categories including small and
            large commercial vehicles and emergency service vehicles</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Examples of Hazard Assessment</title>

    <para>This section presents practical examples of the interpretation of
    flood hazard criteria for people and vehicle stability in a floodplain
    management context. The examples are not intended to be a comprehensive
    analysis of all possible circumstances, but rather provide representative
    case studies, which illustrate practical interpretation of flood hazard
    criteria for floodplain planning and management.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Example - Warehouse Car Park</title>

      <para>A large multinational retailer has identified an existing
      industrial area in an inner city suburb as a suitable site for
      re-development as a warehouse-style retail outlet. The site is gently
      sloping from the northwest to the southeast and, having been previously
      prepared for development, is clear of vegetation. An aging,
      concrete-lined channel runs along the eastern side of the site.</para>

      <para>The retailer has submitted a development application, illustrated
      in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.7"/>, which conceptually has a warehouse
      building situated in the northwest corner of the site with the area
      between the building and the concrete-lined channel earmarked as a car
      park.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.7">
        <title>Schematic of Proposed Warehouse Development</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.7.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The local council as the consent authority has identified a series
      of development constraints including flooding criteria. Amongst other
      criteria, the development must have:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>All retail floor space above the designated flood planning
          level defined as the 1% Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP) flood
          surface plus 500mm freeboard;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A flood free evacuation route for floods above the flood
          planning level; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>All car park areas compliant with ARR flood hazard criteria
          for vehicle stability;</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>As there was no existing flood study, following consultation with
      Council, the developer engaged an experienced flood consultant to
      undertake flood modelling of the site to estimate 1% AEP flood
      behaviour. Flood modelling of the site for the 1% AEP event completed
      using industry best practice guidance as provided by ARR reference “Two
      Dimensional Modelling in Urban and Rural Floodplains” (EA 2012)
      predicted that while the warehouse building met the flood planning
      criteria, the car park was inundated by floodwaters. <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.8"/> illustrates the extent of flood inundation for
      the existing site.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.8">
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth Map – Existing Site</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.8.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Interrogation of the flood model results to determine provisional
      flood hazard as the product of flood depth (D) multiplied by flood
      velocity (V) showed that the peak flood hazard (D.V) corresponded with
      the maximum inundation of the site at the peak of the flood hydrograph.
      Provisional flood hazard for the 1% AEP flood on the existing site as
      illustrated by <xref linkend="figure_9.6.9"/> showed that flooding in
      most of the area identified for car parking exceeds the ARR stability
      criteria for small cars defined in <xref linkend="table_9.6.2"/> and
      illustrated in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.6"/>. In <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.9"/>, areas coloured blue (D.V &lt;0.3
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>) indicate
      locations where small cars are likely to resist being moved by flood
      flows, whereas areas coloured green through red indicate areas where
      small cars are very likely to be pushed across the floodplain by
      floodwaters, with the flow having the potential to move larger cars
      closer to the creek channel. Based on this information, Council’s
      preliminary advice to the developer was that the existing flood hazard
      conditions for the designated car parking area were incompatible with
      the nominated use.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.9">
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Existing Car Park</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.9.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>As the concrete lined channel had low environmental value, Council
      was not opposed to the developer’s proposed adjustment of the channel
      flow conveyance capacity to reduce the proportion of overbank flow at
      the site. The developer, in consultation with the flood consultant ran a
      range of cut and fill scenarios through the flood model aimed at
      expanding the channel capacity while raising the relative ground level
      of the car park to the flood peak. <xref linkend="figure_9.6.10"/> shows
      the adjustment of the channel and overbank area through the car park on
      the longitudinal section identified as ‘A-A’ in <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.7"/>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.10">
        <title>Comparison of Car Park Cross Sections (A-A)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%"
                       fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.10.jpg" scalefit="1"
                       width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>This section is representative of a balance between the minimum
      volume of earthworks to meet the car parking capacity criteria for the
      development. The car park area adjacent to section A-A was graded to
      meet the natural surface areas outside of the development site.</para>

      <para>Flood modelling for the revised site including the proposed
      earthworks is presented in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.11"/>. The flood
      model results show that the site flood inundation area is significantly
      reduced with the works in place.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.11">
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth Map – Revised Car Park</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.11.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Importantly, analysis of the provisional flood hazard as presented
      in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.12"/> shows that flood hazard for the area
      designated as car park in the conceptual site design now meets the ARR
      flood stability criteria for small vehicles. The nominated car park area
      has a D.V product of less than 0.3
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> as indicated
      by the blue shaded area of <xref linkend="figure_9.6.12"/>. This
      indicates that it is now unlikely that cars inundated by floodwaters in
      the 1% AEP flood will be pushed across the floodplain and potentially
      into the channel creating a possible downstream blockage hazard.</para>

      <para>Council’s planners also suggested to the developer that the yellow
      zone of <xref linkend="figure_9.6.12"/> could be landscaped as gardens
      providing clear separation of the car park from the channel. From a
      floodplain management perspective, this suggested change would provide a
      significant further reduction in exposure risk with little impact on
      available car parking space.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.12">
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Revised Car Park</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.12.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Example - Detention Basin</title>

      <para>Council’s conditions of consent for a proposed retirement village
      development require that on-site detention be provided so that peak
      flows from the site in floods up to the 1% AEP event remain similar to
      existing local runoff conditions.</para>

      <para>The developer considers that a centralised detention basin on the
      site can be designed to have a dual use and integrated into the site
      grounds as a bowling green when not operating as a detention basin.
      <xref linkend="figure_9.6.13"/> illustrates the proposed design.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.13">
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth - Proposed Flood Detention Basin</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.13.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>As the catchment contributing runoff to the site is steep,
      Council’s flood expert considers that there is some risk in a dual
      purpose design for the basin due to flash flooding in prevailing
      thunderstorms. Council’s advice is that the developer engage a qualified
      flood expert to determine whether the basin meets the ARR hazard
      criteria for people safety.</para>

      <para>The basin design philosophy is that the local catchment stormwater
      will collect both overland flows and also surcharge from the pit and
      pipe stormwater system. If the basin capacity is exceeded, flows spill
      at a designated location and flow overland to the adjacent creek
      channel. Flows that remain in the basin discharge through a grated pit
      in the lowest location in the basin floor.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.14">
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map - Proposed Flood Detention
        Basin</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.14.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>An assessment of the provisional flood hazard (flood depth
      multiplied by the flood velocity) is presented in <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.14"/>. When compared to flood hazard criteria
      presented in <xref linkend="table_9.6.1"/> and <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.4"/>, the provisional hazard meets the safety
      criteria for the elderly in most areas of the basin. This is because at
      full capacity, the basin is no greater than 0.5m deep. Analysis shows
      that a dangerous flood hazard is likely to occur near to the basin’s
      outlet pit when the basin begins to drain at full capacity.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.15">
        <title>Basin Overflow Spillway – Flood Depth</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.15.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Further analysis of the full design presented in <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.15"/> shows that when the basin capacity is exceeded
      overflows will cross a public footpath adjacent the creek reserve.
      Provisional flood hazard analysis of the overflow path presented in
      <xref linkend="figure_9.6.16"/> shows that the flood hazard in the flow
      path will exceed the people stability criteria for adults and be a
      dangerous hazard to passing pedestrians.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.16">
        <title>Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Basin Overflow Spillway</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="doc_figures/figure_9.6.16.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>As a result of the analysis, Council consent criteria require
      signage to be placed in appropriate locations informing residents of the
      retirement village and the public passing the site on the public
      footpath of the dual purpose use of the basin and the danger of entering
      floodwaters when the basin is inundated. Further, Council’s consent
      criteria require that the developer upgrade the footpath to include a
      bridge of suitable span over the basin spillway flow path so that safe
      thoroughfare of the footpath can be maintained during flood
      conditions.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusions and Recommendations</title>

    <para>Recent flood events on the east coast of Australia in 2010 and 2011
    have highlighted that people continue to be exposed to dangerous and life
    threatening flow conditions in urban and rural floodplains. While
    floodplain management activities are continuing to mitigate problems
    associated the community’s exposure to floodwaters, ongoing human activity
    in floods is largely unavoidable while significant areas of existing
    development and transport infrastructure in Australia remain flood
    prone.</para>

    <para>This chapter of Australian Rainfall and Runoff presents a summary
    with an explanation of the limitations of recent analysis of flood
    stability thresholds for pedestrians and vehicles in floodwaters.
    Recommended flood hazard criteria for use within Australia based on the
    stability of people and vehicles in flood flows has also been
    presented.</para>

    <para>Finally, the presented examples illustrate practical applications of
    these flood hazard criteria. While not exhaustive of all cases, the
    examples show how the criteria can be pragmatically applied to reduce the
    community’s exposure to flood danger.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Abt, S.R, Wittler, R.J, Taylor, A and Love, DJ. (1989). Human
    Stability in a High Flood Hazard Zone, <emphasis>Water Resources
    Bulletin</emphasis>, American Water Resources Association, 25 (4), pp
    881-890.</para>

    <para>Coates, L and Haynes, K (2008), <emphasis>Flash flood
    shelter-in-place vs. evacuation research: Flash flood fatalities within
    Australia, 1950 – 2008.</emphasis> Report prepared for the New South Wales
    State Emergency Service.</para>

    <para>Cox, R.J., Yee, M. and Ball, J.E. (2004). Safety of People in
    Flooded Streets and Floodways. <emphasis>8th National Conference on
    Hydraulics in Water Engineering, Gold Coast.</emphasis> The Institution of
    Engineers, Australia.</para>

    <para>Cox, R J, Shand, T D and Blacka, M J (2010), <emphasis>“Appropriate
    Safety Criteria for People in Floods”, </emphasis><emphasis>WRL Research
    Report 240.</emphasis> Report for Institution of Engineers Australia,
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff Guidelines: Project 10. 22p.</para>

    <para>Engineers Australia, 2012. “Two Dimensional Modelling in Urban and
    Rural Floodplains”. Project 15, Mark Babister, editor.</para>

    <para>French J, Ing, R, Von Allmen, S and Wood, R (1983),
    <emphasis>“Mortality from Flash Floods: a Review of National Weather
    Service Reports, 1969-81.”</emphasis> Public Health Reports: Nov-Dec 1983,
    98(6), pp.584-588.</para>

    <para>Gruntfest, E, and Ripps, A (2000), Flash floods: warning and
    mitigation efforts and prospects. In: Parker, D.J. (Ed.), Floods, vol. 1.
    Routledge, London, pp. 377–390.</para>

    <para>Jonkman, S.N. and Penning-Rowsell, E. (2008). Human Instability in
    Flood Flows. Journal of the American Water Resources Association, Vol. 44,
    No. 4, pp 1 – 11.</para>

    <para>National Flood Risk Advisory Group (NFRAG), 2012. “Managing the
    Floodplain: A Guide to best Practice in Floodplain Risk Management in
    Australia”. Consultation Draft.</para>

    <para>Queensland Commission for Children, Young People, and Child Guardian
    (CCYPCG), 2012.
    https://www.fire.qld.gov.au/communitysafety/swiftwater/default.asp -
    accessed 11 August 2012</para>

    <para>Queensland Fire and Rescue Service, (QFRS) 2012
    https://www.fire.qld.gov.au/communitysafety/swiftwater/default.asp,
    accessed 11 August 2012.</para>

    <para>Shand, T D, Cox, R J, Blacka, M J and Smith G P (2011), “Appropriate
    Safety Criteria for Vehicles – Literature Review”. AR&amp;R Report Number:
    P10/S2/020. Report for Institution of Engineers Australia, Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff Guidelines: Project 10. ISBN 978-0-85825-948-5.</para>

    <para>Smith G P, and Wasko C D, (2012), <emphasis>Two Dimensional
    Simulations in Urban Areas: Representation of Buildings In 2d Numerical
    Flood Models.</emphasis> Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project
    15. Final Report, February 2012.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
