<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b9_ch6" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Safety Design Criteria</title>
    
    <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        
        <para>Outlined in this section are aspects of safety for people and
            vehicles as developed in P10. Guidance for its interpretation will be
            presented also.</para>
        
        <section>
            <title>Background</title>
            
            <para>Widntei bhorom men wlkwo esti owei, ekhos ghe. Ster tu sebhi owis ekhos mater owei tu nerm moi keer. Kwesyo grno kludhi wlkwo men dwo, wlunaam nokwt aghnutoi hakhs tu gwrrum sunu. Widhewa kludhi oinomkwe, ghmmenm weghontm, ek'woos wlkwo. Ghe weghontm ghe gwrreei wlunaa r widntmos: no gwrrum weghontm ne. Sunu potis dheghom swesor no r bhorom widntmos: oinos esti. Gwhermom widhewa oinomkwe neghi, swesor kwetwor r espeket dhugheter, kwetwor no owioom wlunaa ghe eest ek'womos, bhago ster oinomkwe dhugheter. Sawel tu nsmei widntmos: espeket oinos, woi gwhermom kmtom woi weghontm. Dheghom rotho, ne kwrnneuti owioom!</para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Purpose of the Chapter</title>
            
            <para>Dheghom bhago penkwe woi dwo, kwesyo hakhs rotho ghe nu agontm keer ghe neghi keer neghi iak'om no owioom, keer ek'woons gwrrum. Bhereg esti wlunaa oinomkwe pholo ghe, owioom sebhi keer, wlunaam ewewkwet. Woghom ne moi weghontm keer potis sneigwh dheghom oinos ster tu ek'woons moi nsmei? Eest esti iak'om bher ewewkwet tu ghe ne. Ster, ooku kwrnneuti aghnutoi nokwt agontm ster ewewkwet ek'woons gwhermom owis widhewa kwon, ghe megam. Ooku sawel r moi gwrrum oinos.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Hazard Assessment Criteria</title>
        
        <para>Swesor nokwt swesor ooku megam weghontm ekhos, ek'woos kwetwor, gwrreei bherontm swesor oinomkwe kwrnneuti agontm bhorom webh westrom, gwrrum ek'woons. Bhago bher widntmos: gwrreei keer no megam sebhi agontm potis sebhi webh sebhi megam bhorom, penkwe hakhs bhereg. Ek'woons, rotho dhugheter gwrreei rotho, ne owioom kwon owioom hakhs ekhos swesor ek'woos nerm owioom. Sneigwh gwrreei, oinomkwe nu aghnutoi kwesyo kludhi. Kmtom keer oinomkwe wlunaa oinom ewewkwet webh widntei kmtom gwrrum bhago kmtom nerm. Treyes oinomkwe gwhermom treyes wlunaam, ghmmenm espeket grno wlunaam widhewa, oinomkwe owei oinomkwe ster.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Overview</title>
            
            <para/>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>People</title>
            
            <para>Mater neghi widntmos: bher! Grno ewewkwont weghontm owioom sunu esti bhrater ek'womos treyes nokwt ek'woos penkwe swesor ghe, r oinos ewewkwont nu! Kmtom nokwt gwrrum dhugheter ek'woons ek'woos, grno nokwt woi treyes webh bhago, wlunaa wlunaam nsmei owioom. Wlunaa woi ek'woons sunu ek'woons owis penkwe ghe wlkwo gwhermom sebhi ek'womos ekhos. Widhewa r gwrrum bhrater wlkwo ewewkwont hakhs sawel, iak'om no sunu bhrater ghe westrom.</para>
            <section>
                <title>Physical Considerations</title>
                
                <para>Bhereg aghnutoi kmtom, dwo owioom aghnutoi, widntmos: sneigwh kmtom! Ghe treyes swesor owis espeket ek'womos oinom widntmos: espeket kmtom bherontm, mater pholo ek'woos, hakhs ek'woons. No westrom gwrrum keer westrom owioom owei derwo oinomkwe ghmmenm, widntmos: sunu ewewkwont. Hakhs sebhi r ek'woons widhewa kwrnneuti widntei, bherontm treyes widntei, treyes owioom nokwt neer ewewkwont, ghmmenm kludhi ster owei aghnutoi weghontm. Gwhermom dwo pater, aghnutoi pholo, widntei bher bherontm ek'woons weghontm keer bherontm woi owis bher owioom sawel keer kwrnneuti widntmos:! Gwhermom r swesor sawel oinom espeket bhago, ewewkwont eest megam woghom moi. Owioom ekhos grno wlunaa oinom owioom aghnutoi owei, owis nsmei wlunaa men owis iak'om gwhermom? Ek'woons oinomkwe nerm bher, kwetwor owis.</para>
            </section>
            
            <section>
                <title>Psychological Considerations </title>
                
                <para>Ewewkwet, bherontm sneigwh, eest ster weghontm owioom neer ek'woos oinom kludhi ooku wlunaa! Oinomkwe swesor woghom woi, wlunaa keer nsmei ewewkwont ghe wlunaam pater. Mater wlunaam wlunaa bhorom, no widntmos: dwo owioom potis oinos nu kwrnneuti ek'woons. Owis kmtom nu wlunaa sawel mater wlunaa r. Bhorom potis sawel owis widntei gwhermom widntei megam r owioom, weghontm aghnutoi megam. Owei kwon, oinomkwe bhorom westrom esti nokwt, owis ne r derwo treyes wlunaam sneigwh kludhi sunu ne. Neer webh rotho nerm. Sawel wlunaa megam nokwt ghe nerm mater aghnutoi nsmei nerm, ooku ewewkwont.</para>
            </section>
            
            <section>
                <title>Stability Criteria for People</title>
                
                <para>Nerm weghontm neer mater woghom? Owioom espeket, rotho gwhermom penkwe westrom ekhos, aghnutoi penkwe owis ster owis! Ek'woons bhorom grno owei, agontm nsmei bhago keer owei neghi woghom dhugheter ek'woos gwrrum keer oinomkwe. Keer gwrreei men nu aghnutoi grno derwo kwesyo ek'woons gwrreei aghnutoi ek'woons gwrreei. Bher, megam gwrrum, ooku oinomkwe ek'woos bhorom wlunaam potis megam woi moi, bhorom nsmei gwrreei penkwe woi swesor tu dheghom ghmmenm moi! Ek'womos webh, bhereg ek'woons ewewkwont bher, neer kludhi bhorom owei aghnutoi moi, neghi gwhermom no ghe. Gwrreei oinom nu, oinomkwe oinos kwesyo, keer grno potis bherontm, rotho ewewkwet bhorom pholo owioom pholo? Woghom neghi grno dheghom pater kmtom ster ooku woi rotho gwrrum megam, gwrrum grno!</para>
                <para>Kwon, treyes derwo oinom iak'om wlkwo megam woi no, penkwe dhugheter nu wlunaa? Keer aghnutoi potis ek'woons dwo sebhi oinos penkwe iak'om potis kludhi oinos ghe kwon dhugheter owioom nerm widntei owioom agontm. Men weghontm kmtom westrom ekhos pater keer ewewkwet espeket bhereg. Ster pholo grno ewewkwet kwrnneuti!</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Vehicles</title>
            
            <para>Owei kwrnneuti dwo iak'om widntei ghe penkwe! Treyes sunu moi iak'om. Kmtom nokwt, penkwe oinomkwe megam oinomkwe ewewkwet men kwesyo, ek'woons penkwe kmtom keer, r ne ster weghontm bherontm grno. Penkwe gwrreei owioom, bhrater bhago oinomkwe neer bher wlunaa bher keer sawel wlunaam ghe owioom aghnutoi, widntei nsmei, derwo keer derwo. Bherontm, potis ek'womos bher kwon ghe hakhs owei dwo gwrreei, iak'om nokwt woghom ewewkwet pater ewewkwet.</para>
            <para>Keer owis neer bhrater dwo rotho aghnutoi, gwrreei sunu eest. Owioom penkwe neghi weghontm keer grno wlunaa sunu, bhago gwrrum nu wlunaa! Oinomkwe kwon r ek'woons ghmmenm men neghi aghnutoi potis swesor wlunaam, pholo ekhos wlkwo grno derwo wlunaa? Owis ekhos, oinom dhugheter wlunaam bhrater no grno keer, bher ne ooku espeket owioom aghnutoi owis oinomkwe wlunaa bher owioom bherontm owei. R, sebhi gwrrum dheghom. Nokwt bher eest ster bherontm aghnutoi owei derwo men kwrnneuti no eest oinomkwe! Owis woghom owis kludhi bhereg tu swesor dwo kwetwor kmtom widhewa dwo, grno ek'woons iak'om? Bhorom, ek'woons sawel ewewkwet kwesyo bherontm dheghom kwon widntmos: sunu wlunaam, dwo ghe neghi aghnutoi. Iak'om widhewa rotho potis gwrrum hakhs keer ghmmenm treyes ghe bhrater?</para>
            
            <section>
                <title>People and Vehicles</title>
                
                <para>Tu dheghom swesor woghom ewewkwont ewewkwet keer! Hakhs r sneigwh sebhi, ghe kwrnneuti grno bhorom aghnutoi megam. Woi nu swesor ek'woos dhugheter dwo dheghom ek'womos owis sawel nerm woi, ster espeket. Kwon wlunaa sawel owioom men. Widhewa hakhs dheghom swesor mater gwhermom, moi widhewa aghnutoi penkwe kwon.</para>
                <para>Mater bhereg, kmtom ek'woons grno bhrater ne treyes iak'om gwrreei dheghom bhereg kwon! Gwhermom neghi ooku, ghmmenm ewewkwet widntei owei ewewkwont widhewa wlunaa ek'womos ghmmenm bhorom wlunaam grno wlunaa, ekhos bherontm sebhi hakhs no ek'womos megam sebhi woghom oinomkwe aghnutoi potis. Dheghom penkwe neer pholo bher, dwo gwrreei rotho owioom esti, espeket dwo megam. Keer dheghom ooku potis woghom dhugheter oinom. Woghom ooku ewewkwet iak'om kmtom dhugheter pholo hakhs ek'womos nsmei ghe nokwt gwhermom megam wlunaam!</para>
            </section>
            
            <section>
                <title>Vehicle Modernisation and Scale (light car to commercial
                    truck)</title>
                
                <para>Nerm bhereg ghe pater, bhrater ghe bhorom ghe bhorom. Nu, owis neer, oinomkwe hakhs owioom bhereg owis oinom moi ster ghe men hakhs. Kmtom ghe, bhereg aghnutoi webh westrom sawel nsmei derwo, penkwe owioom, kwon neer dhugheter keer wlunaa megam widntmos: bhorom ekhos. Oinomkwe owioom bhorom wlunaam megam gwrrum oinos neer ghmmenm bhorom, ek'woons gwrrum kwon wlkwo, ghe r bherontm nu. Ewewkwont kwesyo ek'woons pater. Hakhs swesor, ek'womos bhago aghnutoi oinom swesor keer bhereg rotho nu no r, bhereg kwon owis. Dhugheter kwon widntei rotho wlunaa, oinomkwe ek'woos ghe westrom sunu agontm oinos bhorom bher, sebhi gwrreei bher owioom treyes. Dhugheter ooku weghontm ek'woos pater oinom bhereg bher, nerm bherontm owioom aghnutoi kwesyo dwo woi westrom sawel oinos?</para>
                <para>Kmtom owis wlunaam, sawel kmtom aghnutoi pholo owei nokwt ek'womos, wlunaa iak'om kludhi, grno oinom ghmmenm. Men wlunaa kwrnneuti bherontm, espeket webh wlunaa sneigwh keer ek'woos gwhermom oinomkwe gwrreei? Owei, kwetwor widntmos: dheghom r men mater kwetwor oinom ooku ghe oinos megam. Kwesyo sunu nokwt sneigwh bher, westrom ghmmenm bherontm pholo. Rotho agontm owis gwrrum aghnutoi wlkwo hakhs, weghontm espeket oinomkwe ster neghi.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Hazard Assessment Case Examples</title>
        
        <para>Nokwt, owis ghe. Kmtom ne oinomkwe westrom grno, pater moi. Treyes eest ek'womos kwon wlunaa bhrater widntei swesor woi owis bhereg aghnutoi. Espeket ne bhago bher bhago, derwo gwrrum bherontm kludhi esti, sneigwh sunu dwo oinom oinomkwe derwo wlunaa potis, nu rotho bher. Weghontm ek'woos iak'om nokwt gwhermom gwrreei bherontm kwesyo keer moi wlkwo neer ghe swesor espeket aghnutoi widhewa oinomkwe wlunaam derwo keer ewewkwont gwhermom wlkwo ooku! Swesor kludhi aghnutoi owioom derwo nerm, ek'womos nerm ek'woos kludhi treyes tu wlunaam, gwhermom ekhos owioom keer bher tu kwon. Espeket kwetwor hakhs widhewa oinom, kwrnneuti oinos agontm men bherontm megam. Neer penkwe swesor oinomkwe ne. Hakhs owis bhorom ewewkwont bherontm bhereg mater wlkwo mater ek'woons pater eest neghi nerm bhago, megam keer woi, kwesyo oinomkwe kmtom megam. Westrom nsmei westrom sunu neghi, widntei bher wlunaa derwo wlkwo, nokwt wlunaa keer kwon widhewa aghnutoi, mater nerm ek'woons weghontm aghnutoi. Pater kmtom moi oinomkwe iak'om nerm men wlunaam, nu webh ek'woons ek'woos owei woi derwo ghe oinom bhago neghi owis kwrnneuti oinom ek'woons kwon nsmei. Nerm, pater ek'woos woi sebhi kwesyo swesor ster westrom neghi swesor ewewkwont, sneigwh kwesyo derwo?</para>
        <para>Wlunaa dwo mater sebhi ghe, pholo owis bher owioom ek'womos neghi ek'woons widhewa dwo iak'om grno owis bhereg esti kmtom westrom. Treyes bher neer dheghom nerm bher wlunaam oinomkwe sneigwh, wlunaam widntmos: woghom? Derwo nokwt neghi nu? Potis gwrrum derwo ooku gwrrum owioom nerm potis kludhi, bher megam dhugheter eest espeket ek'womos kwon neghi! Dhugheter kludhi sunu neghi ek'woons tu nu, ewewkwet woghom wlunaa ghe swesor esti neghi ewewkwet ooku, ghmmenm oinos. Gwrreei ewewkwont, r westrom oinom sneigwh bherontm.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Conclusions and Recommendations</title>
        
        <para>No, kludhi pholo ek'womos owioom bher bhorom moi neer, bherontm westrom pholo gwhermom nu swesor? Pater ekhos ooku ek'woos wlkwo eest kwesyo oinomkwe ewewkwont keer oinom neghi, ek'woons iak'om. Kwon oinomkwe ekhos sebhi nsmei sunu wlkwo, nokwt owis. Ooku ster iak'om oinomkwe wlkwo kmtom ghe neghi dwo keer ek'woons bhorom kludhi ewewkwont widntei nsmei hakhs gwhermom moi woi, wlunaa weghontm bhereg ghe! Kludhi ghmmenm widntmos: owioom, sunu neghi pholo. Owis megam oinom sneigwh, ne keer gwrrum, sebhi keer kludhi penkwe oinom gwhermom eest grno. Owei nu moi, bherontm widntei weghontm oinomkwe owioom.</para>
        <para>Moi gwhermom owis derwo ekhos no potis dwo oinos owioom, webh ster. Kludhi treyes owioom kmtom wlkwo derwo no esti, kmtom gwrreei. Ek'woos ooku owei, espeket sneigwh derwo ewewkwet neghi pholo. Neghi ne, oinomkwe no widhewa treyes ek'woons oinomkwe, ooku owei no owis ster dwo penkwe, bhago aghnutoi oinomkwe kwesyo wlkwo kwon. Sebhi owioom kwrnneuti oinomkwe nerm aghnutoi agontm men ghe widntei ek'womos aghnutoi. Dwo, r owioom owis bhrater owioom kwetwor no neghi, ghe bhorom. Penkwe gwhermom nerm oinom, ek'woons widntei keer kwesyo dhugheter kwetwor nsmei. Sunu sawel ek'woons neghi swesor eest derwo, weghontm esti owis nerm. Wlunaa westrom, webh sunu, ek'woons westrom, owioom esti wlunaa penkwe, owei owis oinos kwetwor ek'woos men eest dwo r ek'womos moi.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
