<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b7_ch5" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
  xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  
  <info>
  
    <title>Determination of Model Parameters</title>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weeks_william.xml"/>
       
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>
  
  </info>
  
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section>
    <title>Introduction </title>
    <para>Following the selection of the catchment modelling system and the catchment and floodplain
      representation required, the next step is the estimation of appropriate model parameters to
      apply to the model platforms in the required application. </para>
    <para>A flood model is a representation of the physical catchment processes affecting floods and
      the implementation is defined by a parameter set to apply the model to the specific problem
      being considered. The estimation of these parameters is often referred to as the calibration
      process.</para>
    <para>While the term calibration strictly applies only where there is observed data to calibrate
      against, in this chapter calibration is defined here in general terms as the process for
      determining appropriate model parameters for the hydrologic and hydraulic models to ensure
      that they can be applied to the design flood estimation problem being considered. It involves
      varying model parameters to ensure that model results match observed data, to confirm that the
      model is performing adequately and is consistent with the records. Calibration can be carried
      out in a variety of ways and this chapter discusses appropriate methods of calibrating
      hydrologic and hydraulic models.</para>
    <para>While the models used for these applications will generally have some representation of
      the physical characteristics of the catchment, meaning that the model parameters should be
      based on these physical features, there will always be uncertainty and the parameters will
      need to be estimated using available data to ensure that the model is at least consistent with
      the observed catchment performance. If the model represents physical processes closely,
      parameter values could be measured from catchment characteristics, but this is an uncommon
      situation.</para>
    <para>The parameter estimation process may be based on recorded data (if there are suitable
      records in the project area) or may be based on regional estimates if the local catchment is
      ungauged or data is limited. There is a gradation between these two extremes however, it is
      rare that there is absolutely no available information to assist in setting parameters. It is
      also rare to find that there is sufficient data to allow a precise parameter determination, so
      the objective in determining parameters is to ensure that as much data as possible is used in
      this exercise. </para>
    <para>Flood investigations usually require both hydrologic (calculation of design flood
      discharges) and hydraulic (calculation of flood levels, velocities and flow distributions as
      well as design of drainage systems) modelling applications, so this chapter covers both of
      these.</para>
    <para> This chapter describes the different approaches to determining model parameters for the
      range of flood investigations and for the different amounts of available data.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>The approach to parameter determination will depend on a number of factors which will
      determine the approach to the calibration and the level of detail sought in the process. This
      includes the model platform and the design problem.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Physical basis of model</title>
      <para>Some models platforms may be purely ‘black-box’ or heavily conceptualised mathematical
        representations of the physical processes while others are more directly based on actual
        physical processes. Parameter estimation will be based on measurable catchment
        characteristics for model platforms where there is a direct physical basis for the
        parameters, and in these cases it is easier to establish model parameters. Most model
        platforms are likely to have at least some physical basis; it is thus possible to establish
        an acceptable range for model parameters, and model parameters calibrated to observed data
        should only be allowed to vary within this range.</para>
      <para>During calibration, the parameters that are physically based should be defined using the
        catchment characteristics, while the other parameters can be varied so that the model
        results match the observed data, ensuring that the values remain within reasonable and
        acceptable limits.</para>
      <para> The sensitivity of model parameters is also variable and some parameters have a greater
        influence on the model output than others. In some cases, there may be inadequate data to
        allow an accurate determination of actual parameter values. Therefore, these parameter
        values must be set using knowledge of model and catchment processes. There is a concern
        though that some parameters (eg. Non-linearity parameters in runoff-routing models) may be
        important in design situations where rare floods are to be modelled but the observed data
        does not include any floods of the required magnitude. Therefore these parameters may appear
        insensitive during calibration but they have a major influence in the design
        situation.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Guiding Principles</title>
    <para>Establishment of and applying models will vary depending on particular circumstances.
      However, for flood estimation applications, the following guiding principles will
      apply:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>All Available Data both formal and anecdotal should be considered in the calibration
          and the best use should be made of this data, in-line with its assessed accuracy and
          reliability. This data is the only way to ensure that the model application can be
          consistent with available local information. It is also important to carefully review the
          data to ensure that it is consistent and there are no obvious errors that will affect
          model performance.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>When calibrating the model parameters, it is important that the practitioner has an
          understanding of the role and relative importance of the different parameters and how they
          influence model operation. During calibration it is then important to concentrate on the
          most influential parameters, especially those that affect the model performance in the
          areas of particular concern for the specific model application.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Model parameters when fitted to the data should be reasonable and within the range
          expected for the model platform and should be consistent with the physical features of the
          catchment being considered. If parameters are not within this typical range , the model
          conceptualisation could be incorrect and while the model may appear reasonable during
          calibration, there will be serious concerns for design events modelled where the event
          magnitude is run outside the range of that used for calibration. It is also possible that
          parameters outside the typical range may indicate errors in the observed data, and the
          calibration may be attempting to fit the model to these errors. The data quality and
          consistency then needs to be reconsidered and the calibration reanalysed
          accordingly.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Even if the data is of poor quality and incomplete, it is important that the model
      calibration be at least consistent with the available information, especially local or
      anecdotal information where formal data collection is lacking. Even very poor quality
      observations may be sufficient to apply a ‘common sense test’ and to ensure that even an
      essentially uncalibrated model can be a reasonable representation of local conditions. </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Parameter Determination for Catchment Modelling Systems</title>
    <section>
      <title>General Approach</title>
      <para>This section provides guidance on the parameter estimation for model platforms (both
        hydrologic and hydraulic models). Many principles are the same for these two calibration
        processes, but there are some differences in the data and approaches.</para>
      <para>There are four basic approaches that will normally be dictated by the available
        calibration data and sometimes by the project budget and timeframe, and this classification
        is not as simple as the division into gauged or ungauged catchments.</para>
      <para>The four primary categories are:</para>
      <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">No Data</emphasis>
           - This is the lower limit to data availability, and having no data at all is
            probably not a common situation. In this situation, regional methods of some type are
            required. In addition to formal regional methods, parameters can be determined from
            experience with applications on similar systems or where the physical characteristics
            are similar.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Very Limited Data</emphasis> - The limited data may be some
            anecdotal records (<xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>). An example for the design of drainage
            structures on a road or railway would be reports on the frequency of closure by
            flooding. In this case, it is possible to develop parameters that mean that the model is
            at least consistent with local observations. It may also be the case that the limited
            data is apparently inaccurate or inconsistent, though the exact source of this
            inaccuracy may be difficult to detect. In any case, efforts should be made to
            incorporate any information available in accordance with its assessed accuracy and
            reliability, no matter how limited this may be.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Some Data </emphasis>- In this case there may be a streamflow gauge with a
            very short period of record, records of flood levels for a single flood event or there
            may be records for a very frequent flood event. Some rainfall gauge information may be
            available. In this case, there will be a greater degree of confidence in the
            calibration, but the limited data means that there will still be uncertainty in the
            model performance, especially when the model is used for extrapolation to larger design
            events outside the range of the limited data or applied to alternative development
            scenarios.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Extensive Data</emphasis> - In this case, there is extensive data
            throughout the floodplain and catchment of interest. Data is available for a range of
            flood magnitudes and conditions and the flood data is accurate, reliable and consistent.
            In this case, the model calibration will be reliable and the model can be confidently
            used for design flood investigations.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>These four categories blend together and there will be a gradation from one to the
        other. Projects where data is totally lacking are not common and projects with extensive
        data are also unusual. The objective is to consider all available data and to make the best
        use of all available information. </para>
      <para> In the following sections the term <emphasis role="italic">‘calibration’</emphasis> is
        applied to parameter estimation approaches c) and d), where the availability of flood data
        is sufficient to allow a calibration process that compares model results to observed flood
        data.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Types of Calibration Data</title>
      <para>Types of calibration data are detailed in <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/> and include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Historical changes to topography, land-use, structures and drainage
            infrastructure;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Records (photographs) of bed, bank and floodplain vegetation levels to assist with
            interpretation of roughness and provide record of prevailing conditions;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Rainfall records (daily and pluviograph records), including in adjacent
            catchments;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Gauged water level hydrographs, rating curves and derived flow hydrographs at
            streamflow gauge sites;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Streamflow gauging at gauge sites and over the side of bridge structures (rare, but
            useful);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tidal level records if in a tidal area;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flood mark levels, location and measure of reliability. For example, debris marks,
            watermarks on/in buildings;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Descriptive anecdotal information and past reports of flood behaviour in
            general;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Observations of the rate of rise of flood waters and the time of peak;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Photographs or videos of historical floods;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Records or observations on water speeds and/or flow patterns;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Records of blockage at hydraulic structures such as culverts and gully traps;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Records and photography of the extent of inundation, noting the time of the photos;
            and</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Information on road/railway closures.</para>
      <sidebar>
        <para>A flood occurred whilst calibrating a model. One of the local landowners phoned and
          asked if there was anything he could do? Make as many flood marks as you can, and if
          possible try to record when the marks were made. The local diligently went round hammering
          nails into trees until the flood peaked. After several weeks trying to calibrate to this
          fantastic data set, the practitioners were desperate, and visited the landowner. The model
          is always showing much higher levels than you’ve recorded. After a while the landowner
          took them over to the creek bank and showed them a levee hidden amongst the trees. Don’t
          tell anyone he says, as I’m not sure if it’s legal. In the end he agreed to have it
          surveyed, and lo and behold the model calibrated beautifully!</para>
      </sidebar>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Anecdotal Information</title>
      <para>While sourcing the observed flood data, it is important to also source descriptive or
        anecdotal information. This information can be just as valuable in the calibration process,
        especially where the observed data are scarce. Anecdotal information is best sourced
        through:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Discussions with Local Residents on their Recollections and
            Observations </emphasis>
          - For example, they may have experienced a flood event and have noted features such
            as flow directions, water speeds and the timing of the flood’s rise and fall. This
            information can be valuable to help check that the model’s representation of flow
            behaviour is realistic; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem><para><emphasis role="italic">Information From Stakeholders</emphasis> - For example, a road
          or railway authority may be able to advise how frequently a crossing is inundated and/or for
          how long. While this may not provide event specific observed data, it could be useful as to
          whether the model is in the right general area of performance.</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <sidebar>
        <para>An old timer recalled how his grandfather remembered a large flood in the 1860s that
          broke across a ridge in two locations. Today, this would isolate the hospital and be a
          significant flood risk to homes. The 1% AEP flood did not show this flood behaviour,
          however, when the 0.2% AEP event was run, these floodways developed. This helped convince
          the old timer that the modelling was good, and the local council incorporated these
          floodways into their flood risk management planning.</para>
      </sidebar>
      <sidebar>
        <para>During a resident survey a local shop owner took the practitioner to look at a tree.
          “See that fork up there; well that was where a pig got stuck.” Fortunately, the modelling
          for that event showed flooding to that height, and was proof to the local that the model
          was “doing the right thing”.</para>
      </sidebar>
      
     
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Range of Flood Data</title>
      <para>Calibration of flood models requires observed flood data (<xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>) and
        generally data for several different flood events is needed. Application with data only from
        a single flood event means that there is less confidence in the calibration when
        extrapolating to design flood applications, especially considering that there may be errors
        in the data from the single event and this cannot be checked for consistency with
        others.</para>
      <para>It is therefore desirable to have data for more than one flood event available for
        calibration, and hopefully several floods where a range of conditions is covered. Having
        floods of different magnitudes so that the flooding covers in-bank and floodplain flows and
        where flooding occurs in different seasons and with different rainfall distributions and
        catchment conditions will build confidence in the model performance. Successful calibration
        on a wide range of calibration events means that the model can be extrapolated to a wider
        range of design flood situations confidently.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Hydrologic and Hydraulic Models</title>
      <para>The use of catchment modelling systems for design flood estimation generally involves
        two applications, namely the hydrologic and hydraulic components.</para>
      <para>The hydrologic component, which is the model used to calculate flood peak discharges or
        flood hydrographs, is the more critical of the two, as any errors from hydrologic modelling
        will also transfer to the hydraulic modelling component. Calibration of the hydrologic model
        requires recorded flood flows, and these generally require a streamflow gauge. Availability
        of a streamflow gauge measuring discharges is less common than having flood level
        observations which may be provided by local residents and other non-experts. In some cases
        observed flood levels can be converted to flood flows by application of a stage-discharge
        relationship derived by a theoretical method (<xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>), but this introduces
        another level of uncertainty into the calculation of discharge. The hydrologic model should
        be calibrated to ensure that the model can calculate flood flows to match the recordings.
        Calibration of hydrologic models must consider the accuracy of the recorded data and the
        consistency between different observations. These issues are discussed further below.</para>
      <para>The hydraulic modelling process involves setting relevant parameters so that the
        modelled flood levels or flood hydrographs match the observed data. Observed flood levels
        are more commonly measured than flood discharges so there is often more extensive data.
        However, flood levels may be matched with a hydraulic model where the calculated discharges
        and hydraulic model parameters (primarily hydraulic roughness) are both incorrect and the
        errors compensate. While this is not necessarily a problem for the actual historical flood
        used for calibration, this can lead to significant errors when using the model for design
        applications over a larger range of flood events.</para>
      <para>In many cases though, the hydrologic and hydraulic models may be calibrated together,
        ie. Joint calibration. In this situation, there may be observed flood levels but no recorded
        discharges, and the parameters for both the hydrologic and hydraulic models are adjusted
        together and the discharge determined such that the final flood levels are matched. As with
        the calibration of hydraulic models, this situation may lead to compensating errors in the
        two models, and the calibration may appear reasonable but the compensating errors mean that
        flood estimation for floods of different magnitude may be significantly in error. The
        compensating errors mean that the flood discharge is too low and the roughness is too high
        and the flood levels match, or the opposite.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Selection of Calibration Events</title>
      <para>Prior to collecting and analysing all data for a calibration exercise, suitable historic
        events need to be identified and selected. The practitioner should primarily consider
        the:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Amount, type and quality of suitable data available for each event; and </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Magnitudes of the events as to whether they are of a similar size to that of the
            primary design events. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Each calibration event must have sufficient historic flood observation and reliable
        topographic information and boundary data at the time of the flood. Often this means that
        events used for calibration are relatively recent, as the data sets are likely to be more
        complete. Larger floods that may have occurred longer ago may not be suitable for
        calibrating to due to the lack or scarcity of key data sets.</para>
      <para>Calibration events should ideally also span the magnitude range of the intended design
        events with a preference for the more important design floods (eg. 1% Annual Exceedance
        Probability event). This instils confidence in the ability of the model to replicate flow
        behaviour over the full range of event magnitudes. For example, a frequent flow event that
        is confined to the channel and drainage infrastructure will have a substantially different
        behaviour to a rare flood event that has broken the banks and is flowing overland. If the
        model has only been calibrated to the in-bank flow magnitude, confidence in its ability to
        replicate overland flow will be lower.</para>
      <para>For tidal sections of a flood model, a tidal calibration is a useful additional
        calibration step, and is particularly recommended where storm tide inundation and
        interaction with catchment flooding is important. Tidal calibration data often exists, or
        can be readily measured, and is usually an accurate data set. It also provides a check that
        the model can reproduce any tidal amplification.</para>
      <sidebar>
        <para>The 1998 flood in Katherine was larger than a 1% AEP event. There were extensive water
          level measurements taken throughout the town, many photographs and videos and the flood
          discharge was gauged at the gauging station. Therefore, the data available for calibration
          at Katherine for this event could be regarded as ideal: a large recent event with a
          reliable and extensive dataset.</para>
      </sidebar>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Calibration Processes</title>
      <para>The calibration process for flood models involves the adjustment of model parameters so
        that the model results match the recorded data. This process can proceed in one of several
        ways, though often a combination of different approaches is most effective.</para>
      <para>When there is good quality data, there are automatic calibration algorithms that follow
        a defined search procedure to result in an “optimum” parameter set. While in theory, this
        procedure can result in a good quality parameter set with a minimum of effort, this approach
        is not as straightforward as first impressions indicate. The first step is to define an
        objective function that must be minimised for the optimisation. This may be minimising the
        root mean square error for the differences between observed and modelled flows. While this
        function may lead to a generally overall reasonable result, it may be more important to
        concentrate on high flows for example (a common requirement for flood studies), the rising
        limb of flood hydrographs (required for flood forecasting) or hydrograph volumes and shape
        (commonly needed for floodplains with extensive floodplain storage). These secondary details
        are often equally important and it is generally found that a purely automatic optimisation
        procedure does not converge to the optimum parameter set for a particular application,
        unless the objective function of the optimisation procedure has been carefully
        chosen.</para>
      <para>Automatic parameter optimisation routines do not necessarily include an understanding of
        model processes and, if the objective function is not well selected, the optimisation may
        not represent the particular model application and produce realistic parameters. Manual
        parameter optimisation is the situation where the practitioner can vary model parameters
        based on the results of earlier model runs to progressively adjust model performance, and to
        incorporate an understanding of the model and catchment processes and the required model
        application.</para>
      <para>Automatic optimisation procedures provide an approach for parameter estimation that in
        some situations can result in a good fit to the calibration data. However, in large and
        complex models there are usually many parameters, some of which only influence the model
        performance in particular circumstances. These automatic procedures may result in
        unrealistic parameter values and the performance outside the calibration range depends to a
        large extent on the objective function chosen for optimisation. Many objective functions
        will focus on the rarer floods while baseflow and frequent floods are poorly represented.
        These other details of the streamflow pattern are often important and it is difficult to
        find an objective function that can operate for all of the different conditions that may be
        needed.</para>
      <para>Because of this, the most appropriate means of model parameter estimation should involve
        both automatic and manual parameter estimation where the modeller uses experience and
        understanding to estimate parameters appropriate for the particular application and the
        automatic procedures can refine and polish the optimisation.</para>
      <para>Calibration, especially for large and complex models, may require a long process and
        tests on a large number of parameter combinations and variations. In this situation (which
        is common, except for the most simple situations) it is important that the practitioner
        maintains a log of calibration tests so that the impact of parameter changes can be
        understood and the calibration can proceed without retracing previous calibration
        tests.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Objective Function for Calibration</title>
      <para>When a hydrologic or hydraulic model is being calibrated, the objective is to match the
        model results to observed data, but there are different ways of measuring the quality of the
        model fit.</para>
      <para>A common application is to fit the model results to observed flood levels or flood
        hydrographs. Obviously, the objective is to fit the observations as closely as possible.
        However, the model will often show that it is over-estimating for some points and
        under-estimating for others or one flood may be consistently over-estimated while another is
        consistently under-estimated.</para>
      <para>The aim therefore should be to provide the best “overall” match, though this is hard to
        define. Points to consider are that there should not be any consistent error, there should
        be some recorded points above the model results and some below and points of lower accuracy
        should not be weighted as heavily as those regarded of high accuracy. Estimates of rare
        design floods are most often required for flood studies, so the optimisation should normally
        be weighted towards the larger calibration events.</para>
      <para>In most situations, flood peak levels are the most important objective, but in some
        cases, the hydrograph shape or flood volume may be of as much significance as the flood peak
        levels, so the model application must be considered when deciding on the objective
        function.</para>
      <para>The objective function may be a mathematical parameter, such as minimising the sum of
        squares of the errors, or the function may be based more simply on fitting “by eye”, where
        judgement can be used to determine the quality of fit for different features of the observed
        flood record. There is a place for both of these approaches, even in a single
        application.</para>
      <para>The calibration is assisted when the practitioner has a good understanding of the model
        processes and the influence of all parameters in the model. Knowledge of which parameters
        are most influential, and the influence of each parameter on different aspects of the flood
        process, is important in ensuring that the model parameters are maintained with realistic
        values and that efforts are not wasted working on insensitive parameters. Models with
        multiple parameters will usually exhibit interaction between the parameters so that it is
        possible that a similar calibration performance is achieved with different parameter sets.
        With incorrect parameter combinations, while the calibration performance may be similar,
        there are likely to be major differences in the design application results when the model is
        applied to conditions outside the range used for calibration. It is important therefore to
        have an understanding of the model operation and the relationship between parameters and
        physical characteristics to help keep parameters within reasonable bounds, especially when
        considering interactions between parameters.</para>
      <para>Therefore a single objective function cannot be recommended for all model calibrations,
        a variety of methods will be applicable for particular applications.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Data Issues</title>
    <section>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <para>When calibrating models for flood analysis, the first point is the assessment of the
        available data. Clearly maximising the quantity of data used for calibration will be a
        priority. However the data should be accurate and consistent or the calibration process may
        be impossible or it may lead to an incorrect model application and the catchment modelling
        system will be impossible to apply in practice. It is important to be aware that the flood
        estimation models need to be applied to practical problems, and the focus of model
        calibration is not just the preparation of a model that is well calibrated to the available
        flood data. Application of the model to the design requirements must be the primary focus,
        and the calibration must be prepared to the extent needed to have confidence in the design
        application.</para>
      <para>While it is important to critically review the quality of the data available for
        calibration, it is also important to carefully review all available data and maximise the
        information available in this data to ensure the best possible calibration process. Formal
        data collection programmes are an immediately obvious source, but all available information
        should be examined. For example, old historic records from newspapers may be available to
        give an indication of major historic floods from before official records are available.
        These old records though do need careful study, since the survey datum may be hard to
        identify but some “detective” work can yield valuable information.</para>
      <para>Careful review of the quality and properties of the data being applied for calibration
        is essential to ensure that it is appropriate and that the practitioner has a good
        understanding of the availability and applicability of the data. This is especially
        important for older historic data. Issues can include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The datum used for level survey where older data may use a different datum or two
            sets of survey data may be to two different datums;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Streamflow gauge records of water levels are often measured to a local datum, which
            may be difficult to relate to topographic data;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Stream channels may scour or silt up over time so current conditions may be
            different from those when the flood records were collected; and </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Floodplain roughness may vary with time, for example, sugar cane fields may be bare
            ground or very dense sugar cane depending on the time of year when the flood
            occurs.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Many types of informal data collection can assist in ensuring that model calibration is
        as accurate as possible, and these are discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>, where the
        value of data in all types of flood estimation is identified.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Changes to Catchment Conditions</title>
      <para>The catchment condition data used in a model platform is typically that of the current
        day. This is due to the fact that an airborne and infrastructure survey is usually
        undertaken close to study commencement. In using this current day dataset, there are a
        number of potential calibration issues that the practitioner needs to consider.</para>
      <para>As described in <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>, catchment conditions at each of the relevant
        historic calibration/verification periods must be established and used in the model. Changes
        to conditions that may affect flood behaviour include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>dam construction;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>changes to initial dam storage levels and/or operations;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>dredging or siltation of river entrances;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>levee construction or raising;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>road/railway raising or duplication;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>new road/railway embankments;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>new culverts or bridges;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>upgraded drainage networks;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>development on the floodplain;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>different crop types or growth stage;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>changes in stream bed and bank profiles; and</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para> changes to vegetation including seasonal variations.</para>
      <sidebar>
        <para>The last major river flood in one coastal area occurred in 1974 and resulted in
          extensive inundation of the floodplains. At this time, the floodplain was mostly utilised
          as grazing land. That land is now developed with extensive canal and flood mitigation
          works. While model calibrations for these rivers must rely on data from the 1974 flood,
          the drastically changed conditions mean that calibration results must be treated with
          appropriate caution.</para>
      </sidebar>
      <sidebar>
        <para>A 2D model was constantly producing flood levels that were too low in the upper tidal
          reaches of one branch of a coastal river. However, modelled flood levels matched recorded
          well in all other locations. Not even extremely high Manning's n values would lift
          modelled levels to those recorded. It was initially suspected that the recorded levels
          were erroneous, but this was proved incorrect when the recorded flood levels were
          independently resurveyed and found to be accurate. It was later revealed by a long term
          resident that a weir that had been installed to prevent saline water penetrating upstream,
          had never been completely removed and was still controlling flows. Once this partial weir
          was included in the model, a good fit was obtained with the same parameters used elsewhere
          in the model.</para>
      </sidebar>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Acceptance of Calibration</title>
    <para>When calibrating model parameters an important decision is to determine when the
      calibration is acceptable and when further refinement cannot be justified. There is often a
      temptation to continue to refine model parameters beyond what can be justified by the
      available data, which may be a lengthy process that does not lead to any improved performance
      in model application.</para>
    <sidebar>
      <para>It is far more important to understand why a model may not be calibrating well at a
        particular location than to use unrealistic parameter values to ‘force’ the model to
        calibrate.</para>
    </sidebar>
    <para>Considerations in the decision on when calibration can be accepted are:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Accuracy of Calibration Data </emphasis>
        - The quality of calibration will depend on the assessed accuracy of the calibration
          data (refer to section on Data Issues above). For example, if the calibration of a
          hydraulic model is based on flood levels from observed debris marks, these levels may not
          be more accurate than ± 300 mm, so working towards matching a number of levels to a higher
          level of accuracy cannot be justified. Even where there is a streamflow gauge located on
          the catchment, the quality of the measured discharge will depend on the quality of the
          rating curve, which could cause quite significant inaccuracy in this measured data.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Representativeness of Calibration Data</emphasis>
         - Calibration data may not be representative of the floods required for application
          of the model. For example, it is often the case that calibration floods are relatively
          frequent while design applications require much rare floods. In this case, the value of
          refining the model calibration extensively to the frequent floods cannot be justified,
          since the significant extrapolation of the model means that the parameters may not be
          justified.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Number of Calibration Events</emphasis>
         - The quality of calibration depends on the representativeness of the data and an
          important factor in this area is the number and range of events with suitable calibration
          data. In some cases, there may be only a single frequent flood event available for
          calibration and in this case, the quality of calibration will be poor especially where the
          model must be extrapolated to rare design events. When a model can be calibrated to
          several different flood events of a range of sizes and covering a range of different
          conditions (such as rainfall distribution or season), the resulting model can be applied
          with much more confidence than is possible where the data is limited.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Model Response and Catchment Consistency</emphasis>
         - The calibration of models relies on the available data and the estimated parameters
          are based on the data used to estimate the parameters. However, the catchment conditions
          that applied during model calibration, especially if rare historic floods have occurred,
          may not be completely representative of conditions required for design applications.
          Because of this the model parameters required for design should be “generic” parameters
          based on the calibration but applicable for the design application. The exact catchment
          conditions for design applications may not be consistent with the particular conditions
          that applied for the calibration process. For example, vegetation coverage on a floodplain
          or the channel conditions in water courses will vary from time to time, so the conditions
          that applied for a single calibration flood event may not be representative of long term
          average conditions. Parameter values therefore must be modified to account for the
          expected future design conditions, rather than an unrepresentative calibration
          event.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Consistency of Data</emphasis>
         - Review of data may indicate that the recorded data is inconsistent. For example,
          recorded flood levels for two different floods may be impossible to model with the same
          parameter set. There are several possible reasons for this possibility. For example, the
          recordings may be inaccurate, the catchment or floodplain may have changed between flood
          events or the model may be inappropriate for the analysis required. The effort should then
          be concentrated on resolving the source of the inconsistency rather than pursuing further
          calibration.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Requirements for Model</emphasis>
         - The calibration acceptance may vary depending on the application required. For
          example, if the model is required for a bridge design, the calibration is only really
          critical for the bridge site, but model performance over a wider extent of the catchment
          is needed for floodplain planning. Also if the model is required for assessment of
          frequent floods, the performance for major overbank flooding is not as relevant so poor
          performance for these events is not a serious concern.
      </para></listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        <emphasis role="italic">"Overfitting"</emphasis>
         - This is the process where the model calibration process is taken to an extreme,
          and the model parameters are extended to possibly unrealistic values and can vary
          unrealistically throughout a catchment or floodplain to ensure that the model fit is close
          for all data points and all events. This situation may result when there are unrealistic
          calibration acceptance criteria adopted for the project and the only way of meeting the
          criteria is by an extreme and unrealistic parameter set. While the resulting model
          calibration may appear to be high quality and does meet calibration performance criteria,
          the resulting model parameters will not improve the performance of the model for
          extrapolation to the design situation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <sidebar>
      <para>It is extremely rare that a flood model will fit all data well. This usually means one
        of the following: </para>
      <para>1. The model has been overfitted to the data with unrealistic parameter values;
        and</para>
      <para>2. Some of the data that does not fit well, has been ignored and not presented.</para>
      <para> It is extremely unlikely that your simple model is perfectly representing the complex
        real world well, all your data has been collected without error, or is unaffected by local
        factors.</para>
    </sidebar>
    <para>For these reasons, it is difficult to define an acceptance criterion for model calibration
      and the quality of calibration may vary depending on particular conditions. It is important
      though to consider all the issues covered here when deciding on calibration performance.
      Unrealistic calibration criteria do not lead to an improvement in model design applications so
      the criteria need to be tailored for the particular application and local situation.</para>
    <para>The quality of calibration depends on the quality of the data applied so the model
      application and results should consider this in interpretations of model results.</para>
    <para>It is recommended that specifications for flood studies should not be prescriptive in
      defining calibration criteria, but should aim for realistic and applicable criteria.</para>
    <para>It is important to note that a calibration process may not always result in a parameter
      set that is suitable for application to design conditions, and it is always necessary to
      approach calibration data critically. In these cases, the calibration process must be
      supplemented with other information such as regional parameter estimates as discussed in <xref
        linkend="b7_ch6"/>.</para>
    <para>Sensitivity testing of inputs and parameter values is a good way of understanding and
      resolving the importance of the input/parameter on the model’s calibration results. This is
      discussed further in <xref linkend="b7_ch7"/>.</para>
    <sidebar>
      <para>Following a large flood event that occurred in 1984, Council organised the survey of
        over 400 peak flood marks across the floodplains of the affected catchment. These were
        primarily flood debris marks. Prior to model calibration, Council specified that the
        calibration criteria was for modelled peak water levels to be within 300mm of recorded.
        However, calibration was accepted with 50% of points meeting this criterion in recognition
        of significant proven uncertainties in debris mark levels and some of the model
        inputs.</para>
    </sidebar>
    <sidebar>
      <para>When calibrating a model to peak flood levels for one historic event, a good match
        between modelled and observed was obtained for all levels with the exception of the one
        recorded by the most upstream automatic gauge. The datum of the offending gauge was checked
        and no problem was found. In order to match this gauge, Manning's n values needed to be set
        at values that were outside the normal range and very different to elsewhere in the model.
        In addition, the peak level at this gauge looked out of place on a longitudinal plot of the
        river profile. Despite a strong desire to have the model calibrate well to this one gauge
        level, the client accepted the practitioner’s advice that confidence in the accuracy of the
        observed level was low and it would be compromising the model to fit the data. Not long
        after the study was complete, a larger flood occurred and the model fitted all gauge data
        very well, including the troublesome gauge. It was concluded that something had gone wrong
        with the automatic gauge in the earlier event.</para>
    </sidebar>
    <section>
      <title>Matching Timing and Magnitude</title>
      <para>Ideally, a model is calibrated to observed water level marks and hydrographs. Observed
        marks are usually at the flood peak and often spread throughout the model domain.
        Calibrating to these marks shows that the model is capable of reproducing the peak water
        level distribution. However, especially if the model only covers a small extent of the
        overall river/creek system, this does not necessarily mean that the model is well
        calibrated. </para>
      <para>Also, fundamental to a good calibration is the demonstration that the model reproduces
        the timing of flood events. This may be achieved through calibrating to recorded water level
        hydrographs (if available), and to observations by locals (eg. “the flood peaked around
        midday”). Water level hydrographs give the added benefit of showing whether a model is
        reproducing the shape (rise and fall) of the flood. </para>
      <para>Calibrating to information on the timing of the flood shows that the flood dynamics are
        being reproduced, and this only occurs if the model’s input data and schematisation are
        satisfactory, parameter values are within typical ranges, the software is suited to the
        application, and most importantly, the hydrologic method is also reproducing the correct
        timing. The latter is particularly important when it comes to calibrating a hydraulic model.
        If the hydrologic method is inaccurate with respect to timing and/or magnitude, satisfactory
        calibration of the hydraulic model will be difficult, if not impossible. For this reason,
        jointly calibrating the hydrologic and hydraulic modelling is always recommended.</para>
      <para>If parameters such as hydraulic roughness are outside standard values, the calibration
        may be “acceptable” for that particular event, but will very likely be compensating for
        inaccuracies in the hydrologic modelling, input data and model schematisation. In this case,
        the “calibrated” model is not suited to representing floods of smaller or larger size than
        the calibration event, and will be of limited use.</para>
      <para>It is important to note that should flow/discharge hydrographs exist for a study area,
        the flows are not “recorded” but “derived”. A rating curve is used to convert the water
        levels recorded by the stream gauge into flows. Details on this process and its limitations
        are provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>. However, it is worth reiterating that the
        reliability of discharge data is limited by the number and quality of manual gaugings
        undertaken at the site, the extent of extrapolation beyond the highest gauging of the rating
        curve and the means by which the rating curve is developed by the hydrographer. In
        undertaking a calibration using flow discharge hydrographs, it is essential to consider the
        quality and reliability of the rating curve used to derive the flows. Inaccurate rating
        curves produce inaccurate flows that will potentially mislead the practitioner into using
        inappropriate parameter values.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Ungauged Catchments</title>
    <para>The model calibration processes discussed in this chapter apply when there is data (of
      varying levels of completeness and accuracy) to assist in the calibration. However in many
      cases, if not most, calibration data is either totally lacking or limited to sparse anecdotal
      information on flooding. The term ‘ungauged catchment’ here is meant to include also flooding
      areas with no or only very limited flood level observations. In these situations, the model
      parameters must be estimated to the best degree possible using what information is available.
      In these cases, while a complete calibration procedure is not possible, the model parameters
      can be estimated to some extent by other means, though there will obviously be additional
      uncertainty compared to the situation when there is adequate calibration data.</para>
    <para>While many applications are required on totally ungauged catchments, it is common to have
      at least some minimal records of flooding available. The minimal descriptive data availability
      is discussed further in <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>, but where there is some anecdotal data, the
      parameter determination process must use this data to at least ensure that the model
      performance is consistent with this minimal data even if the data is insufficient to provide a
      calibration.</para>
    <para>An important issue with the estimation of parameters for ungauged catchments is that the
      methods rely on transfer of parameter values from neighbouring catchments. The methods
      therefore rely on the assumption that the catchments used to estimate parameters are
      sufficiently similar to the catchment being analysed. It is important to carry out as many
      checks as possible to confirm that this is the case, but there will always be some
      uncertainty.</para>
    <para>There are several different methods of estimating model parameters for ungauged
      catchments.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">General Guidance</emphasis>
         - Published documentation, including user guides for particular modelling platforms
          as well as textbooks and research publications, provide guidance for estimating parameters
          for ungauged catchments. These include advice on Manning’s n values for example which is
          widely available in textbooks and manuals. However many modelling platforms provide
          general guidance and in some cases, user forums can be of assistance.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Regional Relationships</emphasis>
         - These are developed for particular model parameters and for particular regions. For
          example, there are published relationships for runoff-routing parameters which are related
          to catchment area, for several regions of Australia. In some cases, specific regional
          relationships are developed for particular project areas from limited data and then
          adopted for the whole project area.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">Transfer from Neighbouring Catchments</emphasis>
         - This is a special case of the regional relationship type approach. If the catchment
          being analysed is not gauged but there is a neighbouring gauged catchment that has similar
          characteristics, it is possible to calibrate a model on the neighbouring catchment and
          then transfer the parameters across perhaps with adjustments for the known differences,
          such as catchment area. There is a risk in this case that the neighbouring catchment may
          appear superficially similar, but may have a quite different catchment response.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The principal issue with parameter estimation for ungauged catchments is to use whatever
      data may be available, no matter how poor quality this may be, understand the physical
      processes represented by the models to ensure that the parameters are realistic, and to use
      regional relationships and information from neighbouring catchments to the maximum extent
      possible. The uncertainty in the resulting model operation must be considered in any model
      application for ungauged catchments, since this will be greater than would be the case for a
      well gauged catchment.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Adopted Parameter Set</title>
    <para>The ultimate requirement for model parameter determination is to apply the calibrated
      model to certain design situations, as discussed further in <xref linkend="book8"/> of this
      book. However some comments are provided here to give advice on the final step of the
      calibration process where the parameters resulting from the calibration process and from other
      sources of parameter estimates are accepted and reviewed further in a validation process
        (<xref linkend="b7_ch7"/> of this book) and then applied to design.</para>
    <para>Often the calibration process will result in different parameter sets applying for
      different calibration events.</para>
    <para>In general, this is not allowable, since a single parameter set will be required for
      application so after completing calibration on a number of different flood events, the
      calibration process must continue to calculate a single parameter set to best fit all of the
      available data. Therefore a procedure is needed to select a representative parameter set for
      application to the design situation.</para>
    <para>The simplest approach would be to “average” the parameters, which will result in
      parameters that are representative, but may not result in a model that “averages” performance.
      An alternative approach to simple averaging would be to average them with a weighting towards
      the rarer floods. It is also possible to adopt the parameter set that has been estimated from
      the historic flood that is most similar to the design flood requirements, which may be the
      largest flood event.</para>
    <para>Whichever technique is adopted to interpret the calibration results and adopt parameters
      for a design application, these adopted parameters should then be used with the model on all
      of the design flood events to confirm the performance for all the data. The results from this
      should show at least a reasonable performance for all of the calibration flood events and no
      bias in the results, that is the calibration on all historic floods should not be all under-
      or over-estimations.</para>
    <para>It is desirable to compare the adopted parameter set from the calibration events with
      parameter estimates from catchments and flooding areas with similar characteristics and with
      parameter values obtained from regional parameter estimation procedures. If there are any
      significant discrepancies between the parameter estimates from different sources, the possible
      reasons should be investigated and the final parameter selection decision made in the light of
      the findings from these considerations.</para>
    <para> Once the calibration has been accepted, the model should then be transferred to the
      validation phase, where the parameters are confirmed and determined to be available for
      application.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
