<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter>
<chapter xml:id="b5_ch4" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    status ="Draft for Review">
    <info> <title>Baseflow Models</title>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/hill_peter.xml" />
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/brown_rachel.xml" /></info>

    <section>
        <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
        
        <para>Streamflow is made up of two main conceptual components which are
            categorised using the catchment response following a rainfall event. Water
            that enters a stream rapidly is termed “quickflow” or “direct runoff” and
            is sourced from short-term storages within the catchment; these short-term
            storages form the catchment storage through which the runoff flows while
            travelling to the catchment outlet. Water that takes longer to reach a
            river is termed “baseflow” and is sourced primarily from depletion of
            long-term storages within the catchment; typically, water in these
            long-term storages is held as soil moisture or as groundwater. At any
            instance in time, different locations will have varying magnitudes of
            baseflow contribution to the streamflow due to differing regional
            hydrogeological conditions and antecedent conditions.</para>
        
        <para>A baseflow hydrograph as described by Nathan and McMahon (1990) and
            Brodie and Hostetler (2005) is considered to have the following
            features:</para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The flow before the start of a flood event generally is assumed
                    to consist entirely of baseflow. In other words, during the initial
                    periods of a runoff event, the flow is considered to consist entirely
                    of baseflow.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>The rapid rise of the streamflow during a rainfall event
                    increases the volume of water held as bank storage. This water returns
                    to the main streamflow after a delay and creates a baseflow peak after
                    the main flood peak.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>The recession of the baseflow peak continues after the recession
                    of the streamflow peak.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>The baseflow recession generally follows an exponential decay
                    function.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>The baseflow hydrograph re-joins the total hydrograph as the
                    direct runoff ceases.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>As discussed earlier in Book 1 of Australian Rainfall and Runoff and
            by Ball <emphasis>et al.</emphasis> (2011), a common approach to
            generation of the data necessary for prediction of design flood
            characteristics is the use of catchment modelling systems. These catchment
            modelling systems focus on the simulation of those processes influencing
            “<emphasis>direct runoff</emphasis>” and the baseflow component of
            streamflow either is ignored or is incorporated after the direct runoff
            has been estimated. It is the later approach that is the focus herein,
            namely the estimation of the baseflow hydrograph for addition to the
            direct runoff hydrograph after the direct runoff hydrograph has been
            predicted.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>BASEFLOW CHARACTERISTICS</title>
        
        <para>For design flood estimation in Australia, baseflow has typically
            been considered to be a relatively minor contributor, but can potentially
            be significant in more frequent events. This is particularly the case
            where the catchment geology consists of high yielding aquifers with high
            levels of baseflow.</para>
        
        <para>In the context of design flood estimation, a surface runoff
            hydrograph will typically be generated that excludes baseflow. It is
            necessary to estimate the baseflow contribution in order to completely
            represent the total event peak and volume, and to generate a total
            streamflow hydrograph. This concept is represented in Figure 1. This
            document provides a technique for quantifying baseflow contribution to
            design flood estimates.</para>
        
        <para>To support this, it is relevant to identify a number of features of
            an event hydrograph, shown in Figure 1:</para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Surface runoff peak: the maximum flow associated with the
                    surface runoff event.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>Time to the surface runoff peak: measured from the start of the
                    event to the surface runoff peak.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>Volume of surface runoff for the event: event volume,
                    represented by the area under the hydrograph.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>Information on the surface runoff characteristics will generally be
            available directly from the surface runoff hydrograph generated by
            practitioners for the design flood event.</para>
        
        <para>Key baseflow features are also presented for the same event in
            Figure 1:</para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Baseflow peak: maximum baseflow associated with the
                    event.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>Time to the baseflow peak: measured from the start of the event
                    to the baseflow peak.</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>Baseflow under the surface runoff peak: baseflow that occurs at
                    the time of the surface runoff peak.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>The total streamflow hydrograph can be estimated by combining the
            surface runoff and baseflow components. This concept is also depicted in
            Figure 1.</para>
        
        <figure>
            <title>Key characteristics for calculation in a flood hydrograph</title>
            
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_1.JPG"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
        <para/>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>SELECTION OF APPROACH</title>
        
        <para>The approach to quantifying baseflow is dependent upon the catchment
            characteristics, data availability and baseflow characteristics of the
            catchment. Figure 2 provides a decision pathway to determine the most
            suitable approach to estimate baseflow contribution to design flood
            events, based on site specific criteria. Further details of the decision
            pathway and most appropriate approach are outlined below.</para>
        
        <figure>
            <title>Decision tree for method to estimate baseflow contribution to
                design flood</title>
            
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_2.JPG"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
        <section>
            <title>Preliminary assessment of baseflow</title>
            
            <para>A preliminary assessment should be undertaken to consider whether
                baseflow is likely to be a significant component of the design flood
                hydrograph. A detailed analysis task is not suggested at this point.
                Instead, this assessment is intended to be a coarse screening test to
                help determine the most appropriate approach to estimate baseflow for
                the catchment of interest based on local baseflow characteristics. A
                number of tools are available to support this assessment:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Figure 3 is provided to readily identify the relative
                        magnitude of baseflow compared to surface runoff for catchments
                        across Australia. Practitioners can identify their catchment of
                        interest within this data set and note the value of the Baseflow
                        Peak Factor. This map shows catchments to match with the screening
                        criteria identified below, while Figure 5 and Figure 6 (and
                        associated spatial data) provide a more detailed estimate of
                        baseflow.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>If available, streamflow data for the catchment should be
                        reviewed. The magnitude of low flows relative to peaks can be used
                        to determine whether baseflow is likely to be an important component
                        of the flood hydrograph.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>Where baseflow is a small component compared to the surface
                runoff, the design flood peak can simply be adjusted by up to 5% to make
                an allowance for baseflow. This approach is considered relevant for
                catchments where baseflow is estimated to represent less than
                approximately 5% of the surface runoff for a flood event. Catchments
                with a Baseflow Peak Factor less than 0.05 are considered suitable for
                this approach. This reflects approximately 30% of the catchments mapped
                in Figure 3.</para>
            
            <para>It is suggested that catchments that have a baseflow contribution
                greater than approximately 5% of the surface runoff should explicitly
                incorporate the baseflow component into the design flood using a more
                rigorous approach.</para>
            
            <para>Where baseflow is a very large component of the event (a
                contribution of more than 30% is suggested, reflected by a Baseflow Peak
                Factor greater than 0.3), it is considered important that baseflow is
                considered based on site-specific analyses using techniques that are
                suited to the nature and availability of local data (e.g. see Brodie and
                Hostetler, 2005; Chapman and Maxwell, 1996; Nathan and McMahon, 1990).
                Catchments located in tropical north Australia, south-west Western
                Australia and the south east coastline of South Australia may fall into
                this category.</para>
            
            <para>Where baseflow is between approximately 5% and 30% of the surface
                runoff (Baseflow Peak Factor between 0.05 and 0.3), the approach
                outlined below is recommended. This relates to approximately 75% of the
                catchments mapped in Figure 3.</para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Suitability of stream flow data</title>
            
            <para>Where possible, recorded streamflow data should be used directly
                to quantify baseflow. However, ideally more than 10 years of continuous
                streamflow data would be required to undertake detailed site-specific
                analyses. Appropriate data quality checks should be undertaken prior to
                ascertaining the period of record available for analysis. Preferably,
                the streamflow data should extend over a period of record that enables
                the identification of an event of similar magnitude to the design flood
                of interest.</para>
            
            <para>In addition, there are various activities that can affect
                streamflows and interfere with the flow characteristics usually
                associated with baseflow. These activities include:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Flow regulation from upstream reservoirs – reservoirs that
                        release outflows that are different to inflows will produce a low
                        flow response that can be misinterpreted as baseflow at downstream
                        flow gauges.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Catchment farm dams: high concentrations of catchment farm
                        dams could also influence baseflow but only where the dams are
                        located on-stream or where they interact with groundwater.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Major diversions – diversions for consumptive use such as
                        irrigation channels, urban diversions, etc. These diversions can
                        decrease low flows and hence appear to reduce estimates of baseflow.
                        Allowances can be made for those diversions where they are
                        metered.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Urbanisation – In urban areas, activities such as excess
                        garden or sports field watering can increase low flows during summer
                        that appear similar to baseflow in streamflow data.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Return flows – Water can be returned to rivers from sewage
                        treatment plants or from industry. This will increase low flows and
                        appear similar to baseflow.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>Where present, these activities will influence the observed flow
                characteristics making it difficult to identify and quantify baseflow.
                While it is possible to estimate baseflow in these locations using the
                regional approach, the baseflow estimate will reflect the unregulated
                baseflow conditions.</para>
            
            <figure><?landscapeFigure?>
                <title>Preliminary Assessment of Baseflow Peak Factor for ARI of 10
                    years</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure_3.JPG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>QUANTIFYING BASEFLOW CONTRIBUTION TO DESIGN FLOOD ESTIMATES</title>
        
        <section>
            <title>Estimating baseflow using streamflow data</title>
            
            <para>As outlined in Section 3.2, available streamflow criteria should
                meet a number of conditions to be considered suitable for application to
                assess baseflow. If streamflow data does not meet these criteria, this
                approach is not relevant and practitioners are directed to the regional
                approach outlined in Section 4.2.</para>
            
            <para>To estimate baseflow directly from available streamflow data, the
                following steps should be followed:</para>
            
            <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Review data quality</emphasis></para>
                    
                    <para>Review the streamflow data and eliminate any poor quality data
                        as determined using the quality codes for each time step.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Check record length</emphasis></para>
                    
                    <para>Determine the resulting period of record available for
                        analysis. If less than 10 years of data is available, the regional
                        approach in Section 4.2 is more appropriate for application. If more
                        than 10 years of data is available, the following steps can be
                        applied.</para>
                    
                    <para>Ideally, in order to identify flood events of similar
                        magnitude to the design flood of interest, the period of available
                        streamflow data should be greater than the Average Recurrence
                        Interval ARI<superscript>1</superscript><footnote>
                            <para><superscript>1</superscript>Note that the exceedance
                                probability has been expressed as an average recurrence interval
                                as the approach caters down to 2-per-year. For ARI &gt;1 the
                                values should be interpreted as annual exceedance probabilities
                                rather than periods between exceedances.</para>
                        </footnote> of interest.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Flood frequency
                        analysis</emphasis></para>
                    
                    <para>Undertake an analysis of the available streamflow data to
                        identify flood events in the data record. It is recommended that as
                        a minimum, the 10 year ARI event should be identified. If the
                        streamflow data record is suitable, identify events of similar
                        magnitude to the design flood of interest.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Estimate baseflow from recorded
                        floods</emphasis></para>
                    
                    <para>Estimate the baseflow for the flood events identified in the
                        step above. Literature such as Nathan and McMahon (1990), Chapman
                        &amp; Maxwell, 1996 and Brodie and Hostetler (2005) provide guidance
                        on key features of the baseflow hydrograph. Again, the 10 year event
                        should be estimated as a minimum. If the streamflow data is
                        suitable, the baseflow should be estimated for events of similar
                        magnitude to the design flood of interest. Baseflow should be
                        estimated graphically from the streamflow hydrograph.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Adjust for different
                        ARIs</emphasis></para>
                    
                    <para>If the above step has been applied to events of similar
                        magnitude to the design flood of interest, the estimated baseflow
                        magnitude and volume can be used directly with the design flood
                        surface runoff hydrograph to generate the total streamflow estimate.
                        Refer to Section 4.3 for a description of how to generate the total
                        streamflow hydrograph. In this case, the key baseflow features,
                        including the time series of the baseflow, should be taken from the
                        baseflow estimated in the above step.</para>
                    
                    <para>If the above step has been applied only to the 10 year event,
                        it is necessary to scale the baseflow to reflect the ARI of
                        interest. The method outlined in Section 4.2 should be applied, with
                        the key baseflow characteristics calculated based on the outcomes
                        from the step above rather than sourced from the national catchment
                        maps.</para>
                    
                    <para>The remaining steps in Section 4.3 should be implemented based
                        on the baseflow characteristics identified in the streamflow data
                        for the 10 year ARI event.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Estimating baseflow in the absence of streamflow data</title>
            
            <para>A regional method to estimate baseflow contribution to design
                flood events has been developed that is applicable for unregulated
                catchments across Australia. This method was developed using catchments
                across Australia with catchment areas between 7 and 7800
                km<superscript>2</superscript>, and as such the approach is considered
                most suitable for application for catchments within this range.
                Practitioners should be mindful of these constraints when applying and
                interpreting the outcomes from this method.</para>
            
            <para>Three concepts have been established to estimate baseflow from
                surface runoff characteristics:</para>
            
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Peak Factor.</emphasis> This
                        factor is applied to the estimated surface runoff peak flow to give
                        the value of peak baseflow for an ARI of 10 years.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Volume Factor.</emphasis> This
                        factor is applied to the estimated surface runoff volume to give the
                        volume of the baseflow for an ARI of 10 years.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Under Peak Factor.</emphasis>
                        This factor is applied to the estimated surface runoff peak flow to
                        give the baseflow at the time of the peak surface runoff. This
                        factor can be determined from the Baseflow Peak Factor, such that
                        the Baseflow Under Peak Factor = 0.7 x Baseflow Peak Factor.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
            <para>The Baseflow Peak Factor and Baseflow Volume Factor are presented
                in Figure 5 and Figure 6, which cover the whole of Australia. It should
                be noted that the maps represent the values for the total area upstream
                of the main stem of the river rather than any smaller
                sub-catchments.</para>
            
            <para>ARR Project 7 developed a series of regression relationships to
                estimate the Baseflow Peak Factor and Baseflow Peak Volume based on
                catchment characteristics (SKM 2010). These are presented in Figure 5
                and Figure 6 (and supporting spatial data for use with ArcGIS), and can
                be used to determine the Baseflow Peak Factor and the Baseflow Volume
                Factor for the 10 year ARI event for the catchment of interest.</para>
            
            <para>These factors provide information on the baseflow contribution to
                design flood events for 10 year ARI event magnitudes. Table 1 shows the
                ARI scaling factors that should be applied to the 10 year ARI Baseflow
                Peak Factor and Baseflow Volume Factor to scale the relevant factor to
                reflect events of other ARIs.</para>
            
            <table>
                <title>ARI Scaling Factors, FARI, to be applied to the 10 year
                    Baseflow Peak Factor and the Baseflow Volume Factor to determine the
                    Baseflow Peak Factor for events of various ARIs</title>
                
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>ARI (years)</entry>
                            
                            <entry>ARI Factor for Baseflow Peak</entry>
                            
                            <entry>ARI Factor for Baseflow Volume</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>0.5</entry>
                            
                            <entry>3.0</entry>
                            
                            <entry>2.6</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>1</entry>
                            
                            <entry>2.2</entry>
                            
                            <entry>2.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>2</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.7</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.6</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>5</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.2</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.2</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>10</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>20</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0.8</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0.8</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>50</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0.7</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0.7</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>100</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0.6</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0.6</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            
            <para>For events of ARIs not shown in Table 1, Figure 4 can be used to
                determine an appropriate ARI factor. This is to be multiplied by the 10
                year ARI Baseflow Peak Factor or the Baseflow Volume Factor as relevant
                to determine the factor for other event magnitudes.</para>
            
            <para>This information is then applied to the design flood event using
                the procedure outlined in the relationships below which relate to the
                typical flood hydrograph in Figure 1.</para>
            
            <figure>
                <title>ARI Factors, FARI, to be applied to the 10 year Baseflow Volume
                    Factor to determined the Baseflow Volume Factor for events of various
                    ARIs</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_4.JPG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            
            <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the peak baseflow (point C in
                Figure 1):</emphasis></para>
            
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Determine the Baseflow Peak Factor for a 10 year ARI (RBPF,
                        10yrARI) from Figure 5.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Determine the ARI factor corresponding to the event ARI using
                        Table 1 or Figure 4. Scale the 10 year Baseflow Peak Factor
                        appropriately to determine the Baseflow Peak Factor for the event
                        magnitude of interest.]</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Apply the Baseflow Peak Factor to the calculated peak surface
                        runoff as in Equation 1.</para>
                    
                    <equation>
                        <m:math display="block">
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>Q</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>Peak baseflow</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                                
                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>BPF</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:msub>
                                            <m:mi>Q</m:mi>
                                            
                                            <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                                        </m:msub>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:math>
                    </equation>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Calculate the timing of the baseflow peak (in hours from the
                        start of the event) using Equation 2. This step is further described
                        in Appendix A. The time to the peak surface runoff should be applied
                        in units of hours from the start of the event.</para>
                    
                    <equation>
                        <m:math display="block">
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>Peak baseflow</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                                
                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:msub>
                                            <m:mi>0.92 T</m:mi>
                                            
                                            <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                                        </m:msub>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>+ 33.4</m:mi>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:math>
                    </equation>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
            <figure><?landscapeFigure?>
                <title>Map of Baseflow Peak Factor for ARI of 10 years</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_5.JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            
            <figure><?landscapeFigure?>
                <title>Map of Baseflow Volume Factor for ARI of 10 years</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_6.JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            
            <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the baseflow under the peak
                streamflow (point B in Figure 1):</emphasis></para>
            
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The Baseflow Peak Factor (R<subscript>BPF</subscript>)
                        calculated for the appropriate event ARI as above should be used in
                        Equation 3 to calculate the Baseflow Under Peak Factor
                        (R<subscript>BUPF</subscript>).</para>
                    
                    <equation>
                        <m:math display="block">
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>BUPF</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                                
                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:msub>
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mi>0.7</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mo>×</m:mo>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>BPF</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:math>
                    </equation>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>R<subscript>BUPF</subscript> should be used as in Equation 4
                        to calculate the baseflow under the peak streamflow.</para>
                    
                    <equation>
                        <m:math display="block">
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>Q</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>Baseflow under peak streamflow</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                                
                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>BUPF</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                    
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>Q</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:math>
                    </equation>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">To calculate the total streamflow peak (point
                    A in Figure 1):</emphasis>
            </para>
            
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Calculate the baseflow under the streamflow peak for the
                        appropriate ARI as above</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Add the baseflow under the streamflow peak calculated using
                        Equation 4 to the calculated peak surface runoff as in Equation
                        5.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
            <equation>
                <m:math display="block">
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>Q</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mi>Peak streamflow</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        
                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>
                                
                                <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>
                            
                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                            
                            <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>
                                
                                <m:mi>Baseflow under peak streamflow</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the total baseflow volume for
                an event:</emphasis></para>
            
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Determine the Baseflow Volume Factor for a 10 year ARI
                        (R<subscript>BVF,10yrARI</subscript>) from Figure 6</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Determine the ARI factor corresponding to the event ARI using
                        Table 1 or Figure 4. Scale the 10 year Baseflow Volume Factor
                        appropriately to determine the Baseflow Volume Factor
                        (R<subscript>BVF</subscript>) for the event.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>Apply the Baseflow Volume Factor to the calculated surface
                        runoff volume as in Equation 6.</para>
                    
                    <equation>
                        <m:math display="block">
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>V</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>Baseflow</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                                
                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>BVF</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                    
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>V</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>Surface Runoff</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:math>
                    </equation>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
            <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the total streamflow volume for
                an event:</emphasis></para>
            
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Calculate the baseflow volume for the event using the
                        appropriate ARI factors.</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>The baseflow volume calculated using Equation 6 should be
                        added to the calculated surface runoff as in Equation 7.</para>
                    
                    <equation>
                        <m:math display="block">
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>V</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>Total streamflow</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                                
                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>V</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>Surface runoff</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                    
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>+ V</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>Baseflow</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:math>
                    </equation>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
            <para>This approach can be directly applied to estimate the baseflow
                contribution to any event size between 0.5 year ARI and 100 year ARI.
                This approach is consistent with the logic that baseflow is only a small
                proportion of the total surface runoff for rare and extreme
                events.</para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Generating the total streamflow hydrograph</title>
            
            <para>The characteristics of the surface runoff, baseflow and total
                streamflow can be used to estimate the hydrograph for the event. For
                simplicity, a linear approach can typically be used to estimate the
                baseflow at each time step, by fitting between the data values estimated
                through the process described above and matching the baseflow volume.
                This time series can be manually added to the surface runoff time series
                data to generate a time series for the total streamflow. The time series
                generated through this process should be reviewed, and may require
                smoothing to produce a more realistic temporal distribution of baseflow.
                This process is presented in Figure 7.</para>
            
            <figure>
                <title>Total streamflow hydrograph generation approach, where (a) the
                    data values calculated through the baseflow estimation process are
                    plotted; (b) linear interpolation between the baseflow data points and
                    matching the area under the curve to the baseflow event volume is used
                    to estimate the baseflow time series, which is plotted on the
                    hydrograph in green; and (c) the total streamflow time series is
                    generated by summing the surface runoff and baseflow time series
                    values, with the streamflow hydrograph plotted in red.</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_7.jpg"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>CASE STUDY APPLICATIONS</title>
        
        <para>The process described in Section 3 is worked through in a number of
            different case study examples.</para>
        
        <section>
            <title>North Maroochy River at Eumundi, Queensland</title>
            
            <para>Streamflow gauge 141009 is located on the North Maroochy River at
                Eumundi. Hourly flow data has been collected at this location since
                1982, providing approximately 30 years of data. Very little data is
                missing or poor quality during this period. The catchment area is 40
                km<superscript>2</superscript>.</para>
            
            <para>The 10 year ARI event is of interest for this case study. The
                reviewed flow data was used to identify flood peaks, in particular the
                10 year event. A comparable event was identified in the record in
                February 1999. The event hydrograph was plotted and key characteristics
                of the baseflow were identified manually (Figure 8; manually identified
                basaeflow features shown by black points). Straight lines were used to
                join the key baseflow features, to estimate the baseflow time series. In
                this instance, the baseflow peak occurs 18 hours after the peak of the
                streamflow</para>
            
            <figure>
                <title>Streamflow hydrograph approximating the 10 year event for the
                    North Maroochy River at Eumundi</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_8.jpg"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            
            <para>The surface runoff hydrograph for the design flood event was
                generated using a flood event model with a critical duration of 18 hours
                (Figure 11, and details in Table 3).</para>
            
            <figure>
                <title>Surface runoff hydrograph for the 10 year ARI design flood
                    event at Eumundi</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_9.jpg"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            
            <table>
                <title>Key surface runoff characteristics for the 10 year ARI design
                    flood event at Eumundi</title>
                
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Characteristic</entry>
                            
                            <entry>Data from design flood</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Surface runoff peak flow
                                (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s)</entry>
                            
                            <entry>160.6</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Time to the surface runoff peak (hours, from the start of
                                the event)</entry>
                            
                            <entry>16</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Volume of surface runoff for the event
                                (m<superscript>3</superscript>)s</entry>
                            
                            <entry>9.9 x 10<superscript>6</superscript></entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            
            <para>The baseflow series estimated above was used directly to
                approximate the baseflow for the 10 year ARI design flood event. The
                baseflow at the time of the streamflow peak (from Figure 8) was aligned
                with the surface runoff peak in the design hydrograph (Figure 11), with
                the rest of the baseflow time series used to guide the behaviour through
                the duration of the design event.</para>
            
            <figure>
                <title>Surface runoff, baseflow and total streamflow hydrographs for
                    the 10 year ARI event at Eumundi</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_10.jpg"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Dirk Brook, Western Australia</title>
            
            <para>The Dirk Brook catchment is located in Western Australia. The 100
                year ARI event is of interest. The surface runoff hydrograph for this
                event was generated using a flood event model with a critical duration
                of 18 hours (Figure 11, and details in Table 3). This case study assumes
                that no streamflow data is available for use. The process described in
                Section 4.2 has been used to estimate baseflow.</para>
            
            <figure>
                <title>Surface runoff hydrograph for the 100 year ARI design flood
                    event at Dirk Brook</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_11.jpg"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            
            <table>
                <title>Key surface runoff characteristics for the 100 year ARI design
                    flood event at Dirk Brook</title>
                
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Characteristic</entry>
                            
                            <entry>Data from design flood event</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Surface runoff peak flow
                                (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s)</entry>
                            
                            <entry>23.91</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Time to the surface runoff peak (hours, from the start of
                                the event)</entry>
                            
                            <entry>8</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Volume of surface runoff for the event
                                (m<superscript>3</superscript>)</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.25 x 10<superscript>6</superscript></entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            
            <para>Aligning the catchment boundary shapefile with the spatial data
                from Figure 5 and Figure 6 allows the Baseflow Peak Factor and Baseflow
                Volume Factor for the 10 year event to be extracted for the catchment
                area directly:</para>
            
            <para>R<subscript>BPF 10 yr ARI</subscript> = 0.186</para>
            
            <para>R<subscript>BVF 10 yr ARI</subscript> =1.099</para>
            
            <para>The scaling factor for the 100 year ARI event is sourced from
                Table 1, with a value of 0.6 for both the peak and volume calculations.
                Using the relationships described earlier, the final Baseflow Peak
                Factor, Baseflow Volume Factor and Baseflow Under Peak Factor for
                application are outlined in Table 4. These values are applied to
                calculate the baseflow and total streamflow characteristics in Table 5,
                and plotted in Figure 12.</para>
            
            <table>
                <title>Calculation of Baseflow Factors for the 100 year ARI event for
                    the Dirk Brook</title>
                
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Factors for application</entry>
                            
                            <entry>Factor values for 100 year ARI</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Final Baseflow Peak Factor R<subscript>BPF</subscript> =
                                F<subscript>ARI</subscript>R<subscript>BPF, 10 yr
                                    ARI</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 0.6 x 0.186 = 0.11</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Final Baseflow Volume Factor R<subscript>BVF</subscript>
                                = F<subscript>ARI</subscript>R<subscript>BVF, 10 yr
                                    ARI</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 0.6 x 1.099 = 0.66</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Final Baseflow Under Peak Factor
                                R<subscript>BUBF</subscript> = 0.7 ×
                                R<subscript>BPF</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 0.7 x 0.112 = 0.08</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            
            <table>
                <title>Calculation of baseflow and total streamflow characteristics
                    for the 100 year ARI event for the Dirk Brook catchment</title>
                
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Baseflow and total streamflow characteristics</entry>
                            
                            <entry>Factor values for 100 year ARI</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry><emphasis role="bold">Peak Baseflow</emphasis></entry>
                            
                            <entry/>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Peak baseflow (refer to Equation 1) Q<subscript>Peak
                                baseflow</subscript>= R<subscript>BPF</subscript>
                                Q<subscript>Peak surface runoff</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 0.11 x 23.9 = 2.6
                                m<superscript>3</superscript>/s</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Time to peak baseflow (Equation 2) T<subscript>Peak
                                baseflow</subscript> = 0.92T<subscript>Peak surface
                                    runoff</subscript> + 33.4</entry>
                            
                            <entry>= (0.92 x 8) +33.4 = 41 hours</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Under the
                                Peak</emphasis></entry>
                            
                            <entry/>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Baseflow under the streamflow peak (Equation 4)
                                Q<subscript>Baseflow under peak streamflow</subscript> =
                                R<subscript>BUPF</subscript> Q<subscript>Peak surface
                                    runoff</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 0.08 x 23.9 = 1.9
                                m<superscript>3</superscript>/s</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry><emphasis role="bold">Total Streamflow Peak
                            </emphasis></entry>
                            
                            <entry/>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Total streamflow peak flow (Equation 5) Q<subscript>Peak
                                streamflow</subscript> = Q<subscript>Peak surface
                                    runoff</subscript> + Q<subscript>Baseflow under peak
                                        streamflow</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 23.9 + 1.9 = 25.8
                                m<superscript>3</superscript>/s</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Volume </emphasis></entry>
                            
                            <entry/>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Baseflow volume (Equation 6) V<subscript>Baseflow
                            </subscript> = R<subscript>BVF</subscript> V<subscript>Surface
                                runoff</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 0.66 x 1.25 x 10<superscript>6</superscript> = 0.83 x
                                10<superscript>6</superscript></entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry><emphasis role="bold">Total Streamflow Volume
                            </emphasis></entry>
                            
                            <entry/>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>Total streamflow volume (Equation 7) V<subscript>Total
                                streamflow</subscript> = V<subscript>Surface runoff</subscript>
                                + V<subscript>Baseflow</subscript></entry>
                            
                            <entry>= 1.25 x 10<superscript>6</superscript> + 0.83 x
                                10<superscript>6</superscript> = 2.08 x
                                10<superscript>6</superscript></entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            
            <figure>
                <title>Surface runoff, baseflow and total streamflow hydrographs for
                    the 100 year ARI event at Dirk Brook</title>
                
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_12.jpg"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        
        <para>Brodie, R.S. and Hostetler, S. (2005) <emphasis>A review of
            techniques for analysing baseflow from stream hydrographs</emphasis> in
            <emphasis>Proceedings of the NZHS-IAH-NZSSS 2005 conference</emphasis>,
            Auckland, New Zealand, 28 November – 2 December, 2005.</para>
        
        <para>Chapman, T.G. and Maxwell, A.I. (1996) <emphasis>Baseflow separation
            – Comparison of numerical methods with tracer experiments,</emphasis>
            Proceedings of the 23rd Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Hobart
            Australia, 21-24 May 1996.</para>
        
        <para>Nathan, R.J, and McMahon, T.A. (1990) <emphasis>Evaluation of
            Automated Techniques for Base Flow and Recession Analyses,</emphasis>
            Water Resources Research, 26(7), 1465-1473.</para>
        
        <para>Sinclair Knight Merz (2009) <emphasis>Project 7: Baseflow for
            catchment simulation. Phase 1 – selection of baseflow separation
            approach,</emphasis> Report prepared for the Australian Rainfall and
            Runoff Technical Committee.</para>
        
        <para>Sinclair Knight Merz (2010) Project 7: <emphasis>Baseflow for
            catchment simulation. Phase 2 – development of baseflow estimation
            approach.</emphasis> Draft report prepared for the Australian Rainfall and
            Runoff Technical Committee.</para>
        
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Appendix A Calculation of the timing of the
            baseflow peak</emphasis></para>
        
        <para>Analyses undertaken to develop most of the method outlined in
            Section 4.2 is described in detail in separate technical documents,
            available online at the ARR update website (SKM, 2010, available online
            http://www.arr.org.au/p7.html). However, the background behind the
            calculation of the timing of the baseflow peak is not captured in those
            documents. A full description of the development of Equation 2 is provided
            below. The description below assumes that the reader has an understanding
            of the work presented in the separate technical documents, and a full
            background of the broader study concepts is not provided here.</para>
        
        <para>More than 230 suitable catchments across Australia were identified
            for analysis for ARR Update Project 7, and hourly streamflow data was
            collated for each of these locations. A baseflow time series was generated
            from each flow record using the Lyne and Hollick digital filter, modified
            to suit hourly streamflow data. The top 4N flood events were identified in
            the hourly time series data for each catchment, generating a data set of
            more than 30,000 flood events across the 236 catchments. For each of these
            events, the magnitude and timing of the total streamflow peak and baseflow
            peak were identified. The time to these peaks was calculated from the
            start of the event. At each location, the average time to the streamflow
            and baseflow peaks were then calculated based on the 4N events.</para>
        
        <para>For the purposes of this assessment, it was assumed that the total
            streamflow and surface runoff peaks would coincide. This is considered a
            reasonable assumption since surface runoff is generally the main component
            of the total streamflow hydrograph.</para>
        
        <para>Analysis of the average time to peak data identified a strong
            relationship between the time to the surface runoff (and streamflow) and
            baseflow peaks, as presented in Figure 13. This relationship provides a
            direct calculation from which to estimate the timing of the baseflow peak,
            based upon knowledge of the surface runoff event generated using a flood
            event model. That is, the time to the baseflow peak (in hours from the
            start of the event) can be calculated as:</para>
        
        <equation>
            <m:math display="block">
                <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                        
                        <m:mi>Peak baseflow</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                    
                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                    
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>0.92 T</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        
                        <m:mo>+ 33.4</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
        </equation>
        
        <figure>
            <title>Comparison of average time to surface runoff peak and time to
                baseflow peak, based on analysis of more than 30,000 flood events from
                catchments across Australia.</title>
            
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_13.jpg"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
        <para/>
    </section>
</chapter>
