<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter>
<chapter status="External Review" xml:id="b5_ch4"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Baseflow Models</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/hill_peter.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/brown_rachel.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/graszkiewicz_zuzanna.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section xml:id="section_71967788">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Streamflow is made up of two main components based on the timing of
    response following a rainfall event. The water that enters a stream
    rapidly is termed “quickflow” and is sourced from rainfall excess after
    loss has been satisfied (representing a range of processes such as
    interception, infiltration and depression storage). Water that takes
    longer to reach a river is termed “baseflow” and is sourced primarily from
    groundwater discharge into the river. Different locations have varying
    degrees of baseflow contribution to streamflow based on regional
    hydrogeological conditions.</para>

    <para>The baseflow hydrograph is considered to have features as described
    by Nathan and McMahon (1990) and Brodie and Hostetler (2005):</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The low flow before the start of a flood event is generally
        assumed to consist entirely of baseflow.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The rapid rise of the river during a rainfall event increases
        the volume of water held as bank storage. This water returns to the
        main streamflow after a delay and creates a baseflow peak after the
        main flood peak.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The recession of the baseflow peak continues after the recession
        of the streamflow peak.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The baseflow recession generally follows an exponential decay
        function.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The baseflow hydrograph re-joins the total hydrograph as the
        quickflow ceases.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The majority of design flood estimation in Australia utilises flood
    event models that focus on surface runoff processes and in such models the
    baseflow component is either ignored or incorporated after the surface
    runoff has been estimated. The conceptualisation of some continuous models
    or fully integrated surface water - groundwater models do explicitly
    incorporate the estimation of the baseflow component. However, given the
    prevalence of flood event models for design flood estimation, the
    following guidance concentrates on estimating a baseflow hydrographs to
    combine with an existing estimate of surface runoff.</para>

    <para>ARR Update Project 7 developed a method for calculating and
    incorporating the contribution from baseflow to design flood estimates.
    Phase 1 of the project (Murphy et al. 2009 and 2011, and Graszkiewicz et
    al. 2011) focussed on the physical processes of groundwater-surface water
    interaction and theoretical approaches to baseflow separation. The
    identified methods were applied to eight case study catchments across
    Australia in order to develop a suitable approach for more wide scale
    application. Phase 2 of Project 7 (Murphy et al. 2011) covered the
    analysis of 236 catchments across Australia, the development of prediction
    equations to estimate baseflow parameters and the development of a method
    for the application of these to design estimates for catchments across
    Australia.</para>

    <para>This document utilises the method developed in ARR Project 7 to
    provide guidance on how to estimate baseflow for design flood
    estimation.</para>

    <para>This remainder of this guide is structured as follows:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b5_ch4_s_4iwkw"/> describes those characteristics
        of the baseflow that need to be estimated</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="section_93981341"/>discusses considerations when
        selecting the approach to estimating baseflow</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="section_53207573"/> outlines the different
        approaches to estimating the baseflow contribution to design
        hydrographs</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="section_03656764"/> provides 2 worked
        examples</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch4_s_4iwkw">
    <title>Guiding Principles</title>

    <para>This guidance on baseflow draws upon a significant body of work
    undertaken through ARR Project 7, and provides advice on how to estimate
    baseflow for design flood estimation.</para>

    <para>Users should consider the characteristics of the particular
    catchment with respect to the underlying assumptions that form the basis
    of the method outlined in this chapter. The following approach is
    considered applicable across the vast majority of Australian catchments.
    However, users should draw upon their understanding of the particular
    catchment of interest to make an informed decision regarding the relevance
    of each step considering the following issues:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Snow melt, which is not considered in this approach.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Significant farm dam development or other flow regulation in the
        catchment, which can mask the contribution of baseflow.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Design flood estimation for Rare to Extreme events. The method
        outlined below is only relevant to events up to an AEP of
        approximately 1% and guidance for baseflow contribution to Rare and
        Extreme Events is provided in Book 8.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Seasonality of events, which is not explicitly considered in
        this approach. Region-specific analysis should be undertaken for those
        regions of Australia where seasonality of flood producing factors is
        important. Kinkela and Pearce (2014) outline such a study for the
        southwest of WA.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Urbanised catchments. The approach and catchments considered in
        developed of the method were selected to represent rural conditions
        and as such the approach is not applicable for urban catchments (flood
        estimation for urban catchments is covered in Book 9).</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Small catchments away from the main stem of the river network.
        The regional estimates relate to a location on the main stem of the
        river and reflect the characteristics of the entire contributing
        catchments. The baseflow characteristics of individual tributaries may
        be different from those in the larger contributing catchment.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Estimation of streamflow. The approach in this document has been
        developed for application in design flood estimation, not the
        estimation of the baseflow component of streamflow for individual
        historic events.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Estimation of baseflow for extended periods. This guidance is
        relevant for design events only. Users should refer to the technical
        documents supporting ARR Project 7 for more general information on
        baseflow estimation for longer sequences.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>If any of the above factors are deemed to be important for the
    catchment of interest, then it is recommended that the user consider the
    suitability of this approach to their catchment of interest. It is
    relevant to interpret the outcomes in light of the underlying assumptions,
    and to draw on local data to supplement the approach or to consider
    alternative methods where these assumptions are not fully met.</para>

    <para>Users are referred to the technical reports and analyses undertaken
    for ARR Project 7 (Murphy et al. 2009 and et al. 2011) for full details of
    the data analysis and assumptions that form the basis of the method
    outlined in this document. Users may also like to refer to these
    supporting documents and data to draw further local conclusions from the
    significant body of work undertaken through the study.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="section_93981341">
    <title>Baseflow Characteristics</title>

    <para>For design flood estimation in Australia, baseflow has traditionally
    been considered to be a relatively minor contributor to the flood
    hydrograph, but baseflow can potentially be significant in more frequent
    events. This is particularly the case where the catchment geology consists
    of high yielding aquifers.</para>

    <para>For instance, for a 10% AEP, about two-thirds of Australian
    unregulated rural catchments have baseflow contributions that are
    estimated to be between approximately 5 and 30% of the peak flow. There
    are only approximately 5% of catchments which have a higher proportion of
    baseflow and these tend to be located in south-west WA, southeast SA and
    some areas in the tropics. In just less than a third of unregulated rural
    catchments the baseflow is estimated to be less than 5% of the peak (for a
    10% AEP). Baseflow is typically insignificant in urban catchments due to
    the degree of channel modifications and extent of impervious areas.</para>

    <para>The variation of baseflow with exceedance probability is discussed
    in <xref linkend="b5_ch4_s_4iwkw"/>. For events more frequent than a 10%
    AEP, the baseflow can represent a significant proportion of the peak flow
    and particularly volume. For rarer events, baseflow makes up a smaller
    relative contribution to the surface runoff. For the majority of
    catchments, it is likely that the contribution of baseflow for Extreme
    events will be less important although for volume dependent systems, the
    baseflow volume may still be significant. Guidance for baseflow
    contribution to Rare and Extreme Events is provided in Book 8.</para>

    <para>This guidance concentrates on the estimation of baseflow
    contribution to be included with surface runoff estimated from a flood
    event model, rather than separating baseflow from recorded streamflow.
    Approaches for separating baseflow are described in the ARR Project 7
    Phase 1 report (Murphy, et al. 2009).</para>

    <para>In the context of design flood estimation, a surface runoff
    hydrograph will typically be generated using a flood event model that
    excludes baseflow. It is therefore necessary to estimate the baseflow
    contribution in order to completely represent the total event peak and
    volume, and to generate a total streamflow hydrograph. This concept is
    represented in <xref linkend="figure_28340800"/> which depicts the
    following features of an event hydrograph:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Surface runoff peak: the maximum flow associated with the
        surface runoff event.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Time to the surface runoff peak: measured from the start of the
        event to the surface runoff peak.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Volume of surface runoff for the event: event volume,
        represented by the area under the hydrograph.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Baseflow peak: maximum baseflow associated with the
        event.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Time to the baseflow peak: measured from the start of the event
        to the baseflow peak.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Baseflow under the surface runoff peak: baseflow that occurs at
        the time of the surface runoff peak.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <figure xml:id="figure_28340800">
      <title>Key characteristics for calculation in a flood hydrograph</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5001.JPG"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="section_53207573">
    <title>Selection of Approach</title>

    <para>The approach to quantifying baseflow is dependent upon the catchment
    characteristics, data availability and baseflow characteristics of the
    catchment. <xref linkend="figure_97744967"/> provides a decision pathway
    to determine the most suitable approach to estimate baseflow contribution
    to design flood events, based on site specific criteria.</para>

    <figure xml:id="figure_97744967">
      <title>Decision tree for method to estimate baseflow contribution to
      design flood</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5002.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <section xml:id="section_40603913">
      <title>Preliminary assessment of baseflow</title>

      <para>A preliminary assessment should be undertaken to consider whether
      baseflow is likely to be a significant component of the design flood
      hydrograph. A detailed analysis is not suggested at this point. Instead,
      this assessment is intended to be a coarse screening test to help
      determine the most appropriate approach to estimate baseflow for the
      catchment of interest based on the expected baseflow characteristics. A
      number of tools are available to support this assessment:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><xref linkend="figure_15142923"/> is provided to readily
          identify the relative magnitude of baseflow compared to surface
          runoff for catchments across Australia for a 10% AEP. Practitioners
          can identify their catchment of interest within this data set and
          note the value of the Baseflow Peak Factor. This map shows
          catchments to match with the screening criteria identified below,
          while <xref linkend="figure_85594555"/> and <xref
          linkend="figure_05634839"/> provide a more detailed estimate of
          baseflow. The data used to generate these figures are available in
          GIS format to assist locating catchments/points of interest.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>If available, streamflow data for the catchment should be
          reviewed. The magnitude of low flows relative to peaks can be used
          to determine whether baseflow is likely to be an important component
          of the design flood hydrograph.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Where baseflow is expected to be a small component compared to the
      surface runoff, the design flood peak can simply be adjusted by up to
      approximately 5% to make an allowance for baseflow. Catchments with a
      Baseflow Peak Factor less than 0.05 are considered suitable for this
      approach. This reflects approximately 30% of the catchments mapped in
      <xref linkend="figure_15142923"/>.</para>

      <para>It is suggested that catchments that have a baseflow contribution
      greater than approximately 5% of the surface runoff should explicitly
      incorporate the baseflow component into the design flood using a more
      rigorous approach.</para>

      <para>Where baseflow is a very large component of the event (a
      contribution of more than approximately 30% is suggested, reflected by a
      Baseflow Peak Factor greater than 0.3), the baseflow contributions
      should be estimated using techniques that are suited to the nature and
      availability of local data (e.g. see Brodie and Hostetler 2005; Chapman
      and Maxwell 1996; Nathan and McMahon 1990; Ladson et al. 2013).
      Approximately 5% of Australian catchments, generally located in tropical
      north Australia, south-west Western Australia and the south east
      coastline of South Australia, fall into this category. The specific
      approach of relevance will depend on local conditions, and the user is
      guided to the above references to determine the most appropriate
      baseflow estimation technique.</para>

      <para>Where baseflow is between approximately 5% and 30% of the surface
      runoff (Baseflow Peak Factor between 0.05 and 0.3), the approach
      outlined below is recommended. This relates to approximately 65% of the
      catchments mapped in <xref linkend="figure_15142923"/>.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="section_87631628">
      <title>Suitability of stream flow data</title>

      <para>Where possible, recorded streamflow data should be used directly
      to quantify baseflow. However, ideally more than 10 years of continuous
      streamflow data would be required to undertake detailed site-specific
      analyses. Appropriate data quality checks should be undertaken prior to
      ascertaining the period of record available for analysis. Preferably,
      the streamflow data should extend over a period of record that enables
      the identification of an event of similar magnitude to the design flood
      of interest. Some subjectivity may be required to determine the
      suitability of available streamflow for this approach, depending on the
      period of record and the events represented within this data, with
      reference to the event magnitude and duration of interest.</para>

      <para>In addition, there are various activities that can impact upon the
      flow characteristics usually associated with baseflow. These activities
      include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flow regulation from upstream reservoirs – reservoirs that
          release outflows that are different to inflows will produce a low
          flow response that can be misinterpreted as baseflow at downstream
          flow gauges.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Catchment farm dams – high concentrations of catchment farm
          dams could influence baseflow but only where the dams are located in
          a manner where they intercept and store flows arising from long-term
          depletion of catchment storage.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Major diversions – diversions for consumptive use such as
          irrigation channels, urban diversions, etc. These diversions can
          decrease low flows and hence appear to reduce estimates of baseflow.
          Allowances can be made for those diversions where they are
          metered.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Urbanisation – In urban areas, features such as excess garden
          or sports field watering can increase low flows during summer that
          appear similar to baseflow in streamflow data.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Return flows – Water can be returned to rivers from sewage
          treatment plants or from industry. This will increase low flows and
          appear similar to baseflow.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Where present, these activities will influence the observed flow
      characteristics making it difficult to identify and quantify baseflow.
      While it is possible to estimate baseflow in these locations using the
      regional approach, the baseflow estimate will reflect the unregulated
      baseflow conditions.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_15142923">
        <?landscapeFigure ?>

        <title>Preliminary Assessment of Baseflow Peak Factor for a 10%
        AEP</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure_3.JPG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="section_03656764">
    <title>Quantifying Baseflow Contribution to Design Flood Estimates</title>

    <section xml:id="section_53663056">
      <title>Estimating baseflow using streamflow data</title>

      <para>As outlined in <xref linkend="section_87631628"/>, available
      streamflow criteria should meet a number of conditions to be considered
      suitable for application to assess baseflow. If streamflow data does not
      meet these criteria, this approach is not relevant and practitioners are
      directed to the regional approach outlined in <xref
      linkend="section_75228116"/>.</para>

      <para>To estimate baseflow directly from available streamflow data, the
      following steps should be followed:</para>

      <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Review data quality</emphasis></para>

          <para>Review the streamflow data and eliminate any poor quality data
          as determined using the quality codes for each time step.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Check record length</emphasis></para>

          <para>Determine the resulting period of record available for
          analysis. If less than 10 years of data is available, the regional
          approach in <xref linkend="section_75228116"/> may be more
          appropriate for application. If more than approximately 10 years of
          data is available, the following steps can be applied.</para>

          <para>Ideally, in order to identify flood events of similar
          magnitude to the design flood of interest, the period of available
          streamflow data should be greater than the Annual Exceedance
          Probability (AEP)<superscript>1</superscript><footnote>
              <para><superscript>1</superscript>Note that the exceedance
              probability has been expressed as an average recurrence interval
              as the approach caters down to 2-per-year. For ARI &gt;1 the
              values should be interpreted as annual exceedance probabilities
              rather than periods between exceedances.<emphasis role="bold">
              THIS NEEDS TO BE CHECKED!!!! </emphasis></para>
            </footnote> of interest.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Flood frequency
          analysis</emphasis></para>

          <para>Extract a series of peak flows from the recorded streamflow
          data and undertake a flood frequency analysis as described in
          Chapter 2 of Book 3. It is recommended that as a minimum, the 10%
          AEP event should be identified. If the streamflow data record is
          suitable, identify events of similar magnitude to the design flood
          of interest.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Estimate baseflow from recorded
          floods</emphasis></para>

          <para>Estimate the baseflow for the flood events identified in the
          step above. Literature such as Nathan and McMahon (1990), Chapman
          &amp; Maxwell (1996) and Brodie and Hostetler (2005) provide
          guidance on key features of the baseflow hydrograph. If the
          streamflow data is suitable, the baseflow should be estimated for
          events of similar magnitude to the design flood of interest.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Adjust for different
          AEPs</emphasis></para>

          <para>If the above step has been applied to events of similar
          magnitude to the design flood of interest, the estimated baseflow
          magnitude and volume can be used directly with the design flood
          surface runoff hydrograph to generate the total streamflow estimate.
          Refer to <xref linkend="section_70922883"/> for a description of how
          to generate the total streamflow hydrograph. In this case, the key
          baseflow features, including the timing, should be taken from the
          baseflow estimated in the above step.</para>

          <para>If the design events are outside of the range of recorded
          events then it is necessary to scale the baseflow contribution to
          reflect the AEP of interest. The method outlined in <xref
          linkend="section_75228116"/> should be applied, with the key
          baseflow characteristics determined from the recorded streamflow
          rather than the regional approach as outlined in the following
          section.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="section_75228116">
      <title>Estimating baseflow in the absence of streamflow data</title>

      <para>A regional method to estimate baseflow contribution to design
      flood events has been developed that is applicable for unregulated
      catchments across Australia. This method was developed using catchments
      across Australia with catchment areas between 7 and 7800
      km<superscript>2</superscript>, and as such the approach is considered
      most suitable for application for catchments within this range.
      Practitioners should be mindful of these constraints when applying and
      interpreting the outcomes from this method.</para>

      <para>The following three parameters have been defined to characterise
      the contribution of baseflow to design flood hydrographs:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Peak Factor.</emphasis> This
          factor is applied to the estimated surface runoff peak flow to give
          the value of peak baseflow for a 10% AEP.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Volume Factor.</emphasis> This
          factor is applied to the estimated surface runoff volume to give the
          volume of the baseflow for a 10% AEP.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Under Peak Factor.</emphasis>
          This factor is applied to the estimated surface runoff peak flow to
          give the baseflow at the time of the peak surface runoff. This
          factor can be determined from the Baseflow Peak Factor, such that
          the Baseflow Under Peak Factor = 0.7 x Baseflow Peak Factor.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>The Baseflow Peak Factor and Baseflow Volume Factor are presented
      in <xref linkend="figure_85594555"/> and <xref
      linkend="figure_05634839"/>, which cover the whole of Australia. . It
      should be noted that the maps represent the values for the total area
      upstream of the main stem of the river rather than any smaller
      sub-catchments. As baseflow characteristics may vary away from the main
      stream, the estimation of baseflow in sub-catchments may require the
      approach to be supplemented with additional local data or through an
      alternative approach such as transposition from another location.</para>

      <para>ARR Project 7 developed a series of regression relationships to
      estimate the Baseflow Peak Factor and Baseflow Peak Volume based on
      catchment characteristics (Murphy et al 2011). These are presented in
      <xref linkend="figure_85594555"/> and <xref linkend="figure_05634839"/>
      and supporting spatial data for use with ArcGIS), and can be used to
      determine the Baseflow Peak Factor and the Baseflow Volume Factor for a
      10% AEP event for the catchment of interest.</para>

      <para>These factors provide information on the baseflow contribution to
      design flood events for a 10% AEP event magnitudes. <xref
      linkend="table_35408146"/> shows the AEP scaling factors that should be
      applied to the 10% AEP Baseflow Peak Factor and Baseflow Volume Factor
      to scale the relevant factor to reflect events of other AEPs.</para>

      <table xml:id="table_35408146">
        <caption>AEP Scaling Factors, F<subscript>AEP</subscript>, to be
        applied to the 10% AEP Baseflow Peak Factor and the Baseflow Volume
        Factor to determine the Baseflow Peak Factor for events of various
        AEPs</caption>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>EY</td>

            <td>AEP (%)</td>

            <td>ARI (years)</td>

            <td>AEP (ARI) Factor for Baseflow Peak</td>

            <td>AEP (ARI) Factor for Baseflow Volume</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>2</td>

            <td>86.47</td>

            <td>0.5</td>

            <td>3.0</td>

            <td>2.6</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>1</td>

            <td>63.21</td>

            <td>1</td>

            <td>2.2</td>

            <td>2.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>0.5</td>

            <td>50</td>

            <td>2</td>

            <td>1.7</td>

            <td>1.6</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>0.2</td>

            <td>18.13</td>

            <td>5</td>

            <td>1.2</td>

            <td>1.2</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>0.11</td>

            <td>10</td>

            <td>10</td>

            <td>1.0</td>

            <td>1.0</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>0.05</td>

            <td>5</td>

            <td>20</td>

            <td>0.8</td>

            <td>0.8</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>0.02</td>

            <td>2</td>

            <td>50</td>

            <td>0.7</td>

            <td>0.7</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>0.01</td>

            <td>1</td>

            <td>100</td>

            <td>0.6</td>

            <td>0.6</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para>For events of AEPs not shown in <xref linkend="table_35408146"/>,
      <xref linkend="figure_19570097"/> can be used to determine an
      appropriate AEP factor. This is to be multiplied by the 10% AEP Baseflow
      Peak Factor or the Baseflow Volume Factor as relevant to determine the
      factor for other event magnitudes. Guidance for baseflow contribution to
      Rare and Extreme Events is provided in Book 8.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_19570097">
        <title>AEP Factors, F<subscript>AEP</subscript> to be applied to the
        10% AEP Baseflow Volume Factor to determined the Baseflow Volume
        Factor for events of various AEPs</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_4.JPG" scalefit="1"
                       width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>This information is then applied to the design flood event using
      the procedure outlined in the relationships below which relate to the
      typical flood hydrograph in <xref linkend="figure_28340800"/>.</para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the peak baseflow (point C in
      <xref linkend="figure_28340800"/>):</emphasis></para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Determine the Baseflow Peak Factor for a 10% AEP
          (<inlineequation>
              <m:math display="inline">
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>BPF,10%AEP</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:math>
            </inlineequation>) from <xref linkend="figure_85594555"/>.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Determine the AEP factor corresponding to the event AEP using
          <xref linkend="table_35408146"/> or <xref
          linkend="figure_19570097"/>. Scale the 10% AEP Baseflow Peak Factor
          appropriately to determine the Baseflow Peak Factor for the event
          severity of interest.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Apply the Baseflow Peak Factor to the calculated peak surface
          runoff as in <xref linkend="equation_23454030"/>.</para>

          <equation xml:id="equation_23454030">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>Peak baseflow</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>BPF</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Calculate the timing of the baseflow peak using <xref
          linkend="equation_56532397"/>. The time to the peak surface runoff
          should be applied in units of hours from the start of the
          event.</para>

          <equation xml:id="equation_56532397">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>T</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>Peak baseflow</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>0.92 T</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>

                    <m:mi>+ 33.4</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <figure xml:id="figure_85594555">
        <?landscapeFigure ?>

        <title>Map of Baseflow Peak Factor for a 10% AEP (ARI of 10
        years)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure_5.JPG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="figure_05634839">
        <?landscapeFigure ?>

        <title>Map of Baseflow Volume Factor for a 10% AEP (ARI of 10
        years)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure_6.JPG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the baseflow under the peak
      streamflow (point B in <xref
      linkend="figure_28340800"/>):</emphasis></para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The Baseflow Peak Factor (R<subscript>BPF</subscript>)
          calculated for the appropriate AEP event as above should be used in
          <xref linkend="equation_99686820"/> to calculate the Baseflow Under
          Peak Factor (R<subscript>BUPF</subscript>).</para>

          <equation xml:id="equation_99686820">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>BUPF</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>0.7</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>×</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>BPF</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>R<subscript>BUPF</subscript> should be used as in <xref
          linkend="equation_47798745"/> to calculate the baseflow under the
          peak streamflow.</para>

          <equation xml:id="equation_47798745">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>Baseflow under peak streamflow</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>BUPF</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the total streamflow peak
      (point A in <xref linkend="figure_28340800"/>):</emphasis></para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Calculate the baseflow under the streamflow peak for the
          appropriate AEP as above</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Add the baseflow under the streamflow peak calculated using
          <xref linkend="equation_47798745"/> to the calculated peak surface
          runoff as in <xref linkend="equation_31567661"/>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <equation xml:id="equation_31567661">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

              <m:mi>Peak streamflow</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mi>Baseflow under peak streamflow</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the total baseflow volume for
      an event:</emphasis></para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Determine the Baseflow Volume Factor for a 10% AEP
          (R<subscript>BVF,10yrARI</subscript>) from <xref
          linkend="figure_05634839"/></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Determine the AEP (ARI) factor corresponding to the AEP event
          using <xref linkend="table_35408146"/> or <xref
          linkend="figure_19570097"/>. Scale the 10% AEP Baseflow Volume
          Factor appropriately to determine the Baseflow Volume Factor
          (R<subscript>BVF</subscript>) for the event.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Apply the Baseflow Volume Factor to the calculated surface
          runoff volume as in <xref linkend="equation_59216713"/>.</para>

          <equation xml:id="equation_59216713">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>Baseflow</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>R</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>BVF</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>Surface Runoff</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">To calculate the total streamflow volume for
      an event:</emphasis></para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Calculate the baseflow volume for the event using the
          appropriate AEP factors.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The baseflow volume calculated using <xref
          linkend="equation_59216713"/> should be added to the calculated
          surface runoff as in <xref linkend="equation_67337800"/>.</para>

          <equation xml:id="equation_67337800">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>Total streamflow</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>Surface runoff</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>+ V</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>Baseflow</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>This approach can be directly applied to estimate the baseflow
      contribution to any event between an EY of 2 and a 1% AEP.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="section_70922883">
      <title>Generating the total streamflow hydrograph</title>

      <para>The characteristics of the surface runoff, baseflow and total
      streamflow can be used to estimate the hydrograph for the event. For
      simplicity, a linear approach can typically be used to estimate the
      baseflow at each time step, by fitting between the data values estimated
      through the process described above and matching the baseflow volume.
      This time series can be manually added to the surface runoff time series
      data to generate a time series for the total streamflow. The time series
      generated through this process should be reviewed, and may require
      smoothing to produce a more realistic temporal distribution of baseflow.
      This process is presented in <xref linkend="figure_93046598"/>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_93046598">
        <title>Total streamflow hydrograph generation approach, where (a) the
        data values calculated through the baseflow estimation process are
        plotted; (b) linear interpolation between the baseflow data points and
        matching the area under the curve to the baseflow event volume is used
        to estimate the baseflow time series, which is plotted on the
        hydrograph in green; and (c) the total streamflow time series is
        generated by summing the surface runoff and baseflow time series
        values, with the streamflow hydrograph plotted in red.</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_7.jpg" scalefit="1" width="75%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="section_23859128">
    <title>Case Study Applications</title>

    <para>The process described in <xref linkend="section_70922883"/> is
    worked through in a number of different case study examples.</para>

    <section xml:id="section_72945007">
      <title>North Maroochy River at Eumundi, Queensland</title>

      <para>Catchment 1 is located in southeast Queensland and has a catchment
      area of 40 km<superscript>2</superscript>. Hourly flow data has been
      collected at this location since 1982, providing approximately 30 years
      of data. Very little data is missing or poor quality during this
      period.</para>

      <para>The 10% AEP event is of interest for this case study. The reviewed
      flow data was used to identify flood peaks, in particular the 10% AEP
      event. A comparable event was identified in the record in February 1999.
      The event hydrograph was plotted and key characteristics of the baseflow
      were identified manually (<xref linkend="figure_20223222"/>; manually
      identified baseflow features shown by black points). Straight lines were
      used to join the key baseflow features, to estimate the baseflow time
      series. In this instance, the baseflow peak occurs 18 hours after the
      peak of the streamflow.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_20223222">
        <title>Streamflow hydrograph approximating the 10% AEP event for the
        North Maroochy River at Eumundi</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_8.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The surface runoff hydrograph for the design flood event was
      generated using a flood event model with a critical duration of 18 hours
      (<xref linkend="figure_75706184"/>, and details in <xref
      linkend="table_87725131"/>).</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_21301951">
        <title>Surface runoff hydrograph for the 10% AEP design flood event at
        Eumundi</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_9.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <table xml:id="table_01057465">
        <caption>Key surface runoff characteristics for the 10% AEP design
        flood event at Eumundi</caption>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>Characteristic</td>

            <td>Data from design flood</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Surface runoff peak flow
            (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s)</td>

            <td>160.6</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Time to the surface runoff peak (hours, from the start of the
            event)</td>

            <td>16</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Volume of surface runoff for the event
            (m<superscript>3</superscript>)s</td>

            <td>9.9 x 10<superscript>6</superscript></td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para>The baseflow series estimated above was used directly to
      approximate the baseflow for the 10% AEP design flood event. The
      baseflow at the time of the streamflow peak (from <xref
      linkend="figure_20223222"/>) was aligned with the surface runoff peak in
      the design hydrograph (<xref linkend="figure_75706184"/>), with the rest
      of the baseflow hydrograph used to guide the behaviour through the
      duration of the design event.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_57998828">
        <title>Surface runoff, baseflow and total streamflow hydrographs for
        the 10% AEP event at Eumundi</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_10.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="section_94910940">
      <title>Dirk Brook, Western Australia</title>

      <para>Catchment 2 is located in southwest Western Australia. The 1% AEP
      event is of interest. The surface runoff hydrograph for this event was
      generated using a flood event model with a critical duration of 18 hours
      (<xref linkend="figure_75706184"/>, and details in <xref
      linkend="table_87725131"/>). This case study assumes that no streamflow
      data is available for use. The process described in <xref
      linkend="section_75228116"/> has been used to estimate baseflow.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_75706184">
        <title>Surface runoff hydrograph for the 1% AEP design flood event at
        Dirk Brook</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_11.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <table xml:id="table_87725131">
        <caption>Key surface runoff characteristics for the 1% AEP design
        flood event at Dirk Brook</caption>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>Characteristic</td>

            <td>Data from design flood event</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Surface runoff peak flow
            (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s)</td>

            <td>23.91</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Time to the surface runoff peak (hours, from the start of the
            event)</td>

            <td>8</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Volume of surface runoff for the event
            (m<superscript>3</superscript>)</td>

            <td>1.25 x 10<superscript>6</superscript></td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para>Aligning the catchment boundary shapefile with the spatial data
      from <xref linkend="figure_85594555"/> and <xref
      linkend="figure_05634839"/> allows the Baseflow Peak Factor and Baseflow
      Volume Factor for the 10% event to be extracted for the catchment area
      directly:</para>

      <para>R<subscript>BPF 10 % AEP</subscript> = 0.186</para>

      <para>R<subscript>BVF 10 % AEP</subscript> =1.099</para>

      <para>The scaling factor for the 1% AEP event is sourced from <xref
      linkend="table_35408146"/>, with a value of 0.6 for both the peak and
      volume calculations. Using the relationships described earlier, the
      final Baseflow Peak Factor, Baseflow Volume Factor and Baseflow Under
      Peak Factor for application are outlined in <xref
      linkend="table_00839046"/>. These values are applied to calculate the
      baseflow and total streamflow characteristics in <xref
      linkend="table_74453170"/>, and plotted in <xref
      linkend="figure_86477209"/>.</para>

      <table xml:id="table_00839046">
        <caption>Calculation of Baseflow Factors for the 1% AEP design event
        for the Dirk Brook</caption>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>Factors for application</td>

            <td>Factor values for 1% AEP design event</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><para>Final Baseflow Peak
            Factor</para><para>R<subscript>BPF</subscript> =
            F<subscript>AEP</subscript>R<subscript>BPF, 10 %
            AEP</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 0.6 x 0.186</para><para>= 0.11</para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Final Baseflow Volume
            Factor</para><para>R<subscript>BVF</subscript> =
            F<subscript>AEP</subscript>R<subscript>BVF, 10 %
            AEP</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 0.6 x 1.099</para><para>= 0.66</para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Final Baseflow Under Peak
            Factor</para><para>R<subscript>BUBF</subscript> = 0.7 ×
            R<subscript>BPF</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 0.7 x 0.112</para><para>= 0.08</para></td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <table xml:id="table_74453170">
        <caption>Calculation of baseflow and total streamflow characteristics
        for the 1% AEP event for the Dirk Brook catchment</caption>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>Baseflow and total streamflow characteristics</td>

            <td>Factor values for 1% AEP</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Peak Baseflow</emphasis></td>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Peak baseflow (refer to <xref
            linkend="equation_23454030"/>)</para><para>Q<subscript>Peak
            baseflow</subscript>= R<subscript>BPF</subscript> Q<subscript>Peak
            surface runoff</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 0.11 x 23.9</para><para>= 2.6
            m<superscript>3</superscript>/s</para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Time to peak baseflow (<xref
            linkend="equation_56532397"/>)</para><para>T<subscript>Peak
            baseflow</subscript> = 0.92T<subscript>Peak surface
            runoff</subscript> + 33.4</para></td>

            <td><para>= (0.92 x 8) +33.4</para><para>= 41 hours</para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Under the Peak</emphasis></td>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Baseflow under the streamflow peak (<xref
            linkend="equation_47798745"/>)</para><para>Q<subscript>Baseflow
            under peak streamflow</subscript> = R<subscript>BUPF</subscript>
            Q<subscript>Peak surface runoff</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 0.08 x 23.9</para><para>= 1.9
            m<superscript>3</superscript>/s</para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Total Streamflow Peak </emphasis></td>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Total streamflow peak flow (<xref
            linkend="equation_31567661"/>)</para><para>Q<subscript>Peak
            streamflow</subscript> = Q<subscript>Peak surface
            runoff</subscript> + Q<subscript>Baseflow under peak
            streamflow</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 23.9 + 1.9</para><para>= 25.8
            m<superscript>3</superscript>/s</para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow Volume </emphasis></td>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Baseflow volume (<xref
            linkend="equation_59216713"/>)</para><para>V<subscript>Baseflow
            </subscript> = R<subscript>BVF</subscript> V<subscript>Surface
            runoff</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 0.66 x 1.25 x
            10<superscript>6</superscript></para><para>= 0.83 x
            10<superscript>6</superscript></para></td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Total Streamflow Volume </emphasis></td>

            <td/>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td><para>Total streamflow volume (<xref
            linkend="equation_67337800"/>)</para><para>V<subscript>Total
            streamflow</subscript> = V<subscript>Surface runoff</subscript> +
            V<subscript>Baseflow</subscript></para></td>

            <td><para>= 1.25 x 10<superscript>6</superscript> + 0.83 x
            10<superscript>6</superscript></para><para>= 2.08 x
            10<superscript>6</superscript></para></td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <figure xml:id="figure_86477209">
        <title>Surface runoff, baseflow and total streamflow hydrographs for
        the 1% AEP event at Dirk Brook</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_12.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="section_53645143">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Brodie, R.S. and Hostetler, S. (2005) <emphasis>A review of
    techniques for analysing baseflow from stream hydrographs</emphasis> in
    <emphasis>Proceedings of the NZHS-IAH-NZSSS 2005 conference</emphasis>,
    Auckland, New Zealand, 28 November – 2 December, 2005.</para>

    <para>Chapman, T.G. and Maxwell, A.I. (1996) <emphasis>Baseflow separation
    – Comparison of numerical methods with tracer experiments,</emphasis>
    Proceedings of the 23rd Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Hobart
    Australia, 21-24 May 1996.</para>

    <para>Graszkiewicz, Z, Murphy, R.E, Hill, P.I., Nathan, R.J (2011) Review
    of techniques for estimating the contribution of baseflow to flood
    hydrographs. <emphasis>34th IAHR World Congress.</emphasis> 26 June to 1
    July 2011 Brisbane, Australia.</para>

    <para>Kinkela, K., Pearce, L.J. (2014) Assessment of baseflow seasonality
    and application to design flood events in southwest Western Australia.
    Australian Journal of Water Resources. Vol 18. No. 1</para>

    <para>Ladson, A.R., Brown, R., Neal, B., and Nathan, R. (2013): A standard
    approach to baseflow separation using the Lyne and Hollick
    filter.<emphasis> Aus J Water Resour.</emphasis> 17(1): 25-33.</para>

    <para>Murphy, R., Graszkiewicz, Z., Hill, P., Neal, B., Nathan, R., and
    Ladson, T. (2009) <emphasis>Project 7: Baseflow for catchment simulation.
    Phase 1 – selection of baseflow separation approach, </emphasis>Report
    prepared for the Australian Rainfall and Runoff Technical Committee by
    Sinclair Knight Merz. AR&amp;R Report Number P7/S1/004, ISBN
    978-085825-9218.</para>

    <para>Murphy, R.E., Graszkiewicz, Z, Hill, P.I., Neal, B.P., Nathan, R.J.
    (2011a) Predicting baseflow contributions to design flood events in
    Australia. <emphasis>34th IAHR World Congress.</emphasis> 26 June to 1
    July 2011 Brisbane, Australia.</para>

    <para>Murphy, R., Graszkiewicz, Z., Hill, P., Neal, B., and Nathan, R.
    (2011b)<emphasis> Project 7: Baseflow for catchment simulation. Phase 2 –
    development of baseflow estimation approach.</emphasis> Report prepared
    for the Australian Rainfall and Runoff Technical Committee by Sinclair
    Knight Merz. AR&amp;R Report Number P7/S2/017, ISBN
    978-0-85825-916-4.</para>

    <para>Nathan, R.J, and McMahon, T.A. (1990) <emphasis>Evaluation of
    Automated Techniques for Base Flow and Recession Analyses,</emphasis>
    Water Resources Research, 26(7), 1465-1473.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold">Appendix A Calculation of the timing of the
    baseflow peak</emphasis></para>

    <para>Analyses undertaken to develop most of the method outlined in <xref
    linkend="section_75228116"/> is described in detail in separate technical
    documents, available online at the ARR update website (SKM, 2010,
    available online http://www.arr.org.au/p7.html). However, the background
    behind the calculation of the timing of the baseflow peak is not captured
    in those documents. A full description of the development of <xref
    linkend="equation_56532397"/> is provided below. The description below
    assumes that the reader has an understanding of the work presented in the
    separate technical documents, and a full background of the broader study
    concepts is not provided here.</para>

    <para>More than 230 suitable catchments across Australia were identified
    for analysis for ARR Update Project 7, and hourly streamflow data was
    collated for each of these locations. A baseflow time series was generated
    from each flow record using the Lyne and Hollick digital filter, modified
    to suit hourly streamflow data. The top 4N flood events were identified in
    the hourly time series data for each catchment, generating a data set of
    more than 30,000 flood events across the 236 catchments. For each of these
    events, the magnitude and timing of the total streamflow peak and baseflow
    peak were identified. The time to these peaks was calculated from the
    start of the event. At each location, the average time to the streamflow
    and baseflow peaks were then calculated based on the 4N events.</para>

    <para>For the purposes of this assessment, it was assumed that the total
    streamflow and surface runoff peaks would coincide. This is considered a
    reasonable assumption since surface runoff is generally the main component
    of the total streamflow hydrograph.</para>

    <para>Analysis of the average time to peak data identified a strong
    relationship between the time to the surface runoff (and streamflow) and
    baseflow peaks, as presented in <xref linkend="figure_74876507"/>. This
    relationship provides a direct calculation from which to estimate the
    timing of the baseflow peak, based upon knowledge of the surface runoff
    event generated using a flood event model. That is, the time to the
    baseflow peak (in hours from the start of the event) can be calculated
    as:</para>

    <equation xml:id="equation_08366567">
      <m:math display="block">
        <m:mrow>
          <m:msub>
            <m:mi>T</m:mi>

            <m:mi>Peak baseflow</m:mi>
          </m:msub>

          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>0.92 T</m:mi>

              <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>+ 33.4</m:mo>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:mrow>
      </m:math>
    </equation>

    <figure xml:id="figure_74876507">
      <title>Comparison of average time to surface runoff peak and time to
      baseflow peak, based on analysis of more than 30,000 flood events from
      catchments across Australia.</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure_13.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para/>
  </section>
</chapter>
