<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b5_ch2" version= "5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         status = "In Preparation">
         
         <info><title>Catchment Representation</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>

   </info>
  <para>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Date last updated</td>
        <td>13/5/2019</td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
  </para>
  <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_001">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>The representation of a catchment in a flood hydrograph estimation model is, by necessity,
      highly conceptualised and aims to represent those features and characteristics that are most
      influential in determining the overall flood response of the catchment. The distribution of
      storm rainfall over different parts of the catchment and the flood response to it may vary
      considerably, depending on the details of topography, vegetation cover, land use and drainage
      network characteristics. However, as the hydrograph inputs from different parts of the
      catchment are progressively combined on their way to the catchment outlet, only some of these
      differences in response characteristics are directly reflected in the combined hydrographs at
      downstream points of interest. Different catchment modelling approaches have therefore evolved
      to find an appropriate compromise between required model complexity and spatial resolution on
      the one hand, and desirable modelling efficiency on the other. These different modelling
      approaches can be applied with different degrees of complexity, and often more simple methods
      may be quite appropriate.</para>
    <para>As is explained in more detail in <xref linkend="b5_ch3"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch6"/>,
      the various forms of <emphasis role="italic">temporary flood storage</emphasis> available in
      different parts of the catchment play a key role in determining how the runoff inputs from
      different parts of the catchment are transformed into the flood hydrograph at the catchment
      outlet. The effect of catchment storage on the routing of hydrographs is twofold and involves:
        <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">translation</emphasis> of the hydrograph peak and other
            ordinates forward in time and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">attenuation</emphasis> of the peak as the hydrograph moves
            along the stream network.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>The different catchment representations in flood hydrograph estimation models
      can therefore be classified on the basis of how the different forms of temporary flood storage
      are conceptualised and in how much detail they are represented in the model. Other factors
      such as losses, which determine the flood volume (covered in <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/>) and
      baseflow, which may modify the flood hydrograph shape and volume (covered in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch4"/>), must also be a part of the modelling of flood hydrographs.</para>
    <para>In situations where the interest is only on the combined hydrograph at the catchment
      outlet and where good flood records for current conditions are available at that point,
      modelling of the catchment as a single ‘lumped’ response unit may be sufficient. This is the
      approach adopted by a number of traditional flood hydrograph estimation methods such as the
      unit hydrograph approach, the time-area approach and the Clark and Nash models of
      runoff-routing. In these modelling approaches, discussed further in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch2_s_002"/>, the rainfall excess input is ‘lumped’ for the whole catchment and
      then transformed by some routing method to a hydrograph at the catchment outlet.</para>
    <para>For catchments with more complex runoff production and flood hydrograph formation
      characteristics it is more usual to adopt a semi-distributed rather than a lumped modelling
      approach. Adoption of a semi-distributed approach allows the key factors that influence flood
      response to be represented in a spatially explicit fashion. Common factors represented in a
      semi-distributed manner include rainfall, losses and routing parameters, though such models
      also facilitate the representation of influential catchment features that control variation in
      the timing and/or magnitude of flood runoff from different parts of the catchment. The
      category of semi-distributed models (or node-link type models), dealt with in <xref
        linkend="b5_ch2_s_003"/>, allows for an appropriate matching of spatial model resolution
      with the degree of spatial variation of catchment characteristics and inputs.</para>
    <para>Finally, developments in computing power and the availability of digital terrain
      information now allow a fully distributed representation of catchments in grid-based models.
      The emerging rainfall-on-grid modelling approach is discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch2_s_009"
      />.</para>
    <para>Many of the following considerations on how to represent catchments in hydrologic flood
      estimation models apply to both rural and urban catchments. However, modelling of urban
      catchments is treated in more detail in <xref linkend="book9"/>. </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_002">
    <title>Lumped Models</title>
    <para>In relatively small catchments (or within each sub-catchment of a larger catchment) there
      is often only limited spatial variation in rainfall and loss characteristics, and it is thus
      acceptable to treat the catchment (or sub-catchment) as a homogeneous unit. Models that do not
      allow for spatial variation in runoff or routing characteristics within a catchment are
      referred to as ‘lumped’ models. It is possible to link the outputs of several lumped models to
      form a quasi-distributed catchment model.</para>
    <para>The peak flow estimation methods described in <xref linkend="book3"/> can be regarded as
      “lumped” type models, since the flood peaks are calculated at a single point only, without the
      internal characteristics of the catchment being considered.</para>
    <para>In the runoff generation phase of lumped models, the conceptual loss and baseflow models
      described in <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/> can be applied using the
      assumption that the rainfall inputs, losses and baseflow contributions are the same over the
      whole catchment. Such a simplifying assumption may be appropriate when rainfall and streamflow
      data are only available from a single gauge and it is thus difficult to infer any internal
      variation of the rainfall and runoff generation characteristics. </para>
    <para>In the hydrograph formation or routing phase of lumped models, a range of
      conceptualisations may be used to represent the hydrograph translation and attenuation effects
      of the catchment on the runoff hydrograph input. These conceptualisations may aim to represent
      physical catchment processes, but they are essentially ‘black box’ mathematical
      representations. The different lumped flood modelling approaches include:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The Time-Area Approach</emphasis> (<xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_ypsrh"/>) - in
          which the different degree of translation (time lag) experienced by runoff from different
          parts of the catchment is modelled by dividing the catchment into a number of areas with
          the same delay time to the catchment outlet (‘isochronal areas’). The runoff inputs to the
          different sub-areas are then lagged accordingly to represent the translation effects of
          the total catchment, but this routing method does not provide for any attenuation of peak
          flows on their way to the catchment outlet. </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The Unit Hydrograph Approach</emphasis> (<xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_7b1zz"/>) -
          which converts rainfall excess inputs to a flood hydrograph by applying a transfer
          function (the unit hydrograph). The transfer function is generally inferred from the
          analysis of observed rainfall inputs and streamflow outputs, and there is limited
          potential to relate its parameterisation to measurable catchment characteristics, though
          the parameters for the method may be developed from recorded data.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Other lumped flood hydrograph estimation methods</emphasis> - that involve
          use of a single (concentrated) linear storage (e.g. Clarke) or a distributed form of
          storage represented by a cascade of several linear storages (e.g. Nash). Variations of
          these methods with non-linear storages are also used. The fundamental flood routing
          concepts applied in these methods are further explained in <xref linkend="b5_c5_s_002"/>
          to <xref linkend="b5_c5_s_004"/>. </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>While lumped flood hydrograph estimation models have the advantage of simplicity, they are
      limited in their application to the following situations:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchments with relatively uniform spatial rainfall, loss and baseflow characteristics
          or where the variation of these characteristics between events is relatively minor, so
          that the derived unit hydrograph or other model parameters are applicable to a range of
          design events;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchments with no significant artificial storages (reservoirs or flood detention
          basins);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Applications where a flood hydrograph is only required at the catchment outlet, as for
          the design of drainage structures on roads and railway lines; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Applications that do not require extrapolation to the range of Very Rare to Extreme
          floods.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>To the extent that they adopt a ‘black box’ approach (ie. the functions used to transform
      rainfalls to streamflows do not have direct links to physical catchment characteristics),
      lumped models depend on the availability of observed flood hydrographs for their calibration.
      The scope for application to ungauged catchments is thus more limited but the Clark-Johnstone
      synthetic unit hydrograph method (<xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_rsmli"/>) has in the past been
      widely used for catchments on the east coast of Australia
      <citation>b5_c2_r2</citation>.</para>
    <para>The semi-distributed (node-link type) models described in the next section offer a broader
      range of application but are also more demanding in terms of model development, data
      requirements and understanding/skill of the practitioner. The lumped flood hydrograph
      estimation approach can be seen as a simplified version of the semi-distributed  flood
      hydrograph estimation approach, and it is worth noting that the most widely used
      runoff-routing models (described in <xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_do8jr"/>) can be configured to
      represent catchment response in a lumped fashion.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_003">
    <title>Semi-Distributed (Node-Link Type) Models</title>
    <para>Semi-distributed models allow the spatial variation of inputs and key processes to be
      modelled explicitly. This is particularly important in large catchments and in catchments
      where the natural flooding characteristics have been significantly modified by various forms
      of development, including the construction of reservoirs, flood mitigation works and transport
      and drainage infrastructure. </para>
    <para>Because of their flexibility and ability to calculate flood hydrographs throughout the
      catchment and to model land use and catchment changes, as well as being relatively
      straightforward to establish and run, node-link type models are currently the most widely used
      modelling approach for flood hydrograph estimation in Australia. A range of ready-to-use
      modelling systems (<xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_do8jr"/>) are available to set up models for
      catchments of different size and complexity. These modelling systems allow the influential
      features and characteristics of a catchment to be represented in the model but in a highly
      conceptualised form. All conceptualisations involve some degree of lumping in terms of the
      processes modelled and spatial averaging of inputs, but the different modelling systems differ
      in the way they divide the catchment into various conceptual elements and in the methods they
      use to model the processes represented by these elements. </para>
    <para><xref linkend="b5_ch2_f_007"/> shows a simple conceptual representation of the
      runoff-routing process in a node-link type model. Each subarea receives a rainfall excess
      input which is converted to a runoff hydrograph at the node representing this subarea. The
      hydrographs are then routed successively through the links representing the drainage network
      to form the hydrograph at the catchment outlet.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b5_ch2_f_007">
      <title>Conceptual Representation of the Runoff Routing Process in a Node-Link Type Model </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5075.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_004">
      <title>Conceptual Model Elements</title>
      <para>To build a semi-distributed model, the real catchment has to be conceptually represented
        as a system of nodes and links, each representing a different element of the actual
        catchment system. The following set of basic nodes and links can be used in different
        catchment models, but different models vary in how these basic elements are applied.</para>
      <para><emphasis>Nodes</emphasis>: </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Input nodes for hyetographs of rainfall excess or hydrographs of direct runoff (and
            possibly baseflow) from model sub-areas;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Input nodes for inflow hydrographs from separately modelled catchments;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Junction nodes – where different branches of the drainage network join (or where
            diversion flows re-enter);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Diversion nodes – points where some of the flow is diverted or abstracted from the
            network;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Reservoir routing nodes;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flood detention routing nodes; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Nodes for hydrograph outputs (including at gauging locations for comparison of
            modelled and observed hydrographs). </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis>Links</emphasis>:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Stream or channel routing links;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Bypass links; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Floodplain storage links.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_005">
      <title>Catchment Sub-Division</title>
      <para>The basic principle applied in dividing the catchment into a number of sub-areas for
        semi-distributed modelling is to provide a simplified but physically-based representation of
        the spatial features of the catchment, using a relatively small number of sub-areas
        (typically 10 to 100). The delineation of these sub-areas should generally follow
        topographic features that control the movement and storage of flood waters. Relevant land
        use features, such as the urban sections of the catchment, or areas inundated by large water
        bodies, need to be specifically delineated. The features that control flowpaths in
        relatively flat catchments may not be evident, and careful analysis of available topographic
        and flood data is required to define the sub-area boundaries. Detailed survey as well as
        aerial or satellite images may assist the catchment delineation in areas where the drainage
        characteristics are unclear.</para>
      <para>The catchment sub-division should also have regard to the prevailing land uses in
        different parts of the catchment and should aim at sub-areas that are essentially
        homogeneous in terms of their runoff characteristics. This is particularly relevant in urban
        or urbanising catchments. Large areas with immediate runoff response, such as natural lakes
        and reservoirs also require special consideration. <xref linkend="b7_ch4"/> provides more
        detailed guidance. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_006">
      <title>Modelling of Runoff from 'Hill Slopes' (Overland Flow)</title>
      <para>The term “contributing areas” is used to describe those areas of catchments where
        surface runoff occurs in the form of overland flow, sheet flow or flow in small channels
        that are not significant enough to be modelled separately (<xref linkend="b4ch2_s_bp6h9"/>).
        There are two distinctly different methods used to model this runoff component:</para>
      <orderedlist numeration = "lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para>The input hyetograph (areal average rainfall excess) for the sub-area is directly
            converted into a runoff hydrograph at a representative point within the sub-area
            (usually at or close to the centroid). This assumes that all runoff from the sub-area
            reaches this input node without any delay and there is no flow attenuation within the
            sub-area. Any translation and attenuation effects occurring within the hill slope
            elements thus need to be represented in the routing through the drainage network from
            the subarea input node to downstream points of interest; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The input hyetograph to the sub-area is transformed to an output hydrograph using
            one of the lumped catchment models introduced in <xref linkend="b5_ch2_s_002"/>.
            Different models use time-area, unit hydrograph or different forms of storage routing or
            kinematic wave routing concepts for this transformation.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>Method (i) has the advantage of simplicity in that it avoids having to determine
        additional model parameters for runoff from contributing areas. In catchments with
        relatively uniform land use, when the interest is mainly on flood hydrographs at the
        catchment outlet for a limited range of flood magnitudes, this method can be expected to
        provide satisfactory results. However, it may provide conservatively high estimates of
        hydrograph peaks at internal points in the upper parts of the catchment due to the neglect
        of routing effects in the contributing areas of the catchment. <xref
          linkend="b5_ch6_s_zd6cp"/> provides more detailed discussion of this method. </para>
      <para>Method (ii) allows for better representation of processes that contribute to hydrographs
        in the upper parts of the catchment but it requires additional parameters. It is also better
        able to deal with the effects of significant land use changes in parts of the catchment and
        with changed runoff behaviour in Very Rare to Extreme flood events (<xref linkend="b8_ch5"
        />). A more detailed discussion of this approach is provided in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch6_s_8qwmr"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_007">
      <title>Routing Through Network of Stream/Channel/Floodplain Elements </title>
      <para>Except in small rural catchments, most of the translation and attenuation effects in the
        transformation of rainfall inputs to hydrograph outputs occur in the routing of hydrographs
        through the network of streams/channels, floodplains and major storages. The capability of a
        modelling system to adequately reflect the translation and attenuation involved in this
        transformation is therefore an important prerequisite for accurate flood hydrograph
        estimation.</para>
      <para>Two distinctly different groups of flood routing approaches are used in node-link type
        flood hydrograph estimation models:</para>
      <orderedlist numeration = "lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Hydrologic Routing Approaches</emphasis>- these flood routing methods are
            based on the storage routing principles described in <xref linkend="b5_c5_s_004"/>
            (linear storage routing) and <xref linkend="b5_c5_s_022"/> (non-linear storage routing).
            An important characteristic of hydrologic flood routing models is that their parameters
            are generally inferred from observed flood hydrographs, but it is possible to infer
            their parameters through close links with hydraulic methods (e.g. Muskingum-Cunge
            Method, <xref linkend="b5_c5_s_004"/>) or from the results of hydraulic modelling;
            and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Hydraulic Routing Approaches</emphasis> - these flood routing methods are
            based directly on the full unsteady flow equations or various simplified forms of these
            equations, as described in <xref linkend="b5_c5_s_022"/>. Their parameters are inferred
            from the cross-sectional characteristics of streams, channels and floodplains, and the
            hydraulic characteristics of controlling features. The kinematic wave and diffusion wave
            approaches described in <xref linkend="b5_c5_s_024"/> are the most widely used hydraulic
            routing approaches incorporated into flood hydrograph estimation models.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>The hydrologic routing approaches have the advantage that, by deriving their parameters
        from observed hydrographs, they represent an integrated routing response from the complex
        stream and floodplain system that is often too complex to be represented in detail. However,
        application of such calibrated parameters to conditions outside the ones reflected in the
        observed hydrographs (ie. for changed catchment conditions or significantly different flood
        magnitudes) involves assumptions that may not be justifiable. The hydraulic routing methods
        have closer links to the physical characteristics of the routing reaches, but their
        application still involves a significant degree of conceptualisation and some form of
        calibration.</para>
      <para>Modelling of the flood routing effects over a range of flow conditions requires a clear
        understanding of the flood dynamics so that the simulated response can be appropriately
        matched to the actual flooding behaviour. Specifically this means that the adopted network
        should represent any breakout flows and bypass flows occurring during larger floods, as well
        as the effects of significant floodplain storage areas activated during large events. The
        additional storage availability in large flood events may be counter-balanced by increased
        flow efficiency as the flow depth increases. Where backwater effects are likely to have a
        significant impact not only on flood levels but also on the routing of flood flows through
        the drainage network, hydraulic routing methods based on the full unsteady flow equations
        may be required.</para>
      <para>The model should also represent the varying impact of flow restrictions for different
        flow magnitudes. In some cases the results of detailed hydraulic modelling may be required
        to develop a clear understanding of the changes in flood flow behaviour with flood
        magnitude, so that they can be adequately reflected in the hydrologic catchment model. </para>
      <para>One important limitation of node-link type models is that the different routing elements
        are conceptualised as one dimensional flow links. This means that a dominant flow direction
        needs to be assumed when the routing elements are defined. In cases where the flow direction
        changes for floods of different magnitudes, it may be necessary to introduce more complexity
        into the channel network so that different flowpaths are activated at different flow
        magnitudes. The two dimensional rainfall-on-grid approaches discussed in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch2_s_009"/> are in principle better equipped to deal with changes in flow
        direction during a flood event and between flood events of different magnitude, but this
        advantage may be off-set by the difficulty of using such models to adequately represent loss
        processes and roughness characteristics at the scale of individual grid cells. </para>
      <para>Whatever routing method is used, it is important to ensure that any application of the
        model outside its range of calibration is guided by consideration of changes in hydraulic
        characteristics and then reflected in the adopted network conceptualisation and parameter
        values. This is further discussed in <xref linkend="b7_ch4"/> and <xref linkend="b7_ch5"
        />.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_008">
      <title>Routing Trough Special Storages</title>
      <para>When flood storage occurs in a concentrated form, such as in lakes, reservoirs,
        detention basins and large natural or artificial flood storageage areas, it is appropriate
        to model the flood modifying effects of such storages by a ’special storage’ routine. Where
        the relevant survey and hydrographic data are available, the storage-discharge
        characteristics of such special storages may be defined by storage rating curves and
        discharge rating curves in terms of depth or elevation. In other situations, simplified
        storage-discharge relationships need to be derived from observed inflow and outflow
        hydrographs or by trial and error during model calibration. Methods for deriving
        storage-discharge relationships for different conceptual storage elements are discussed in
          <xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_6plz4"/>.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b5_ch2_s_009">
    <title>Grid-based (Distributed) Models</title>
    <para>In the fully distributed or grid-based flood hydrograph estimation models (also referred
      to as ‘rainfall-on-grid’ models) the catchment is represented by a large number of grid cells,
      based on topographic data from a Digital Elevation Model (DEM). More detailed survey
      information on the drainage network and flow controlling features of the catchment may be
      superimposed on the DEM data.</para>
    <para>Different models vary in the degree of detail adopted in modelling the runoff generated
      from rainfall falling on a grid element. In principle the method allows more physically-based
      representations of runoff processes; however, this is only likely to be valid at larger depths
      of overland flow. Such models currently represent saturation and ponding processes in a
      simplistic fashion, and similar simplifications are adopted in modelling the baseflow
      contribution at the scale of individual cells. </para>
    <para>The routing of runoff from individual cells through the catchment and the stream network
      is then based on the principles of two dimensional dynamic wave modelling introduced in <xref
        linkend="b5_c5_s_023"/> and described in more detail in <xref linkend="b6_ch4_s_v3f40"/>.
      Particular issues to be dealt with in these models are the significantly larger data
      requirements than for node-link type models to give a realistic representation of the
      catchment, characterisation of hydraulic roughness for different catchment elements, and how
      to deal with computational stability problems that arise when runoff is generated from
      initially dry cells. </para>
    <para>As the direction of the flow between cells is determined as part of the solution process
      at each time step, drainage paths do not need to be pre-defined as in traditional one
      dimensional runoff-routing approaches. The application of hydraulic methods in the
      runoff-routing process also means that there is no need for linking the hydrologic model with
      a hydraulic model of the floodplain area. </para>
    <para>In most catchments the catchment boundaries and the drainage network are quite well
      defined in the upper part of the catchment, and traditional runoff-routing models can thus
      adequately describe the flood hydrograph formation for these parts of the catchment. A
      ‘hybrid’ approach, where a two dimensional model is only used for runoff-routing in the
      flatter or urbanised parts of the catchment that are influenced by complex hydraulic controls,
      may be the most efficient approach in these situations.</para>
    <para>The theoretical advantage of grid-based models is that a lesser degree of
      conceptualisation in the catchment representation is required, thus requiring less hydrologic
      expertise of the practitioner. However, the modelling of the overland flow phase at the scale
      of individual grid cells still poses challenges and requires further research. The principles
      applied in rainfall-on-grid models and their advantages and limitations are discussed in more
      detail in <xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_lgabf"/>. While grid-based methods are apparently more
      directly based on physical catchment data than alternative methods, they still need to be
      calibrated with recorded data, and there is still uncertainty in the results from their
      application. This is discussed further in <xref linkend="book7"/>.</para>
    <para>At the current stage of development of these models and with the limited level of
      experience gained with their practical application, it is considered premature to recommend
      their general use in these Guidelines. However, it is expected that further development and
      testing will allow rainfall-on-grid models to be more widely applied.</para>
  </section>
  
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
  
</chapter>
