<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b4_ch1" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    status = "In Preparation">
    <info>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
</info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>24/4/2018 </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
    <section>
      <title>Simulation of Design Flood Hydrographs</title>
      <para>There are many problems where design flood characteristics other than the peak flows are
      required. Most commonly this involves problems where the volume of the flood hydrograph has a
      dominant influence on the design objective of interest. Typical problems include the design of
      urban stormwater drainage systems where it is necessary to size on-site detention storages,
      the estimation of maximum surcharge levels in detention basins and dams, and the derivation of
      design flood levels in situations where the floodplain can store an appreciable proportion of
      the event. It may also be necessary to characterise the rate of rise of selected events for
      flood warning purposes. The assessment of such problems requires the simulation of complete
      design flood hydrographs, where it may be necessary to give particular attention to the rate
      of rise and the total volume of the hydrograph. If design interest is focused on a location in
      the catchment that is materially influenced by hydraulic controls (as in many urban
      catchments), then it is likely that it will be necessary to model the catchment as a “system”
      using an integrated combination of hydrologic and hydraulic modelling (therefore use of a
      catchment modelling system, <xref linkend="book7"/>). Conversely, if the point of interest is
      largely uninfluenced by hydraulic controls (as in many rural catchments or trunk drainage
      networks in urban areas) then it should be sufficient to model the catchment with a hydrologic
      model.</para>
    <para>The simulation of design flood hydrographs is most easily undertaken using rainfall data.
      While the methods presented in <xref linkend="book3"/> provide useful independent estimates on
      the peak of simulated hydrographs, additional information is required to check the shape and
      volume of design flood hydrographs. Rainfall-based methods involve the transformation of
      rainfalls into a selected flood characteristic: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>event-based models transform probabilistic bursts of rainfall to corresponding
            estimates of floods; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>continuous simulation models transform a time series of rainfall into probabilistic
            flood estimates</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist> Hydraulic models are then used to simulate flood levels from hydrologic
      (and/or rainfall) inputs. The challenge with these methods is how to achieve probability
      neutrality, that is how to ensure that the method used to transform rainfalls into design
      floods is undertaken in a fashion that minimises bias in the resulting exceedance
      probabilities.</para>
    <para>The guidance in this Book is focused on the conceptual frameworks used to derive design
      flood hydrographs, rather than on the models used to transform rainfall into runoff. Detailed
      guidance on the different types of hydrologic models is provided in <xref linkend="book5"/>,
      and guidance on the hydraulic modelling of runoff through the catchment is provided in <xref
        linkend="book6"/>. Guidance on the application of catchment modelling systems and the
      interpretation of the results obtained is provided in <xref linkend="book7"/>.</para>
      
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Difference Between Historic and Design Flood Simulations</title>
    <para>It is worth noting that there is a considerable difference in the modelling approaches
      required to simulate historic (or observed) and design floods. Although the same mathematical
      procedures (and software) may be involved in both, the simulation objectives and modelling
      considerations are markedly different. </para>
    <para>Estimation of a design flood involves the derivation of the relationship between the
      magnitude and probability of a given flood characteristic. The objective of the analysis is to
      provide information for risk-based planning or design purposes. Such information can be
      extended to provide standards-based estimates such as the Probable Maximum Flood, but the
      simulation objective is still to assess the performance of a system under particular set of
      loading conditions. </para>
    <para>In contrast, the modelling required to simulate floods using historic or forecast
      rainfalls involves quite different considerations. The challenge of selecting data inputs and
      analysis frameworks to estimate the exceedance probability of a particular outcome is replaced
      by the difficulty of preparing data to reflect conditions specific to a particular event in
      time. The focus of the analysis might be on simulating a particular historic flood, or it may
      involve assessment of the antecedent conditions and forecast rainfalls associated with a flood
      forecast required at a particular point in time.</para>
    <para>Identical models might be used to simulate the response of the catchment under historic or
      design conditions. The essential difference is that design flood simulations are undertaken to
      derive the best estimate of the relationship between flood magnitude and exceedance
      probability, whereas simulation of actual floods represent the best estimate of flood
      characteristics for a particular point in time. The Guidance provided in <xref linkend="book6"
      /> and <xref linkend="book7"/> is equally applicable to models used for the simulation of
      design or actual floods. The guidance provided in this Book is specific to the issues involved
      in assigning an exceedance probability to flood characteristics.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Scope</title>
    <para>The scope of this Book is largely on the simulation frameworks used to derive design
      floods. Particular attention is paid to those hydrologic processes that most influence flood
      magnitude, and on the approaches required to estimate the exceedance probability of a flood
      characteristic of interest. Guidance is included on the treatment of joint probability, as the
      explicit analysis of the way in which factors combine to influence the frequency of floods is
      an essential consideration in the estimation of design floods. Worked examples are provided to
      assist practitioners apply the guidance to typical real-world problems.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Outline</title>
    <para>This book is structured as follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b4_ch2"/> provide a broad description of the runoff processes that
          contribute to streamflows (interception, depression storage, infiltration, interflow, and
          groundwater contributions), and identifies those components of most relevance to flood
          generation;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b4_ch3"/> describes three different approaches to event-based modelling
          (simple, ensemble, and Monte Carlo methods) and describes how increasing levels of
          sophistication can be used to minimise bias in the transformation of design rainfalls into
          design floods; <xref linkend="b4_ch3"/> also describes the use of continuous (and hybrid)
          simulation approaches to flood estimation, and summarises the strengths and weaknesses of
          the various approaches;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b4_ch4"/> introduces the generic nature of joint probability
          requirements; it covers the factors involved in the transformation of rainfall to runoff,
          and other factors (e.g. initial reservoir level or tide levels) that may influence the
          design performance of interest; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b4_ch3"/> and <xref linkend="b4_ch4"/> include worked examples that
          illustrate application of the techniques to practical problems.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  
</chapter>


