<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xml:id="b4_ch2" version="5.0" status="In Preparation">
    <info>
        <title>Hydrologic Processes Contributing to Floods</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ladson_anthony.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
        
    </info>
    <informaltable border="1">
        <tr>
            <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Date last updated</td>
            <td>06/07/16 </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Content</td>
            <td>Advanced draft</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>General</td>
            <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
        </tr>
    </informaltable>
    <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_f2ad3">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>This chapter outlines the hydrologic processes that contribute to floods including a
            review of runoff generation, baseflow contributions to flood flow, flow routing and
            losses. The chapter concludes with a discussion of the conceptualisation of these
            processes in models and case studies of floods in tropical and temperate rural
            catchments, and in urban areas. </para>
        <para>Under Australian conditions, the ultimate cause of the large streamflows that result
            in floods is usually rainfall. Other causes, such as melting of snow and ice, are less
            important in our temperate climate. In places storm surge may combine with stream flows
            to cause flooding as discussed in <xref linkend="b6_ch5"/>. </para>
        <para>The link between rainfall and streamflow is mediated by a number of processes (<xref
                linkend="b4ch2_f_odmn5"/>). Rainfall landing on the catchment surface can be
            converted to runoff in different ways that depend on infiltration capacity and whether
            soils are saturated. Four runoff processes are discussed in <xref
                linkend="b4ch2_s_bp6h9"/>: those relating to infiltration excess, saturation excess,
            sub-surface stormflow and impervious area runoff. Typically, only a small proportion of
            rainfall will become streamflow with the rest being evaporated perhaps after being
            intercepted by vegetation, stored in surface depressions or infiltrated to become soil
            moisture or groundwater. Some groundwater may contribute to floods via baseflow (refer
            to <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>). </para>
        <para>There are particular conditions that can lead to high streamflow, and flooding. A
            'wet' catchment means reduced losses so that a greater proportion of rainfall will be
            converted to runoff. A catchment could be wet up by a long period of low intensity
            rainfall, particularly when evaportranspiration is low, such as in winter. A short burst
            of high intensity rainfall can lead to flooding if there are limited opportunities for
            rain to be lost. This is particularly the case in catchments where impervious surfaces
            and piped drainage systems link runoff to streams. </para>
        <para><xref linkend="b4ch2_f_odmn5"/> summarises the physical processes that can lead to
            floods, but floods can also be considered stochastic events caused by the random
            simultaneous occurrence of unusual conditions. The stochastic nature of flooding was
            illustrated in <xref linkend="b1_ch3"/>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160630T144918+1000" comment="is this needed "?>where
            it was shown that flood peaks resulting from 1% AEP rainfalls ranged in magnitude from
            500 m<superscript>3</superscript>/s to 2000
            m<superscript>3</superscript>/s.<?oxy_comment_end?> The cause of this disparity in
            response is random variation in catchment processes, such as interception and storage,
            and other factors such as the spatial and temporal patterns of rainfall. The series of
            peak flows at a gauge are manifestations of the joint probability of these random
            processes. </para>
        <figure xml:id="b4ch2_f_odmn5">
            <title>Catchment and Runoff Generation Processes</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/4003.PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

    </section>
    <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_bp6h9">
        <title>Runoff Generation</title>
        <para>This section outlines some of the key runoff generation processes that can lead to
            floods. In particular, the following topics are addressed:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Infiltration excess runoff;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Saturation excess runoff;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Variable source areas;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Partial area runoff;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Subsurface storm flow; and</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Impervious area runoff.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>Here we are focussing on quickflow and the mechanisms that rapidly convert rainfall to
            streamflow and so cause a flood hydrograph. <xref linkend="b4ch2_s_2nv2f"/> briefly
            discusses the slower process of baseflow along with losses and flow routing (<xref
                linkend="b4ch2_f_nou74"/>). </para>
        
        <figure xml:id="b4ch2_f_nou74">
            <title>Simplified Description of the Process of Converting Rainfall to Runoff and
                Streamflow</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/4002.PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>        
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_dr7u9">
            <title>Infiltration Excess Runoff</title>
            <para>Once rainfall on a catchment reaches the soil surface, some will infiltrate into
                the soil. The infiltration rate, the rate at which water enters the soil, depends
                on: </para>
            <para><itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>the rate at which water is supplied to the soil surface; and</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>the infiltration capacity which is the maximum rate at which water can
                            enter the soil.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>If the rainfall rate (mm/hr) is greater than the infiltration
                capacity, water will pond at the soil surface; if the ground is sloping, then water
                will runoff. Runoff produced in this way is called infiltration excess overland
                flow, or Hortonian<footnote>
                    <para>Hortonian runoff is named for Robert E. Horton (1875-1945); a pioneer of
                        modern hydrology.</para>
                </footnote>overland flow. Hortonian overland flow can provide a rapid pathway for
                water to be converted from rainfall to runoff. Hortonian flow is likely to
                contribute to floods when catchment surfaces have low infiltration capacity, when
                there is intense rainfall and where there is a rapid mechanism for runoff to reach a
                stream.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_5k7dj">
            <title>Saturation Excess Runoff, Variable Source Areas and Partial Area Runoff</title>
            <para>If soil becomes saturated, from rising soil moisture or because of flow from
                up-slope, then no additional rainfall can infiltrate. Any rainfall striking the
                saturated soil surface will be converted to saturation excess runoff. These
                saturated regions of a catchment are referred to as source areas. </para>
            <para>Usually there are some areas within a catchment that are wetter than others. Areas
                along valleys and adjacent to streams may remain saturated for long periods with
                up-slope areas being dryer. Saturated areas enlarge and contract with the seasonal
                wetting and drying of a catchment. Saturated areas may expand during a storm and
                then shrink once rainfall ceases. As the amount of saturated area changes so does
                the source area contributing to runoff. </para>
            <para>The concept of partial area runoff arises because only part of a catchment may be
                saturated and this area may be the only contributor to streamflow
                    <citation>b4_c2_r10</citation>. Saturation excess runoff can contribute to
                floods when source areas are large and convert intense rainfall to runoff that flows
                directly to streams. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_7nskv">
            <title>Impervious Area Runoff</title>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160630T213631+1000" comment="bad sentence "?>
            <para>Some natural catchments may contain impervious areas, such as rocky outcrops.
                <?oxy_comment_end?>Urbanisation leads to catchments being covered with roofs, roads,
                car parks and other impervious surfaces. A large proportion of rainfall landing on
                these surfaces is converted to runoff as there are few opportunities for rainfall to
                be intercepted and lost. Consequently, urbanisation leads to a large increase in
                runoff volume, flood frequency and magnitude. The hydrologic impacts of urbanisation
                have been quantified in a wide range of studies. Urbanisation causes up to a 10-fold
                increase in peak flows of floods in the range of 1 to 4 Exceedances per Year (EY),
                with diminishing impacts on larger floods
                    <citation>b4_c2_r26,b4_c2_r1,b4_c2_r11,b4_c2_r18,b4_c2_r6,b4_c2_r12</citation>.
                Runoff in urban streams responds more rapidly compared to rural catchments
                    <citation>b4_c2_r21</citation> and flow volumes increase
                    <citation>b4_c2_r15,b4_c2_r6,b4_c2_r12</citation>. Hydrologic impacts of
                urbanisation are discussed in <xref linkend="b4ch2_s_sgovb"/> and in <xref
                    linkend="book9"/>.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_66x2t">
            <title>Subsurface Storm Flow</title>
            <para>Subsurface flows can be an important source of flood runoff in areas with steep
                slopes, conductive soils and where the soil profile becomes saturated so that water
                can move through large pores. In many forested catchments surface runoff is rare.
                Soil infiltration rates are never exceeded by rainfall and confined streams limit
                opportunities for formation of saturated source areas. Instead, given appropriate
                soil conditions, water may be rapidly transferred down-slope as subsurface flow.
                This process is enhanced where there is an impeding soil layer that leads to the
                formation of perched water tables which cause soils to saturate and become highly
                conductive <citation>b4_c2_r27</citation>. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_6acwa">
            <title>Runoff in Real Catchments</title>
            <para>Although the distinctions between the various runoff mechanisms are useful and
                important, they may not be so clear cut in real catchments where runoff may be
                produced from a variety of mechanisms which vary between and during storms. Runoff
                processes may also differ compared to what would be expected. The runoff production
                that occurs during extreme events may not just be a variation on normal behaviour
                but the result of completely different processes. For example, infiltration excess
                processes may switch on during very intense rainfall in a catchment where runoff is
                normally contributed  to by saturated source areas. In many cases, the catchment
                area can change if water flows across a drainage divide because of blockage or
                insufficient capacity of drainage structures. These issues are discussed further in
                the case studies in <xref linkend="b4ch2_s_sgovb"/>. Blockage issues are
                specifically addressed in <xref linkend="b6_ch6"/>.</para>
        </section>
   
     
     
        
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_2nv2f">
        <title>Baseflow</title>
        <para>Streamflow is often divided into quickflow and baseflow. Quickflow is the
            characteristic rapid response of a stream to rainfall and catchment runoff while
            baseflow is contributed by slow release of stored water. Quickflow is often referred to
            as ‘direct runoff’ or as ‘surface runoff’ but, as noted above, can include subsurface
            stormflow. During floods, quickflow is of the greatest relevance but, particularly for
            modelling, baseflow must be considered where it provides a significant contribution to a
            flood hydrograph (<xref linkend="b4ch2_f_jg49k"/>). </para>
        <para>There are a range of processes that contribute to the conceptual baseflow hydrograph
            as shown in <xref linkend="b4ch2_f_jg49k"/>. The initial baseflow represents the
            contribution from previous events; then as the hydrograph rises, baseflow can be
            depleted as water enters bank storage or is removed by transmission loss. Later,
            baseflow can increase as bank storage re-enters the stream, or through other processes
            such as interflow and discharge from groundwater <citation>b4_c2_r19</citation>. </para>
        <para>Generally, quickflow will be explicitly modelled, by for example, a runoff-routing
            model, and then baseflow must be added to produce a flood hydrograph and unbiased
            estimate of the peak flow. Baseflow provides a significant contribution to peak flows in
            around 70% of Australian catchments (refer to <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>).</para>
        <para>
            <figure xml:id="b4ch2_f_jg49k">
                <title>Observed Hydrograph - Sum of the Baseflow Hydrograph and the
                    Quickflow</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/4001.PNG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_n5abk">
        <title>Losses</title>
        <para>In flood hydrology, losses refer to any rainfall that is not converted to quickflow.
            The amount of loss is subtracted from storm rainfall to leave the “rainfall excess”,
            that is, quickflow is produced by the rainfall excess on the catchment. Some of the
            water accounted for in losses is evaporated, perhaps after being intercepted by
            vegetation or held in surface depressions. Some losses are infiltrated rainfall that may
            contribute baseflow to the stream.</para>
        <para>Losses can be estimated for historic events. Where there are measurements of the
            volume of runoff, catchment area and rainfall depth, losses can be calculated as the
            difference between the volume of rainfall and the volume of the quickflow hydrograph
            (the flood hydrograph with the baseflow removed). This approach was used to estimate
            losses for a range of catchments as discussed in <xref linkend="book5"/> and in earlier
            work on losses e.g. <citation>b4_c2_r16+1,b4_c2_r7+1,b4_c2_r20+1</citation>. </para>
        <para>Losses must also be predicted as part of flood forecasting and design values for
            losses are required as part of design flood estimation. A variety of loss models have
            been developed as discussed in <xref linkend="b4ch2_s_9vhzi"/> and in <xref
                linkend="b5_ch5_s_8u8o4"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_th1tf">
        <title>Flow Routing</title>
        <para>During a flood, rainfall is converted to runoff and is transferred through a network
            of flow paths to the catchment outlet. These flow paths include overland flow on hill
            slopes, down tributaries, across floodplains, through natural and artificial storages
            and along main streams. Flow routing is the mathematical description of flow processes
            that model the attenuation and translation of hydrographs as water moves through this
            network. A variety of flood routing approaches are described in <xref linkend="book5"
            />.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_au5mo">
        <title>Conceptualising Processes in Models</title>
        <para>The physical processes related to losses, runoff production, baseflow and routing need
            to be conceptualised and made mathematically explicit if they are to be used in
            modelling. This conceptualisation can vary in complexity as a function of the scales
            used for space and time and the representation of the underlying physics
                <citation>b4_c2_r14,b4_c2_r25,b4_c3_r1,b4_c2_r31,b4_c2_r32,b4_c2_r34,b4_c2_r35</citation>. </para>
        <para>In general, the choice of model should depend on the amount of data that is available
                (<xref linkend="b4ch2_f_knr8c"/>). Models that are too simple are not able to
            exploit the available data, while models that are too complex may suffer from ‘over
            fitting’ and have poor predictive ability. The enduring popularity of reasonably simple
            hydrologic
            models,<?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160701T114922+1000" comment="?"?>
            such as RORB<?oxy_comment_end?>, is because they have been found to be of a complexity
            that matches the reasonably limited data that is available for most catchments. </para>
        <para>This section briefly reviews the conceptualisation of hydrologic processes leading to
            floods and refers to other sections where more detail is available.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b4ch2_f_knr8c">
            <title>Conceptual Relationship between Data Availability, Model Complexity and
                Predictive Performance <citation>b4_c2_r13</citation></title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/4005.PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_yicyj">
            <title>Runoff Production</title>
            <para>Models of runoff production usually require rainfall as an input, which is then
                allocated to surface runoff and possibly infiltration and evaporation. Rigorous
                approaches to modelling infiltration are available such as those based on the
                Richards Equation or the Green and Ampt approach
                    <citation>b4_c2_r22,b4_c2_r8</citation>. Evaporation can be modelled as a
                function of meteorological drivers, soil properties and moisture content (Soil
                Vegetation Atmosphere Transfer (SVAT) models) <citation>b4_c2_r9</citation>.</para>
            <para>For flood modelling the physics of infiltration or evaporation, are seldom
                modelled explicitly, instead design or observed rainfall is converted to ‘rainfall
                excess’ by subtracting losses ie. the portion of rainfall that does not become
                direct runoff. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_9vhzi">
            <title>Losses</title>
            <para>The loss models used in flood modelling are often simple, based on two parameters,
                one to characterise the Initial Loss (IL) (the water required to wet up the
                catchment) and one to characterise the Continuing Loss (CL). The output of these
                models is the rainfall excess that is then used to generate a direct flow
                hydrograph. Loss models can be standalone, ie. the rainfall excess can be calculated
                separately, or integrated within acatchment modelling system. </para>
            <para>The current recommendation in ARR (<xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_8u8o4"/>) is that the
                IL/CL model is the most suitable for design flood estimation for both rural and
                urban catchments. This model uses a constant value of initial loss and constant
                value of continuing loss for a flood event. </para>
            <para>For urban catchments, ARR (<xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_3w0mq"/>) provides IL and CL
                values for three hydrologically distinct surfaces:</para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Effective Impervious Areas (impervious areas that are connected to
                            streams by hydraulically efficient drainage); </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Pervious Areas - recommended loss values are the same as those for
                            rural areas; and </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Indirectly Connected Areas (a combination of indirectly connected
                            impervious and pervious areas). Recommended loss values are between
                            those recommended for pervious and effective impervious areas. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>Where losses must be estimated for flood forecasting, continuous simulation or
                other design problems, more complex loss model may be appropriate. Potential
                candidate models are discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_s_8u8o4"/>.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_jghc6">
            <title>Baseflow</title>
            <para>For flood modelling, important aspects of baseflow that must be addressed
                are:</para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The removal of baseflow from measured hydrographs of historic flood events
                        so that the quickflow hydrograph can be determined; and </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The addition of a baseflow hydrograph to modelled direct flow so the total
                        flood hydrograph, and particularly flood peak, can be correctly
                        estimated.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            <para>Features of the baseflow hydrograph and the key processes are discussed in <xref
                    linkend="b5_ch4"/>. </para>
            <para>When determining a design baseflow hydrograph, of particular relevance is the
                baseflow under the hydrograph peak as this provides a direct contribution to the
                maximum flood flow for an event. Procedures to estimate baseflow characteristics for
                design flood estimation are provided in <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_wwln6">
            <title>Routing</title>
            <para>The purpose of flow routing in models is to provide a calculated estimate of the
                hydrograph at the downstream end of a reach given a hydrograph at the upstream end.
                This section briefly reviews catchment processes that are represented by routing
                methods in flood models. For further information on these methods, see <xref
                    linkend="b5_ch3"/>. </para>
            <para>At any point in a stream, at a particular time during a flood event, the water
                flowing past will be contributed by a variety of pathways and processes that all
                come together to make up the flow at that instant. If we traced each drop of water
                within the flow, all would have originated as rainfall but have been on a variety of
                journeys through the catchment and travelled at different speeds: one drop of
                streamflow may have started as rainfall on the water surface a short distance
                upstream, another may have come from rain falling on saturated soil beside the river
                bank; yet another may have originated from a previous storm event and travelled to
                the stream via groundwater.</para>
            <para>Streamflow derived from rainfall, passes through various storages. Groundwater
                represents long-term storage. There is also temporary storage, lasting as long as a
                flood event, consisting of water in transit in each element of the drainage system
                including water in the main stream, tributaries, hill slopes and overland flow.
                Water can be temporarily stored on floodplains and in retarding basins. There is
                also riverbank storage, water wetting up the bank profile at the start of an event
                and later flowing back into the stream as the water level drops.</para>
            <para>This process description suggests routing models would need to be highly complex
                to represent the large number of pathways, flow speeds, and storage characteristics.
                However, surprisingly, simple mathematical approaches can be used to represent the
                movement of water along the different catchment pathways. Catchment response is
                usually highly damped so that short-term fluctuations in rainfall have little
                influence on the streamflow hydrograph and individual pathways do not need to be
                explicitly modelled. Instead, the dominant effect of routing is attenuation and
                translation which can be well represented by average response over longer time
                periods. </para>
            <para>Routing of flows in a catchment may be achieved using hydrologic or hydraulic
                methods, and the various approaches to this are discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch3"
                />. The simplest representation of routing in models is hydrologic routing which
                combines continuity with a relationship between storage and flow. With this
                approach, flow paths in a catchment are divided into a series of elements, where the
                volume of storage at any time is related to the discharge in each element.
                Differences between rural and urban streams may be represented by parameters which
                control the amount of water that is stored temporarily for a given flow rate.
                Hydrologic routing methods cannot easily accommodate backwater effects, and thus
                they are not well suited to situations which are influenced by tides and storm
                surges, or reaches in which waves propagate upstream due to the effects of large
                tributary inflows and waterway constrictions.</para>
            <para>Hydraulic routing provides an increase in complexity and a reduction in the
                requirements for simplifying assumptions. Unsteady modelling of flows in two
                dimensions can be undertaken by solving the depth-averaged equations that describe
                the conservation of mass and momentum. These two dimesnaional (2D) models are
                described in more detail in <xref linkend="b6_ch4_s_onrm9"/> along with one
                dimensional (1D) unsteady models and coupled 1D/2D approaches. The limitations and
                appropriate use of these procedures, and others, are described in detail in <xref
                    linkend="book6"/>.</para>
            <para>It is possible to combine hydrologic and hydraulic routing. Hydrologic models have
                a short run time which facilitates the use of Monte Carlo approaches while hydraulic
                models are better able to represent complex routing situations. If a hydraulic model
                can be used to establish a storage discharge relationship, then this can be included
                in the hydrologic model which can then be run multiple times as part of an ensemble
                or Monte Carlo analysis. The use of 1D hydraulic models with short run time coupled
                with hydrologic models for Monte Carlo modelling is also possible.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_pfupn">
            <title>Spatial Representation of Hydrological Processes</title>
            <para>The sections above have outlined the conceptual representation of flood processes
                in models. Another key issue is how processes are represented spatially. In order of
                increasing complexity, models may be described as being lumped, semi-distributed, or
                distributed (<xref linkend="b4ch2_f_lsm3n"/>).</para>
            <para> </para>
            <para>Lumped models (left panel of <xref linkend="b4ch2_f_lsm3n"/>) treat a drainage
                area as a single unit and use catchment averaged values of inputs and parameters.
                For example, spatially averaged rainfall is used as the main driver with single
                average values for initial and continuing loss. Simple routing approaches are used
                perhaps based on the passage of a hydrograph through a single storage or separate
                storages for surface water and groundwater. Lumped models are less common in design
                flood estimation or flood forecasting.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b4ch2_f_lsm3n">
                <title>Spatial Representation of Physical Processes in Hydrologic Models</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/4004.PNG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Semi-distributed models (middle panel of <xref linkend="b4ch2_f_lsm3n"/>) consider
                catchments as a number of reasonably large sub-areas. The spatial distribution of
                catchment rainfall is represented by the rainfall depth on each sub-catchment and
                losses and routing parameters can vary by sub-area. This approach is commonly used
                in design flood estimation to represents areal variations in rainfall and losses,
                and the effects of varying flow distance to the catchment outlet. Semi-distributed
                approaches can be used to create groups of hydrologic processes that are modelled in
                a consistent way. For example, the routing of flow down hill slopes can be modelled
                separately from flow routing in channels. Model setup then requires the explicit
                identification of hill slopes and channels that are to be modelled. The modelling
                equations, inputs and parameters for these areas must be provided. This group of
                models is discussed in detail in <xref linkend="b5_ch6_s_do8jr"/>.</para>
            <para>Distributed models (right panel of <xref linkend="b4ch2_f_lsm3n"/>) use a more
                spatially explicit approach, usually based on a grid that may be of a consistent
                size and shape across a study area or may be varied adaptively. Distributed models
                require inputs and parameters for each grid cell; the advantage is that results can
                then be produced for each grid cell. For example, two dimensional unsteady hydraulic
                routing approaches are commonly applied to grids to create spatially detailed
                information on flow depths, velocities and flood hazard in rural and urban areas. </para>
            <para>Current approaches to design flood modelling are commonly based on a
                semi-distributed hydrologic model of an upper catchment area providing inputs to a
                distributed hydraulic model that generates outputs suitable for spatial flood
                mapping. The hydrologic model uses a semi-distributed approach to deal with losses
                and runoff generation. Hydrologic routing is used for flow down hill slopes and the
                upper reaches of the stream channel system. Hydraulic routing characterises flow
                both within channels and overbank areas where detailed information on depths and
                extents are required. </para>
            <para>An alternative to combining a semi-distributed hydrologic model with a distributed
                hydraulic model is ‘direct rainfall’ or ‘rainfall on grid’ models. These types of
                models use a distributed approach to both hydrology and hydraulics by gridding an
                entire catchment and simulating the runoff-routing process for each grid cell. Rain
                falling on a grid cell is converted to runoff, after allowing for losses, and this
                is added to any existing flow and hydraulically routed downstream using an unsteady
                2D approach. Some information on these models is provided in <xref
                    linkend="b6_ch4_s_9f1m8"/> with additional detail. </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_sgovb">
        <title>Examples </title>
        <para>Three case studies are provided that outline flood runoff processes in:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>A tropical catchment (South Creek, North Queensland);</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A temperate catchment (Tarrawarra, Victoria); and</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Urban areas.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_rr81s">
            <title>South Creek -  North Queensland</title>
            <para>The South Creek catchment provides a surprising example of flood runoff processes
                in a tropical environment with steep slopes and soils with high infiltration
                capacity. South Creek is 6 km east of Babinda, between Townsville and Cairns in
                north-east Queensland (17.35S, 145.98E) and has been well studied to determine key
                hydrological processes. The climate is tropical with high average annual rainfall
                compared to other regions of Australia. Cyclones produce rainfall intensities
                amongst the highest in Australia and daily rainfalls in excess of 250 mm have been
                reported. The catchment area is 25.7 ha with steep slopes (mean catchment slope
                34%). The average saturated hydraulic conductivity of the surface soils is very
                high, mean value 1350 mm/hour which is higher than the rainfall intensity during the
                most extreme storms (the 1% Annual Exceedance Probability, 5 minute rainfall
                intensity is about 300 mm/hr). Saturated hydraulic conductivity decreases rapidly
                with depth to about 13 mm/hr below 0.2 m <citation>b4_c2_r4</citation>. </para>
            <para>At the time the South Creek catchment was instrumented, it was expected that there
                would be little or no overland flow. The steep, well drained and permeable slopes,
                along with high annual rainfall (> 4000 mm), and restricted layer at shallow depth,
                was expected to result in the upper layers of the soil profile becoming saturated,
                suggesting ideal conditions for lateral subsurface stormflow. However, this was
                found not to be the case.</para>
            <para>Measurements showed that overland flow was the dominant runoff process. For
                example, during storms in January and March 1976, over 90% of runoff was produced by
                overland flow. Although rain infiltrated into the soils, the restricting layer at
                200 mm depth led to a perched water table and caused saturation at the surface.
                Exfiltration and further rainfall landing on saturated areas, which covered most of
                the catchment, led to overland flow <citation>b4_c2_r3</citation>.</para>
            <para>The dominance of overland flow has implications for modelling of South Creek and
                similar catchments. The routing approach must be suitable for rapid flow down steep
                slopes that results in short lag times between rainfall and streamflow
                    <citation>b4_c2_r4</citation>. A constant continuing loss model may be suitable
                although this would need to be tested. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_xahlw">
            <title>Tarrawarra – Southern Victoria</title>
            <para>There has been extensive collection of hydrologic data at a small catchment (10.5
                ha) at Tarrawarra 50 km ENE of Melbourne (37.66S, 145.42E), which demonstrates
                runoff processes in this agricultural environment <citation>b4_c2_r28</citation>.
                The climate is temperate with annual rainfall 820 mm and annual potential
                evaporation 830 mm. Evaporation exceeds rainfall in summer and surface soils dry out
                and crack.</para>
            <para>During dry periods, runoff has not been observed, even during summer storms with
                rainfall intensities up to 50 mm/hr. When the catchment is dry, there may be local
                areas where rainfall intensity exceeds infiltration capacity, but any runoff that is
                produced enters the soil by running down surface cracks or infiltrating further
                down-slope and never reaches the catchment outlet.</para>
            <para>Runoff only occurs after the catchment wets up, cracks close, and a zone of
                saturated soil provides a link to the catchment outlet. During wet periods, the
                soils at the bottom of swales saturate creating variable source areas that expand
                with additional rainfall. For example, during the storms of 29 and 30 July 1996
                approximately half of the rainfall was converted to runoff
                    <citation>b4_c2_r29</citation>. </para>
            <para>The runoff production processes at Tarrawarra have implications for modelling of
                this type of catchment. For runoff-routing models, spatially explicit soil moisture
                accounting will be important as the water content of soils has a strong influence on
                losses <citation>b4_c2_r29</citation>. For event models, seasonal estimates of
                losses may be necessary. A proportional loss model may be more appropriate than one
                that relies on constant continuing loss. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b4ch2_s_0hsvn">
            <title>Runoff from Urban Areas</title>
            <para>Flood runoff from urban areas is larger than from rural catchments both because of
                catchment process and because of efficient drainage.</para>
            <para>In an urban catchment, runoff is produced from impervious surfaces. On these
                surfaces: interception loss are low, because there is little vegetation; depression
                storage is small because the surfaces are smooth, and there is low infiltration.
                This means that even small amounts of rainfall will produce runoff. </para>
            <para>In the analysis of events in urban areas, a significant feature is the small
                values of initial loss. <citation>b4_c2_r5+1</citation> analysed 763 events in urban
                areas. For most of these, the initial loss was less than 1 mm. The average initial
                loss weighted by the number of events was 0.62 mm. Considering initial loss on
                individual catchments, information summarised in <xref linkend="b5_ch5_t_o0kcz"/>
                shows that 70% of catchments have an initial loss of 1 mm or less (refer also <xref
                    linkend="b5_ch5_s_gpuyp"/>).</para>
            <para>It is possible to compare the initial loss on rural and urbanised catchments. Data
                for Australian catchments is summarised in the Appendix to Book 5 (<xref
                    linkend="b5_ch5_a"/>). A density plot of this data shows the substantially lower
                initial loss for urban catchments and the concentration near 0 mm. For rural
                catchments, the mean initial loss across all catchments is 32 mm but the high
                standard deviation (16.8 mm) means the density is spread across a wide range of
                values.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Comparison of Initial Loss in Urban and Rural Catchments</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/4027.jpg"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>During larger events in urban areas, pervious surfaces also produce runoff either
                through infiltration excess or saturation excess processes. Many pervious surfaces
                in urban areas are compacted because they are walked or driven on, decreasing
                infiltration capacity and increasing the proportion of rainfall running off.</para>
            <para>Along with these catchment processes, the piped drainage system in urban areas
                efficiently delivers water to streams. Piped drainage represents an extension of the
                drainage network so that even areas distant from the original natural waterways
                contribute flow to those waterways. In highly urbanised catchments every impervious
                surface will be drained to the stream. </para>
            <para>In addition to catchment changes, the modification to urban streams also changes
                the transfer of flood flows. Modified urban streams have less attenuation,
                transmission losses are reduced and water travels more quickly. The results is a
                substantial increase in magnitude and frequency of flooding. Further details are
                provided in <xref linkend="book9"/>. </para>
            <para>Modelling urban hydrology can be challenging because of the variety of different
                surface types and variation in connections between surfaces and drains. There are
                parallel flow paths with different routing characteristics. Some water will pass
                through the piped system while some will flow overland. Water can surcharge out of
                pipes or enter pipes at various locations in the catchment. Flow behaviour, and even
                catchment area, depends on flood magnitude. Modelling approaches for urban areas are
                discussed in <xref linkend="book9"/>.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
        <xi:fallback>
            <para>No included references yet...</para>
        </xi:fallback>
    </xi:include>
</chapter>
