<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b7_ch1" version='5.0' xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
       xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
       xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
       xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
       status="In Preparation">
       
       <info>
              <title>Introduction</title>
                          
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>
              
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>
              
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/testoni_isabelle.xml"/>
       </info>
       
       
       <informaltable border="1">
              <tr>
                     <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Date last updated</td>
                     <td>24/4/2018 </td>
              </tr>
       </informaltable>
       <section>
              <title>Scope and Intent</title>
              <para>Catchment modelling has become the dominant flood estimation technique. This is
                     because it: </para>
              <itemizedlist>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Allows different options to be simulated.</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Can be used with no data, limited data and in data rich
                                   situations</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Can be used to transfer estimations from one location to
                                   another</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Default parameters are available </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Well designed catchment modelling systems will reproduce flood
                                   behaviour over a range of floods</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>A full hydrograph produced and can be used to assess
                                   storage</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Results can be easily visualised </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Is relatively easy to set up and reliable to do</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Can be reused by others for similar problems</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Helps to document the process of how the flood estimation was
                                   carried out</para>
                     </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <para>Scope is to provide practical guidance on the application of these models. </para>
              <para>Because of the wide variety of flood estimation problems no modelling framework
                     is suitable for all problems. </para>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Application of guidelines</title>
     
       
              <para>List types of problems the book is applicable to. Urban drainage design,
                     detention basins, overland flooding, trunk drainage design, floodplain
                     management, bridges and other infrastructure.</para>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Specific Terminology</title>
              <para>Generally the same terminology is used in this book as used elsewhere other than
                     highlighting that while traditionally there has been rigid divide between
                     hydrologic and hydraulic models the separation is largely artificial. Many
                     components of a catchment model can be represented by either type of model.
                     This book aims to guide the user in the application of a catchment model
                     without predisposing which model is used to represent each of the processes. </para>
              <para>An example of this divide is that routing does not only occur in hydrologic
                     models and in this book when routing is referred to it includes routing in a
                     hydraulic model. </para>
              <para>A catchment modelling system refers a set of modelling processes or components
                     that are used together to produce estimates of flood characteristics. These
                     modelling processes can be available within a single modelling platform (such
                     as a runoff-routing model) or can be the combination of a number of modelling
                     platforms (where a runoff-routing model is used to generate inflows to a
                     hydraulic model). <xref linkend="b7_ch1_t_1"/> defines some key terminology for
                     Book 7. </para>
              <table frame="void" xml:id="b7_ch1_t_1">
                     <caption>Terminology of Book 7</caption>
                     <col width="32%"/>
                     <col width="30%"/>
                     <col width="50%"/>
                     <thead>
                            <tr>
                                   <th>Terminology</th>
                                   <th>Description</th>
                                   <th>Example</th>
                            </tr>
                     </thead>
                     <tbody>
                            <tr>
                                   <td>Modelling Process</td>
                                   <td>Representation of conceptualised physical process in
                                          simulation models</td>
                                   <td>Rainfall excess model, runoff-routing model</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                   <td>Modelling Platform</td>
                                   <td>Software implementation of the modelling process (simulation
                                          model)</td>
                                   <td>
                                          <para>Software packages such as: RORB, RAFTS  WBNM, MIKE
                                                 SHE, TuFLOW, SOBEK, HEC-RAS, Spreadsheet
                                                 software</para>
                                   </td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                   <td>Catchment Modelling System</td>
                                   <td>Combines different modelling processes and may combine
                                          platforms </td>
                                   <td>RORB to TuFLOW, or just RORB</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                   <td>Modelling Framework</td>
                                   <td>Any statistical framework that is used to derive exceedance
                                          probability of flood characteristics from simulation model
                                          results</td>
                                   <td>Ensemble or Monte Carlo framework </td>
                            </tr>
                     </tbody>
              </table>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Relationship with other sections of Australian Rainfall and Runoff</title>
              <para>This book draws together much of the advice and guidance in other books. <xref
                            linkend="book1"/> provides philosophy, <xref linkend="book2"/> provides
                     rainfall information, <xref linkend="book3"/> provides alternative estimation
                     techniques for comparison to results, <xref linkend="book4"/>, <xref
                            linkend="book5"/> and <xref linkend="book6"/> provide theory and details
                     on models discussed within this book. <xref linkend="book8"/> deals with
                     extreme flood and <xref linkend="book9"/> deals with urban applications. </para>
       </section>
</chapter>
