<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b9_ch4">
    <info><title>Stormwater Volume Management</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/roso_steve.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/vandersterren_marlene.xml"/>
    

    </info>
  <para>With contributions from John Argue, Brett Phillips and Urban Book Editor Peter
    Coombes</para>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Final</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>For Publication </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00001">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Progressing from the urban stormwater philosophy discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>,
      this<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141313+1000" content=" current"?>
      chapter provides introductory guidance on
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141321+1000" content="the "?>design of
      ‘volume management facilities’. These are discrete infrastructure measures, in various forms
      and configurations, each of which are designed to store and release runoff volumes to manage
      the changes caused by urbanisation. They are linked by conveyance infrastructure (see <xref
        linkend="b9_ch5"/>) to form an urban stormwater network. </para>
    <para>This chapter focusses on the
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141329+1000" content="concept "?>design
      phase of a volume management facility and outlines the detailed design process. Before
      applying the content in this chapter it is assumed
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141336+1000"?>that
      <?oxy_insert_end?>the general position of the facility within the catchment is already largely
      understood, and preferably informed by a catchment strategy, as discussed in <xref
        linkend="b9_ch3"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>.</para>
    <para>Stormwater storages receive runoff volumes from the catchment via upstream conveyance
      infrastructure.
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141352+1000" content="The manner in which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141352+1000"?>Management
      of<?oxy_insert_end?> these runoff volumes
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141405+1000" content="are managed"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141405+1000"?>is
      dependant<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141418+1000" content=" depends"?>
      on the practice that is adopted. The storage and release of runoff changes the characteristics
      of the runoff hydrograph and is a fundamentally important feature of all volume management
      facilities. </para>
    <para>There is considerable legacy terminology used to describe these facilities including
      detention (or retarding), retention, extended detention or slow release. These terms are a
      derivative of outlet structures and different operational strategies that change the
      behavio<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141504+1000"?>u<?oxy_insert_end?>r
      of stormwater storages. </para>
    <para>Stormwater storages designed in accordance with ‘detention’ practices include those where
      runoff is temporarily stored and simultaneously released via an outlet structure (see <xref
        linkend="b9ch4_f_00002"/>). This process typically lowers peak discharge and attenuates the
      hydrograph so that the average time of release is delayed. The storage volume and capacity of
      the outlet must be determined by catchment wide modelling to achieve target outflow peak
      discharges at the catchment outlet.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00002">
      <title>Typical hydrograph change generated by a temporary storage (without harvesting)</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9044.bmp"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>Assuming the storage basin is empty at the beginning of a storm, the potential hydrograph
      change that can occur depends on both:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>the outlet’s discharge capacity relative to the peak discharge of the
          storm<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141530+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>the size of the storage basin volume relative to the total runoff volume from the
          storm<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141532+1000"?>,
          and<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>the volume of water harvested from the storage</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>As a general rule, if the storage basin volume is large relative to the total runoff
      volume, the greater the potential hydrograph attenuation that can occur. This performance also
      depends on<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141539+1000" content=" the"?>
      outlet capacity. A small outlet capacity relative to peak inflows will tend to favour
      attenuation of small storms and large storms it will overflow early, whereas a large outlet
      capacity will tend to favour attenuation of large storms and small storms will pass through
      the facility without attenuation in storage.
      Whil<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141549+1000" content="st"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141549+1000"?>e<?oxy_insert_end?>
      the storage and outlet structure are separate physical components of a volume management
      facility, they must be designed in an integrated manner since the capacity of the storage will
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141559+1000" content="a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141559+1000"?>e<?oxy_insert_end?>ffect
      the performance and sizing of the outlet structure and vice versa. This is a critical aspect
      of the design of<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141611+1000" content=" a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141617+1000"?>
      <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141611+1000" content=" "?>volume
      management facility with detention characteristics that requires an iterative approach to
      sizing.</para>
    <para>Stormwater storages designed in accordance with ‘retention’ practices provide sufficient
      storage in the volume management facility to contain additional runoff from urban development.
      The volume of stored stormwater is then drawn down by infiltration, harvesting or slow
      release. Typical hydrographs of flows from a rural catchment and subsequent urban development
      of the catchment are presented in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_mceu"/>. Inflow and outflow
      hydrographs which apply to a volume management facility used in a typical retention
      strategy<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141639+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      are shown in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_jw4h"/>. </para>
    <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_mceu">
      <title>Rural and developed catchment hydrographs</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9095.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_jw4h">
      <title>Developed catchment with retention as compared to detention and slow drainage
        strategies</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9096.bmp"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>The hydrographs in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_mceu"/> represent runoff
      from<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141715+1000" content=" a"?> rural
      catchment and
      from<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141720+1000" content=" the"?> urban
      landscape developed on it. Ideal retention performance of the storage is reproduction of the
      rural hydrograph followed by outflow of the remaining stored runoff via slow release over a
      longer duration (typically greater than 24 hours). <citation>b9_c3_r1+1</citation> outlines
      that it is difficult to achieve this outcome and recommends a storage volume equal to the
      total additional runoff expected from the development and the emptying time of volume
      management facility is a function of outlet infrastructure.</para>
    <para>The outflow hydrograph resulting from this approach should be similar to that shown in
        <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_jw4h"/> (developed catchment with retention). A first approximation
      solution is likely to produce a different outflow hydrograph from that required
      result.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141734+1000"?> It is
      recommended to have<?oxy_insert_end?>
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141745+1000"?>c<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141744+1000" content="C"?>ontinuous
      simulation of
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141751+1000" content="the "?>volume
      management facility<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141802+1000"?>
      <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141800+1000" content=" is recommended "?>with
      the aim
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141811+1000" content="of adjusting"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141811+1000"?>to
      adjust<?oxy_insert_end?> the design i.e. storage and outflow configuration, to produce the
      desired outflow hydrograph. </para>
    <para>The concept design phase of volume management facilities commences with a thorough
      understanding
      of<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141823+1000" content=" the"?> volume
      management objectives intended for the facility (refer <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00002"/>). Once
      these objectives are defined,
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141834+1000" content="consideration can be given to the"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141834+1000"?>one
      should consider<?oxy_insert_end?> configuration of the facility and how its components might
      be sized and positioned to best meet the objectives and local site conditions (refer <xref
        linkend="b9ch4_s_00004"/> and <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00009"/>). Detailed design then follows
      to comprehensively define the facility to permit construction (refer <xref
        linkend="b9ch4_s_00017"/>).</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00002">
    <title>Volume Management Objectives</title>
    <para>The design of a volume management facility must include objectives which are relevant to
      the site, the surrounding catchment and receiving waterways. A summary of the most commonly
      encountered volume management design objectives in Australian practice is provided in <xref
        linkend="b9ch4_t_00003"/>. Each objective has ‘associated benefits’ that are also listed to
      help distinguish the relevance of each objective to a particular site and design.</para>
    <para>An adequate number of facilities are required within catchments to ensure that the
      stored<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141853+1000" content=" or"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141853+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      harvested<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141858+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      or infiltrated volumes of stormwater will significantly
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141921+1000" content="affect"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T141921+1000"?>impact<?oxy_insert_end?>
      peak discharges or volume targets at catchment outlets. A key aspect of
      the<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142025+1000" content=" "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142005+1000"?>
      storage based approaches <?oxy_insert_end?>design
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142018+1000" content="of storage based approaches"?>
      is to ensure that the storages are not full at the commencement of a flood producing rain
      event. It is essential to determine the design flood events that these facilities will manage
      (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). <table frame="void" xml:id="b9ch4_t_00003">
        <caption>Summary of Volume Management Design Objectives</caption>
        <col width="70%"/>
        <col width="30%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Objective</th>
            <th>Potential Associated Benefits</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Control Peak Discharges and Volumes</emphasis></para>
              <para>This objective seeks to limit the peak flood flows and volumes discharging from
                a catchment to a pre-determined and acceptable level. Commonly the acceptable level
                is set at the natural or ‘pre-development’ condition. In some cases the acceptable
                level may be set below the natural condition in order to achieve a net benefit or
                offset an impact elsewhere. In highly developed catchments (infill development), the
                acceptable level may correspond to flows from the original development.</para>
              <para>These objectives may seek to change the total volume of stormwater leaving a
                site (retention), or delay the volume for a short period of time (hours) (detention
                or retarding) which may reduce the peak of the flood hydrograph discharging from a
                catchment. </para>
              <para>Careful consideration of the spectrum of design flood events needs to be given
                and its impact on downstream receiving systems (for example stream forming flows and
                flood flows), which can result in ‘slow release’ systems.</para>
              <para>Emerging stormwater management practices seek to reduce the volume and timing of
                stormwater discharges from catchments. This combined approach is particularly
                relevant for managing stormwater runoff from increasing urban density (see <xref
                  linkend="b9_ch3"/>). </para>
              <para>This objective is a very commonly sought outcome. It is of most relevance to
                urban catchments where there is a constrained floodplain downstream or sensitive
                ecosystem that cannot accommodate increase in peak flood discharges or
                volumes.</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Reduced property flood damage</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Reduced personal safety risks due to flood</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Reduced infrastructure damage</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Reduced conveyance infrastructure requirements (downstream)</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Harvest or Infiltrate <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181010T154230+1100" content="R"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181010T154230+1100"?>r<?oxy_insert_end?>ain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181010T154232+1100"?>
                  <?oxy_insert_end?>water or Stormwater</emphasis></para>
              <para>This objective seeks to extract a proportion of the runoff volume from a
                catchment and either use this water for a consumptive purpose (i.e. consistent use
                to ensure draw down of storages), or infiltrate the runoff directly into local soils
                or subterranean aquifers (possibly for later extraction).</para>
              <para>These integrated design approaches can require interaction with soil properties,
                capacity of aquifers, urban form and demands of water (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"
                />). The designer should account for the elements in the design of a catchment wide
                strategy to ensure that adequate storage space is available in storages to achieve
                the objectives of the strategy. </para>
              <para>Analysis of these measures must include continuous simulation and the use of
                full volume storms to understand the required storage capacity for a given set of
                rainfall events.</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Maintain waterway stability and reduce scour</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Maintain groundwater behaviour </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Maintain hydrologic behaviour including natural runoff regimes</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Increase volume of water stored in an aquifer</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Increased availability of water for harvesting and use</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Improve Water Quality</emphasis></para>
              <para>This objective seeks to reduce concentrations and loads of contaminants within
                urban runoff to pre-determined and acceptable levels. This is achieved by by:
                delaying some of the runoff volume for a period of time (hours to days) (detention),
                or storing part of the stormwater onsite (retention) and passing the retained water
                through treatment processes where physical, chemical and biological processes reduce
                contaminants in the water column. Storage of stormwater can also provide some
                limited water quality treatment through settlement, even where this objective is not
                necessarily sought. </para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Maintain aquatic health</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Maintain visual amenity</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Improved water quality prior to discharge or prior to harvesting
                    activities</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table></para>
    <para>An early design task should examine
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142150+1000" content="the "?>relevance of
      the objectives from <xref linkend="b9ch4_t_00003"/> for a design in the context of prior
      studies, investigations, catchment strategies and receiving waterbody conditions. This process
      allows the designer to establish a preliminary understanding of the
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142209+1000"?>site
      <?oxy_insert_end?>behaviour<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142205+1000" content=" of the site"?>,
      the catchment and receiving system. Another important task is to check
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142221+1000"?>if
      <?oxy_insert_end?>local stormwater authority has specific policy requirements and standards.
      In the absence of background studies and local authority guidance, the designer should
      critically assess the relevance of
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142226+1000" content="the "?>above-listed
      objectives from first principles. The ‘associated benefits’ listed in <xref
        linkend="b9ch4_t_00003"/> may assist.</para>
    <para>Volume management initially emerged as a design consideration to control of peak
      discharges in catchments. This was driven by a need to manage flood impacts associated with
      development and an emerging understanding that the stormwater runoff behaviour of urban
      catchment is volume dependent. Nevertheless, the design process was driven by peak rainfall
      bursts rather than the full volumes of storm events. Progressively, as our understanding of
      urban impacts on waterways has broadened, standards have changed to the point where it is now
      quite common for the other volume management objectives listed in <xref
        linkend="b9ch4_t_00003"/> to also be considered. Facilities that target these multiple
      objectives have a stronger business case and are therefore more commonly sought after in
      modern practice<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142237+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142241+1000" content="and"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142241+1000"?>as
      they<?oxy_insert_end?> use the full spectrum of storms to protect the downstream receiving
      systems.</para>
    <para>If there are indeed multiple objectives sought for a design, it may be advantageous to
      design a single facility that will meet all the desired objectives. However, current
      stormwater management practice incorporates multiple solutions across scales to better manage
      risk profiles (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). The diagram in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00001"/>
      below shows how more than one design objective can be relevant to a site<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142252+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142254+1000" content="or "?>a
      catchment<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142303+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      or an entire stormwater management strategy. For example design objectives for a facility or a
      strategy may include:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>control peak discharges and harvest (or infiltrate)
            stormwater<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142314+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>control peak discharge and improve water
            quality<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142315+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improve water quality and harvest (or infiltrate)
            stormwater<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142309+1000"?>,
            and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142325+1000" content=" "?></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Control peak discharge, improve water quality and harvest (or infiltrate)
            stormwater<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142336+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142335+1000" content=" "?></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Where possible the design process should pursue performance characteristics that target
      all the desired objectives. This goal is most likely to be achieved when a particular
      management strategy is selected as the primary objective, for example peak discharge reduction
      or water quality improvement, and the subsidiary objectives are incorporated by exploiting
      opportunities made available by the primary objective. </para>
    <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00001">
      <title>Potential overlapping volume management design objectives</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9070.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00004">
    <title>Components of a Volume Management Facility</title>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00005">
      <title>Overview</title>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142400+1000" content="There are up to four generic infrastructure components that are common to the majority of volume management facilities; storage, an outlet structure and treatment media."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142400+1000"?>There
        are up to four generic infrastructure components that are common to majority of volume
        management facilities;
        <?oxy_comment_start author="rchho" timestamp="20180904T141416+1000" comment="These are only three components. ARe we missing something? "?>storage,
        an outlet structure, and treatment media<?oxy_comment_end?>.<?oxy_insert_end?> These are
        described in <xref linkend="b9ch4_t_00006"/> below. <table xml:id="b9ch4_t_00006"
          frame="void">
          <caption>Volume Management Facility Components</caption>
          <col width="33%"/>
          <col width="33%"/>
          <col width="33%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Component</th>
              <th>Purpose</th>
              <th>Examples</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Inlet Structure</emphasis></para>
                <para>A conduit or flow path that controls the inflow into the facility and connects
                  the upstream conveyance network to the storage</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>To transition flows from
                  <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142432+1000" content="the"?>
                  upstream conveyance system into the storage device in a controlled manner (see
                    <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/> for more details on conveyance system outlets).</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Headwall outlet structure with riprap</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Level spreader</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Energy dissipator</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Storage</emphasis></para>
                <para>An area of land or a storage structure that contains water after rain</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>To receive and store a pre-determined volume of water for a pre-determined
                  period of time.</para>
                <para>Partial discharge from the site and partial retention in on-site storage
                  facilities.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Small storages such as a OSD tank</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Large storages such as basins</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>‘Nested’ basins</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Roof gardens, rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142514+1000"?>
                      <?oxy_insert_end?>water tanks, bio-retention facilities, raingardens,
                      infiltration trenches, soakaways, access to aquifers </para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Outlet structure </emphasis></para>
                <para>A conduit or flowpath that connects the storage basin to downstream conveyance
                  infrastructure</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>To control water release from the storage at a pre-determined rate and direct
                  it to the appropriate location downstream</para>
                <para>To control water release from the storage to a pre-determined slow release
                  rate</para>
                <para>Control outflow from the storage to satisfy a required emptying time
                  criterion</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Pipe or box culvert through an embankment (with headwall or pit
                      entry)</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Discharge control pit</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142523+1000"?>
                      <?oxy_insert_end?>water distribution system</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Spillway across the top of an embankment</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>High overflow discharge pipe</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Aquifer infiltration zone</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Combinations of above</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Treatment processes </emphasis></para>
                <para>A physical installation located, in-line or off-line, usually within a
                  storage, upstream of a site, neighbourhood or regional discharge point. </para>
                <para>A material or process that removes water-borne contaminants from runoff as it
                  passes through the storage basin.</para>
              </td>
              <td>To reduce or remove concentrations of contaminants from runoff as it passes
                through the device towards the outlet</td>
              <td>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Sediment forebay</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Gross pollutant trap</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Aquatic plants</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Vegetated soil media</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Sand, gravel or other filtration media</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Storage processes including settlement, bio-reaction and natural
                      flocculation</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
      <para>Each of these components can be configured and combined with
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142551+1000" content="the "?>other
        components in different ways to meet different design objectives. The size, shape and
        material of each component can also be selected to respond to performance criteria and site
        constraints. Some components can be omitted depending on the
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142558+1000"?>design
        <?oxy_insert_end?>objectives<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142605+1000" content=" of the design"?>.
        For example treatment processes are only required where the design seeks to improve water
        quality or the impacts of the storage on improving water quality need to be enhanced.</para>
    </section>
    <section  xml:id="b9ch4_s_00007">
      <title>Common Configurations in Australian Practice</title>
      <para>There are a large number of
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142616+1000" content="potential "?>sizing
        and configuration options available
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142620+1000" content="to"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142620+1000"?>for<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the designer. Changes to the relative sizes of each component (from <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_t_00006"/>), along with combinations of different materials and different
        hydraulic designs can adjust the way in which an overall facility or strategy will perform
        against the volume management objectives and respond to different site constraints. </para>
      <para>The volume management facility configurations that are in common use in Australia are
        listed and described in <xref linkend="b9ch4_t_00004"/>. Further guidance on selecting a
        specific design configuration is also provided in <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00009"/> and <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_s_00017"/><table xml:id="b9ch4_t_00004" frame="void">
          <caption>Common Volume Management Facility Configurations in Australian Practice</caption>
          <col width="15%" title="Common Description"/>
          <col width="35%"/>
          <col width="35%"/>
          <col width="15%"/>
          <col/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Common Description</th>
              <th>Storage Basin</th>
              <th>Outlet Structure</th>
              <th>Treatment Processes<superscript>[a]</superscript></th>
              <th>Typical Catchment Scale<superscript>[b]</superscript></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Detention Basin (Retarding Basin)</emphasis></td>
              <td>A storage basin excavated into the ground surface and partially formed by
                embankment on downslope side. The size of storage to be determined from
                catchment-wide analysis focused on the target peak flow at the catchment outlet.
                Normally dry.</td>
              <td>
                <para>A concrete pipe or box culvert passing through the embankment at the base
                  level of the storage.</para>
                <para>A spillway at the top level of the storage to pass flow in excess of the
                  culvert capacity.</para>
              </td>
              <td>Nil</td>
              <td>
                <para>Neighbourhood</para>
                <para> </para>
                <para>Precinct</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">On-Site Detention (OSD)</emphasis></td>
              <td>A small underground tank or surface depression. Normally dry. </td>
              <td>
                <para>A small pipe at the base level of the storage with an orifice to reduce outlet
                  flow rates</para>
                <para>A small weir at the top of the storage to pass flow in excess of orifice
                  capacity. (<xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00005"/> and <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00006"
                  />)</para>
              </td>
              <td>Nil</td>
              <td>
                <para>Lot</para>
                <para> </para>
                <para>Site</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142633+1000"?>
                  <?oxy_insert_end?>water Harvesting</emphasis></td>
              <td>Surface or underground storages capturing runoff from roof surfaces and consumed
                for indoor and outdoor purposes. The storage has a permanent storage volume and may
                have an air space above the permanent storage for stormwater detention.</td>
              <td>
                <para>Constant water usage (such as indoor demands) draws down storage volumes prior
                  to rain events. A small pipe may link to the downstream stormwater network at the
                  top level of the permanent storage.</para>
                <para>A second pipe at the top level of the air space caters for high level
                  overflows (<xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00007"/>).</para>
              </td>
              <td>Volume reduction processes reduce erosion of streams and reduces transport of
                urban pollutants.</td>
              <td>
                <para>Lot</para>
                <para>Site</para>
                <para>Neighbourhood</para>
                <para>Precinct</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Bioretention Basin</emphasis></td>
              <td>
                <para>A storage basin excavated into the ground surface and partially formed by
                  embankment on downslope side. </para>
                <para>Shallow storage over filter media. Experiences a cycle of wetting and
                  drying.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>A network of sub-soil drainage at the bottom of the filter media.</para>
                <para>Outlet pit and pipe culvert for flows that exceed the permeability of the
                  filter.</para>
                <para>A spillway at the top level of the storage to pass flow in excess of the
                  culvert capacity (<xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00008"/>).</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Sandy loam filter media with high permeability and suitable vegetation.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Site</para>
                <para> </para>
                <para>Neighbourhood</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Constructed Wetland</emphasis></td>
              <td>
                <para>A storage basin excavated into the ground surface and partially formed by
                  embankment on downslope side. </para>
                <para>Normally wet with bathymetry designed to support healthy range of aquatic
                  plants. Ephemeral wetlands are subject to a cycle of wetting and drying that
                  replicate natural processes.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Outlet pit and pipe culvert.</para>
                <para>High flow bypass (directs high flows away from wetland area)</para>
                <para>A spillway at the top level of the storage to pass flow in excess of the
                  culvert capacity (<xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00009"/>).</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Aquatic plants growing in a suitable soil substrate.</para>
              </td>
              <td>Precinct</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Managed Aquifer Recharge</emphasis></td>
              <td>An infiltration zone, in the floor of a basin, with good permeable connectivity to
                the groundwater system or a gravel filled soakaway with aquifer access via a bore
                pipe.</td>
              <td>
                <para>A permeable soil layer in the floor of the basin with connectivity to an
                  aquifer</para>
                <para>A spillway at the top level of the basin to pass flow in excess of the
                  permeable layer (<xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00010"/>).</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Removal of stormwater volumes decreases erosion of streams and reduces
                  transport of urban pollutants.</para>
                <para>Normally requires pre-treatment.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Neighbourhood</para>
                <para> </para>
                <para>Precinct</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Infiltration System</emphasis></td>
              <td>
                <para>An infiltration zone, in the floor of a drainage pit, swale, basin, trench or
                  pavement with good permeable connectivity to the groundwater system.</para>
                <para>Overflow from a rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142650+1000"?>
                  <?oxy_insert_end?>water tank passed into bio-retention, raingarden, gravel filled
                  trench or soakaway, normally dry, or directly to a local aquifer</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>A porous floor in the base of the structure with connectivity to deeper
                  sub-soils.</para>
                <para>A spillway, pipe or channel at the top level of the structure to pass flow in
                  excess of the permeable layer (<xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00011"/> and <xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_f_00012"/>).</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Removed contaminants and volumes of stormwater from flows. This further
                  reduces transport of pollutants.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Lot</para>
                <para>Site</para>
                <para>Neighbourhood</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Stormwater Harvest Pond</emphasis></td>
              <td>A large storage pond formed by excavation into the ground surface and possibly
                formed by embankment on downslope side. </td>
              <td>
                <para>A pump system to extract water for use.</para>
                <para>A spillway at the top level of the pond to pass flow in excess of
                  demand.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Reduce runoff volumes diminishes erosion of streams and reduces transport of
                  urban pollutants.</para>
                <para>Normally requires pre-treatment.</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Neighbourhood</para>
                <para> </para>
                <para>Precinct</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">[a] Note those devices without treatment processes may still
          provide water treatment benefits due to the effects of temporary storage and/or harvesting
          of runoff.</emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">[b] Scale definitions taken from <xref linkend="b9_ch6"
          /></emphasis>.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00009">
    <title>Concept Design</title>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00010">
      <title>Overview</title>
      <para>Concept design is an important phase in the overall infrastructure delivery process. It
        provides early insight into the likely physical characteristics of a facility, and allows
        design integration with other nearby infrastructure.
        Including<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142719+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142728+1000" content=" for example,"?>
        stormwater conveyance infrastructure, open space, roads and buildings. If an approval is
        required, then the concept design will form part of the evidence needed for a submission. A
        concept design will also be needed to establish a financial budget.</para>
      <para>The following sub-sections outlines the concept design phase of a typical volume
        management facility. Four concept design tasks are described:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Choosing the best location for the facility (<xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00011"/>)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Choosing the best design solution, having regard to the design objectives and site
            variables (<xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00012"/>)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Preliminary sizing and configuration (<xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00013"/>)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Collaboration and integration with other relevant professional disciplines (<xref
              linkend="b9ch4_s_00014"/>)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142814+1000" content="While these tasks are presented in this sequence, the tasks should not necessarily be completed in this sequence nor in a linear fashion. There"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142814+1000"?>It
        is not necessary to complete these tasks in any linear fashion. There<?oxy_insert_end?> is
        often a need for iteration and concurrent completion of design tasks. For
        example<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142830+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        collaboration
        and<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142838+1000" content=" a"?> preliminary
        sizing may be required to inform the selection of a preferred location. Once the preferred
        location is determined, the preliminary sizing must be updated.</para>
      <para>Concept design can only
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142914+1000"?>begin after
        finalising<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142912+1000" content="commence once"?>
        an overall catchment
        strategy<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142941+1000" content=" has been established"?>
        (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>) and design objectives
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T142949+1000" content="determined "?>(see
          <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00002"/>). These foundational design aspects are assumed to have
        been resolved prior to implementing the following guidance. In particular a decision must be
        made as to the general position of the facility or strategy within the catchment. For
        example, it should be decided prior to commencing concept design whether the facility will
        be constructed to service a catchment comprising a single lot, a
        neighbourhood<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143002+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        or<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143017+1000" content=" an"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143017+1000"?>
        a large<?oxy_insert_end?> urban
        precinct<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143029+1000" content=" that is large in scale"?>.
        With this overall constraint in mind, the following concept design tasks should be
        considered. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00011">
      <title>Choose a Location</title>
      <para>The site chosen for a volume management facility is important to the success of the
        design. The site will have associated site variables, such as topography, soil types,
        catchment characteristics and groundwater characteristics. In some circumstances, the design
        may need to trade off some capabilities or require special features to completely respond to
        these site variables, and avoid
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143043+1000" content="constructability"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143043+1000"?>constructibility<?oxy_insert_end?>
        and long-term performance issues. </para>
      <para>Where there is flexibility, it is best to choose a site that presents the smallest
        design challenge and meets the objectives for the project. The following discussion is
        intended to assist in this regard.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Topography</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>Volume management facilities may be located on or adjacent to the lowest point in the
        catchment to be serviced. This maximises the catchment area to be managed. Similarly the
        location may also need to capture flows from upstream conveyance infrastructure. If the site
        cannot easily service the relevant upstream sub-catchment then performance against the
        design objectives may be compromised.</para>
      <para>Whil<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143100+1000" content="st"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143100+1000"?>e<?oxy_insert_end?>
        catchment hydrology (see <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/>) is an integral part of the design
        process, even before such calculations are undertaken, the concept design should be informed
        by a general appreciation of the catchment draining to the proposed facility. As a minimum,
        the size of the catchment area draining to the facility needs to be determined so that
        preliminary sizing can be undertaken.</para>
      <para>The location chosen may need to be adequately elevated (or able to be raised using an
        embankment), so that hydraulic performance of the outlet structure is not adversely
        influenced by backwater. This is a particular consideration for facilities that have
        treatment processes and vegetation or where the storage is intended to be well drained. </para>
      <para>Areas in low-lying coastal districts
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143207+1000" content="must"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143207+1000"?>should<?oxy_insert_end?>
        also consider the effects of high-tide and possible
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143219+1000" content="future"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143219+1000"?>tide
        level<?oxy_insert_end?>
        changes<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143233+1000" content=" to the tide level"?>
        due to sea-level rise (see <xref linkend="b4_ch4"/> and <xref linkend="b6_ch5"/>). Frequent
        backwater flooding from regional flood events should also be avoided, unless its impact can
        be assessed and proven acceptable.</para>
      <para>The average ground slope
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143259+1000" content="in the location chosen "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143259+1000"?>of
        the preferred location <?oxy_insert_end?>should ideally be no steeper than 5%. Steeper sites
        are not precluded, however they will require more careful consideration of the type and
        shape of storage to avoid excessive earthworks. It may also
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143406+1000" content="introduce the need for"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143406+1000"?>require<?oxy_insert_end?>
        vertical retaining wall
        elements<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143415+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        which may
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143426+1000" content="be undesirable if they "?>hamper
        access, introduce safety risks, increase
        maintenance<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143452+1000"?>
        requirement,<?oxy_insert_end?> and increase longer-term facility replacement and renewal
        costs.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Soils</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143527+1000" content="Ideally the soils in the chosen location will be suitable for construction and sufficiently deep to avoid excavation into rock."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143527+1000"?>Ideally,
        the soil at the preferred location will be suitable for construction and sufficiently deep
        to avoid excavation into rock.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143539+1000" content="Where an embankment is to be formed,"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143539+1000"?>Where
        an embankment is required,<?oxy_insert_end?> the soil properties should allow tight
        compaction in layers to form a cohesive matrix and stable slope within the range of 1 in 2
        to 1 in 10. </para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143629+1000" content="The soils used to construct any embankments or spillways should also have a very low permeability, particularly where significant volumes of water are to be stored or where long-term water storage is intended. If the soil type is not suitable then other soil materials will need to be imported for blending or replacement, or other materials considered such as clay liners."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143629+1000"?>The
        soils used to construct any embankments or spillways should also have very low permeability,
        particularly where significant volumes of water is stored or where long-term water storage
        is intended. If the soil type is not suitable then other soil materials will need to be
        imported for blending or replacement. This may also require considering other materials such
        as clay liners.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para>Sites with dispersive and acid sulphate soils will require a careful selection of
        storage solution. If unavoidable, then the design must include appropriate management
        measures.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Groundwater
          Characteristics</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143640+1000" content="Where stormwater infiltration is one of the overall design objectives, the site selected must be underlain by geologic strata that allow this infiltration to occur. Long-term groundwater behaviour in the vicinity should also be profiled, and a site selected where the elevation of the infiltration zone is not substantially below normal groundwater levels."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143640+1000"?>Where
        stormwater infiltration is one of the overall design objectives, the site selected must be
        underlain by geologic strata that allows infiltration. Long-term groundwater behaviour in
        the vicinity should also be profiled, along with ensuring that the selected site for
        elevation of the infiltration zone is not substantially below normal groundwater
        levels.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143650+1000" content="If infiltration is not required or desired, then a site should be chosen where the groundwater profile is unlikely to intersect the storage profile. This will simplify construction and ensure the storage can be more easily drained."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143650+1000"?>If
        infiltration is not required or desired, then ensure that the groundwater profile of the
        selected site is unlikely to intersect with storage profile. This will simplify construction
        and ensure the storage can be more easily drained.<?oxy_insert_end?>
      </para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143705+1000" content="The stream baseflow, flow regimes and water quality characteristics will also be relevant where water quality improvement or stormwater harvesting or infiltration objectives are targeted."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143705+1000"?>The
        stream baseflow, flow regimes, and water quality characteristics will also be relevant when
        targetting water quality improvement, stormwater harvesting, or infiltration
        objectives.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para>The quality of the groundwater store should also be investigated and water quality
        criteria for infiltration will need to be observed in accordance with local guidelines and
        ANZECC.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Vegetation</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143745+1000" content="The selected site should not require the damage or removal of valuable trees or large stands of native vegetation. If it is determined that this cannot be avoided then special approvals may be required and a flora and fauna specialist should be engaged to assist to provide advise the design team. An environmental offset planting may be necessary."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143745+1000"?>The
        preferred site should not require the damage or removal of valuable trees or large stands of
        native vegetation. If this cannot be avoided then special approvals may be required and a
        flora and fauna specialist should assist the design team for expert advise. An environmental
        offset planting may also be required.<?oxy_insert_end?>
      </para>
      <para>If the facility is intended to be vegetated then an appropriate depth and quality of
        surface soil is required to support healthy plant growth.</para>
    </section>
    <section  xml:id="b9ch4_s_00012">
      <title>Choose a Design Solution</title>
      <para>A design solution should be selected that best targets the established objectives and
        provides
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143809+1000" content="an "?>optimum
        response to the constraints and variables of the site. A listing of common design solutions
        is provided in <xref linkend="b9ch4_t_00010"/>. </para>
      <para>This is a basic
        guide<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143819+1000" content=" aimed"?> to
        provide an indicative starting point for the inexperienced urban stormwater designer and
        should not be interpreted as a barrier to innovative strategies or a replacement for first
        principles analysis. Those with experience will
        recogni<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143831+1000" content="z"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143833+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>e
        opportunities for hybrid solutions that have broader application. For
        example<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143842+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        a hybrid facility involving
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143846+1000" content="a "?>detention
        (retarding) basin with managed aquifer recharge (retention) and stormwater harvesting
        (retention) may provide a more comprehensive design solution
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143916+1000" content="to a volume management problem and for protection of urban waterways."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143916+1000"?>to
        the volume management problem and protection of urban waterways.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para>It is noted that in <xref linkend="b9ch4_t_00010"/> there are several solution and
        objective combinations that are flagged as “suitable with limitations”. This means that the
        solution may not always perform well with respect to the relevant objective, however it can
        in some circumstances. For example, a particular managed aquifer recharge facility may not
        normally provide control of peak discharge in large floods when the water levels in the
        aquifer are high. However, it may still afford some benefits in small floods and greater
        benefits if aquifer levels are low. Some further information about these possible
        limitations is provided in <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00017"/>. <table xml:id="b9ch4_t_00010"
          frame="void">
          <caption>Indicative Suitability of Common Volume Management Design Solutions</caption>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Solution</th>
              <th>Control Peak Discharge</th>
              <th>Improve Water Quality</th>
              <th>Harvest or Infiltrate Stormwater</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Detention (Retarding) Basin</emphasis> (see <xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_s_00018"/>)</para>
              </td>
              <td> Suitable<?oxy_cell_end?></td>
              <td>Not suitable</td>
              <td>Not suitable</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">On-Site Detention (OSD) </emphasis>(see s<xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_s_00019"/>)</para>
              </td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
              <td>Not suitable</td>
              <td>Not suitable</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143935+1000"?>
                    <?oxy_insert_end?>water Harvesting</emphasis> (see <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00020"
                  />)</para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para>Suitable with limitations </para>
              </td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Bioretention Basin</emphasis> (see <xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_s_00021"/>)</para>
              </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Constructed Wetland</emphasis> (see <xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_s_00022"/>)</para>
              </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Managed Aquifer Recharge</emphasis> (see <xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_s_00023"/>)</para>
              </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Infiltration System</emphasis> (see <xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_s_00024"/>)</para>
              </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Stormwater Harvest Pond</emphasis> (see <xref
                    linkend="b9ch4_s_00025"/>)</para>
              </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable with limitations </td>
              <td>Suitable</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00013">
      <title>Preliminary Sizing and Configuration</title>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143949+1000" content="The approximate physical footprint of the structure must be understood to confirm the availability of sufficient space at the site. Where the surrounding infrastructure has yet to be planned, space requirements can be communicated early to other members of the urban design team."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T143949+1000"?>Understanding
        the structure's approximate physical footprint is important to ensure suffecient space is
        available at the site. Where the surrounding infrastructure is under planning, space
        requirements can be communicated early to other members of the urban design
        team.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144000+1000" content="The size of the structure is the first aspect to investigate. Ultimately the size of the structure is determined by detailed calculation and modelling, however in the very early stages of planning it may be possible to use simple hand calculations and ‘rules of thumb’."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144000+1000"?>The
        size of the structure is the first aspect to investigate. Ultimately, the structure size is
        determined by detailed calculation and modelling, however, during the early stages of
        planning, it may be possible to use simple hand calculations and ‘rules of
        thumb’.<?oxy_insert_end?>
      </para>
      <para>Preliminary sizing will depend on local rainfall conditions, climate patterns and
        performance criteria. A value is often selected based on prior experience with the design of
        other nearby facilities.
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144014+1000" content="For example, in the case of an infilttration measure"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144014+1000"?>For
        example, in case of an infiltration measure<?oxy_insert_end?>, the estimated surface area
        can then be combined with length and width limitations to estimate the total requirement for
        land area at a preliminary level of accuracy.</para>
      <para>The shape of the facility must then be considered. The shape of the facility will be
        largely governed by a combination of factors including:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Minimising and balancing earthworks – to suit the site topography and drainage and
            minimise the volume of earthworks relative to the volume of runoff stored. At the same
            time have regard to the design of adjoining infrastructure such as stormwater
            conveyance, roads and buildings.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Visual and landscape objectives – there may be visual and landscape objectives
            sought for the facility that might influence overall shape of the facility.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Maintenance and safety objectives – Suitable allowance should be made for
            maintenance access and safe batter slopes.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Achieving suitable length to width ratios – where the facility targets water quality
            improvement the length to width ratio must sit within a suitable range, typically
            between 3:1 and 10:1.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>While determining the preliminary shape of the structure, consideration should also be
        given to the need for any vertical wall elements, the location of outlet structures and the
        position and alignment of any embankments.</para>
    </section>
    <section  xml:id="b9ch4_s_00014">
      <title>Collaboration and Integration</title>
      <para>The design of a volume management facility is a task best undertaken in close
        collaboration with the client representative, relevant stakeholders and the overall urban
        design team including:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Urban Designers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Local authorities including Councils and government departments</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Civil Engineers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Landscape Architects</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Environmental Engineers, Geomorphologists and Ecologists</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Geotechnical Engineers </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>This collaboration should
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144039+1000" content="occur"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144039+1000"?>be
        considered<?oxy_insert_end?> early in the design process to minimise re-work and maximise
        the potential for integrated outcomes. For example good opportunities exist for co-location
        of volume management facilities within areas that also perform recreation, landscape and
        environmental functions.</para>
      <para>Since the position of volume management facilities is often tightly controlled by site
        topography and hydraulic constraints, it is also important that the design is undertaken in
        conjunction with the overall bulk earthworks and stormwater conveyance solution to yield an
        overall efficient and low cost design. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00015">
      <title>Emergence of Volume Management Research</title>
      <para>The use of volume management measures distributed throughout urban areas to assist in
        the management of peak discharges at the outlets of catchments has been the topic of
        emerging research and practical investigations since the 1990s by an increasing number of
        authors and practitioners (for example: <citation>b9_c4_r129+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r101+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r102+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r103+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r104+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r94+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r117+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r116+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r118+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r162+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r138+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r139+1</citation>).
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144134+1000" type="split"?></para>
      <para><?oxy_insert_end?>More recently, investigations
        have<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144142+1000" content=" also"?> focused
        on understanding the performance of entire linked systems of water cycle management within
        urban catchments
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144153+1000" content="which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144153+1000"?>that<?oxy_insert_end?>
        can reveal the cumulative impacts of integrated or combined strategies that better represent
        real systems <citation>b9_c4_r119, b9_c3_r9, b9_c2_r61, b9_c4_r173</citation>. These issues
        are discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>. This body of research and practice has evolved
        since the previous version of ARR 1987 <citation>arr_1987</citation> and represents
        significant new thinking in the stormwater industry. </para>
      <para>Many authors have established that the use of volume management at a distributed scale
        may not be required to provide significant reductions in peak discharges at the property
        scale because reducing runoff volumes at the top of catchment provide substantial reductions
        in peak flows throughout catchments (for example: <citation>b9_c4_r127+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r94+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r105+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r137+1</citation>). <citation>b9_c4_r105+1</citation> used a large
        catchment scale model to
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144228+1000" content="find"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144228+1000"?>conclude<?oxy_insert_end?>
        that distributed peak discharge control
        (on<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144223+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?>site
        detention) and volume management (rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144235+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>water harvesting) systems produce similar hydrographs at the catchment
        outlet. It was acknowledged that the peak discharges on a lot scale may be larger for volume
        management than for flow management. However, it was
        found<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144245+1000"?>
        that<?oxy_insert_end?> for medium to large catchments<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144325+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144307+1000" content=" that "?>the
        cumulative effect of volume reductions obliterates the effect of peak discharges at
        individual sites.
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144337+1000" content="This indicates"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144337+1000"?>Therefore,
        indicating<?oxy_insert_end?> that
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144348+1000" content="the "?>cumulative
        effects of distributed reductions in stormwater runoff volumes can be significant at a
        catchment scale due to
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144404+1000" content="the "?>reduction in
        overall volume discharged to the catchment outlet (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). These
        results are consistent with the basic elements of peak flows which are volume and time.
        Reducing either element must reduce peak flows within the catchment.</para>
      <para><citation>b9_c4_r116+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r145+1</citation>
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144430+1000" content="also found that at the lot scale the flow management (detention) systems reduced the peak discharge at the lot scale and volume management (rainwater harvesting) provided smaller changes in peak discharges at lot scale but significantly reduced the volumes of stormwater runoff which reduced peak discharges at the street and catchment scale. It was argued that flooding is a volume driven process and peak discharges at the lot scale had little or no bearing on the floods at a catchment scale."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144430+1000"?>also
        found that the flow management (detention) systems reduced the peak discharge at the lot
        scale. On the other hand, volume management (rain water harvesting) provided smaller changes
        in peak discharge at lot scale but significantly reduced the volumes of stormwater runoff,
        which in-turn reduced peak discharges at street and catchment scale. It was argued that
        flooding is a volume driven process and peak discharges at the lot scale had little or no
        bearing on floods at a catchment scale.<?oxy_insert_end?> Use of first
        principle<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144438+1000" content="s"?>
        processes such as continuous simulation and detailed systems analysis rather than empirical
        assumptions (for example antecedent conditions associated with event based analysis)
        has<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144546+1000" content=" also"?> revealed
        that the shape of catchment hydrographs may be significantly altered by distributed and
        integrated solutions within catchments (for example; <citation>b9_c4_r171+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c2_r20+1</citation>). <citation>b9_c4_r158+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r174+1</citation> and <citation>b9_c2_r20+1</citation> highlight the
        benefits of replacing the common design requirements with treatment trains on properties and
        throughout urban areas to manage peak discharges and flow regimes throughout and at the
        outlet of urban catchments. </para>
    </section>
    <section  xml:id="b9ch4_s_00016">
      <title>Use of Computer Models</title>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144601+1000" content="A coupled analysis of storage basin volume and outlet capacity is necessary in order to determine the most appropriate configuration for a facility. This analysis is usually iterative. Firstly, dimensions of the storage basin and outlet are estimated and tested by numerical calculation and then progressively adjusted to achieve the design objectives. This is normally undertaken using computer models that have been developed to assist with these calculations."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144601+1000"?>Coupled
        analysis of storage basin volume and outlet capacity is necessary to determine the most
        appropriate configuration for a facility. This analysis is usually iterative. Firstly,
        storage basin dimensions and outlets are estimated and tested by numerical calculation and
        then progressively adjusted to achieve the design objectives. This is normally undertaken
        using computer models that were developed to assist with these
        calculations.<?oxy_insert_end?>
      </para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144639+1000" content="The design and analysis of these facilities must include the interactions with other stormwater management facilities and urban form in the catchment and catchment behaviours. The adopted modelling approach should also use rainfall time series and resolve full hydrographs of a total duration that is relevant to the objective being analysed. For peak discharge control this may only be minutes or hours. For water quality improvement and stormwater harvesting applications this may be years or decades. The model must have sufficient catchment resolution and detail to adequately represent the linked hydrologic processes in the catchment. Lumped models that simplify catchment representation and behaviours should be used with caution."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144639+1000"?>The
        design and analysis of these facilities must include interactions with other stormwater
        management facilities and urban form in catchment and catchment behaviours. The adopted
        modelling approach should also use rainfall time series and resolve full hydrographs of a
        total duration that is relevant to the objective being analysed. For peak discharge control,
        this may only be minutes or hours. For water quality improvement and stormwater harvesting
        applications, this may be years or decades. The model must have sufficient catchment
        resolution and detail to adequately represent linked hydrologic processes in the catchment.
        Lumped models that simplify catchment representation and behaviours should be used with
        caution.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144654+1000" content="The modelling approach should allow different storm scenarios to be tested since the performance of a volume management facility may be highly sensitive to the selected storm characteristics and volumes. For example, volume management facilities will have a greater impact on peak discharges under conditions where the storm burst occurs in the front of a storm rather than under conditions when the storm burst occurs towards the back of a storm when the detention storage is already partially full.."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144654+1000"?>The
        modelling approach should allow different storm scenarios to be tested since the performance
        of a volume management facility may be highly sensitive to the selected storm
        characteristics and volumes. For example, volume management facilities will have a greater
        impact on peak discharges under conditions where the storm burst occurs in front of a storm,
        rather than under conditions when the storm burst occurs towards the back of a storm, when
        the detention storage is already partially full.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      <para>A designer may therefore need to consider
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144746+1000" content="the use"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144746+1000"?>using<?oxy_insert_end?>
        an ensemble of complete storms with a storm burst of around the critical duration or a storm
        burst only to determine the benchmark condition(s) (<citation>b9_c4_r151+1</citation>; <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6"/>). If a design approach adopts a storm burst only approach, then for a
        given AEP the peak flows are assessed for a range of storm burst durations and the storm
        burst duration
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144754+1000" content="which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144754+1000"?>that<?oxy_insert_end?>
        gives the highest peak flow is adopted as the critical storm.</para>
      <para>If a design approach adopts an ensemble of complete storms of a given AEP, then the
        designer will need to determine if the benchmark condition is to be based on the 50th
        percentile peak flow or on a different percentile of peak flow. Preliminary testing
        indicates that adopting the 50th percentile is a very good indicator of the results from
        more complex Monte-Carlo approaches in most circumstances. Ultimately, the decision of what
        percentile of peak flow to adopt can be informed through identifying the level of risk the
        community is willing to accept within the catchment.</para>
      <para>Once a base model is
        established<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144806+1000"?>,
        which<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144804+1000" content=" that"?>
        includes the proposed facility, the model should be capable of iterative changes to the
        dimensions of the storage and the outlet structure. Using a judgement driven and iterative
        approach, the model is used to determine an optimised configuration that results in the
        required hydrologic performance for the selected range of storms.</para>
      <para>For more detailed guidance regarding the use of computer modelling in urban stormwater
        design see <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/>.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section  xml:id="b9ch4_s_00017">
    <title>Detailed Design Considerations</title>
    <para>This section provides an introductory level of detailed design guidance for each of the
      most common volume management facility types, as listed in <xref linkend="b9ch4_t_00004"/>.
      Further more comprehensive design guidance reflecting local design standards should be sought
      from the relevant local stormwater authority. References to some useful guidelines are
      provided in each of the following sections.</para>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00018">
      <title>Detention Basins</title>
      <para>Detention basins, also sometimes called retarding basins, are measures which temporarily
        store stormwater to reduce peak discharge. Outflows are typically controlled by a low-level
        pipe or culvert and a high-level overflow spillway as shown in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00003"
        />. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00003">
        <title>Detention Basin Typical Section</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9072.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Detention basins can be designed to suit a range of catchment sizes. Community and
        regional scale basins may have considerable community benefits as areas for recreation and
        may be built around specific sizes and shapes of fields for sports such as football, netball
        and cricket. The sides of basins are usually sloping earth embankments, suitable for
        occasional spectator use. Basins used for passive recreation may include stands of trees
        (within the basin but not on any fill embankment), lawns and other vegetation.</para>
      <para>Basins may be placed directly across a watercourse, or located off-stream, with flows in
        excess of a certain flow<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144831+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>rate being diverted into them. They can be arranged in a widened section
        of drainage easement zoned both for recreation and drainage purposes.</para>
      <para>Detention basins themselves are not suited to the improvement of water quality or
        harvesting and infiltration of stormwater. However other types of volume management
        facilities can be nested inside. For example a constructed wetland can be located in the
        floor of a large detention basin storage to also target water quality improvements.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>There are many guidelines on community and regional detention including
          <citation>b9_c4_r1+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r20+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r12+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r22+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r28+1</citation>. These guidelines can be readily used for designing and
        modelling detention systems, using the modelling and storm patterns as described in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6"/>. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Detailed Design
          Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Flood Capacity</emphasis></para>
      <para>The final sizing of any basin should be completed with the aid of a computer model. The
        selected model must accurately simulate the hydraulic behaviour of the basin outlet,
        especially when partial full pipe flow or tailwater submergence occurs
          <citation>b9_c4_r28</citation>. When located in-stream, the hydraulic modelling should
        also represent the stream conditions and the stream flows discharging through the basin in
        addition to the urban areas directed to it.</para>
      <para>Large community and regional basins can be considered dams, as they can store
        significant volumes of stormwater, and therefore may pose a potential threat to communities
        residing downstream of a basin. As a result, the design must have regard to the ANCOLD
        (Australian National Committee on Large Dams, date) guidelines. A detailed risk assessment
        of a storm exceeding the Dam Crest Flood should be considered in the design of a detention
        basin within an urban area due to the potential severe consequences of the sudden failure of
        a basin on any urban development located on the floodplain downstream.</para>
      <para>Detention basins should be designed with a flood capacity to convey appropriate extreme
        storms safely through the basin in accordance with the Hazard Category of the basin as
        defined by ANCOLD, as is the case for conventional dams.</para>
      <para>An ‘Initial Assessment’, as defined by ANCOLD’s guidelines within the
          <citation>b9_c4_r3+1</citation> should be undertaken for any proposed detention basin to
        determine the hazard category of the structure. </para>
      <para>Depending on the findings of the ‘Initial Assessment’ a more detailed assessment
          <citation>b9_c4_r2</citation> including a Dam Break analysis for both ‘flood failure’ and
        ‘sunny day’ scenarios may be required.</para>
      <para>With increasing urbanisation there are now many catchments which contain a series of
        detention basins. Each basin within a catchment should be investigated not only individually
        but also collectively within the catchment, including all basins modelled as a whole
          <citation>b9_c4_r22</citation>. </para>
      <para>In addition, two further issues should be considered:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The consequences of one basin failure cascading downstream into lower basins should
            be evaluated; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The effect of long period releases from upper basins superimposing on flows through
            lower basins may require a revision of the basins’ operation throughout the catchment.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Embankment Design</emphasis></para>
      <para>The embankments of detention basins should be designed using appropriate stability
        analysis and geotechnical design practices.
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144905+1000" content="In particular"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144905+1000"?>Particularly,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        appropriate foundation treatment should be specified. For earthen embankments suitable
        compaction levels, vegetation cover and stabilisation should be specified and protection
        provided to cater for cracking or dispersive soils. Impervious zones of an earthen
        embankment should take the form of a centrally located ‘core’ rather than an upstream face
        zone to reduce the effects of drying which may lead to cracking. </para>
      <para>If the earth fill for any embankment
        is<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T144925+1000" content=" to be"?> taken
        from borrow areas, these areas should be kept as far away from the embankment(s) as
        practicable. Should the borrow area penetrate any alluvial sand layers or lenses, the
        embankment’s cut- offs should be taken to at least 1 m below the estimated depth of such
        sand layers/lenses at the detention basin floor.</para>
      <para>Chimney intercept filters and filter/drainage blankets should be used for all high and
        extreme hazard category detention basins. Such filters may also be required for lower hazard
        category detention basins. All earthen embankments constructed from dispersion soils must
        have a chimney filter and downstream filter/drain <citation>b9_c4_r22</citation>.</para>
      <para>Suggested basin freeboard requirements for a variety of basins are provided in <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_t_00011"/>.<table xml:id="b9ch4_t_00011" frame="void">
          <caption>Detention Basin Freeboard Requirements (after
            <citation>b9_c4_r28+1</citation>)</caption>
          <col width="40%"/>
          <col width="20%"/>
          <col width="40%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Situation</th>
              <th>AEP</th>
              <th>Maximum Depth or Level</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Basin formed by road embankment</emphasis></para>
                <para><emphasis role="bold"> (a)</emphasis></para>
                <para><emphasis role="bold"> (b)</emphasis></para>
              </td>
              <td>
                <para/>
                <para>5% </para>
                <para>2%</para>
              </td>
              <td colspan="3">
                <para/>
                <para>Bottom of pavement box</para>
                <para>0.3 m below edge of shoulder</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Basin formed by railway embankment</emphasis></td>
              <td>2%</td>
              <td>Underside of ballast</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Large basins with separate high level
                spillway</emphasis></td>
              <td>1%</td>
              <td>Embankment crest with freeboard ≥1% AEP storage depth and with minimum freeboard =
                0.3 m <superscript>[1]</superscript></td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
      <para>External earthen embankment slopes and their protection should take into account long
        term maintenance of the structure. The side slopes of a grassed earthen embankment and basin
        storage area should not be steeper than 1(V):4(H) to prevent bank erosion and to facilitate
        maintenance and mowing. </para>
      <para>The surfaces of an earthen embankment and overflow spillway must be protected against
        damage by scour. The degree of protection required is subject to the calculated flow
        velocity. </para>
      <para>The following treatments are recommended as a guide
        <citation>b9_c4_r26</citation>:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>V ≤ 2 m/s a dense well-knit turf cover using for example kikuyu</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>2 m/s &lt; V &lt; 7 m/s a dense well-knit turf cover incorporating a turf
            reinforcement system</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>V ≥ 7 m/s hard surfacing with concrete, riprap or similar</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Practical maintenance access should be provided to the full length of the embankment and
        any hydraulic structures passing through it.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Basin Floor</emphasis></para>
      <para>The floor of basin shall be designed with a suitable grade that provides positive
        drainage to the basin outlet and to prevent water logging. Detention basins may require
        underdrains to positively drain the bottom of the detention facility for ease of
        maintenance. If there are frequent trickle flows entering the basin then a low flow channel
        or pipe passing through the basin should be considered.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Primary Outlets</emphasis></para>
      <para>The key function of primary outlets is to release flows from a detention basin at the
        designed discharge rate. Some typical primary outlets are shown in <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_f_00004"/>. <xref linkend="book6"/> details how these outlets can be
        hydraulically designed.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00004">
        <title>Typical Detention Basin Primary Outlets</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9045.bmp"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Pipe or box culverts are often used as outlet structures for detention basin facilities.
        The design of these outlets can be for either single or multi-stage discharges. A single
        stage discharge system typically consists of a single culvert entrance system, which is not
        designed to carry emergency flows. A multi-stage inlet typically involves the placement of a
        control structure at the inlet to the culvert. In particular, details on the hydraulics of
        rectangular weirs are given in <xref linkend="b6_ch3"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Secondary Outlets</emphasis></para>
      <para>In general, the capacity of secondary outlets (typically spillways) should be based on
        the hazard rating of the structure as defined by the ANCOLD seven level rating system. The
        hazard rating defines the required ‘Fall back’ Design Flood. In some cases where the
        required ‘Fall back’ Design Flood is considered to be impractical, a full risk assessment of
        the basin may allow a lesser capacity spillway in line with ALARP (As Low As Reasonably
        Practicable) principles<citation>b9_c4_r22</citation>.</para>
      <para>The design capacity of spillways should account for the possible reduced capacity of
        primary outlets which have the potential to become blocked during a major storm. The
        assessment of the possible blockage should be undertaken in accordance with the guidance
        provided in <xref linkend="book6"/>.</para>
      <para>Recommendations for the design of outlet structures are provided by
          <citation>b9_c4_r175</citation> while the Design of Small Dams
          <citation>b9_c4_r37+1</citation> provides procedures for the sizing and design of free
        overfall, ogee crest, side channel, labyrinth, chute, conduit, drop inlet (morning glory),
        baffled chute and culvert spillways. </para>
      <para>Details on the hydraulics of rectangular weirs, sharp-crested rectangular weirs,
        broad-crested rectangular weirs, trapezoidal weirs, circular-crested weirs and compound
        weirs are provided in <xref linkend="b6_ch3"/>. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00019">
      <title>On-site Detention</title>
      <para> In many urban areas detention has been implemented, and in particular since 1975 the
        use of detention basins has been widespread in NSW <citation>b9_c4_r74</citation>. However
        in urbanised areas the available sites for large detention basins (as described previously
        in <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00018"/>) are limited or are fully utilised over time. </para>
      <para>To avoid exacerbating what can be already substantial flooding problems in an urbanised
        catchment, planning and development controls are sometimes implemented at the lot scale to
        mitigate the impact of increased impervious surfaces. These are commonly described as
        On-Site Detention (OSD) as shown in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00005"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00005">
        <title>Typical Section through a Below Ground OSD</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9074.bmp"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para> In New South Wales, OSD was developed and first implemented by Ku-ring-gai Council,
        closely followed by Wollongong City Council <citation>b9_c4_r78</citation>. Since then many
        councils in Greater Sydney and elsewhere have implemented OSD systems. Other Councils
        outside of NSW have also adopted On-Site Detention, such as Hobart City Council (TAS), City
        of Casey (VIC), Manningham City Council (VIC), Melton Shire Council (VIC) and the City of
        Tea Tree (SA).</para>
      <para>It is important to note that the imposition of OSD requirements at the lot scale is
        often done on the assumption that there is broader flood benefits at a catchment scale.
        However in some cases there may be little or no catchment wide benefit from OSD, as the
        overall volume of runoff is not reduced, merely detained for a period of time. This effect
        is not always sufficient to influence catchment scale floods. OSD performance is also
        sensitive to the temporal pattern of rainfall. </para>
      <para>Establishment of OSD policy therefore needs careful assessment at the outset using a
        catchment wide strategy to ensure the overall catchments to which the policy is intended to
        be applied are indeed suitable.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>There are many guidelines on the sizing or design of OSD, such as
          <citation>b9_c4_r8+1</citation>, <citation> b9_c4_r169+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r20+1</citation> and <citation>b9_c4_r13+1</citation>. These guidelines
        can be readily used for designing OSD systems, using the modelling approaches outlined in
        <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/>.</para>
      <para>These documents can assist in the design of OSD systems, however, practitioners are
        encouraged to determine if the method identified in the guidelines are consistent and
        suitable for using the contemporary flood estimation techniques identified in <xref
          linkend="b9_ch6"/> and the issues identified in <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Detailed Design
          Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Flood Capacity</emphasis></para>
      <para>Historically, the primary objective of OSD controls was to manage flooding in a 1% AEP
        event only. Further implementation and development on OSD has resulted in many authorities
        now requiring OSD systems to reduce the post-development flows to adopted benchmark peak
        discharges over a range of AEPs up to and including the 1% AEP. </para>
      <para>OSD discharge control requirements should be based on a catchment wide assessment. A
        catchment wide assessment has been typically downscaled to site control requirements, such
        as:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Permissible Site Discharge (PSD) or Site Reference Discharge (SRD), which are
            defined as the maximum allowable discharge leaving the site (determined using
            catchment-based assessment of lot-based measures) with PSD giving a single discharge
            rates and SRD giving multiple discharge rates for different rainfall frequencies;
            and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Site Storage Requirement (SSR), which is defined as the volume required for overall
            storage. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>It should be noted that if the objective of OSD control is to manage flooding in a 1%
        AEP event only then typically only a single set of PSD and SSR values are defined. However
        where authorities require OSD systems to perform over a range of AEPs a nest of frequency
        staged storages and outlets is required with multiple PSD and SSR values. Ab example of an
        OSD design is provided in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00006"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00006">
        <title> Frequency Staged Below Ground OSD System (after
          <citation>b9_c4_r169+1</citation>)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9040.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para> In the event that catchment wide assessments have not been conducted, one of the
        following site controls can be applied to enable the design of OSD systems:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The post-development flows of the subject site should be controlled to meet the
            pre-development flows for the site for a range of complete storms, or</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Determine the capacity of the drainage system and divide by the area of lots that
            drain to the system. This gives an indicative estimate of the amount of the unit runoff
            (i.e. the PSD).</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>Either of these approaches are not as effective as designs based on a holistic catchment
        assessment, but may assist in the short term in managing nuisance flows in existing systems
        immediately downstream from sites. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">OSD Types</emphasis></para>
      <para>OSD systems may comprise above-ground storage or underground storage or a combination of
        both. Above-ground storage has advantages in terms of flexible configuration of site levels
        to achieve the required storage volume, capacity to incorporate retention through
        infiltration and pollutant removal landscaping features, reduced construction cost and
        easier maintenance. The advantages of underground storage are typically a reduced footprint
        in comparison to above-ground storages and limitation of ponding on runoff on the surface.
        It is critical to select an appropriate storage type by considering the site layout, costs
        and effectiveness of OSD.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Above Ground OSD</emphasis></para>
      <para>OSD systems may comprise above-ground storage or underground storage or a combination of
        both. It is critical to select an appropriate storage type by considering the site layout,
        costs and effectiveness of OSD.</para>
      <para>Above ground storage has advantages in terms of flexible configuration of site levels to
        achieve the required storage volume, capacity to incorporate water quality treatment through
        infiltration and treatment media, low construction cost and potentially low
        maintenance.</para>
      <para>The main types of above-ground storages include landscaped storages, parking and paved
        storages, and rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145041+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>water tanks with dedicated airspace for detention. </para>
      <para>Where storage is not provided by a rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145042+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>water tank the typical requirements listed in <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_t_00012"/> should be considered.<table xml:id="b9ch4_t_00012" frame="void">
          <caption>Above Ground OSD Storage Design Considerations</caption>
          <col width="20%"/>
          <col width="80%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Design Aspect</th>
              <th>Typical Considerations</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Structural Adequacy</td>
              <td>
                <para>Design of surrounding embankments or retaining walls should consider
                  structural and geotechnical aspects such as the need for reinforcement, compaction
                  requirements and stable slopes. This includes when the storage is both full and
                  empty.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Storage Configuration</td>
              <td>
                <para>Ponding depths shall not exceed the maximum storage depth requirements
                  required by local standards. As an initial guide a maximum of 0.6 m is suggested
                  for landscape areas with low pedestrian use <citation>b9_c4_r10</citation>. A
                  Council may approve deeper ponding in individual cases where it is demonstrated
                  that safety issues have been adequately addressed. For example, warning signs and
                  or fencing should be installed where the depth exceeds 600 mm or adjacent to
                  pedestrian traffic areas.</para>
                <para>Where ponding occurs in areas for recreational purposes (e.g. a playground)
                  suitable velocity and depth should be selected to ensure the safety of children
                  and the elderly.</para>
                <para>The storage volume should be increased by 20% to compensate for the potential
                  loss of storage due to construction inaccuracies and the build-up of vegetation
                  growth over time.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Floor Slope</td>
              <td>
                <para>The minimum ground surface slope should be 1.0%, while the desirable minimum
                  surface slope is 1.5%.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Vegetation and Soils</td>
              <td>
                <para>Subsoil drainage around the outlet should be designed to prevent the ground
                  becoming saturated during prolonged wet weather.</para>
                <para>Appropriate plant species for the vegetated areas should be selected that can
                  withstand prolonged inundation and frequent wetting and drying.</para>
                <para>Any direct inflow point into a vegetated system (e.g. roof drainage or
                  driveway runoff) should include a small energy dissipation device to reduce
                  velocity and prevent erosion of the basin floor.</para>
                <para>Mulch utilised in the above-ground storages should not be able to float and
                  plants should be capable of withstanding frequent inundation as per the design
                  depth and frequency.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Overflow</td>
              <td>
                <para>An overflow should direct the flows to the legal point of discharge in a
                  controlled and safe manner.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Freeboard</td>
              <td>There should be freeboard above the stored flood level and adjacent habitable
                floor levels in accordance with local standards.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Safety and Access</td>
              <td>
                <para>Balustrades (fences) must comply with the Building Code of Australia (See
                  Section D2.16 of the Code), while safety fences should comply with any legislated
                  requirements for swimming pool fencing.</para>
                <para>Surface storages should be constructed so as to be easily accessible, with
                  gentle side slopes permitting walking in or out. A maximum gradient of 1(V):4(H)
                  (i.e. 1 vertical to 4 horizontal) should be required on at least one side to
                  permit safe egress in an emergency. Where steep or vertical sides are unavoidable,
                  due consideration should be given to safety aspects, such as the need for fencing
                  or steps or a ladder, both when the storage is full and empty. </para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Frequency of Inundation</td>
              <td>
                <para>Frequent ponding can create maintenance problems or personal inconvenience to
                  property owners. The initial 10%-20% of the storage should be provided in an area
                  able to tolerate frequent inundation, e.g. a paved outdoor entertainment area, a
                  permanent water feature, or a rock garden. Alternatively, a frequency staged
                  storage approach should be adopted.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Below Ground Storages</emphasis></para>
      <para>Below ground storage tanks may be considered under the following conditions:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Infeasible to construct above-ground storages due to site constraints or topography;
            and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Frequent inundation areas causing maintenance problems and inconvenience to the
            property owners or community members.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para> Below ground OSD storage tanks are usually made of reinforced concrete and can be
        pre-cast or cast in-situ to meet individual site requirements. When designing below ground
        tanks then typical design considerations include those listed below in  <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_t_00013"/>.<table xml:id="b9ch4_t_00013" frame="void">
          <caption>Below Ground OSD Storage Design Considerations
              <citation>b9_c4_r8,b9_c4_r10</citation></caption>
          <col width="20%"/>
          <col width="80%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Design Aspect</th>
              <th>Typical Considerations</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Structural Adequacy</td>
              <td>
                <para>Storages must be structurally sound and be constructed from durable materials
                  that are not subject to deterioration by corrosion or aggressive soil conditions.
                  Tanks must be designed to withstand the expected live and dead loads on the
                  structure, including external and internal hydrostatic loadings. Buoyancy should
                  also be checked, especially for lightweight tanks, to ensure that the tank will
                  not lift under high groundwater conditions.</para>
                <para>The soils and their impacts on concrete structure should be assessed to ensure
                  that the correct structural specification is made.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Storage Configuration</td>
              <td>
                <para>Site geometry will dictate how the OSD system configured in plan. While a
                  rectangular planform is typical and offers certain cost and maintenance advantages
                  site constraints will sometimes dictate a variation from a rectangular
                  planform.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Floor Slope</td>
              <td>
                <para>To permit easy access to all parts of the storage for maintenance, the floor
                  slope of the tank should be in the range 1% to 10%. </para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Ventilation</td>
              <td>An important consideration for below-ground storage systems is ventilation to
                minimise odour problems. Ventilation may be provided through the storage access
                opening(s) or by separate ventilation pipe risers and should be designed to prevent
                air from being trapped between the roof of the storage and the water surface.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Overflow</td>
              <td>An overflow system must be provided to allow the storage to surcharge in a
                controlled manner if the capacity of the tank is exceeded due to a blockage of the
                outlet pipe or in the event of a storm with a magnitude greater than the design
                storm.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Freeboard</td>
              <td>
                <para>There should be freeboard above the stored flood level and adjacent habitable
                  floor levels in accordance with local standards.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Safe<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145058+1000"?>t<?oxy_insert_end?>y
                and Access</td>
              <td>
                <para>A suitable amount of access hatches should be provided to enable contractors
                  to readily adopt working in confined spaces techniques and equipment.</para>
                <para>Below-ground storage tanks should be provided with openings to allow access
                  for maintenance. An access opening should be located directly above the outlet for
                  cleaning when the storage tank is full and the outlet is clogged. A permanently
                  installed ladder or step iron arrangement should be provided below each access
                  opening if the storage is deeper than 1200 mm.</para>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Frequency of Inundation</td>
              <td>There should be no constraints on the frequency of inundation of the storage
                basin.</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
      <para> Below ground storage could be provided by modular system which could include one or
        more parallel rows of pipes connected by a common inlet and outlet chamber. The size of a
        modular unit is determined by the storage volume requirements, site constraints and the
        number of conduits or modular units which can be installed. When designing modular storage
        systems typical design considerations are similar to the design considerations for below
        ground storages as outlined above. Further guidance on conduit storage systems is provided
        by <citation>b9_c4_r8+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r10+1</citation>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Combined Above and Below Ground Storage</emphasis></para>
      <para>The designer of an OSD system faces a challenging task to achieve a balance between
        creating sufficient storages that are attractive and complementary to the architectural
        design, minimising personal inconvenience for property owners/residents and limiting costs. </para>
      <para>These demands can be balanced by providing storage with a frequency staged storage
        approach. Under this approach, the design of OSD adopts combined storages multiple outlet
        approach, which can consist of an above ground storage and below ground storage. Underground
        storage is designed to store runoff for more frequent storm events, whilst the remainder of
        the required storage, up to the design storm event, is provided as above-ground storage. </para>
      <para>This approach is likely to limit the depth of inundation and extent of area inundated in
        the above ground storage so that the greatest inconvenience to property owners or occupiers
        occurs very infrequently. It recognises that people are generally prepared to accept
        flooding which causes inconvenience as long as it does not cause a significant damage or
        does not happen too often. Conversely, the less the personal inconvenience the more
        frequently the inundation can be tolerated. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Outlet Structures</emphasis></para>
      <para>The outflows from OSD systems are typically controlled by orifices. Details on the
        hydraulics of orifices are discussed in <citation>b9_c4_r165+1</citation>;
          <citation>b9_c4_r164+1</citation>; <citation>b9_c4_r166+1</citation>;
          <citation>b9_c4_r167+1</citation>; <citation>b9_c4_r163+1</citation> and
          <citation>b9_c4_r168+1</citation>.</para>
      <para>The orifice outlets should have a minimum internal diameter of at least 25 mm and need
        to be protected by a mesh screen to reduce the likelihood of the primary or secondary
        outlets being blocked by debris.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Upstream Drainage</emphasis></para>
      <para>The stormwater drainage system (including surface gradings, gutters, pipes, surface
        drains and overland flowpaths) for the property must:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>be able to collectively convey all runoff to the OSD system in a 1% AEP event with a
            duration equal to the time of concentration of the site; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>ensure that the OSD storage is by-passed by all runoff from neighbouring properties
            and any part of the site not being directed to the OSD storage, for storms up to and
            including the 1% AEP event.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Maintenance</emphasis></para>
      <para>While Councils are ultimately responsible for ensuring these systems are maintained
        through field inspections and enforcing the terms of any positive covenant covering OSD
        systems, the designer’s task is to minimise the frequency of maintenance and make the job as
        simple as possible <citation>b9_c4_r169</citation>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00020">
      <title>Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145109+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145240+1000" content="w"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145240+1000"?>W<?oxy_insert_end?>ater
        Harvesting</title>
      <para>Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145251+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>water harvesting at the property or lot scale has been historically used
        for water supply throughout Australia and for the management of stormwater runoff in cities
        since the 1990s.
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145144+1000" content="Rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145144+1000"?>Rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting systems that provide water supply for more frequent
        indoor uses can reduce catchment runoff (peak flow and volumes), improve urban stormwater
        quality and provide a supplementary water source. The effectiveness of distributed
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145159+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145159+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting solutions for management of stormwater within and at the
        outlet of catchments is dependent on the number of facilities, integration with other
        strategies in the catchment, density of development, climate regimes, and magnitude and
        frequency of demand for
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145200+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145200+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> supply. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>Further guidance on
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145201+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145201+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting can be found in the following documents:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Guidance on Use of Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145207+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?>water Tanks <citation>b9_c4_r172</citation></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145211+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?>water Tank Design and Installation Handbook HB 230 see <link
              xlink:href="http://www.rainwaterharvesting.org.au"
              >http://www.rainwaterharvesting.org.au</link></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Interim Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145217+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?>water Harvesting System Guidelines
            <citation>b9_c4_r176</citation></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Design and Operation of Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145221+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145237+1000" content="w"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145237+1000"?>W<?oxy_insert_end?>ater
            Harvesting Systems see <link xlink:href="http://urbanwatercyclesolutions.com"
              >http://urbanwatercyclesolutions.com</link></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Detailed Design
          Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis><emphasis role="underline">Modelling</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145255+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>water harvesting systems were historically designed and considered as a
        stand-alone facility. This process results in assumptions that rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145259+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>water harvesting systems do not contribute to the control of quantity or
        quality of stormwater discharges from a site or throughout a catchment. It was often argued
        that
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145303+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145303+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting does not provide these benefits due to the uncertainty
        associated with antecedent conditions of storm events (how full is the storage prior to the
        design storm?). Methods to determine the antecedent conditions in
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145305+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145305+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> storages prior to storm events and for design
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145306+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145306+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting systems were developed and demonstrated by
          <citation>b9_c4_r116+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r119+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c2_r31+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c3_r9+1</citation>,
          <citation>b9_c4_r170+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c4_r171+1</citation> and
          <citation>b9_c4_r146+1</citation>. This applied research and monitoring has provided a
        design process for
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145307+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145307+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting systems that requires continuous simulation at sub-daily
        intervals – preferably six minute time steps to determine the dynamic airspace (drawn down
        of storages by water demands). This process can also determine any detention airspace
        requirements of
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145308+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145308+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> storages prior to given storm events for allow integration with
        surrounding stormwater management strategies and use in catchment models reliant on design
        storms. These concepts have been applied by <citation>b9_c4_r152+1</citation> for example
        and can be used to address concerns about antecedent conditions in linked stormwater
        designs. The design process for
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145309+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145309+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting systems has been enhanced by many authors including
          <citation>b9_c4_r174+1</citation> and <citation>b9_c4_r158+1</citation> (for example) to
        also account for flow regimes to protect urban waterways. </para>
      <para> The
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145311+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145311+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> or stormwater harvesting system should be designed using continuous
        simulation (as identified in <citation>b9_c4_r170+1</citation>) and should consider the
        following:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Rainfall at the site;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Potential magnitude and frequency of
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145312+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145312+1000"?>rain
            water<?oxy_insert_end?> use and any rate of leakage from a leaky tank;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Roof or catchment area draining to the tank;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Size of inlet configuration, overflow and use (e.g. can the rate of flow be
            discharge into the tank and out of the storage without surcharging); and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>When underground – the backflow potential from downstream systems.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis><emphasis role="underline">Upstream Drainage</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>The design of
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145313+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145313+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting systems can include gutter guards, leaf diverters, first
        flush devices and filter socks can limit the transfer of sediment and debris into
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145314+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145314+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> storages. Mesh screens on inlets, outlets and overflow devices will
        exclude animals and mosquitoes and other insects from entering storages therefore minimising
        the risk of harmful microorganisms and disease-carrying mosquitoes entering the tanks. </para>
      <para>Runoff that is not collected in the storage and overflows from the storage should be
        diverted away from storage foundations, buildings or other structures
          <citation>b9_c4_r172</citation>.</para>
      <para><emphasis><emphasis role="underline">Storage Location</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>The location of the storage infrastructure will be dependent on aesthetic and space
        requirements for the chosen device. The tank must also be located where sufficient roof area
        can be drained by gravity to the top of the tank.</para>
      <para>If the storage system is below-ground, site soil characteristics and surface flows will
        need to be considered. Surface flows should be prevented from entering the tank and soil
        conditions are particularly important if there are salinity or acid sulphate soil concerns
        which would affect the integrity of the structure <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>. </para>
      <para><emphasis><emphasis role="underline">Pumps and Connections</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>The tanks should be connected to internal domestic demands, typically toilet flushing.
        Appropriate flow rates need to be maintained for the user and therefore the majority of
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145315+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145315+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> supply systems will require a pump to distribute water to internal
        and external plumbing fixtures. A pump should be sized to balance the required flow and
        pressure for the intended uses of the
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145316+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145316+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> from the storage whilst minimising energy use. Generally flows of
        less than 30 L/min are suitable for most residential applications
          <citation>b9_c4_r176</citation>. </para>
      <para>Local government or State Government policy requirements may exist in regards to pumps
        and connections.</para>
      <para><emphasis><emphasis role="underline">Outlet</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>Runoff that is not collected in the storage and overflows should be diverted away from
        storage foundations, buildings or other structures <citation>b9_c4_r172</citation>. This
        water should be directed into gardens, infiltration systems or the public stormwater
        management network. The overflow water should not be allowed to cause nuisance to
        neighbouring properties or to areas of public access. </para>
      <para><emphasis><emphasis role="underline">Tanks with Dedicated
        Airspace</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>The increased uptake of
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145317+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145317+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> harvesting also creates an opportunity to adopt an integrated
        approach to lot scale stormwater management by designing the facility to control of peak
        discharge and harvest runoff volume. This approach may result in
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145318+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145318+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> tanks with three outlets, one for use of
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145319+1000" content="rainwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145319+1000"?>rain
        water<?oxy_insert_end?> (e.g. connected to selected indoor plumbing or garden irrigation)
        down the bottom of the tank, one for orifice discharge (i.e. the OSD outlet) half way up the
        tank, and the third outlet is an overflow at the top of the tank (see <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_f_00007"/>) as originally proposed by <citation>b9_c4_r116+1</citation>.
        The dedicated airspace above the minimum level outlet provides for additional attenuation of
        peak discharges.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00007">
        <title>Rain<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145326+1000"?>
          <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145328+1000" content="w"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145328+1000"?>W<?oxy_insert_end?>ater
          Tank with Dedicated Air Space (after <citation>b9_c4_r116+1</citation>)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9043.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00021">
      <title>Bioretention Basins</title>
      <para>A bioretention basin is a shallow depression with a network of under-drainage and a
        soil-based filter media (see <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00008"/>). The filter media is vegetated
        with plants that tolerate periodic inundation. Stormwater is directed into the basin and
        percolates vertically through the soil and plant root zone providing water treatment. These
        facilities are sometimes also referred to as ‘rain gardens’.</para>
      <para>Bioretention basins primarily target water quality treatment objectives for small to
        medium catchments. In some circumstances it may also contribute to peak discharge control.
        Certain design types can also be used to promote the infiltration of stormwater into the
        groundwater system.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00008">
        <title>Components of a Bioretention Basin <citation>b9_c4_r19</citation></title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9077.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r19+1</citation> “Bioretention Technical Design Guidelines”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r12+1</citation> “stormwater management manual for Western
            Australia”. Department of Water, WA, Perth, August.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r15+1</citation> “Guidelines for Filter Media in Biofiltration
            Systems”</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Design
          Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Basin Layout and sizing</emphasis></para>
      <para>The core elements of a bioretention facility including a basin with filter media, an
        inlet structure and an outlet structure.</para>
      <para>In practice a typical basin filter area requirement is between 1% and 2% of the
        catchment it serves. However the overall size of the basin will vary depending on its
        catchment and the treatment performance sought.</para>
      <para>The shape of the basin is flexible but needs to facilitate even distribution of inflows
        across the filter media’s surface. The shape factor should therefore ideally approach a
        length to width ratio of 1 (i.e. square), though rectangular layouts are acceptable and
        common.</para>
      <para>An indicative maximum catchment area constraint of about 10 hectares applies since areas
        greater than this normally produce trickle flows which can compromise the performance of the
        vegetation and filter media. It also becomes more difficult to evenly distribute inflows
        across a large filter area and manage scour velocities. This catchment area constraint will
        vary depending on local climate and soils.</para>
      <para>Designs can be scaled down to lot scale and street scale sub-catchments. These
        facilities are sometimes referred to as bio-pods, raingardens and tree pits.</para>
      <para>The basin is designed to be frequently inundated for a short period of time, however the
        volume temporarily stored and the release rate are not normally effective at controlling
        peak discharge in large floods. Hybrid design opportunities exist where the bioretention
        basin is nested inside a larger detention basin facility to target peak flood discharge as
        well as water quality.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Filter media and layers</emphasis></para>
      <para>The floor of the basin comprises of a carefully blended soil filter media, minimum 400
        mm depth, with a prescribed hydraulic conductivity of between 100 mm and 300 mm/hr. Over
        time the conductivity changes as the media settles and plants establish. The plant root zone
        enhances the water quality treatment performance of the filter and also helps to maintain an
        equilibrium level of hydraulic conductivity in the media.</para>
      <para>Beneath the filter media are a sand transition layer and then a gravel drainage layer.
        The sand transition layer limits progressive migration of the filter media into the drainage
        layer. The drainage layer includes a network of slotted pipes that collect treated
        stormwater for discharge. This drainage layer can be designed as a saturated sump to sustain
        plant growth during extended dry seasons.</para>
      <para>Bioretention basins are normally lined with low permeability clay or a plastic membrane.
        It is possible to design the system without a liner to encourage infiltration into the local
        groundwater table, however success with this approach will heavily depend on plant choice
        and climate.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Inlet structures</emphasis></para>
      <para>The inlet structure receives flow from the upstream conveyance network. Typically the
        inlet comprises a small headwall pipe outlet, roadside kerb and gutter or an open channel
        swale. For large catchments a high-flow bypass is required to limit velocities within the
        basin and avoid scour of plants and filter media. For large catchments a coarse sediment
        capture zone (sometimes referred to as a ‘sediment forebay’) is also required to capture
        sediment and prevent smothering of the filter media. Regular clean-out of the coarse
        sediment capture zone is required. Maintenance access is therefore important.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Outlet structures</emphasis></para>
      <para>The primary outlet is the filter media underdrainage system described previously. This
        is collected into an outlet pit before discharge into the downstream conveyance system. The
        secondary outlet normally comprises of an overflow pit or weir that is engaged once the
        hydraulic conductivity of the filter media is exceeded. The level of the weir is normally
        between 0.1 m and 0.3 m above the filter surface level. For larger systems a small armoured
        spillway or weir may also be provided to augment outlet capacity during a large
        storm.</para>
      <para>The outlet discharge level should be sufficiently elevated above local backwater and
        tide levels to ensure the overall facility is free-draining. Emptying time for these systems
        can be critical and should be checked.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Vegetation and landscape integration</emphasis></para>
      <para>Bioretention basins should be thickly vegetated to encourage water treatment, enhance
        the long-term performance of the filter media and suppress weed growth. A wide range of
        plant species may be suitable, but those that tolerate dry conditions, can be periodically
        inundated and have fibrous root systems are preferred. Native sedges, rushes, grasses, tea
        tree, paper bark and swamp oak have all been found to perform well. The planting scheme that
        is chosen should blend with the surrounding landscape and habitat.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00022">
      <title>Constructed Wetlands</title>
      <para>A constructed wetland is a system of water<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145421+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>bodies that store water and sustain a range of aquatic macrophytes and
        semi-aquatic plants (see <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_njk3b"/> and <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00009"
        />). Stormwater is directed into the wetland and detained for a period of approximately 48
        hours. During this time, physical, chemical and biological processes result in removal of
        water-borne pollutants. </para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_njk3b">
        <title>Schematic Layout of a Typical Constructed Wetland </title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9097.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00009">
        <title>Photo of a Typical Constructed Wetland </title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9078.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>A constructed wetland is most suitable for water quality improvement on catchments
        larger than approximately 10 hectares (indicative only and subject to local climate and
        design features). Subject to design and location it may also provide some peak discharge
        control. It is not directly suitable for harvesting or infiltration of stormwater as this
        can compromise the sustainability of vegetation. If this objective is sought a separate
        downstream pond facility should be provided.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r178+1</citation> “Wetland Technical Design Guidelines”, Brisbane
            Queensland </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r23+1</citation> Design, construction and establishment of
            constructed wetlands: design manual (Final Draft), Melbourne, Victoria</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b8_c_r34+1</citation> “The Constructed wetlands manual” Sydney, New South
            Wales</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Design
        Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Inlet Pond and High Flow Bypass</emphasis></para>
      <para>The inlet pond receives stormwater inflow from the upstream conveyance system. The depth
        and size of the pond should be sufficient to lower flow velocities and promote settling of
        course sediment particles. Regular clean-out of sediment from this area is required.
        Reliable maintenance access for machinery should therefore be considered in the
        design.</para>
      <para>The inlet zone contains drainage structures that direct low flows out of the inlet pond
        and into a downstream wetland area. </para>
      <para>During a storm the wetland area fills to a depth of about 0.5m above the normal
        operating level. Once this threshold is reached, high flows are directed around the wetland
        area via a high flow bypass. This flow split is necessary to avoid re-suspension of sediment
        and plant damage in the wetland area. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Wetland Area</emphasis></para>
      <para>The wetland area is designed with a range of different ponding depths up to 1.5m,
        perpendicular to the flowpath. These different depth zones promote a diversity of
        macrophytes and semi-aquatic plants and enhance the wetlands treatment capacity. The
        majority of the wetland area should comprise emergent macrophytes however deeper zones are
        important for diversity and to sustain the ecosystem during drier periods. The overall shape
        of the wetland should rest within a length to width ratio of between 3 and 10. Typically the
        total wetland area represents about 5% of the catchment area treated however this varies
        depending on the climate and treatment performance that is sought. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Outlet Structure</emphasis></para>
      <para>The stormwater that is temporarily held in the wetland after rain is progressively
        released via a restricted outlet. A typical residence time of 48 hours is sought, however
        this can vary depending on the site constraints and plant selection. </para>
      <para>A secondary outlet is also required to limit the depth of submergence over the
        wetland.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Vegetation and landscape integration</emphasis></para>
      <para>Plant selection requires specialist input to design a planting scheme suited to the
        hydrologic regime and climate and therefore likely to establish and maintain a thick
        vegetation cover. The majority of the wetland footprint should be designed to support
        emergent macrophytes, however deeper zones are important for diversity and to sustain the
        ecosystem during drier periods. Regional biodiversity guidelines should be consulted for
        selection of appropriate plant species.</para>
      <para>Opportunities should also be sought to integrate the wetland into passive open space
        recreation and/or local natural habitat.</para>
      <para>The wetland should be well sealed with low permeability material to ensure water
        retention during dry periods. The bed of the wetland should also be lined with topsoil as a
        growth medium for the selected plants.</para>
      <para>The initial establishment period is critical, careful maintenance is required including
        weeding and replacement of losses. Progressive flooding of the wetland is also needed to
        avoid drowning of small plants. Predation by birds is also sometimes a challenge that needs
        to be managed, particularly during the establishment phase.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00023">
      <title>Managed Aquifer Recharge</title>
      <para>Managed aquifer recharge (MAR), also known as artificial recharge, is the infiltration
        or injection of water into an aquifer <citation>b9_c4_r123</citation> (see <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_f_00010"/>). The water can be withdrawn at a later date, left in the
        aquifer for environmental benefits, such as maintaining water levels in wetlands, or used as
        a barrier to prevent saltwater or other contaminants from entering the aquifer
          <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>.</para>
      <para>MAR may be used as a means of managing water from a number of sources including
        stormwater. The MAR schemes can range in complexity and scale from the precinct scale,
        through local authority infiltration systems for road runoff and public open space
        irrigation bores, through to the regional scale, which involves infiltration or well
        injection of stormwater and provision of third pipe non-potable water supply for domestic
        use.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00010">
        <title>Example of a Managed Aquifer Recharge scheme in an unconfined aquifer (adapted from
            <citation>b9_c4_r24</citation>)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9079.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>Further guidance on Managed Aquifer Recharge can be found in the following
        documents:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r21+1</citation>: WSUD: Engineering Procedures – Stormwater.
            Victorian Stormwater Committee, published CSIRO, Melbourne. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r12+1</citation> “Stormwater management manual for Western
            Australia”. Department of Water, WA, Perth, August.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r24+1</citation> “Australian Guidelines for Water Recycling -
            Managed Aquifer Recharge - National Water Quality Management Strategy -Document No 24,
            Canberra.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Design
          Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">System Components</emphasis></para>
      <para>As an example, a MAR scheme for infiltration of treated stormwater into a shallow
        aquifer could contain the following structural elements
          <citation>b9_c4_r21,b9_c4_r12</citation>:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>soakwells, swales or infiltration basins used to detain runoff and preferentially
            recharge the superficial aquifer with harvested stormwater</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>an abstraction bore to recover water from the superficial aquifer for reuse</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a reticulation system (in the case of irrigation reuse) (will require physical
            separation from potable water supply)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a water quality treatment system for recovered water depending on its intended use
            (eg. removal of iron staining minerals)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>systems to monitor groundwater levels and abstraction volumes; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>systems to monitor the quality of groundwater and recovered water</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>An MAR system may also incorporate the following additional elements
          <citation>b9_c4_r21,b9_c4_r12</citation>:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>a diversion structure from a drain</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a control unit to stop diversions when flows are outside an acceptable range of
            flows or quality</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>some form of treatment for stormwater prior to injection</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a constructed wetland, detention pond, dam or tank, part or all of which acts as a
            temporary storage measure (and which may also be used as a buffer storage during
            recovery and reuse)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a spill or overflow structure incorporated in the constructed wetland or detention
            storage</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>well(s) into which the water is injected (may require extraction equipment for
            periodic purging)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>an equipped well to recover water from the aquifer (injection and recovery may occur
            in the same well)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a treatment system for recovered water (depending on its intended use)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>sampling ports on injection and recovery lines; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a control system to shut down recharge in the event of unfavourable
            conditions</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Site Suitability</emphasis></para>
      <para>Factors to consider in evaluating the suitability of an aquifer for a MAR scheme include
          <citation>b9_c4_r21,b9_c4_r12</citation>:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>environmental values of the aquifer including ecosystem maintenance of caves,
            wetlands, phyreatophytic vegetation, surface water systems and human uses (irrigation,
            drinking water supply)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>adverse impacts on the environment and other aquifer users (e.g. reduced pumping
            pressure for nearby irrigators)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>an existing and/or future drinking water source area</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>sufficient permeability and storage within the receiving aquifer</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>depth of abstraction from the aquifer</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>existing allocation of the aquifer and groundwater resource</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>existing ambient groundwater quality and contaminant concentrations</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>loss of aquifer permeability and/or infiltration due to precipitation of minerals or
            clogging</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>possible damage to confining layers due to pressure increases</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>higher recovery efficiencies of porous media aquifers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>aquifer mineral dissolution, if any, and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>potential for local aquitard collapse or distortion</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9ch4_s_00024">
      <title>Infiltration Systems</title>
      <para>Infiltration systems can come in a number of different forms, each having different size
        and geometry but all with a common purpose to promote infiltration of stormwater. They
        comprise of two main components; a storage basin and an infiltration zone. They are best
        suited to locations where natural soils have high permeability. </para>
      <para>These facilities assist to manage stormwater volume through infiltration of stormwater
        that enters the groundwater system. They may also contribute to peak discharge control where
        rainfall intensities are low relative to the permeability of the infiltration zone. They are
        not intended to provide standalone water quality treatment and should ideally be accompanied
        by a treatment facility to prevent groundwater contamination. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para>Further guidance on infiltration systems can be found in the following documents:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r17+1</citation> “Water Sensitive Urban Design Technical Design
            Guidelines for South-east Queensland”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r12+1</citation> “Stormwater management manual for Western
            Australia”. Department of Water, WA, Perth, August.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r104+1</citation> “WSUD: basic procedures for ‘source control of
            stormwater – a Handbook for Australian practice”</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Design
          Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">System Types</emphasis></para>
      <para>There are several different types of infiltration systems that are available to the
        designer, each of which suit different sites and applications. These are:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Infiltration Trenches</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Infiltration Basins</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Soakage Well</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Permeable Pavement</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Infiltration Swales</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Each of these is described further below.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Infiltration Trenches</emphasis></para>
      <para>An infiltration trench is a trench filled with gravel or other aggregate (e.g. blue
        metal), lined with geotextile and covered with topsoil. Often a perforated pipe runs across
        the media to ensure effective distribution of the stormwater along the system. Recharge
        storages can also be formed using modular plastic open crates or cells which can be laid in
        a trench or in rectangular formation. Such systems are typically 0.5 m to 1.5 m deep,
        surrounded by geotextile and covered with topsoil. stormwater discharged into these systems
        is often pre-treated to reduce ongoing maintenance of such systems. Systems usually have an
        overflow pipe for larger storm events. There are a range of products which have various
        weight-bearing capacities so that the surface of the system can be used for parkland or
        vehicle parking areas. These systems can be combined to treat a large area
          <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Infiltration Basins (also known as retention
          basins)</emphasis></para>
      <para>Community and regional infiltration basins are typically installed within public open
        space parklands. They can consist of a natural or constructed depression designed to capture
        and store the stormwater runoff on the surface prior to infiltrating into the soils. Basins
        are best suited to sandy soils and can be planted out with a range of vegetation to blend
        into the local landscape. The vegetation provides some water quality treatment and the root
        network assists in preventing the basin floor from clogging. Pre-treatment of inflows may be
        required in catchments with high sediment flows <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Soakage Wells</emphasis></para>
      <para>One method for infiltration of urban runoff into suitable soils is using soakage wells
        (for soils with hydraulic conductivity values &gt; 1 x 10-6 m/s). These systems are used
        widely in Western Australia as an at-source stormwater management control, typically in
        small-scale residential and commercial applications, or as road side entry pits at the
        beginning of a stormwater system. Soakage wells can be applied in retrofitting scenarios and
        existing road side entry pits/gullies can be retrofitted to perform an infiltration function
          <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>.</para>
      <para>Soakage wells consist of a vertical perforated liner with stormwater entering the system
        via an inlet pipe at the top of the device (refer <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00011"/>). The base
        of the soakwell is open or perforated and usually covered with a geotextile. Alternatively,
        pervious material, such as gravel or porous pavement, can be used to form the base of the
        soakwell. Where source water may have a high sediment load, there should be pre-treatment,
        such as filtering, as soakage wells are susceptible to clogging.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00011">
        <title>Leaky Well Infiltration System (after <citation>b9_c3_r1+1</citation>)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9041.jpg"/>
            <?oxy_custom_end?>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Permeable Pavement</emphasis></para>
      <para>There are two types of pervious pavements that are effective in intercepting and
        diverting surface runoff into the host soil body:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Permeable paving: concrete blocks incorporating slots or gravel-filled tubes
            providing (vertical) paths for surface flow to access gravel-filled (“leaky”) storages;
            and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Porous paving: grassed surface integrated with a sandy-loam and plastic ring-matrix
            layer laid above a substructure of sand/gravel mix placed under optimum moisture content
            conditions. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The abstraction capabilities of permeable paving system slots and gravel-filled tubes
        can be as high as 4,000 mm/h when new – a performance which can show little deterioration
        over time where surface sediment loads are “light” or where the supply is pre-treated.
        Pre-treatment in a typical urban street context would require the insertion of a simple
        sediment trap (2.0 m<superscript>2</superscript> capacity) immediately upstream of the
        paving (annual clean-out). The alternative to pre-treatment is regular (five-year intervals)
        cleaning of the paved surface. </para>
      <para>Grassed surface paving shows infiltration capacity of, typically, at least 100 mm/h when
        new and, like permeable paving, shows little deterioration over time where supply sediment
        loads are relatively “light”. Porous paving is unsuited to the urban street context where
        permeable paving is used but can be relied upon for many decades of low maintenance service
        receiving runoff from, for example, a (conventional) paved carpark surface. “Low
        maintenance” in this context involves little more than regular mowing. The continued
        impressive performance of a porous paved surface is accounted for by the dynamic nature of
        the interaction – maintaining infiltration capacity - which takes place between the grass
        roots and the host soil. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Infiltration Swales</emphasis></para>
      <para>Infiltration swales are shallow grassed channels – typically 0.30 to 0.50 m (maximum)
        deep, 5 to 6 m wide in residential streets – with longitudinal slopes, preferably, less than
        3%. They have wide application in stormwater retention systems for three main reasons: </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>They can retain runoff through bed infiltration; </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>They can be effective in retaining pollutants conveyed in stormwater;
              <citation>b9_c4_r111,b9_c4_r134</citation> and </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>They can fulfil a role in stormwater harvesting through soil moisture enhancement
            and, possibly, aquifer recharge and recovery. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The configuration of a typical infiltration swale in relation to a residential street
        carriageway is shown in <xref linkend="b9ch4_f_00012"/>. This configuration includes a
        filter strip between the carriageway and the swale invert to provide pre-treatment and
        additional infiltration.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b9ch4_f_00012">
        <title>Main components of an Infiltration Swale (with filter strip) (after
            <citation>b9_c3_r1</citation>,<citation>b9_c4_r99</citation>)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9081.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Swales only abstract flows up to a limit set by the infiltration capacity of the
        near-carriageway “filter strip” and channel bed. All exceedances above this capacity pass as
        open channel flow conveyed downstream within the boundaries of the swale. Another practice
        is to terminate such a swale in a “dry pond” perhaps in the vicinity of a major road
        intersection. </para>
      <para>The process of abstraction is achieved through infiltration alone or by infiltration
        combined with sub-structure retention (gravel-filled trench or similar illustrated in <xref
          linkend="b9ch4_f_00005"/>) with hydraulic disposal to aquifers (if available) or local
        waterways (slow-drainage) if necessary. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Site Selection</emphasis></para>
      <para>Due to their flexibility in shape, infiltration systems can be located in a relatively
        unusable portion of the site. However, design will need to consider clearance distances from
        adjacent building footings or boundaries to protect against cracking of walls and
        footings.</para>
      <para>Identification of suitable sites for infiltration systems should also avoid steep
        terrain and areas of shallow soils overlying largely impervious rock (non-sedimentary rock
        and some sedimentary rock such as shale). An understanding of the seasonal and inter-annual
        variation of the groundwater table is also an essential element in the design of
        infiltration systems.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Soils</emphasis></para>
      <para>Soil types, surface geological conditions and groundwater levels determine the
        suitability of infiltration systems. Infiltration techniques can be implemented in a range
        of soil types, and are typically used in soils ranging from sands to clayey sands. While
        well-compacted sands are suitable these measures should not be installed in loose Aeolian
        wind-blown sands.</para>
      <para>Soils with lower hydraulic conductivities do not necessarily preclude the use of
        infiltration systems, but the size of the required system may typically become prohibitively
        large, or a more complex design approach may be required, such as including a slow drainage
        outlet system. Care should also be taken at sites with shallow soil overlying impervious
        bedrock, as the water stored on the bedrock will provide a stream of flow along the
        soil/rock interface <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Groundwater</emphasis></para>
      <para>The presence of a high groundwater table limits the potential use of infiltration
        systems in some areas, but does not preclude them. There are many instances of the
        successful application of infiltration basins on the Swan Coastal Plain where the basin base
        is located within 0.5 m of the average annual maximum groundwater level. The seasonal nature
        of local rainfall and variability in groundwater level should also be considered.
        Infiltration in areas with rising groundwater tables should be avoided where infiltration
        may accelerate the development of problems such as waterlogging and rising salinity
          <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Pre-treatment</emphasis></para>
      <para>In general, stormwater runoff should not be conveyed directly into an infiltration
        system, but the requirement for pre-treatment will depend on the catchment e.g. residential
        or industrial, etc. Pre-treatment measures include the provision of leaf and roof litter
        guards along roof gutters, vegetated strips or swales, litter and sediment traps, sand
        filters and bioretention systems. To prevent infiltration systems from being clogged with
        sediment/litter during road and housing/building construction, temporary bunding or sediment
        controls need to be installed. It may also be necessary to achieve a prescribed water
        quality standard before stormwater can be discharged into groundwater
          <citation>b9_c4_r12</citation>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Emptying Time</emphasis></para>
      <para>Emptying time is defined as the time taken to completely empty a storage associated with
        an infiltration system following the cessation of rainfall. This is an important design
        consideration as the computation procedures typically assume that the storage is empty prior
        to the commencement of the design storm event.</para>
      <para>Ideally emptying time criteria should be ascertained by undertaking ‘continuous
        simulation’ modelling of a catchment <citation>b9_c3_r1</citation> and should be conducted
        in accordance with <xref linkend="book7"/> and combined with partial series analysis to
        determine the volume, frequency and rate of discharge from the site. In the absence of such
        assessments the emptying times for infiltration systems given in Table 9.4.8 are recommended
        in the interim.</para>
      <para/>
      <table frame="void">
        <caption>Interim Relationship between AEP and ‘Emptying Time
          <citation>b9_c3_r1</citation></caption>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th/>
            <th colspan="3">EY</th>
            <th colspan="4">AEP</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td/>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>0.5</td>
            <td>0.2</td>
            <td>10%</td>
            <td>5%</td>
            <td>2%</td>
            <td>1%</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Emptying Time (days)</td>
            <td>0.5</td>
            <td>1.0</td>
            <td>1.5</td>
            <td>2.0</td>
            <td>2.5</td>
            <td>3.0</td>
            <td>3.5</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section  xml:id="b9ch4_s_00025">
      <title>Stormwater Harvest Ponds</title>
      <para>A stormwater harvest pond comprises of a storage area to collect surface runoff for
        later extraction and use, often for irrigation. Ancillary infrastructure is also required
        for the pre and post treatment and distribution of this water.</para>
      <para>A stormwater harvest pond is best suited to applications that target the harvesting and
        re-use of larger quantities of stormwater for non-potable use. Below a certain size
        threshold a pond may not be an economic way of storing water, in which case an alternative
        may be an underground tank.</para>
      <para>A stormwater harvest pond does not directly target the improvement of water quality,
        however it can provide a minor contribution to this outcome in some circumstances where
        there is suitable irrigation demand. Similarly a stormwater harvest pond does not directly
        target the control of peak discharge but it may contribute to minor reductions in peak flow
        downstream for smaller storms.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Available
        Guidelines</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><citation>b9_c4_r18+1</citation> “stormwater Harvesting Guidelines (Draft)”,
            Brisbane, Queensland</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Design
          Considerations</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Embankment design</emphasis></para>
      <para>The guidance on embankment design given in <xref linkend="b9ch4_s_00018"/> is also
        applicable to any dry ponds which are formed by embankments.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Configuration and sizing</emphasis></para>
      <para>The configuration of a stormwater harvest pond is mostly influenced by physical site
        constraints and geotechnical limitations on batter slope. The shape of the pond does not
        directly affect its performance as a storage, but may affect the cost of civil construction.
        The most efficient shape in this regard approaches a circle or square.</para>
      <para>The size of the pond relative to the estimated catchment yield is a balance between
        capital cost of construction and the reliability of supply. This sizing must be undertaken
        using a water balance of the site with realistic estimates of rainfall, runoff and
        demand.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Liners</emphasis></para>
      <para>A stormwater harvest pond requires a low permeability liner with freeboard above the
        normal maximum operating level. This can comprise of a non-dispersive compacted clay liner,
        or a synthetic membrane. </para>
      <para>A well utilised stormwater harvest pond is not normally full and will experience
        significant fluctuations in water level. The liner may therefore need underdrainage to
        prevent excessive groundwater pressures developing on the outer wall of the membrane. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Treatment</emphasis></para>
      <para>Depending on the anticipated end-use of the stored water, the water extracted from the
        facility may require treatment to improve water quality to the required standard. This may
        involve filtration using a graded sand filter or similar.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="underline">Drainage structures</emphasis></para>
      <para>A stormwater harvest pond requires a suitable inlet structure armoured against erosion
        and designed to accommodate potential inflows when the pond is fully drawn down.</para>
      <para>The outlet structure typically comprises of an enclosed conduit or spillway, with invert
        set at the maximum operating level. The capacity of this spillway should be designed with
        the same level of consideration given to a detention basin spillway, with a capacity and
        freeboard matched to the level of accepted risk.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Acknowledgement</title>
    <para>Parts of this chapter were developed using material provided by John Argue and Brett
      Phillips. Their contributions are gratefully acknowledged.</para>
  </section>
 
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>

  </chapter>
