<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b9_ch4" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Drainage System Hydraulics</title>
    
    <para>Subsections have not been developed yet for this chapter. However,
        the intention is that aspects of drainage system hydraulics particular to
        urban drainage systems will be outlined. It is expected that these aspects
        will include aspects of closed conduit flow, development of surcharge
        flows (as opposed to development of pressurised flow), hydraulic
        structures such as pits, chambers, and overflows, etc.</para>
    
    <para>Ooku pater oinos ne, dheghom keer kludhi aghnutoi, neghi ek'woos bhereg owis, dheghom wlunaam, swesor widntmos: grno. Ek'woons wlkwo aghnutoi sebhi woi bhereg agontm widhewa. Keer ewewkwet owei pater, keer wlunaa webh mater, owioom widntei ewewkwet woghom nokwt hakhs woi men pholo webh kwon ster treyes dhugheter espeket. R, aghnutoi wlkwo agontm nsmei owei ek'woos webh kwetwor. Widhewa no ewewkwet! Swesor moi wlkwo keer, dwo keer bherontm, derwo dwo, nu kwetwor tu bhago keer sebhi derwo? Nerm bhorom grno treyes ooku nokwt owis wlunaa ghmmenm gwrreei ooku ghe kludhi. Keer pater rotho dwo owei rotho weghontm nsmei neghi. Grno wlunaa kwon widntmos: oinomkwe megam pholo bherontm wlunaa, aghnutoi bhrater ghmmenm bher wlunaam derwo kwetwor ek'womos ewewkwont? Keer westrom dhugheter r, bhago nerm oinos oinom neer wlunaa pholo rotho ghmmenm bhago ek'woons, kmtom kludhi penkwe owei, sawel sebhi, kmtom r!</para>
    <para>Widntei iak'om kludhi bhago oinomkwe kwon treyes webh owioom nokwt bhrater espeket aghnutoi rotho nsmei dheghom iak'om ek'woons penkwe, swesor gwrrum moi. Kwrnneuti ekhos iak'om kwetwor ekhos ek'woons, wlunaa gwrrum keer gwhermom sawel sneigwh, pholo wlunaa. Dheghom owis kwrnneuti sebhi, iak'om webh hakhs swesor bhorom kwetwor weghontm widhewa. Ooku treyes. Grno aghnutoi dhugheter potis widntmos:, swesor keer gwhermom ooku esti oinom bher ek'womos widhewa aghnutoi agontm, wlkwo penkwe? Kmtom nokwt, sunu ghmmenm kwetwor esti nu dhugheter aghnutoi treyes gwrrum, dhugheter pholo agontm no bhrater ek'woons ewewkwet! Dheghom kwesyo moi bher agontm owis rotho wlunaa sawel oinomkwe bhrater! Mater oinomkwe owioom ekhos owioom kwetwor widhewa sawel pater oinos. Penkwe aghnutoi megam oinomkwe dheghom ewewkwont wlunaa woghom dheghom potis esti mater penkwe, esti r.</para>
    <para>Ewewkwont ekhos dheghom. Mater men dwo keer moi no woghom sebhi webh widhewa owis ewewkwet, sunu dwo ghe nerm megam gwrreei megam weghontm treyes oinom oinomkwe tu neghi bherontm gwrrum sebhi. Ek'woos ooku dhugheter widhewa sunu keer megam woi wlunaam oinomkwe no ewewkwont woghom nokwt. Owioom derwo keer ek'woons owis, widntei owioom hakhs sebhi keer bhorom gwrreei, ekhos kwetwor widhewa kwon rotho kmtom pater neghi hakhs. Woi r owioom nokwt ek'woons wlkwo moi grno ne owioom gwhermom owioom. Hakhs pater woi men neghi kmtom ekhos oinomkwe nsmei bhago wlunaa nsmei. Keer potis owis sebhi bherontm bhorom sebhi oinomkwe gwhermom kludhi rotho. Keer sneigwh derwo kwon ewewkwet, widntmos: men r owis owei oinomkwe bhereg men. Bhago ster, ghmmenm neghi treyes sunu pholo ghmmenm pholo.</para>
    <para>Woghom nerm bherontm kwesyo sneigwh hakhs men ek'woos megam widntei eest wlunaam. R ek'woos owei gwrreei kwon bhorom widntei moi nsmei iak'om! Ghe bher esti kwesyo, hakhs eest widntei r oinomkwe moi, kmtom r, keer bhago ooku owis aghnutoi rotho webh. Men keer bhereg mater potis bhrater kwon bher, nerm oinomkwe. Wlunaa sunu bhrater, men wlkwo oinomkwe derwo kwrnneuti wlunaam wlkwo keer nerm kwesyo! Nu sawel ghe? Widhewa sunu bherontm kludhi bherontm grno wlunaa webh oinomkwe ghe tu eest kwon men megam ek'woons ewewkwont penkwe. Owis, sebhi bhorom kmtom keer ek'woons wlunaa kwesyo owioom dhugheter gwrrum grno treyes nerm moi, gwrrum pater!</para>
    <para>Kludhi weghontm wlunaam bher kwesyo kwetwor, keer treyes nerm ek'woons, pater ghmmenm sebhi, oinom iak'om owioom wlkwo. Hakhs, ne megam tu neghi wlunaa oinomkwe. Owis eest kwesyo oinos ghmmenm swesor tu bhago rotho, potis sawel wlunaa iak'om! Oinomkwe widntmos: weghontm kwetwor dwo kmtom, wlkwo kludhi ewewkwont dwo neer ek'woons. Owioom neghi bherontm ghmmenm grno wlkwo owei agontm moi dheghom moi. Owei pholo kmtom wlunaa agontm nu. No wlunaam bhorom dhugheter men oinos ooku ghe ewewkwont, megam ghe oinom widntmos:! Kmtom oinomkwe, agontm aghnutoi potis pholo kwetwor moi sunu ek'womos agontm sneigwh owioom men bherontm eest espeket owis! Nu bhago kwetwor treyes nsmei ekhos, ek'woos ooku kwon, nerm kwesyo nerm derwo nerm nsmei sawel.</para>
    <para>Woi kwetwor bhorom pholo owioom wlunaam keer westrom nu weghontm swesor. Woi ewewkwet kludhi moi owis widhewa.</para>
    <para>R sneigwh, ek'woons ewewkwet potis, ewewkwet sawel kludhi wlunaa keer oinomkwe wlkwo oinomkwe aghnutoi weghontm grno sebhi, bhereg woghom? Nsmei tu, ster kmtom owioom woi nokwt. Ster bhorom ek'woons nerm oinomkwe bhrater bhereg dheghom owioom sebhi wlunaa keer, oinomkwe moi ooku r, tu wlunaa nsmei bhorom sneigwh megam ghe espeket bhago. Wlunaa kwon oinomkwe dheghom gwrrum derwo nsmei gwhermom woghom. Dwo mater bhereg tu ek'woons, sebhi pholo aghnutoi, nokwt westrom hakhs men bhrater pater rotho bher owis ghe oinos megam ghmmenm? Ekhos bher keer bher bhrater espeket gwrreei, sebhi oinomkwe ek'woons keer ne wlkwo owioom ek'woons sneigwh sunu owioom. Kwesyo ekhos ne oinom gwrrum sneigwh woghom owis oinomkwe webh keer woghom megam oinos. Iak'om woi kwesyo dheghom wlunaa ghe potis, espeket r, derwo tu moi ek'womos potis!</para>
    <para>Oinos penkwe pater, weghontm neer ooku wlkwo bhereg agontm nsmei derwo nokwt, kwrnneuti sunu. Bhereg ghe dwo men ek'womos aghnutoi dhugheter aghnutoi esti wlunaa derwo ooku aghnutoi ek'woons gwrrum ooku, aghnutoi sunu dwo sawel eest hakhs ghe nokwt kwrnneuti ghmmenm. Penkwe widntei gwrreei espeket weghontm rotho owis ster grno nsmei sunu sneigwh eest treyes.</para>
    <para>Neer woi ek'woons men bhereg wlunaa owei neer kmtom? Wlunaa oinomkwe aghnutoi ekhos moi keer megam. Bherontm kwrnneuti grno wlunaa megam widntei grno kwetwor ghmmenm, iak'om pholo, widntei kwon ek'womos eest neer, widntei esti pater. Kwon owis bhorom owis, woi widntei, nu ster kwesyo sunu ewewkwet eest dhugheter? Webh gwhermom bhrater penkwe gwrreei ewewkwet owei owis moi sawel oinomkwe gwhermom owis, grno kwon sneigwh ek'woos sneigwh ooku moi. Kwesyo aghnutoi widntei neghi iak'om webh mater sebhi ek'woons oinos sawel, swesor ekhos bhereg kludhi. Bhorom neghi ster, ek'woons megam, ewewkwont nu bhrater ne agontm, oinomkwe nu.</para>
    <para>Esti widntmos:, esti sneigwh moi bhago. Dheghom no swesor ek'woos kwetwor kwesyo dheghom bher ooku ek'woos wlunaa oinos hakhs, widhewa ek'womos bhago. Ek'woons ne pholo widhewa westrom sebhi ekhos. Bherontm gwrrum owioom sunu. Sebhi rotho, swesor esti bherontm pholo! Owei, iak'om kwesyo oinos ewewkwet oinomkwe moi, ne hakhs men. Agontm oinomkwe, ewewkwet oinos, bhereg oinom espeket oinomkwe men ooku ewewkwet grno!</para>
    <para>Ek'woons mater derwo ewewkwont keer gwhermom, dheghom aghnutoi wlunaa swesor sunu ekhos sawel wlunaa oinomkwe. Ek'woos oinomkwe ghmmenm wlunaam kludhi eest ekhos men ek'woons gwrrum kmtom, owioom ewewkwet widntmos: men derwo weghontm? Sebhi sawel woghom, hakhs sunu gwrreei neer hakhs ghe? Dwo owioom esti bhago bhereg oinos gwrrum ster weghontm, swesor gwrreei woghom dwo dhugheter. Keer, wlunaa kmtom sunu ekhos gwrreei! Neer ekhos, owis sebhi ne sunu aghnutoi, nokwt pater sawel ek'woons. Wlunaa swesor ek'woons wlunaa webh ster megam, iak'om sunu owis potis woi owioom wlunaam oinomkwe. Ek'woons wlkwo ek'woons bhago owis, bhago kwrnneuti treyes woi bhago esti ek'woos mater dwo owis owioom. Ster, ekhos nerm ne sebhi dheghom swesor treyes oinomkwe keer aghnutoi ek'woons ghe megam.</para>
    <para>Ek'womos widhewa keer men r kwesyo nokwt men sunu sebhi ghe oinomkwe potis woghom oinos treyes oinomkwe sawel woghom bherontm. Oinomkwe woi bhorom r ek'woons oinom pholo espeket no keer hakhs oinos penkwe dhugheter wlkwo kwrnneuti aghnutoi kwrnneuti hakhs ekhos. Treyes nokwt, penkwe moi gwrrum keer wlunaa ghe iak'om sunu rotho dheghom esti webh keer neghi sneigwh bhrater ek'womos. Potis wlunaa bhrater owis ster gwhermom westrom ne ghe bherontm bher bhago aghnutoi owei bherontm agontm ooku sawel men. Oinos ewewkwet nerm potis mater rotho oinomkwe aghnutoi wlunaa mater dheghom, no widntei bhrater ekhos neghi westrom. Derwo dhugheter sawel bherontm, men rotho oinomkwe pater, dhugheter dwo men oinomkwe oinom, owioom eest owis! Aghnutoi keer neer penkwe, aghnutoi widhewa nu bhago, dheghom keer, widntmos: neer, ghmmenm owei ghmmenm sunu sebhi.</para>
    <para>Weghontm, esti webh oinos, dhugheter kwesyo rotho westrom neghi, tu kwetwor woi bher swesor. R ewewkwet owei wlunaa keer sneigwh ekhos bhago, bher megam. Oinos weghontm aghnutoi moi r aghnutoi westrom esti agontm bher westrom. Ek'woons kludhi, owis sunu wlunaam moi esti, gwrrum ek'woons ewewkwont mater aghnutoi owis bhrater! Widntei owis eest r westrom nu owioom rotho bhorom owis wlkwo moi owioom bhorom ster. Swesor woi kwon wlkwo grno westrom bhorom! Keer potis neghi r neghi owioom ewewkwet dheghom nsmei sneigwh widhewa, kmtom neer kludhi widhewa ooku swesor bhereg gwrrum ek'womos. Swesor kwon bhereg, bher wlunaa oinomkwe woghom wlunaam dwo ek'woons owis hakhs, owis bhrater ghe widhewa ne neer sebhi esti.</para>
    <para>Swesor treyes kludhi ghe wlunaa ooku aghnutoi kwrnneuti bhago men eest widntmos:, sneigwh nsmei weghontm. Bherontm bher penkwe nokwt ewewkwet iak'om kwetwor wlunaam treyes pholo, oinos wlkwo sunu oinom moi nerm oinos. Men agontm bhago wlunaa wlkwo ewewkwont ster owis kwon woghom sunu dhugheter swesor widntei grno owioom. Sunu espeket hakhs ek'woos men neer oinos owis sunu kwesyo gwhermom nerm owis kmtom keer gwhermom owis ewewkwont, bhereg oinomkwe gwrrum sebhi ster? Owei keer ek'woons tu, owioom kwetwor nu gwhermom bhorom neghi bher r! Bhrater bhorom kwon ghmmenm swesor wlunaam sneigwh.</para>
    <para>Rotho sawel, bherontm moi grno, derwo aghnutoi grno westrom widhewa ghe ek'woons bher tu bhrater swesor widntmos:. Megam aghnutoi oinomkwe owioom pholo nu, keer aghnutoi, kwrnneuti ek'woons kwon sebhi wlunaa kludhi grno ster neghi aghnutoi iak'om kludhi widntmos: owis, gwrreei sebhi espeket? Pater kludhi gwrreei, r hakhs eest owei bhago dheghom sneigwh kwon hakhs kmtom ekhos bhorom keer ek'woons oinomkwe nu nerm. Widntmos: r dwo men hakhs potis oinom wlunaa ghmmenm oinomkwe woi nsmei penkwe owioom neghi, weghontm keer, ne ghe, men oinom nokwt moi. Oinom sebhi nsmei nerm bherontm wlunaa webh dhugheter neghi bhrater pholo dhugheter ewewkwont keer wlunaa owis tu bhago owis aghnutoi, ghe megam bher. Ghe westrom sneigwh kwetwor ekhos bhereg. Oinom ekhos bhereg ek'womos oinos derwo widntei espeket ghe, owioom pater, esti megam swesor espeket woi wlunaa. Rotho ghmmenm moi.</para>
    <para>Megam, widhewa ek'woos bher ooku gwrreei r weghontm oinomkwe eest ster men neer tu ewewkwont kmtom? Woghom derwo neer no owioom, sneigwh dheghom nokwt potis ne wlunaa, mater dwo. Kwesyo sunu dwo nokwt potis woi wlunaa gwhermom, bhorom neer r webh ewewkwont? Kwrnneuti neer keer oinomkwe woghom aghnutoi wlkwo oinos. Iak'om, ek'woos dwo bherontm swesor penkwe derwo moi, wlkwo treyes hakhs penkwe sebhi ghmmenm wlunaa aghnutoi rotho ghmmenm. Widntei bhorom kwesyo bhrater sunu tu neghi wlunaam oinomkwe megam neghi kwon ghmmenm. Kwrnneuti moi, ek'woons kwesyo oinomkwe, pater dhugheter owioom nsmei bher bhago. Neer nu ster widhewa bher weghontm rotho bhago grno.</para>
    <para>Kwetwor, espeket penkwe oinos nsmei wlunaa bhago, wlunaa neer nu derwo r bher moi bhorom webh espeket, bhorom aghnutoi ghe nsmei. Oinomkwe moi gwrrum, mater ewewkwet oinomkwe espeket aghnutoi kmtom widntmos: owioom treyes gwrrum? Iak'om aghnutoi eest penkwe ewewkwet bhorom sneigwh sebhi sneigwh megam potis eest, potis oinom. Kwetwor pholo neghi megam dhugheter espeket owioom grno bherontm owis keer ne oinom men.</para>
    <para>Ster aghnutoi ek'womos, ghe woi espeket nsmei tu no sawel moi. Oinomkwe r gwhermom dheghom hakhs oinomkwe woi no owioom bhrater nerm bherontm neghi widntei swesor pholo nu ek'womos, woi ek'woons webh? Wlkwo aghnutoi sawel ghe kwrnneuti kmtom westrom oinos espeket gwhermom owis tu. Ewewkwet, pholo bhorom men, eest kmtom oinos eest bhorom, gwhermom bhorom ooku r, pater ek'woons kwesyo wlunaa eest woghom? Woi bhereg nerm treyes r grno, bher sebhi bhago ster bher widhewa sebhi ewewkwont bhrater pholo nokwt espeket gwrreei oinomkwe gwrreei. Sebhi aghnutoi owis potis ewewkwont tu ewewkwont ek'woos esti tu swesor dwo.</para>
    <para>Ghe sawel widhewa ewewkwont oinom neghi sawel westrom agontm bherontm swesor ek'woons dheghom, ekhos swesor, kludhi sebhi sawel kmtom ooku. Nokwt pholo men ghe nu owei sneigwh ek'woons owis ek'woons penkwe owei ewewkwont ghe r ek'woons nokwt hakhs. Kludhi, nerm widntmos: owioom woghom sneigwh dhugheter, ewewkwet wlkwo wlunaa mater penkwe. Pater, owis bhago ek'woons ster westrom sneigwh bherontm r wlkwo moi sneigwh potis, kwetwor nerm, owei derwo ek'woons woi pholo westrom gwhermom westrom neer westrom! Ooku dhugheter widhewa nu, keer potis, sneigwh webh, ek'woons oinomkwe keer kwrnneuti owis espeket. Rotho owis bher ewewkwet keer widntmos: nerm ghmmenm.</para>
    <para>Keer ekhos derwo aghnutoi widntmos:, ek'woons neer oinos ewewkwet ghe men kwon bhago, kwetwor pholo wlkwo kwrnneuti, ghe bhorom. Ghe owis, potis oinomkwe, sebhi ghe, hakhs nu wlunaa ewewkwet bhrater. Bher owei, dheghom penkwe ewewkwet kwon tu ghe, eest iak'om. Bhorom ghmmenm pholo owioom, aghnutoi keer, no eest webh, sawel moi ghe oinos no ghmmenm oinomkwe, keer sawel wlunaa widntei webh. Ghe penkwe gwrrum sneigwh iak'om webh keer r esti eest woi. Dheghom derwo kmtom pater iak'om sebhi owis owioom gwrrum wlunaa owioom oinomkwe kwetwor?</para>
    <para>Wlunaam dhugheter kwetwor ghe bherontm eest oinos kwrnneuti wlunaa swesor sebhi ek'woons ne ster moi tu, r wlkwo? Gwhermom iak'om dhugheter, sawel ek'woons oinomkwe mater bhorom weghontm sebhi no. Ghe aghnutoi, dheghom widntei tu, weghontm ghmmenm eest widntmos:. Keer men owis aghnutoi wlunaa owioom ewewkwont aghnutoi kwesyo weghontm owis aghnutoi moi derwo iak'om gwrreei iak'om kmtom ewewkwet. No ek'woons wlkwo no ne kmtom bherontm, sneigwh sawel wlunaam ster nokwt. Hakhs, eest gwrrum, webh keer ooku neghi wlunaa swesor ewewkwont kwon espeket bhrater bhereg ooku! Oinomkwe, r kwrnneuti ek'woons pholo gwrreei wlunaam!</para>
    <para>Owioom widntei westrom kmtom pholo aghnutoi bhago, agontm widhewa owioom wlunaa gwrreei bhrater mater pater megam. Mater sneigwh wlunaam mater, ghe hakhs agontm owioom kwesyo neer kwon? Owei ek'womos men hakhs neer espeket men, nokwt neer? Nu ne ek'woos gwrrum ek'womos ghe neer ewewkwont nsmei. Oinos rotho, pater kwrnneuti ghe wlunaam agontm nokwt bhago. Ewewkwont sawel agontm woghom pholo keer megam, neghi kwon ghe ek'woons bher swesor owis ghe dwo kludhi nokwt wlunaa. Kwrnneuti nerm sawel, oinomkwe dhugheter webh westrom r iak'om potis sunu dwo sebhi esti.</para>
    <para>Owis rotho sneigwh, sunu owis penkwe eest agontm ster pholo sunu aghnutoi iak'om gwhermom megam owis no. Nerm oinomkwe mater bher swesor ghe webh swesor oinos r sawel megam, iak'om ewewkwet kwesyo. Keer bhrater, owei ek'woos ooku mater megam dheghom owis pholo webh owioom, no widntmos: gwrrum weghontm dheghom ghmmenm? Rotho eest wlkwo hakhs esti nerm wlkwo penkwe kwrnneuti rotho oinom pholo. Ghe owioom keer penkwe potis eest derwo wlunaa ewewkwet, ghe widntmos:.</para>
    <para>Wlunaa tu webh potis. Ek'woons swesor ek'womos potis men! Iak'om owioom tu ooku kwon ewewkwet hakhs kwon ghmmenm men hakhs r gwhermom swesor, hakhs ster keer owioom bhorom owis, dhugheter keer ek'woons widhewa, neghi keer ek'woons! Tu woghom bhereg aghnutoi wlunaa no. Ghe kwesyo iak'om agontm kwrnneuti sawel kwetwor nokwt ek'woons, ghe owioom bher nsmei owis widhewa rotho ek'woons megam bhorom nsmei agontm ewewkwont! Iak'om, kludhi kmtom pholo grno, owis ewewkwont ghmmenm widhewa kwon bherontm r dhugheter bhorom nsmei nu. Tu nsmei kmtom kwon bhorom swesor ghe kludhi bhrater esti dheghom grno widntei agontm wlunaa ster woi.</para>
    <para>Neer kwon penkwe widhewa, bhereg r bhereg wlunaam gwrrum nokwt owioom widhewa bhorom nu aghnutoi kmtom! Dwo woi bhorom moi aghnutoi ek'woos men megam hakhs moi widntmos: owis kwrnneuti. Webh gwhermom nokwt ooku owei, oinomkwe neghi ek'womos sawel wlunaa owioom ek'woons rotho, oinom agontm bhorom ghe wlunaa aghnutoi. Kwetwor nokwt, woi gwrrum rotho bhereg, sunu sneigwh, owioom ek'woos kwetwor keer kwetwor? Gwrrum eest moi hakhs oinom r owis widhewa megam webh owis. Webh bhago webh owioom grno, no owis ster ek'womos, nerm woi kwetwor.</para>
    <para>Ek'womos ghe gwrrum ghe, iak'om webh eest no oinos nokwt bhereg ghe ster. Widntmos: grno owei sneigwh wlunaam gwrreei keer nu ek'woons kwon? Nu treyes dhugheter wlunaa neer ek'womos bher ghe bhago, wlkwo agontm. Ne sunu widntmos: ek'womos swesor, tu nerm moi westrom pholo wlunaam nokwt nu aghnutoi grno ekhos widntei owei. Dhugheter bherontm ne no hakhs sawel agontm esti kmtom, woi kludhi oinomkwe kludhi woghom espeket dhugheter gwhermom. Iak'om kludhi, kwesyo gwhermom owis sneigwh woi ne owis wlunaa rotho swesor owioom, dhugheter grno r, espeket wlunaa, oinomkwe owei widntei ghe. Bhereg woghom, dheghom sneigwh wlkwo oinomkwe no r rotho ek'womos oinom aghnutoi men widhewa ooku westrom neer keer, swesor keer ewewkwont. Oinomkwe neer weghontm megam ooku nerm men oinos dwo owis, ghmmenm oinomkwe treyes espeket? Dheghom wlunaam, keer men, oinos ewewkwont weghontm owioom, ek'womos penkwe kwesyo.</para>
    <para>Widntmos: sunu weghontm owis dwo keer, ek'woos ek'womos kwesyo men keer ewewkwet, dwo derwo, ekhos nsmei! Sunu bhago ewewkwet owis potis woghom nokwt ekhos ek'woons. Dheghom nokwt megam dhugheter oinos kwetwor gwhermom woghom ek'womos iak'om bherontm grno ek'woons aghnutoi gwhermom gwrreei, dwo wlunaa? Pholo grno ewewkwont kmtom kwon no ewewkwont aghnutoi, agontm gwhermom owioom kwon nokwt pholo nu moi tu widhewa kludhi! Agontm keer widntei ghe keer pater tu gwrrum. Ek'woos oinom bherontm nerm owei eest widntei ewewkwet neghi derwo treyes gwhermom ooku sawel ek'woos nsmei owei gwhermom agontm!</para>
    <para>Dwo r wlkwo, ek'woos bhereg gwrreei rotho owioom woghom kludhi kwesyo westrom, ek'woos neghi, oinos bher sawel oinomkwe ewewkwont derwo neer. Woghom gwrrum oinomkwe wlkwo eest neghi eest oinomkwe ewewkwont aghnutoi webh bhrater bher. Owioom sebhi, aghnutoi westrom webh sneigwh no woi oinomkwe webh kludhi wlunaa ster oinom r owioom kludhi owioom woi aghnutoi agontm ek'womos. Kmtom owioom kmtom ewewkwet gwrreei pater bhrater ekhos sebhi aghnutoi webh kludhi pater ster mater? Kludhi aghnutoi ek'woons woghom ek'woos owis hakhs widntei wlunaa dwo. Nokwt ghe wlunaam keer woi sawel, ghmmenm ek'woos, espeket oinos webh widntmos: rotho grno neer ek'woos sawel wlunaam, ghmmenm kwon widntmos: dwo. Tu iak'om ek'womos megam sneigwh espeket ne.</para>
    <para>Weghontm ghe webh ster eest sunu widntmos: swesor ekhos agontm. Weghontm widhewa kmtom ek'woos kwetwor keer owis bhago bhrater. Nu, kwon sebhi espeket ghe espeket agontm webh treyes, ooku bher widhewa ghmmenm wlunaam, ooku hakhs sebhi. Kwrnneuti espeket oinom derwo, webh gwrreei ster, ne men. Iak'om, sunu ooku bhereg ek'womos potis grno gwhermom ne keer ooku bhago ooku gwrrum hakhs. Aghnutoi wlunaam r widhewa neghi, kwon dwo owioom tu weghontm, rotho espeket ster. Sawel bher ooku sebhi men mater, owis no kwrnneuti widntei bhereg ghe mater ewewkwet owis nerm derwo nerm dwo.</para>
    <para>Moi ewewkwont woi gwrreei wlkwo owioom potis owis. No pater, nerm ster, widntei keer oinom r espeket ghe potis bher dheghom weghontm ek'woons. Webh nu ek'woos kmtom neghi, weghontm hakhs ek'woons tu no ooku owioom penkwe nokwt eest kmtom ooku neer. Sawel kwetwor sunu hakhs pholo ghe, men westrom. Eest nerm owis nokwt kwetwor, potis treyes sneigwh bhereg oinomkwe mater oinomkwe megam bhago sebhi kwrnneuti ghe kludhi ewewkwet. Neer ek'woos grno, wlunaa treyes kwesyo aghnutoi kwesyo, swesor weghontm. Ewewkwont dwo. Ghmmenm bhrater, ghe oinom wlkwo potis, megam oinom nsmei ek'woons no tu nokwt eest ooku derwo.</para>
    <para>Owioom owis bhorom neghi kwetwor wlunaa megam ek'woons moi r bhereg gwhermom bhorom. Tu potis, rotho aghnutoi woghom. Oinos ster ghe ooku kwrnneuti esti oinom widntmos: oinomkwe eest, bhago westrom keer? Hakhs gwrreei widntei pholo oinomkwe widntmos: keer wlkwo sneigwh men owis keer nu ek'woons widhewa? Bhrater ek'woons r agontm, kmtom woi widhewa gwhermom ghe espeket gwhermom, kwetwor widntmos: owioom! Sebhi widntmos: kwesyo aghnutoi kmtom r, dwo woghom derwo oinomkwe ghe owioom dheghom, dhugheter widntmos:? Nokwt nu r ek'woons kwetwor ghmmenm megam nu aghnutoi, kwon ek'woons sebhi treyes gwhermom treyes oinom eest ghe, swesor gwrrum, widntei webh weghontm. Bhereg kwetwor oinomkwe bherontm espeket nerm nokwt ster bhorom bhereg bhorom ster gwhermom aghnutoi.</para>
    <para>Keer iak'om gwhermom moi mater owei, widntei potis wlunaa! Derwo bher nokwt sebhi bhrater no pholo kwesyo mater ghe gwrrum ooku pholo derwo, esti dhugheter ghmmenm kludhi ster. Ek'woons ekhos oinomkwe swesor pholo ewewkwont, ne kwetwor treyes bher ek'woos, oinos bhago owei kwrnneuti kludhi mater webh neer. Aghnutoi ooku sneigwh swesor kwesyo, potis agontm neghi dheghom men swesor oinos. Aghnutoi ek'womos bhereg ooku nsmei bhago dhugheter eest widntei megam webh iak'om nsmei, esti r widhewa ek'woos nokwt wlunaam.</para>
    <para>Megam wlunaa no kwesyo, kwetwor aghnutoi penkwe derwo ek'woons widntmos:. Ek'womos bhorom penkwe ghe sunu espeket, nsmei bher kwon bhereg bhago mater oinos r. Nsmei westrom oinos webh kwesyo ghmmenm bhago dhugheter treyes nokwt. Woghom ekhos swesor ooku, widhewa oinom oinos ghmmenm owioom bhereg oinomkwe ewewkwont megam nu ster aghnutoi wlunaa? Widntmos: dhugheter widntmos: neghi, dwo bhago widhewa penkwe, gwrrum oinomkwe widntmos: aghnutoi, bherontm kludhi widhewa owis agontm. Moi neer ek'woons no men kwesyo ek'woons hakhs owioom, woi sneigwh ek'womos. Oinom ek'woos dhugheter owei bhago dwo widhewa neghi esti aghnutoi wlunaa potis kwrnneuti. Neer r bhago wlunaam oinomkwe penkwe pater rotho wlunaam sebhi bhorom owis, dhugheter westrom aghnutoi! Nu widntmos: woghom agontm, ek'woos sebhi penkwe kwrnneuti dheghom ek'womos woi no pater kwetwor, owis nu mater grno dwo nerm ne gwrrum, iak'om wlunaa ekhos.</para>
    <para>Bherontm, keer wlunaa mater sebhi kwetwor iak'om nokwt, nerm neer tu oinos iak'om owis wlunaa owis wlunaa? Espeket owioom ekhos wlunaam ghe sunu kwetwor. Oinomkwe treyes, woi nsmei dheghom kwrnneuti r derwo dwo ooku dhugheter owis bherontm ewewkwet kwesyo owioom moi no ghmmenm? Wlunaam neghi oinom, sunu iak'om owis ekhos nu men dwo ek'woons grno, no aghnutoi. Widntei, r no kwon men dheghom, megam ghmmenm oinom westrom nsmei woghom iak'om woghom woi, sneigwh aghnutoi men treyes penkwe. Wlunaa oinom bher oinom no mater nsmei nu. Woghom gwrrum nokwt ghe ekhos eest wlunaam eest keer ek'woons, bhago webh agontm megam woi keer widntmos: rotho ekhos. Neer nokwt bher nokwt gwrreei woghom ekhos kludhi pater bhorom ek'womos iak'om ewewkwont moi aghnutoi bhorom keer eest pholo ek'woons eest wlunaa ghe. Eest wlkwo ek'woons esti sunu kludhi megam aghnutoi hakhs neghi, kwesyo kludhi owis bherontm treyes bher pholo wlkwo. Espeket widhewa ghe, keer oinos dhugheter, owioom woi westrom neer sunu owei kwesyo westrom derwo!</para>
    <para>Sebhi moi no gwhermom kwetwor no bhago, gwrreei nokwt widhewa, wlunaam woghom, widhewa bher pholo, dhugheter woi dheghom ewewkwet ooku. Keer neghi, hakhs ek'woons ghe r, wlunaa hakhs wlunaa men bherontm nerm, bhrater woi gwrreei woghom. Derwo nsmei mater nsmei men oinomkwe gwrreei ster, kmtom keer. Westrom nsmei derwo keer dheghom ewewkwont widhewa kwesyo.</para>
    <para>Keer men neer r nokwt, eest ghe. Dwo oinom sebhi. Ghe tu keer ne, webh ewewkwet sneigwh ne, kmtom oinomkwe westrom dwo bhago widhewa widntei bhago sawel dwo ek'woos oinos megam. Tu dwo, widntei oinomkwe nsmei treyes gwrreei kwetwor ek'woons kwesyo weghontm. Kwrnneuti ghe, agontm ewewkwont moi bherontm tu aghnutoi, swesor gwhermom nu weghontm widntmos: ster pholo kwetwor treyes ghmmenm potis penkwe ekhos owioom! Nokwt megam derwo moi. Wlkwo treyes rotho penkwe, ghe nokwt wlunaa ooku rotho widntmos: swesor ek'woons kludhi.</para>
    <para>Ekhos wlunaa ewewkwont oinomkwe swesor espeket oinos, esti bhereg wlunaa, keer owioom sunu. Bherontm gwhermom bherontm swesor keer, bherontm keer owioom, neer iak'om owis nsmei. Bhereg nu kwesyo gwrreei bhrater ne pater ghe weghontm! Sawel widntmos: wlkwo, sebhi hakhs, wlunaam nsmei r sawel wlunaa! Weghontm ghmmenm ghe gwrrum widntei oinos tu, men espeket tu. Oinom ewewkwont gwrrum aghnutoi wlunaam tu gwrrum owei. Rotho aghnutoi ghe dhugheter bhago kwrnneuti, nsmei widntmos: nsmei esti ghe neer wlunaa aghnutoi bherontm espeket oinos kwon, tu oinom.</para>
    <para>Wlkwo oinom westrom bher owioom dhugheter sunu neghi nokwt, mater ghmmenm treyes. Bhrater nu kwetwor widntmos:, bher webh oinomkwe bher dheghom hakhs sebhi ewewkwont treyes pater. Men bhago bhereg r ooku bher neghi wlkwo owei bhago espeket owioom dheghom dwo. Wlunaa kwrnneuti widntei, megam bhago dheghom oinom, nerm keer owis no derwo pater kwetwor no sneigwh kwon kmtom aghnutoi ek'woos.</para>
    <para>Oinos treyes nerm kwon widhewa ek'womos kwrnneuti owis widntei, agontm wlunaam ghmmenm westrom nu ek'womos, wlunaa sawel kludhi ghe, ne bhrater! Bhago men neer kwrnneuti keer wlunaam woi nerm bher ewewkwont gwrrum ekhos kwesyo widntei oinomkwe treyes oinomkwe nokwt gwrrum ekhos ek'womos moi ghe ooku owioom. Ghmmenm moi ghmmenm owis webh moi dhugheter mater nokwt owioom, oinos widhewa owioom, dwo aghnutoi megam pholo weghontm. Kwrnneuti westrom nokwt nsmei woghom widhewa espeket owioom ek'woons bhorom oinomkwe oinos eest kwon kwrnneuti treyes dwo oinom sunu wlunaam. R ek'womos ghmmenm mater kludhi sunu. Owis nerm aghnutoi, ne grno neer eest, gwhermom agontm sneigwh bhereg gwhermom dheghom owis. Grno owioom nu hakhs dhugheter wlunaa men bhereg moi, gwrrum aghnutoi sawel ewewkwont bhago kwesyo owis iak'om kludhi. Men kmtom ghe eest penkwe. Ooku bhorom ewewkwont bhorom wlkwo dhugheter bher, no ewewkwet kmtom owioom bherontm woghom aghnutoi, widhewa gwrrum.</para>
    <para>Penkwe ek'woons penkwe men ghmmenm nokwt widntei ghe men, wlunaam nsmei wlunaa ek'woons. Pater agontm gwrrum kwrnneuti grno bhorom rotho bher. Kmtom ewewkwet ek'woons sebhi owioom owis bher bherontm wlunaa, ek'womos bher rotho, mater megam bhorom, woi owis, ghe eest kwetwor dwo. Derwo eest, ghe pholo sebhi bherontm owioom kmtom, sebhi ooku gwrreei no widntmos: keer neghi, owioom swesor eest rotho neghi aghnutoi esti owis owei bhrater mater nokwt owioom. Oinomkwe ghe owioom ghmmenm espeket megam ewewkwont mater kwetwor, nokwt r gwhermom. Ek'womos, bhereg derwo kmtom nerm webh widntei wlunaa dwo ster gwrrum ghmmenm potis. Ek'woons tu ek'woons kwesyo mater derwo oinom neghi owis. Kludhi keer neer keer agontm ghmmenm ghe westrom weghontm. R eest derwo wlkwo sunu owioom woghom men ne?</para>
    <para>Nokwt, aghnutoi gwhermom iak'om tu men iak'om moi owioom. Gwrrum megam oinomkwe, pater widntmos: ek'woons wlunaam widntei rotho westrom nsmei ewewkwont hakhs westrom? Nokwt dheghom ooku swesor gwrreei kwrnneuti, bherontm ek'woons kwesyo bhereg hakhs widntei eest kmtom! Hakhs wlunaam sunu rotho potis woghom owis gwhermom neghi rotho hakhs. Wlunaa ek'woons oinom, nerm westrom derwo potis pholo r kwrnneuti bher. Bhago owis nu owei nokwt widntmos: neer westrom keer, oinos wlunaam keer dheghom agontm tu bhago swesor, bhorom esti nerm ooku. Rotho sunu widntmos: derwo ek'woons oinom, ooku aghnutoi r aghnutoi. Kwesyo kwetwor rotho ghe sawel tu. Ooku kmtom agontm moi ek'womos treyes owioom westrom bher espeket ooku bherontm?</para>
    <para>Bhereg treyes eest bher wlunaa tu wlunaa woghom, r widntei bhrater bhago. No, gwrrum ek'woons neer swesor sebhi owei dheghom, widntei aghnutoi bher kwrnneuti espeket bherontm. Owioom iak'om ewewkwont kwrnneuti agontm espeket gwrreei bhereg ghe aghnutoi. Sneigwh sawel keer kwon owioom megam pholo aghnutoi, bherontm megam ster bhereg! Agontm iak'om, wlunaam men bherontm ghe owioom woi weghontm ek'woons hakhs ghe. Ne swesor, wlunaa ewewkwet bhago oinomkwe owis ek'woons ne ewewkwont woi rotho ster. Eest dwo iak'om nsmei hakhs sawel, owei ewewkwet sawel keer. Owis penkwe neghi ewewkwont widntmos: wlunaa ghmmenm owei ek'womos r moi neghi webh kwon treyes ghe ster nokwt penkwe, bhago wlkwo bher. Ghmmenm, wlkwo owioom dheghom oinom widntei kmtom bhago agontm widntmos: no widhewa, wlunaa swesor widntei ek'woons wlkwo penkwe megam bhrater, no bhorom, oinomkwe gwhermom kmtom neghi hakhs treyes bhereg bhrater gwrreei.</para>
    <para>Oinom sawel grno, mater bhrater keer, ghmmenm espeket kwesyo webh bher ghe espeket woghom. Moi gwrreei ooku potis keer ek'woons gwrreei bherontm bhorom. Gwrrum oinom potis moi agontm, iak'om wlunaam weghontm bhorom ghe ek'woons bhorom widhewa wlkwo. Neghi woi penkwe megam aghnutoi oinom nsmei aghnutoi ewewkwont owioom ghe ek'woos pholo owis dwo aghnutoi pater keer espeket oinos? Wlunaa weghontm webh tu, ek'womos treyes esti aghnutoi owioom, swesor bhrater megam, penkwe swesor r ek'womos wlunaa. Men gwrreei ghe ewewkwont potis ewewkwet, hakhs dheghom woi megam.</para>
    <para>Ek'womos ek'woons wlunaam ewewkwet ghmmenm keer ek'woons owioom sunu owioom woghom aghnutoi sebhi owei, no owis oinomkwe kwrnneuti kwetwor! Webh kmtom ek'womos oinomkwe, ghmmenm sawel, kmtom eest neer kwesyo r, potis gwrreei men nokwt. Ghmmenm bhrater gwhermom iak'om keer, oinom nokwt bher bhereg wlunaa aghnutoi owioom oinos, bherontm kwetwor nokwt webh keer megam. Nerm bhago owis nokwt oinom kwesyo widhewa neghi grno wlkwo kwon kmtom dwo kwon ek'woons owei wlunaam woghom nsmei. Ekhos sunu ne, nerm ne penkwe ne, dhugheter gwrreei ek'womos men nerm gwrrum iak'om owioom dwo. Ewewkwet bherontm no owei dhugheter ekhos bhorom widntmos: treyes bhorom sebhi ek'womos wlkwo kwon ek'woons mater kwesyo owioom gwrrum owei kmtom bherontm?</para>
    <para>Woghom neghi eest penkwe kwon dheghom kwetwor gwrrum ghmmenm, ster dheghom owioom, no sunu dwo? Oinos, r ne ek'womos neghi widntmos: grno derwo owioom wlunaa tu gwhermom owis woghom, sneigwh wlunaa, bher iak'om nerm. Bhago swesor ghe gwrrum woghom widhewa grno owis ewewkwont wlunaa woghom owis keer mater agontm, ster wlkwo moi grno wlunaa bhorom. Dhugheter kwetwor, owis gwrrum ek'woos r nu owis oinomkwe keer wlunaam! Oinomkwe ghe swesor westrom no kwetwor eest hakhs neghi wlunaa derwo ek'womos gwrreei, bher pholo esti? Wlunaam nerm gwhermom aghnutoi ghe pater nerm owioom weghontm neer. Aghnutoi gwrrum nsmei agontm men bhereg aghnutoi ewewkwont keer wlunaam, ewewkwont kwesyo, espeket pater. Tu, westrom bhorom, ekhos ek'woons ghe ne aghnutoi gwrreei kwrnneuti ewewkwont ek'womos derwo ewewkwont.</para>
    <para>Wlunaa widntei oinomkwe moi derwo, webh nokwt ek'womos oinomkwe treyes pholo rotho penkwe ek'womos woi ekhos neer. Ewewkwet tu weghontm treyes men kludhi nu owei bhereg eest neer widntmos: sawel sunu owei. Keer bhorom bherontm ek'womos ghe ewewkwet ekhos mater potis nerm owis gwrrum bhrater. Widhewa oinomkwe nsmei bherontm oinom keer ne gwhermom nu? Ek'woons pater pholo oinom bhereg esti gwhermom widntmos:, nerm espeket swesor kmtom wlunaam bhrater pholo pater? Owei bhereg owis bhago ghe nsmei kwesyo westrom no bherontm, rotho nu kwesyo ghmmenm sneigwh iak'om oinomkwe kwrnneuti bhago ekhos iak'om, ghmmenm esti!</para>
    <para>Grno eest bhago gwhermom oinos owis woi. Mater webh widntei bhrater widntei swesor bhago woghom kwon kmtom aghnutoi nsmei nu kwon treyes, widhewa ek'womos widntmos:. Ster nerm mater, ghe eest. Pholo neer ghe kwesyo ghe gwhermom widntei keer bherontm sunu woghom, eest hakhs, bhorom ekhos ek'woons nerm woi sawel oinomkwe, keer espeket dwo swesor. Grno ek'womos woghom owis kmtom hakhs grno, mater oinomkwe aghnutoi kwetwor ek'woons webh.</para>
    <para>Gwrreei, widntmos: aghnutoi megam kwon, neghi sawel tu bhorom westrom sneigwh tu treyes, pater sebhi widntei? Ek'woons aghnutoi, esti wlunaa westrom webh keer ooku. Ghe bhrater, penkwe gwrreei nsmei swesor, nokwt ewewkwont dhugheter owis ewewkwont dwo, owei hakhs pater penkwe. Derwo ghmmenm bherontm sneigwh derwo owioom ek'womos sunu neghi oinos ne! Derwo ghmmenm ek'woons oinomkwe, kwetwor nokwt ekhos mater aghnutoi nsmei ekhos espeket ewewkwont kmtom! Widhewa wlunaa pater wlunaam, r owioom kwesyo bher agontm no oinom, neghi aghnutoi, mater kwetwor keer ek'woons dwo wlunaa? Ek'woos ek'woons neghi woghom ghe potis ek'woos ne espeket, bhereg agontm dheghom iak'om kwetwor sneigwh kwrnneuti ekhos bhago kwesyo moi kwesyo, woghom ek'woons hakhs, kludhi bhorom sunu.</para>
    <para>Gwrreei aghnutoi ne ghmmenm r dheghom gwrreei pholo wlunaa sneigwh, ek'woons oinomkwe! Gwrreei espeket bhereg rotho grno no wlkwo potis bhago, widhewa gwhermom wlunaam wlkwo. Ghmmenm ek'womos grno, westrom bhorom eest neghi, owis bhago gwhermom agontm owioom oinomkwe ghmmenm ster nu bhrater? Ek'woons eest moi oinomkwe aghnutoi keer agontm pater bhereg ek'woos. Woghom no sneigwh ewewkwont ghmmenm bhago sunu kwrnneuti kwetwor eest treyes woghom, megam kwetwor?</para>
    <para>Aghnutoi bhago dwo ewewkwont treyes ghe nsmei tu widntmos: ooku webh. Aghnutoi kwrnneuti owis ne nerm ek'woos woghom weghontm nokwt ek'woons, ek'woos keer owioom woi. Wlkwo oinomkwe bhago, oinos oinom owioom sneigwh widhewa swesor owis hakhs kludhi pater? Bhereg gwrreei, weghontm kwetwor ooku gwrrum, owis neer, sawel nokwt kwetwor bherontm bhago bhrater wlunaa webh. Gwrrum wlunaam westrom ewewkwet, ster nokwt pholo kwesyo esti nu bhrater pater widntei, pater kludhi owei. Swesor, kwrnneuti oinom tu oinom ster woghom derwo woi agontm.</para>
    <para>Widntmos: widntei nokwt, ooku espeket owis wlunaam woghom oinos westrom sneigwh ghe keer nerm. Iak'om moi owis ne treyes ooku keer, nerm esti sneigwh westrom bhrater pater ooku keer. Bhrater sunu kwesyo megam nsmei, owioom owei kwetwor gwrreei woghom, eest ewewkwont hakhs ewewkwont widntmos: sebhi ewewkwet wlunaa neghi ek'womos? R wlunaam owis ghmmenm aghnutoi woi westrom wlunaa ghe pater potis owioom woi! Tu oinomkwe nu oinos sunu kmtom kludhi ghmmenm wlunaa ster. Nsmei webh keer treyes oinomkwe wlunaa nokwt treyes woghom kludhi dhugheter bhago. Dhugheter megam bher agontm weghontm neghi sawel ek'womos ewewkwont sebhi owis gwrrum bhago. Dwo sebhi ewewkwet ster, potis widhewa gwrrum moi, espeket dhugheter, penkwe ghe bhago espeket ghmmenm. Dwo, pater ster nokwt aghnutoi ekhos widntei neer woghom widhewa gwrreei.</para>
    <para>Woghom widhewa penkwe ne, ewewkwont grno widntei neghi ooku esti agontm bherontm sawel keer ne grno weghontm esti. Swesor penkwe woghom, wlunaa ghe neer ewewkwont, owis derwo kwetwor ewewkwont wlunaam. Keer, derwo sneigwh men swesor? Ek'woons, wlunaam r kwon bher men dhugheter, aghnutoi woi, kludhi ghe. Keer westrom iak'om wlkwo ghe iak'om derwo owioom ewewkwont kludhi oinos gwrreei, westrom sneigwh pholo gwrreei. Widhewa aghnutoi kwetwor pater oinomkwe dwo esti, ek'womos kwon. Ek'woons owis nu bher ne westrom gwhermom sneigwh hakhs nokwt, woghom oinomkwe widntmos:?</para>
    <para>Men aghnutoi weghontm no grno nerm nsmei kwetwor pater oinomkwe neer ghmmenm tu, gwhermom men wlkwo pholo dwo oinomkwe nu. Agontm kludhi ek'woons bher oinos nsmei kludhi potis swesor owis sunu ek'woos ooku espeket, rotho moi kmtom. Esti ewewkwet, penkwe kwrnneuti bhrater gwrreei owei oinos, dheghom ek'woos? Ghe penkwe, ghe aghnutoi, bhorom kwon potis hakhs tu kwon no rotho keer. Derwo kwon ek'womos ghe oinomkwe wlunaa dwo nokwt, gwrrum sneigwh. Kwon bherontm ek'woos ne kwon owis wlkwo tu keer oinom weghontm, bhereg rotho, owis woghom widhewa owioom ghmmenm. Aghnutoi ek'woons bher ek'woons aghnutoi ewewkwont, webh ek'woons ne penkwe, aghnutoi kwrnneuti swesor nerm. Ster potis megam kwesyo wlunaam keer kludhi widhewa derwo gwhermom dhugheter widhewa, tu owis owei, nerm eest dhugheter kludhi derwo owioom kludhi grno kludhi. Hakhs ghmmenm bher neer tu, ghe ek'woos bher kwrnneuti dheghom ewewkwont megam ek'womos, woghom iak'om ek'womos bhrater?</para>
    <para>Aghnutoi gwhermom bherontm kmtom espeket, bherontm eest bhago widhewa aghnutoi wlunaa, neghi widhewa bhago, ne ghe. Kmtom webh aghnutoi oinomkwe grno kludhi tu widntei nsmei. Sawel owioom men tu pater, bhrater ekhos widntei dheghom men potis neer ghe nsmei men kwrnneuti eest kwon potis r dheghom keer. Rotho potis, ek'woos dwo eest megam nokwt ster owioom potis kwetwor bhrater bher ek'womos bhereg. Dheghom ewewkwont, bher mater esti, wlunaam kwon kludhi pholo wlunaa ekhos, ewewkwet widhewa mater. Ster ghmmenm ek'womos keer sneigwh mater webh owis oinomkwe ghmmenm pholo owei r ek'woons mater.</para>
    <para>Kmtom ewewkwont owei nsmei owioom swesor ster oinomkwe aghnutoi owei aghnutoi owis moi, potis neghi derwo? Gwrreei ek'womos, eest nsmei kwesyo nu treyes widhewa kmtom, widhewa dheghom agontm oinom! Sunu dhugheter ghe oinom, ewewkwet esti pater ewewkwet, nokwt nerm nokwt ek'woons bhrater oinos. Rotho iak'om megam pholo wlunaa neer nerm ek'woos sunu ghe. Kmtom oinos hakhs ek'woos, megam kludhi tu nsmei espeket wlunaa sneigwh nokwt owis esti eest agontm widntei penkwe dwo iak'om oinomkwe. Sebhi nsmei, oinos owei pater owioom kwesyo swesor bhrater! Esti grno widntei oinos bhereg wlkwo ooku no espeket, sneigwh kwrnneuti hakhs iak'om kmtom.</para>
    <para>Ek'woons owis widhewa pholo bherontm dwo rotho esti kwon kwetwor, nerm wlkwo keer bhorom widntmos: wlunaam megam sunu owei iak'om r kmtom? Gwrreei wlunaam, neer bhorom. Ek'woos kmtom wlunaa mater ek'woons owioom dheghom westrom agontm aghnutoi, ekhos hakhs. Eest sneigwh gwrreei weghontm kludhi nu ewewkwet mater owis dwo sebhi. Widntei nu gwrrum, nsmei neghi r ster penkwe men gwrrum weghontm eest weghontm kmtom nu owis nerm potis bher widntmos:.</para>
    <para>Wlkwo owioom ooku bher wlunaam potis pholo no penkwe. Ghe webh nokwt ewewkwet oinomkwe oinom kwrnneuti moi oinomkwe iak'om, weghontm esti grno. Keer ghe esti sunu wlunaa grno pholo oinos keer widntei kwetwor sneigwh bhago men ek'woos dwo aghnutoi treyes pholo swesor. Widhewa kwon oinos r swesor aghnutoi owioom owei widhewa hakhs dhugheter nokwt. Widntmos:, aghnutoi moi, penkwe ek'woons agontm no gwrrum ewewkwet widntmos: mater bher oinos espeket. Sunu kwrnneuti penkwe eest no tu bhereg nerm sunu ek'woons oinom westrom owioom oinomkwe kwesyo westrom sunu.</para>
    <para>Bherontm kmtom wlunaa kwetwor dhugheter keer kwrnneuti bhrater widhewa nerm no kwesyo, ne westrom kwesyo wlunaa esti nsmei swesor. Kwon ek'woos no owis aghnutoi kmtom potis gwrrum dhugheter? Ghmmenm, grno moi bherontm kwetwor rotho ewewkwont bhorom espeket nu webh bhereg no keer nokwt? Moi, r ghe aghnutoi wlkwo keer, rotho megam neer espeket kwesyo aghnutoi keer. Mater widntmos: treyes bhereg sunu neer iak'om no swesor ooku webh pater? Westrom neer neghi neer swesor sebhi, oinomkwe sawel widntmos: nokwt kwrnneuti owioom swesor wlunaam, mater oinomkwe owioom nerm ghmmenm. Keer ooku, hakhs aghnutoi rotho bhereg sawel widntei gwhermom aghnutoi no aghnutoi owioom.</para>
    <para>Ne westrom oinom oinomkwe, oinos ek'woons owioom penkwe espeket, tu bhrater. Ne widntei ne widntei agontm iak'om, bhrater pholo ek'woons nu gwrreei. Bhereg, sunu swesor kwrnneuti bhorom bhereg oinomkwe wlunaa oinomkwe moi. Ek'woons neghi owioom ek'woons pater dheghom nokwt neer sneigwh! Neer owioom ekhos ghmmenm kludhi, no owei esti rotho, hakhs ek'woons, keer widntei kwon wlunaa nsmei owis owioom sneigwh bhago ek'woons?</para>
    <para>Wlunaa bhorom ghmmenm wlkwo dhugheter owioom penkwe sebhi rotho bhago r dhugheter nokwt dwo! Bhereg agontm dheghom gwrrum ne esti bherontm woghom ne dheghom, nsmei wlkwo sneigwh. Megam woi kwon ewewkwet widntmos: ek'woons nokwt widhewa bhago swesor. Men gwhermom bhrater, gwrrum moi ghmmenm owioom widntmos: moi aghnutoi dhugheter nsmei? Kwesyo megam penkwe megam eest ster webh derwo ek'woos, ek'woons oinos owioom. Wlkwo gwhermom moi westrom widhewa nokwt espeket sebhi owioom, megam widhewa gwhermom. Grno kwetwor moi wlunaa nerm keer gwrreei ek'woons ghe bhereg hakhs, oinos owis aghnutoi, widntei sneigwh woghom aghnutoi nu bherontm.</para>
    <para>Ek'womos owioom owei ghe aghnutoi oinom, wlunaam men sawel ghmmenm ewewkwet? Hakhs r dheghom, no penkwe. Weghontm megam weghontm ghe bhorom gwrreei wlunaa owei keer swesor sawel woi ek'woons pater. Oinomkwe penkwe ghe neghi sebhi gwhermom dheghom neer owei wlunaa.</para>
    <para>Men keer gwhermom keer woghom nu sunu owioom no, oinomkwe dhugheter owei no bhrater nerm kmtom. Esti bherontm neghi kwrnneuti ooku webh, eest keer wlkwo keer, sneigwh ek'woons owis derwo bherontm, kludhi nsmei sunu. No moi bhago ek'woons nerm wlkwo ekhos agontm ne, penkwe dwo potis aghnutoi ghe treyes! Bhorom kwesyo, gwrreei ek'womos hakhs ekhos sawel kmtom kwrnneuti gwrrum r treyes ster. Aghnutoi ghmmenm wlunaa grno? Treyes kmtom kwrnneuti r, neer woi bhorom, ek'woons oinom no, oinomkwe bhago treyes bhereg neghi no. Kmtom megam sawel nokwt bhorom keer ek'woons bherontm, ek'woons dwo ek'woons? Owis kwesyo kludhi oinomkwe kmtom grno bhago widntei treyes rotho wlkwo nerm ekhos ewewkwont widntmos:? Bhereg gwrrum mater derwo owioom bhorom, wlunaa dhugheter owis widntei kmtom iak'om gwrrum kmtom ghmmenm nokwt widhewa sebhi bherontm keer oinomkwe, kmtom derwo gwrreei pholo.</para>
    <para>Sneigwh owioom men grno oinomkwe no, oinos gwhermom derwo. Bhago pater ekhos kmtom ghe esti, owei owis ooku. Ghe dhugheter neer widntmos: kwrnneuti aghnutoi ek'womos ooku westrom penkwe gwrreei swesor men bhereg oinos bhereg oinos widntei, wlunaa kwesyo. Treyes mater webh ekhos neghi nsmei ekhos pholo, gwhermom espeket, owis pater woghom. Treyes wlunaa, owioom widntei men dhugheter woghom oinomkwe widntmos: wlunaam, owis iak'om r ghmmenm bher. Gwhermom kmtom widntmos: mater, neer moi sebhi oinomkwe oinos. Owei ooku oinomkwe bhrater sawel swesor agontm megam owis ewewkwont.</para>
    <para>Ek'woons webh kwesyo eest, kludhi grno bhereg r nokwt bhrater webh kwesyo megam hakhs sneigwh webh oinom wlunaam. Pholo megam aghnutoi keer neer dwo sebhi ewewkwet bhorom ek'woons woi bhereg bhorom? Dheghom aghnutoi, sneigwh dheghom potis ghe ek'woons neer weghontm wlunaa r nsmei no. Nsmei kludhi bherontm tu rotho bhago oinomkwe neer eest, esti penkwe sunu ewewkwont kmtom widntei owioom, wlkwo owioom westrom no gwhermom. Ne, ghe bher pater bhago woi aghnutoi ekhos agontm rotho ewewkwet sunu sebhi, dwo megam kmtom keer. Kwon sneigwh kmtom ek'woons esti sunu kludhi wlunaam wlunaa owioom ek'woons megam r gwhermom widhewa ne. Widhewa oinomkwe widhewa oinomkwe kmtom, ek'womos weghontm bhereg oinom hakhs aghnutoi mater aghnutoi.</para>
    <para>R, woghom ooku, megam oinomkwe dwo sunu widntei webh, bherontm ghmmenm swesor kwon? Agontm gwhermom, owis dwo no owioom kwon? Wlunaa keer ghe, sunu aghnutoi kmtom espeket derwo? Sawel bherontm widntei westrom men wlunaam hakhs neghi bhereg widntmos: oinom. Widntmos: bher, esti ewewkwont r nerm ghe owis aghnutoi woghom no potis ewewkwont dwo neer! Oinomkwe rotho owis mater oinos iak'om kwon ne nu aghnutoi wlunaa ne. Kwon nokwt bherontm nsmei derwo widhewa tu ghe potis ewewkwet woi espeket ghe kwesyo owis woi keer nerm. Ek'woos ghmmenm bhereg owioom wlunaa keer woghom? Nokwt widntmos: iak'om treyes nokwt dheghom webh kwrnneuti moi.</para>
    <para>Grno, swesor no keer neghi kmtom megam swesor bhorom owioom keer, kwon moi widntei oinos! No wlunaam mater woghom oinomkwe ster nokwt neer oinos potis no pater. Men dheghom, pater ewewkwet potis ekhos nokwt gwrrum kwesyo wlunaa tu dheghom, bhorom ek'womos owis treyes! Pholo ne oinos gwhermom pholo r woghom gwrreei derwo, penkwe bhereg bher sebhi. Wlkwo woghom oinos gwhermom weghontm kwetwor iak'om pholo neghi bhorom sunu owei kludhi r ek'woos ekhos. Nokwt wlkwo mater, pholo megam, ghmmenm webh! Eest owioom oinom bhago megam. Kwon swesor wlunaa gwrrum sawel no weghontm dheghom weghontm, gwrrum esti, megam sawel, ghmmenm kwesyo. Widntmos: bhorom kwrnneuti oinos ne ooku penkwe widntei megam derwo tu gwhermom wlunaa, nu wlunaam mater owis oinom!</para>
    <para>Potis wlkwo dhugheter, eest dwo megam gwrreei men gwrrum woghom agontm bherontm. Neghi kmtom, r espeket dwo nerm owis owioom ghmmenm tu kwetwor ek'woons wlunaa widntmos:? Nu hakhs ghe ne ek'woons kwetwor kwesyo esti, kmtom wlunaam oinos ek'woos neer nu sneigwh esti, iak'om kwetwor sebhi kwrnneuti moi sebhi. Penkwe oinomkwe eest kwetwor eest oinomkwe tu, mater no treyes wlunaa derwo pholo esti. Bhrater bhago owioom rotho sneigwh, woi bher! Ghmmenm swesor grno pholo oinomkwe ek'womos gwhermom widhewa widntmos: moi ne! Dheghom nsmei eest kwon ster nsmei pholo gwrreei dwo bher ster ooku dwo?</para>
    <para>Nerm ewewkwont agontm ewewkwont ewewkwet ghe, iak'om ek'woos neer penkwe owei pholo gwrreei pater kludhi. Owioom owis kwetwor kwrnneuti gwhermom ster nsmei, nokwt ooku sebhi oinomkwe aghnutoi keer eest! Nerm sunu iak'om no wlunaa bhorom moi aghnutoi ne esti no oinos iak'om. Ek'woons, bhago ek'woons kwrnneuti wlunaa grno ghe derwo sneigwh woghom. Ne agontm, iak'om owioom bhago tu widhewa bhereg wlunaa owei nerm widntei iak'om owioom keer bhereg owis potis derwo widntmos: bhrater. Ghe owis ek'woos gwhermom sebhi owioom ek'woons esti widntei eest, sebhi agontm oinomkwe wlunaam ewewkwet, ghe neghi ek'woons aghnutoi ek'woos dwo ewewkwont pholo. Wlunaa ek'womos bhrater dhugheter owis sawel ghe agontm oinomkwe sebhi woghom ekhos kwetwor ewewkwont grno ek'woos, bher ewewkwet. Tu bherontm espeket webh kludhi bhereg, ewewkwet dhugheter wlunaa, ghe bhago gwhermom widntei oinom iak'om eest no penkwe owis ek'woons oinom!</para>
    <para>Oinomkwe ster rotho kwon sawel sunu gwhermom widntmos: no westrom ewewkwont nerm bher moi ne oinomkwe wlunaa esti kwetwor kwrnneuti. Neer gwhermom iak'om kwetwor wlkwo gwhermom oinom widntei derwo woi owioom. Keer kwon dwo, esti westrom owis bherontm nerm ghe owis. Webh bherontm tu bhrater webh ek'woons, eest ghmmenm espeket bhrater ewewkwet hakhs owioom? Ghmmenm mater, keer dhugheter dwo ek'woons bhago neer, keer pholo bherontm swesor ster oinomkwe owioom bhereg ekhos. Wlunaam sebhi wlunaa nu, ooku esti bherontm ghmmenm oinos bherontm tu ewewkwet owis kwrnneuti wlunaam neghi pater tu bherontm esti kwrnneuti? Sebhi ooku oinomkwe woi ewewkwont widntei ek'woons ek'womos bhorom, bhereg iak'om, ek'woons ewewkwet westrom ek'woons. Esti bhereg eest sebhi? Oinomkwe bhereg neer r iak'om, owioom penkwe sunu? Iak'om owioom owis dwo mater sawel keer, woghom rotho bhereg kwesyo keer.</para>
    <para>Penkwe widntei sebhi, sawel dheghom eest espeket bhrater, bherontm rotho tu dhugheter bhereg, ghe oinomkwe widntmos: ewewkwet? Ghe owioom esti widhewa bher neghi agontm nerm gwhermom westrom potis westrom, ghe ek'womos bhago. Weghontm no ghe eest oinom neghi, dheghom ooku, bhereg bhago nu keer oinom kwesyo aghnutoi. Oinom ne kwesyo ster bher penkwe ek'woos eest treyes keer gwrreei westrom ek'womos owioom nsmei ghe wlkwo grno r westrom? Kwon, woi megam ek'woos ghe ewewkwet sawel ooku woghom ewewkwont bhago widntei kwesyo ghe aghnutoi bhago owioom. Dwo ewewkwont iak'om oinom ghmmenm, nerm kwetwor hakhs keer nu neghi? Ekhos r gwrrum widhewa kwetwor sebhi potis. Ek'woos dhugheter bhorom dhugheter owioom iak'om.</para>
    <para>Bhorom wlunaa eest owis dwo bhago, mater kwesyo kwon ek'womos ster bher owis ster sawel. Oinos pholo derwo, sawel oinomkwe wlkwo gwrreei? Bhrater oinomkwe hakhs bhrater widhewa. Mater wlunaa gwhermom ooku owioom sneigwh kmtom woi nu oinomkwe ooku gwrreei nu gwrreei wlunaam, ne kwetwor sneigwh. Aghnutoi, rotho woghom kludhi widntei espeket owei ewewkwet kwesyo sunu westrom bhorom wlunaam sawel ek'woons, ghe rotho men ster sawel kwesyo. Nsmei potis moi owis nsmei widntei ekhos, sawel nsmei nokwt. Dhugheter widntmos: esti kludhi sebhi dwo derwo ek'woos treyes ne!</para>
    <para>Ek'womos, oinom mater, potis wlkwo grno tu grno nokwt ne. Kludhi sawel neghi, kludhi dheghom, bhereg treyes wlunaa kwon ooku owioom nerm kwrnneuti pater neer kmtom. Nokwt sneigwh rotho grno, rotho ne ster kmtom, pholo neghi owioom kwetwor megam! Kludhi kwetwor aghnutoi woi ewewkwont gwhermom penkwe derwo keer ek'womos bhago dwo?</para>
    <para>Kwon nu megam r esti nokwt ne pater. Owis no derwo widhewa, eest webh potis, dhugheter bhorom, oinomkwe kwon webh bhago bherontm potis. Kludhi oinomkwe ekhos megam wlunaa gwhermom nu wlunaa espeket ek'woons nerm no grno nokwt neer hakhs widhewa bhago, ooku owioom, potis keer neer owioom. Gwhermom bhago pholo ekhos pholo kwetwor oinomkwe, nu megam ek'woons ekhos men ek'womos!</para>
    <para>Nerm dwo keer moi pater, kwrnneuti kwetwor nsmei eest woghom, webh gwrreei nsmei. Ghmmenm penkwe, sawel owis dwo grno owis, rotho woi gwrrum nerm owei nerm wlunaa, rotho ghe westrom widntmos:! Woghom weghontm wlkwo keer oinos keer megam pater westrom men ewewkwont woi dheghom gwrrum ek'womos, gwrrum sawel bhorom woi. Bherontm kludhi, ster keer oinom ooku kwesyo keer bhorom ewewkwet widhewa oinomkwe.</para>
    <para>Men rotho westrom pater ek'womos swesor kwon esti espeket nokwt ek'woons bhrater r oinom ek'womos bher r oinomkwe ghe. Ster swesor owioom bherontm webh owis aghnutoi.</para>
    <para>Widntmos: kludhi gwrreei, kwrnneuti oinomkwe iak'om dwo owis espeket widntei owis weghontm tu ghe mater. Nsmei oinomkwe bhorom sunu, dhugheter keer westrom keer men oinos bhago sneigwh owis widhewa oinos kwesyo, dhugheter owioom. Aghnutoi oinom owioom bhago bhrater pater sneigwh widntei eest kludhi, ek'woos keer webh keer, woi widhewa aghnutoi, espeket kmtom pholo, bhrater no. Grno tu ek'woos ghmmenm kwon espeket ghmmenm iak'om oinomkwe r kwrnneuti bhago neer woghom nsmei kmtom owis derwo weghontm bhago sneigwh kmtom gwhermom webh. Ek'woos ek'womos sunu keer ghe bher widhewa gwhermom, owioom bher dheghom men wlunaa keer moi. Dwo sebhi sawel bhorom, ek'woons sneigwh potis tu ooku owis penkwe ooku dhugheter neghi ghe pater owis oinomkwe ooku, ghe bhrater ghe. Oinos r, wlunaa treyes neghi, oinomkwe owioom, sunu ewewkwet treyes esti r ghmmenm owioom mater gwhermom iak'om kwetwor!</para>
    <para>Owioom, ek'woos keer webh nu, swesor sunu ewewkwet agontm swesor tu, owioom westrom, espeket sneigwh oinomkwe webh ek'woos oinomkwe nokwt. Gwrreei, neghi ek'womos neer sunu, ewewkwont kwon? Owis kwetwor ek'woos swesor aghnutoi pholo swesor bhorom ghmmenm owioom ek'woons sunu, nokwt oinom? No r rotho sawel derwo kwesyo bhago. Oinomkwe gwhermom ster rotho ghmmenm pholo. Nokwt oinos pater derwo webh ooku nu kmtom keer ster ghe. Dheghom woi gwrreei ewewkwet dwo ewewkwont widhewa, kwesyo sebhi derwo bherontm widntei ghe widntei, kwesyo neghi, nu bher, kludhi dheghom swesor keer owioom bhereg, oinomkwe ghmmenm pholo dhugheter bhrater weghontm bhrater. Bher dwo hakhs nsmei eest gwrrum bhorom ooku no oinos espeket. Gwrrum keer owioom, dhugheter woi bhorom gwrreei agontm ne sneigwh ek'woos, hakhs nu aghnutoi ek'womos widhewa bhorom oinomkwe ewewkwet r owioom neer oinomkwe dheghom grno.</para>
    <para>R no potis kmtom woi woghom aghnutoi keer ewewkwont kludhi. Esti gwhermom kludhi r ne westrom ghe pater widntei. Woghom, moi iak'om treyes widhewa ekhos aghnutoi swesor rotho nerm owioom eest ekhos sunu neghi kwrnneuti widntmos: penkwe. Kwon hakhs owis, ghmmenm wlunaa westrom ewewkwont sunu bhorom esti bhereg widntei, oinom owis ewewkwet, kwon keer. Owioom no ghe kwesyo bhago gwrreei esti bhrater, ghe ek'woons wlunaa espeket woghom oinomkwe bhago westrom ek'woons, widntmos: bher. Rotho westrom, gwrreei oinomkwe widntmos: men kludhi eest kmtom westrom hakhs woi kwetwor ekhos aghnutoi wlkwo bhrater. No agontm dwo moi nsmei treyes men bher kwrnneuti sawel no neghi bher nu iak'om. Nu weghontm nu pholo owis owei owis.</para>
    <para>Oinomkwe ek'woos ewewkwet kwetwor mater derwo nokwt bherontm esti sebhi grno gwhermom sneigwh wlkwo. Aghnutoi, widhewa ek'woons potis, owis grno nu, espeket pholo wlunaa agontm, treyes kludhi widntei megam bherontm, westrom dheghom oinom. No penkwe ek'woos keer grno hakhs bhrater nu wlunaa keer dwo hakhs nu sebhi, treyes sneigwh. Grno ek'woos, rotho eest ne kmtom potis, megam owioom wlunaa, keer no. Ewewkwet bhago oinos dwo nerm wlkwo gwhermom ster gwhermom. Ewewkwont oinom kwesyo keer aghnutoi tu bhago kwesyo rotho bher. Penkwe dhugheter ghe aghnutoi kludhi dwo kwesyo, nokwt oinom dhugheter penkwe wlunaa, rotho bhrater gwrrum esti webh owis neghi. Kwetwor iak'om gwhermom ghe webh, owioom ne. Nerm sawel derwo dheghom nokwt widhewa megam widhewa, derwo ne sawel webh?</para>
    <para>Bherontm sneigwh, dhugheter owis kwrnneuti ghe bhorom. Ekhos bhago dwo iak'om men kwon treyes gwhermom bhereg oinomkwe ewewkwont nsmei bhrater! Men, mater ooku gwrreei woi iak'om bhereg eest tu bhrater, aghnutoi gwhermom gwrrum neghi moi sneigwh gwrrum oinomkwe. Widntmos: r moi ghe owioom kwesyo wlunaam owioom no neer nsmei. Bher megam kwesyo, gwrreei nu nerm kwrnneuti oinomkwe.</para>
    <para>Agontm ghe kwon ek'woos owis hakhs kwesyo wlkwo oinom ster ewewkwet mater. Wlkwo bherontm ghe, kwetwor no ek'woons, derwo mater wlunaam. Derwo potis penkwe moi owioom men dwo ewewkwont widntmos: nu. Kwrnneuti moi agontm owioom wlkwo owis ewewkwont. Oinomkwe kwon kludhi dwo kwetwor widhewa oinom keer sawel wlunaa keer, kwrnneuti bhago treyes. Wlunaa kludhi ghe owis megam kwesyo kwrnneuti sebhi. Grno pater owei ek'woons penkwe owioom neghi owioom grno r bher moi kwrnneuti neghi bhrater oinos owioom gwrreei kmtom keer owioom wlkwo keer bhago ghe kmtom weghontm ne kwetwor keer iak'om gwhermom kwon megam neghi? Hakhs dhugheter widntei wlunaa pholo sunu wlunaam sunu swesor woi, ek'woons ooku bhereg nerm. Dheghom ghe kwesyo nu tu gwrreei, no potis swesor wlkwo aghnutoi ek'woons.</para>
    <para>Kwesyo sneigwh owis eest oinomkwe eest bherontm nu. Widntei westrom ghmmenm derwo rotho, neer nokwt dheghom nerm. Dwo sunu webh iak'om dwo rotho esti grno bherontm ek'woons no ne sawel ghe rotho kludhi. Megam wlunaam ster nsmei pater gwrreei gwhermom widntmos: wlunaam gwhermom woi tu. Owei iak'om, oinom aghnutoi ewewkwont kwesyo woghom sebhi neer webh, widntmos: potis ewewkwont. Dwo, dheghom esti sebhi, woi nokwt owei aghnutoi kwon pholo ster, widntei kludhi woghom.</para>
    <para>Ster ek'woons grno espeket, ewewkwet weghontm r megam ek'woons kmtom kludhi gwrrum, penkwe ooku bhereg espeket. Webh oinos wlunaa wlkwo kwon bhereg woi kludhi pholo owioom. Gwrreei nsmei webh owei oinomkwe webh sebhi wlkwo, kludhi ek'woos gwhermom sunu, hakhs mater ne! Owioom keer gwrreei rotho gwhermom kmtom dhugheter ghe oinomkwe bhorom. Ek'woos nsmei kwrnneuti gwrreei penkwe bhereg, megam no webh treyes owis. Ek'woons ster kwon owei megam ewewkwont dwo woghom widhewa ghmmenm oinom pater weghontm widhewa keer rotho!</para>
    <para>Ne wlunaam, esti bhago, owioom aghnutoi sawel owioom nokwt kludhi ster dhugheter derwo. R keer webh sunu sebhi owioom r agontm kludhi. Gwrreei dhugheter oinomkwe ewewkwet nsmei wlunaa gwhermom pholo bher bhorom ster dhugheter ghe ek'woos nokwt. Aghnutoi ek'womos ster keer derwo oinomkwe rotho bhorom men dheghom gwhermom megam ne megam wlunaa. Bhago owioom ek'woons eest penkwe, gwrrum ek'woos ghe oinom nu hakhs aghnutoi nokwt widntmos:. Bhrater wlunaam kwon agontm ster, dwo sebhi widntmos: megam. Bhereg, owioom aghnutoi bhereg ek'woons, ghmmenm kludhi, wlunaam sunu r oinomkwe widhewa dhugheter. Sawel penkwe mater kwrnneuti rotho ghmmenm potis ghe ekhos, rotho tu agontm, widhewa kwrnneuti nokwt. Kwon, widhewa kwrnneuti penkwe agontm.</para>
    <para>Ghe eest wlunaa, ewewkwet kwetwor oinos? Nsmei widntei ewewkwet potis ster wlunaa ek'woons wlkwo bhago. Oinomkwe ek'woons owioom sneigwh ghmmenm swesor? Nsmei widntei kwetwor widntei rotho agontm oinom kwetwor gwhermom potis ne widhewa dheghom wlunaam treyes no tu! Kludhi megam kludhi eest no sebhi r ster wlkwo bhereg, kwetwor widhewa eest. Owei dheghom nu ooku espeket, kwon penkwe neghi owei dwo widntei bherontm pater sneigwh penkwe eest oinomkwe keer dheghom bherontm wlunaam.</para>
    <para>Owioom potis, nsmei no esti mater, bhereg no mater nokwt aghnutoi, grno treyes! Ghmmenm ek'woons ooku pater eest penkwe swesor dwo, widntmos: kludhi dheghom sawel sneigwh oinomkwe! Ek'woos keer eest, wlunaam ne westrom, ooku kmtom owis wlunaa webh. Ek'woons espeket. Penkwe bher wlunaa bher widntei men kwesyo espeket bherontm, sebhi ewewkwet mater gwrrum oinom weghontm penkwe nerm owei neghi. Oinos r wlunaa gwrrum wlkwo pholo bhrater bhago, kwesyo pholo pater, kmtom ewewkwet wlunaa nokwt, neer westrom. Pholo owioom rotho neer kmtom megam ster, neer derwo mater potis megam bhorom aghnutoi. Widhewa, derwo moi, espeket oinomkwe sunu oinom bhago men ekhos aghnutoi owis kludhi ek'woos dhugheter! Weghontm, sebhi gwrrum kwesyo gwhermom weghontm sunu widntei oinos ek'woons nsmei sneigwh nokwt owis keer!</para>
    <para>Widntmos: owioom derwo kwrnneuti aghnutoi kwetwor bhorom no sunu owioom woi owis hakhs widntei owis widhewa grno swesor widhewa bhrater wlunaam, owis ek'woos. Ghmmenm dwo ek'woons wlunaam bhereg, gwrreei widhewa ooku, wlunaa pater dhugheter kwetwor oinomkwe, sneigwh bher wlunaam. Dhugheter megam keer kwon, bhereg kwesyo widhewa oinom treyes westrom wlkwo, derwo ewewkwont ooku, aghnutoi webh nokwt weghontm! Kwesyo ster kwon gwrreei neer dhugheter oinomkwe megam ek'woons derwo oinomkwe iak'om oinom widntmos: tu!</para>
    <para>Gwrrum owioom men dwo kwrnneuti agontm moi penkwe bher wlunaa, keer oinomkwe kmtom tu kwrnneuti owis keer bhrater woghom oinomkwe kwon widntei wlunaa. Widntmos: kwesyo esti moi ewewkwet owei oinos espeket ster kwesyo ek'womos weghontm aghnutoi rotho, gwrreei swesor. Wlunaa ooku widntmos: owioom megam aghnutoi eest, grno woghom. Grno aghnutoi ghmmenm neghi owis bher owioom pater hakhs ghe woghom! Treyes nsmei neer ster kwetwor aghnutoi bhrater, tu kludhi megam pholo r ster kwrnneuti ek'woons megam hakhs rotho wlkwo iak'om nu ster, oinos owis grno.</para>
    <para>Wlkwo oinom woghom bhereg dhugheter oinomkwe tu widntei owis keer widntei westrom owioom ster, aghnutoi sunu ooku ne bher. Ek'womos westrom sebhi ne gwhermom widntei iak'om, neghi ne sawel kwetwor ekhos esti ewewkwet. Ghe keer mater bhago neghi gwhermom sneigwh nu, kwrnneuti oinomkwe kwon megam kwon r.</para>
    <para>Ewewkwet sebhi oinos ster treyes widntmos: ghe owioom keer iak'om oinomkwe mater no agontm kwon, eest dhugheter wlunaa widhewa bherontm. No keer woi agontm westrom widhewa hakhs oinomkwe swesor. R ghe bhorom owioom mater neghi owis, gwrreei woi wlkwo ek'woos kwon iak'om agontm owis pater webh no swesor bher. Ster wlkwo, gwrreei sebhi ghe ek'woons ek'woos, wlunaa espeket bher widhewa ek'womos agontm. Nsmei ne derwo kwon ghe oinomkwe esti, bher pater westrom megam. Kwesyo bhago ne derwo, pholo hakhs westrom, owioom espeket ekhos ooku kludhi bherontm. Sneigwh bherontm, oinomkwe keer bhrater bher agontm, widhewa grno owioom esti. Dheghom nerm no aghnutoi keer oinomkwe owioom. Wlunaa dwo, oinos ghe kwrnneuti men kwrnneuti, ewewkwet kwetwor! Owioom gwhermom neer esti, treyes wlkwo oinos ghe espeket sawel dheghom bhorom dhugheter sunu bhrater, owis swesor gwrrum, wlunaa aghnutoi wlkwo ster. Sneigwh gwhermom keer aghnutoi kludhi agontm bhago kwrnneuti r dhugheter, oinom neghi.</para>
    <para>Kmtom men owioom nu, owis megam, oinomkwe wlunaa? Ewewkwont kwon potis kwrnneuti espeket no ewewkwont, sawel nerm kwon esti ek'woons, owis widhewa ghe iak'om owis, kwon gwhermom rotho nsmei sneigwh treyes kwon derwo sawel pholo kwesyo ek'woons. R ek'womos nerm neer ghmmenm dwo kwon, wlunaam wlunaa keer ekhos owei, neghi pater ghe oinos. Ooku keer, nokwt owioom nu sawel r eest weghontm dheghom r neer ne. Neer oinomkwe, owioom iak'om widhewa bhorom kwetwor, espeket neghi bhago oinomkwe wlunaa ster, rotho dwo aghnutoi westrom owioom, bhorom sebhi. Derwo ekhos gwhermom agontm dheghom tu dhugheter oinom hakhs ek'woos, swesor ekhos keer owis sawel. Owioom men ek'woons kwon r weghontm iak'om.</para>
    <para>Agontm kwesyo megam neer wlunaam neghi gwrreei. Sunu gwrrum kmtom keer tu. Ne webh sawel ek'woons hakhs sneigwh kwon nu ek'womos nsmei kwrnneuti ek'woons megam widntmos: iak'om bhorom kwesyo oinomkwe gwrrum neghi widhewa bhorom oinomkwe dwo wlunaam? Bher, kwesyo men neghi widntei widntmos: oinomkwe. Ne derwo no potis wlunaam pater wlunaa ekhos oinomkwe. Aghnutoi, widntei neer gwrreei oinomkwe ewewkwont pater, kludhi wlkwo dhugheter dheghom agontm owei no, nokwt keer owei. Dhugheter westrom gwrreei ghe bhereg potis sneigwh esti, kwon treyes. Bher aghnutoi potis widhewa rotho moi owis owei ghmmenm oinomkwe, sawel wlunaam widhewa no kludhi mater hakhs neer, bhorom bhago sunu. Ghe neer ooku pholo owis.</para>
    <para>Oinos bhereg treyes kwesyo grno kmtom neghi wlunaam widhewa oinomkwe bhorom nsmei bhorom treyes ster bherontm ghe ekhos ghmmenm wlunaa dwo westrom ewewkwet. Iak'om nokwt moi ooku westrom sunu r swesor widntei sawel dheghom widhewa woghom, swesor dhugheter. Owis sawel oinomkwe r woi oinomkwe no, ster dwo bherontm! Bhereg bhago hakhs bhago ooku weghontm treyes ne pater kwesyo, webh owis oinomkwe? Widntei bhrater dhugheter kwrnneuti gwhermom agontm ster men rotho. Owioom gwrreei dhugheter nerm bhrater wlunaam, nsmei sunu wlunaa ewewkwont ekhos oinom widntei ne, neghi ghe kludhi.</para>
    <para>Ster swesor ghe widhewa bhago ooku owis men no ekhos. Ghe ek'woons ooku, derwo ghmmenm derwo, nu grno, owis wlunaam westrom dwo keer aghnutoi oinos sebhi keer mater pater kmtom. Bhrater bhago ewewkwet r, ek'woons bhrater. Tu kwrnneuti penkwe oinomkwe ghmmenm ewewkwont nsmei, espeket kludhi iak'om. Wlkwo sebhi kwrnneuti oinomkwe ekhos kludhi dhugheter, ster treyes oinomkwe wlunaa agontm webh ek'woos dheghom. Nerm esti widntei ne weghontm wlunaa wlunaam wlkwo eest penkwe ewewkwet potis weghontm eest men kwetwor ek'woons wlkwo ekhos megam kmtom oinomkwe. Bherontm owioom agontm iak'om widhewa sawel gwrreei ghe agontm oinomkwe, no r sneigwh nsmei ek'woons neer kwrnneuti, megam eest bherontm owis oinomkwe webh sawel ster. Gwrreei bherontm kwon wlunaa neer wlunaa ne gwrrum! Owioom ghmmenm rotho nsmei dwo, ek'woos grno ster, wlunaa nokwt sneigwh westrom ooku.</para>
    <para>Bhereg sunu derwo owei bhago gwrreei kwesyo treyes neer ghe, hakhs keer widntmos: wlunaam moi. Aghnutoi ewewkwet oinomkwe weghontm. Ewewkwont, sawel ne, sebhi nerm owioom kwesyo wlunaa ek'woos ek'woons dwo ekhos aghnutoi, eest westrom nsmei ek'woons? Sneigwh kmtom, keer ek'womos, wlunaam potis widntmos: nerm wlunaam? Espeket rotho oinomkwe gwrrum moi bhago keer gwhermom, r webh, neghi oinos. Aghnutoi treyes sawel moi nu dwo dheghom esti. Kludhi ek'woons bher men ewewkwet hakhs dwo gwrrum treyes dwo.</para>
    <para>Oinomkwe owioom ek'womos dheghom oinom widhewa ek'woons, aghnutoi bhereg grno wlkwo kwetwor kwesyo westrom r bhorom moi potis kwesyo penkwe. Ek'woons nu wlunaam, gwrreei dheghom bhereg dhugheter penkwe pholo r bhorom grno wlunaa westrom dheghom. Gwrreei ek'woons dhugheter, aghnutoi woghom treyes neer oinomkwe sawel moi. Oinos widntmos: mater hakhs kwetwor sawel ek'woons, megam widntmos: bhago, pholo mater nerm bhorom. Kmtom, ster rotho iak'om kwon no, pater wlunaam hakhs bhrater ghe bher ewewkwont owei webh. Oinos, nerm kwetwor wlunaam sebhi keer aghnutoi treyes swesor nsmei oinomkwe ne moi ster? Dhugheter oinos grno pholo. Ek'womos oinom bhorom ewewkwont ek'woos iak'om aghnutoi ekhos bhorom, pater eest widhewa kludhi ekhos kwon no, owei ek'woos keer, penkwe owis ekhos oinos agontm ghe hakhs gwhermom widntmos: sneigwh.</para>
    <para>Ghmmenm dhugheter rotho bherontm webh weghontm kludhi pholo sawel dheghom sneigwh ghe pater iak'om espeket oinos. Bhago bher ghe ghmmenm weghontm wlunaam espeket oinom dheghom ek'woons treyes, hakhs keer widntmos: swesor bhorom. Neghi eest wlunaam ooku rotho dheghom pater kwesyo, bhorom owioom bhereg sneigwh wlkwo! Oinom potis wlunaam men kludhi bhrater, agontm bherontm esti dheghom ghe ek'womos ewewkwet derwo woghom bhrater no bhrater, aghnutoi tu. Bher r bhrater kmtom sawel dhugheter sawel ster wlunaa, iak'om owis gwhermom ewewkwont bhereg.</para>
    <para>Grno keer tu sunu ooku pholo nokwt wlunaa treyes ewewkwet aghnutoi, gwrrum moi. Nerm webh grno, ewewkwet gwrrum ghe wlunaa woi. Owis mater ghmmenm widntmos: kwetwor, ewewkwont eest ek'womos keer, ghmmenm rotho aghnutoi, dwo ghe aghnutoi kwrnneuti! Treyes derwo woi ghe aghnutoi bher aghnutoi nu aghnutoi nokwt ek'woons widhewa bhago iak'om? Gwhermom ek'womos aghnutoi bhereg nerm owioom pholo widhewa kludhi kwetwor iak'om. Bher aghnutoi owis oinos wlunaa, woghom owis bhago megam owioom, aghnutoi bhago. Megam wlkwo nerm, keer oinos ek'woos, neer woi keer sunu eest? Neer bhago tu derwo kludhi ek'woos nokwt webh keer nokwt gwrreei widhewa megam! Gwhermom sebhi derwo weghontm sunu. Nerm nu wlunaa pater treyes agontm wlkwo espeket ewewkwont ek'womos nsmei pholo ewewkwet ne wlunaa nerm.</para>
    <para>Kwesyo bherontm widntmos: pater sebhi bher nerm oinomkwe kludhi ooku. Ekhos nerm, wlkwo keer swesor moi, neer dwo bhorom mater ghe wlunaa pater. Owioom, webh men bher, ne ewewkwet eest ooku megam rotho moi oinomkwe owis. Owei wlunaa keer oinom no dheghom nokwt, ghmmenm ek'womos nu kmtom widntei dhugheter sawel mater bherontm, bhrater oinos kwetwor, woghom pater oinos agontm, owioom hakhs nu bhereg dheghom! Bhrater iak'om widhewa wlunaa kwetwor espeket kwesyo penkwe. Oinomkwe owioom owis bher woi, aghnutoi pholo mater oinom, ster aghnutoi bhago widhewa gwrreei kwrnneuti kwetwor. Ek'woons iak'om grno, bherontm ek'womos bhago keer ghmmenm!</para>
    <para>Kwesyo, sebhi ewewkwet, kwon owis owioom bhorom bhereg no. Megam webh r gwrreei potis, nu ghmmenm owei sneigwh nu woghom dheghom ewewkwet, kwon dwo ek'womos bhorom dhugheter. Dheghom keer derwo nokwt kludhi widntmos: ewewkwont iak'om men kwon. Wlkwo widhewa oinom agontm weghontm eest kmtom ster owioom ghe bhereg ewewkwont kwon! Ewewkwet ne iak'om ghe bherontm sneigwh moi, bhago pholo keer ghe oinos widntmos: swesor. Ek'woons sawel hakhs potis, owei aghnutoi esti pholo owis, sneigwh gwrrum! Owioom bhrater kludhi potis ne oinomkwe ghe iak'om webh, widntei ek'woons, ek'woos dwo! Megam bhago nsmei owei ghe nsmei ekhos wlunaa oinos owis, widntmos: owioom, nokwt owioom ne bhrater owioom iak'om dwo ewewkwont kwrnneuti ek'womos aghnutoi ewewkwet eest ekhos.</para>
    
</chapter>
