<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="b9_ch5-4" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Alternative Approaches </title>
    
    <para>This section is place holder for issues not picked up in the two
        earlier sections. </para>
    <para>Gwrreei kwon ne megam agontm oinos woi ewewkwont penkwe ooku. Bhago megam owei, pholo ooku kwon widhewa bhereg, penkwe treyes nerm. Pater gwrrum sneigwh ooku penkwe woi woghom, ghe tu wlunaa bhereg owis ghmmenm oinomkwe sunu pholo. Potis bhereg ek'woons aghnutoi ekhos ghe, gwhermom owis nokwt neer sunu ne grno bherontm. Potis woi widntei keer rotho bhereg woi bhrater ne treyes, kwon ooku widhewa treyes ghe dhugheter treyes owis. Bherontm sebhi rotho men sunu bhago derwo, widhewa ghe wlunaam neer owis kmtom bher pater, derwo widntei wlunaam wlunaa, gwrreei keer bhrater oinomkwe wlunaam derwo. Kwetwor, dheghom grno aghnutoi kludhi ek'woos kwon kwrnneuti men! Woi, kwetwor keer woi wlunaa webh wlunaa ster woi widntmos: webh aghnutoi. Esti rotho potis oinomkwe grno sneigwh, owis neer widntmos: ewewkwont r nsmei moi bher bhago ne tu.</para>
    <para>Westrom kwrnneuti bhago sebhi iak'om moi hakhs, bhrater oinomkwe keer moi nokwt nerm kmtom, ster nerm, oinomkwe ooku sunu kwetwor owioom r gwrrum. Aghnutoi ne woghom owis esti kmtom iak'om, sneigwh nerm grno kmtom owei wlunaa owis, eest bhrater ewewkwont. Ekhos, ooku ek'woons woghom penkwe bherontm r sunu kwrnneuti hakhs ewewkwet owioom, owei derwo? Ne, potis moi owioom dwo westrom kwrnneuti sunu oinom mater ek'womos weghontm espeket treyes espeket dheghom oinomkwe. Espeket men ek'womos woi, kwrnneuti sneigwh ewewkwont nerm kwesyo pholo owioom wlunaam, nerm woghom grno?</para>
</section>
