<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xml:id="b9_ch5" version="5.0" status="In Preparation">
    <info><title>Stormwater Conveyance</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kus_ben.xml"/>

    </info>
    <para>With contributions from the Book 9 editors (Peter Coombes and Steve Roso)</para>
    <informaltable border="1">
        <tr>
            <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Date last updated</td>
            <td>15/05/2018</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Content</td>
            <td>Final</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>General</td>
            <td>For publication </td>
        </tr>
    </informaltable>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_seut7">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>Stormwater conveyance combines hydrological and hydraulic methods to safely convey
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145752+1000" content="stormwater generated by rain falling on urban surfaces"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145752+1000"?>rainfall
            generated stormwater<?oxy_insert_end?> to an outlet.
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145806+1000" content="The a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145806+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?>nalysis
            of conveyance infrastructure
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145811+1000" content="will"?>
            typically
            include<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145815+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>
            the hydrology of sub-catchments that transfer rainfall runoff to inlet structures
            feeding a network of other conveyance infrastructure including pipes, open channels,
            roadways and open space. </para>
        <para>Conveyance infrastructure is one of the many tools available to the designer for urban
            stormwater management which is part of the process of managing the water cycle. For
            example a stormwater management strategy for an urban area will include a wide range of
            measures to manage stormwater runoff volumes and flow rates,
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145838+1000" content="such as"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145838+1000"?>for
            example<?oxy_insert_end?> on-site detention, bio-retention,
            rainwater<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145859+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145904+1000" content=" and"?>
            stormwater harvesting and infiltration systems. These may alter the
            inflows<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145920+1000" content=" to"?>
            and the design of the stormwater conveyance network as shown in <xref
                linkend="b9_ch5_f_s4eek"/>. These volume management measures (as described in <xref
                linkend="b9_ch4"/>) can operate at different scales such as source and neighbourhood
            controls that alter inputs to conveyance networks and regional controls that mitigate
            outflows from conveyance networks. </para>
        <para>This chapter focuses on the design and analysis of stormwater conveyance
            networks.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_s4eek">
            <title>Stormwater conveyance and volume management within an urban stormwater
                network</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9083.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_j339y">
        <title>Design Philosophy and Objectives</title>
        <para>Design of urban stormwater conveyance networks
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145934+1000" content="has been"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145934+1000"?>are<?oxy_insert_end?>
            comprehensively addressed in guidelines within Australia and internationally. These
            guidelines include
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145943+1000"?>various
            <?oxy_insert_end?>aspects of
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145956+1000" content="the"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T145956+1000"?>stormwater<?oxy_insert_end?>
            design<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150009+1000" content=" of stormwater"?>
            infrastructure with different
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150024+1000"?>detail
            <?oxy_insert_end?>levels<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150030+1000" content=" of detail"?>
            that
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150041+1000" content="often "?>concentrate
            on key areas of design focus (such as urban developments or main highways) or on
            problematic areas of concern that are specific to a locality or past events. It is
            generally the responsibility of the designer to select an adequate design procedure.
            However,
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150048+1000" content="the "?>objectives
            and attributes of stormwater conveyance networks are often specified by
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150055+1000" content="the "?>local
            approval authority. These authorities may base their guidance on other design
            specifications and guidelines such as Aus-Spec, Austroads, or the Victorian
            Infrastructure Design manual</para>
        <para>This section provides an overview of the philosophy and objectives for design of
            stormwater conveyance networks. The primary focus of this section is hydraulics and
            hydrology, and design safety requirements. Nevertheless, there are other important
            aspects that should be considered during the planning and design of conveyance networks.
            These include constructability, aesthetics, future maintenance, direct costs, long term
            economic factors, and the potential liability created by a conveyance network. The
            design should also account for the practicality of replacing conveyance infrastructure
            at the end of its design life. </para>
        <para>A key hydraulic criterion is to define a conveyance network that restricts surface
            flows to safe limits. The primary design requirement is that stormwater depths should
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150128+1000" content="be "?>not be
            greater than a threshold value above the top of inlet pit or invert of a road gutter.
            This prevents inlet pits filling to the brim under design conditions which inhibits
            stormwater flows from entering conveyance networks. The threshold depth is typically set
            by
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150139+1000" content="the "?>relevant
            approval
            authorit<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150145+1000" content="y"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150145+1000"?>ies<?oxy_insert_end?>
            and is in
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150152+1000" content="the "?>order of
            150 mm. Approval authorities also typically specify maximum velocities of surface flows
            and minimum velocities of flows in conveyance infrastructure. </para>
        <para>In situations where surface flows are conveyed through public places, including
            footpaths, roads and public places, it is important to ensure that unacceptable hazards
            to people are not created (see <xref linkend="b9_ch8"/>).
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150203+1000" content="These hazards are minimised by k"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150203+1000"?>K<?oxy_insert_end?>eeping
            the depth and velocity-depth attributes of surface flow within acceptable
            limits<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150213+1000"?> will
            minimise the hazards<?oxy_insert_end?>. When the primary purpose of a pathway is for
            conveyance of stormwater, it will usually be more efficient to convey flows in a
            dedicated watercourse that can accept higher velocity and depths of flows. These types
            of flow paths can be designed for dual uses (stormwater conveyance and public access)
            provided that the design ensures that people cannot be trapped by stormwater flows. </para>
        <para>These limits are intended to ensure that networks operate at given levels of service
            without causing<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150230+1000"?>
            peoperty<?oxy_insert_end?>
            flooding<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150239+1000" content=" of properties"?>,
            nuisance or hazard to pedestrians and to traffic on streets. An approval authority
            typically specifies the design AEP of
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150249+1000" content="the "?>minor and
            major storm events required for different land uses. Designs usually involve minor
            system capacity criteria for
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150313+1000" content="design of "?>conveyance
            infrastructure
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150315+1000"?>design
            <?oxy_insert_end?>and major system assumptions to ensure the urban area can safely cope
            with larger storm events as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_sdilj"/>.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_sdilj">
            <title>Minor and Major concepts for conveyance networks</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9038.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_sdilj"/>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150405+1000" content="shows that the minor system is used to define the performance of the conveyance networks which include overland and bypass flows on roads, and performance of conveyance infrastructure (such as pipes and culverts). The major conveyance system includes the road profile and overland flow paths, and aims to ensure the safety of pedestrian and vehicle traffic whilst avoiding property damage and risk to life. In the absence of guidance from a consent authority"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150405+1000"?>shows
            that the minor system is used to define the performance of conveyance networks that
            include overland and bypass flows on roads, and performance of conveyance infrastructure
            (such as pipes and culverts). The major conveyance system includes road profile and
            overland flow paths, aiming to ensure pedestrian and vehicle traffic safety while
            avoiding property damage and life risk. In the absence of guidance from consent
            authority<?oxy_insert_end?>, the design AEP storm events are selected to reflect the
            importance of a facility or urban area and the consequences of failure. Some examples
            are:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Roof drainage systems: 5% to 1% AEP;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Conduit drainage systems through lots or sites: 0.5 EY to 1% AEP, depending on
                    consequences of failure;</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Conveyance networks in streets: 0.5 EY to 5% AEP for minor flows, 2% or 1% AEP
                    for major flows (See <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>) (note that the street profile is
                    part of the major conveyance network);</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Trunk conveyance networks: 1% AEP or higher, with checks on effects created by
                    PMP storm events;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Stormwater quality and sediment control devices: 4 EY to 1 EY but may address
                    the full spectrum of rainfall frequencies (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>);</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>On-site detention (see <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>): the requirements vary but
                    should aim to improve the performance of stormwater management scheme at a
                    sub-catchment scale; and</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Large detention basins (see <xref linkend="b9_ch4"/> and <xref
                        linkend="b9_ch6"/>) that may endanger lives if failure occurs: 1% AEP with
                    checks using probable maximum precipitation (PMP) storm events.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Both design and analysis processes involve modelling
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150454+1000" content="the operation of a "?>conveyance
            network
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150459+1000"?>operation,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150507+1000" content="that is"?>
            subject to critical rare storm events that produce maximum flowrates for the selected
            AEP events.
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150516+1000" content="The s"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150516+1000"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?>election
            of critical storm
            events<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150522+1000" content=" will"?>
            involve finding storm durations<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150528+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150534+1000" content="or particular "?>storms
            within ensembles or continuous sequences of rainfall that create maximum outputs for a
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150546+1000" content="particular "?>location.
            Typically,
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150554+1000" content="the design of a "?>conveyance
            network <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150559+1000"?>design
            <?oxy_insert_end?>is shaped and sized to cater for critical storms for selected AEP
            events. This approach recognises that:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>It is not practical or economically feasible to design conveyance networks to
                    be free of failure for all events. An attempt to do this would result in very
                    large and expensive conveyance networks that would occupy a considerable land
                    space. This would impact on the optimum provision other infrastructure services,
                    such as water pipes and electricity conduits;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Failures can occur in response to rare or extreme storm events or other
                    factors such as blockages due to poor maintenance, and exacerbating
                    circumstances such as high tide levels in coastal areas;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A risk management approach should be adopted that accepts controlled
                    failure;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Ideally the acceptable level of risk should be set by community values and
                    economic analysis, and;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The effects of potentially rare failures should be limited by providing a
                    ‘fail safe’ system that does not fail disastrously.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para> Analysis techniques should include sensitivity checks to ensure that damage and risks
            to lives due to failures are limited. Some
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150610+1000" content="failures of the "?>network
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150612+1000"?>failures
            <?oxy_insert_end?>and overflows can be expected during major storm events, as shown in
                <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_sdilj"/>, but the network should operate without causing
            safety hazards or large-scale property damage.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_h00bb">
        <title>Conveyance Networks</title>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150624+1000" content="The d"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150624+1000"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?>esign
            or analysis process for conveyance networks requires observation of the real world
            situation; definition of the problem and objectives of the design; development of a
            conceptual model of real world behaviours; calibration using observed data; and
            predictions or design. A conceptual model of a conveyance network involves hydrological
            and hydraulic modelling
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150632+1000" content="that includes"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150632+1000"?>including<?oxy_insert_end?>
            components such as inlet pits, pipes, open channels, roadways and storages. A general
            overview of the modelling and design process is presented in <xref
                linkend="b9_ch5_f_2a26n"/>.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_2a26n">
            <title>The Stormwater Design Process</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9084.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_2a26n"/> shows that the stormwater design process includes
            hydrological modelling of rainfall runoff from urban surfaces to generate inputs to
            hydraulic modelling of the conveyance network. This process usually incorporates a
            hydrological model than translates design or real rainfall patterns into design
            flowrates and volumes of stormwater arriving at inlet structures within a conveyance
            network. A hydraulic model then converts these inflows into flow characteristics
            (depths, elevations, widths,
            velocities<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150713+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            and volumes) throughout the network. The design analysis then
            determines<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150721+1000" content=" the"?>
            attributes of the conveyance
            infrastructure<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150740+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            such as pipe diameters and invert levels. The steps in the conveyance design process
            include:</para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Define the real world situation to be modelled. This will include land use,
                    demographics, topography, urban form, local climate, upstream and downstream
                    conditions, and location within a river basin or waterway catchment.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Determine the objectives and design standards that should apply to the
                    drainage network.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Locate any available rainfall runoff data that can be used to calibrate models
                    used to design the drainage network or collate the most appropriate parameters
                    for the catchment.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Choose the rainfall inputs, hydrological and hydraulic modelling methods for
                    design or analysis:</para>
                <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Rainfall inputs may be design storm temporal patterns of storm bursts
                            or full volume storms, ensembles of peak burst or full storms, or long
                            sequences of real rainfall (see <xref linkend="book2"/> and ARR Data
                            Hub). </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The hydrology and hydraulic models may be hand calculations but will
                            typically be some form of computer model (See <xref linkend="book5"/>
                            and <xref linkend="book7"/>).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Analyse land uses, road and open space networks, and topography to develop the
                    connectivity stormwater runoff processes throughout the catchment. This includes
                    gathering information such as: </para>
                <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Survey and information defining topography;</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Geotechnical and soil information;</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Plans of the development or facility to be designed; and</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Identifying constraints, such as easements and external drainage
                            networks.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Define a model network of sub-catchments and drainage infrastructure that is
                    an acceptable approximation of the real system. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Using topography, rainfall, land uses, the spatial location of other urban
                    infrastructure and knowledge of the capacity of various drainage inlet
                    structures, define the spacing of nodes in the conveyance network and the
                    routing processes. The routing processes can include gutter flows, overland
                    flows, bypass flows and pipe, culvert or channel flows.</para>
                <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The routing processes can include gutter flows, overland flows, bypass
                            flows and pipe or culvert or channel flows</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Calibrate or validate the hydrology and hydraulics of the existing catchment
                    to any gauged data or nearby flood frequency information or accepted parameters
                    for the area</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Use the model to design the capacity and spacing in inlet structures, and to
                    size the conveyance infrastructure. This design process will be guided by the
                    objectives and design standards that are applied to the project at Step 2. This
                    process includes:</para>
                <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Definition of a trial layout of a drainage system made up of inlets,
                            pipes, open channels, and storages;</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Using a model to define the sizes and locations of components.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Determine the adequacy and safety of the design for all relevant storm events
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Prepare plans, specifications and design reports and provide essential
                    instructions on how to build the conveyance network.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Review the design, obtain approval from the required authorities and proceed
                    with construction or implementation.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>Urban stormwater conveyance networks are usually a dendritic or tree-like structure
            that transports stormwater by gravity. Stormwater runoff is collected using inlet
            structures (pits) in different branches that converge at junctions along main lines and
            flow toward an outlet. Inlets structures located at the top of and along network
            branches:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>admit stormwater runoff into the conveyance infrastructure,</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>provide locations where pipe diameters and directions can change,</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>provide access for inspection and maintenance, and</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>provide overflow points (if necessary).</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Examples of underground pipe conveyance networks used in New South Wales and
            Queensland are provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_qpbaz"/>. </para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_qpbaz">
            <title>Examples of configurations of conveyance networks in New South Wales (left) and
                Queensland (right)</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9085.bmp"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_qpbaz"/> shows
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150936+1000" content="the "?>different
            configurations of conveyance networks used in New South Wales and Queensland
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150945+1000" content="which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T150945+1000"?>that<?oxy_insert_end?>
            highlights<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151057+1000"?> that<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151052+1000" content=" that "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151111+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?>a range of configurations are favoured across different jurisdictions.
            For example, in some Queensland jurisdictions, pipes are located under road
            centrelines<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151140+1000"?>, while
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151144+1000" content=" and "?>manholes
            at junctions in the conveyance network are used as collectors from inlet pits.
            Differences in terminology also occur across
            jurisdictions.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151156+1000"?> For
            example,
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151155+1000" content=" In "?>New
            South Wales
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151213+1000" content="(for example)"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151213+1000"?>uses<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151216+1000" content=","?>
            ‘kerb and
            gutter’<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151220+1000" content=" is used"?>,
            while in Victoria and Queensland
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151236+1000"?>uses
            <?oxy_insert_end?>the term ‘kerb and
            channel’<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151241+1000" content=" is employed"?>.</para>
        <para>In some cases, maintenance holes, junctions or junction boxes (pits) are provided as
            nodes linking branches in the conveyance network. Other pits that are intended to
            overflow are called surcharge pits, overflow
            pits<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151300+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            or ‘bubble up’ pits. In established urban areas, looped networks may occur where
            additional pipes are added to provide additional conveyance capacity
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151303+1000" content="which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151303+1000"?>that<?oxy_insert_end?>
            can change the behaviour of the original conveyance network. </para>
        <para>Conveyance infrastructure (for example: pipes, culverts,
            channels<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151310+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            and swales) are, mostly, constructed as straight sections with constant slope. Pipe and
            culvert conveyance infrastructure are available in standard dimensions supplied by the
            manufacturers. For example, the diameters of PVC pipes range from 90 mm to about 600 mm,
            and the diameters of reinforced concrete pipes start at 225 mm and increase to over 2
            metres. Road authorities usually specify a minimum pipe diameter
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151319+1000" content="of"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151319+1000"?>from<?oxy_insert_end?>
            300 mm to 375 mm within road reserves to improve maintenance outcomes.</para>
        <para> It is vital that conveyance networks include overland flow paths to control major
            stormwater runoff events. These overland flow paths should be within road profiles or
            through open space and pedestrian pathways. Flow paths through private property should
            be
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151342+1000" content="provided as a "?>last
            resort and will require an easement (a legal instrument providing a right to drain
            stormwater through a property and permitting authorities to enter the site for
            maintenance). Overland flows directed through private property can create hazards and
            inhibit
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151353+1000" content="the"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151353+1000"?>property<?oxy_insert_end?>
            development
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151426+1000" content="of the property as"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151426+1000"?>given<?oxy_insert_end?>
            the required easement cannot be blocked or built upon.</para>
        <para>Conveyance infrastructures (pipes) are designed to limit surface flows on roads to
            avoid nuisance to pedestrians and motorists. This process incorporates the design of
            roads <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151450+1000" content="which include"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151450+1000"?>including<?oxy_insert_end?>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151458+1000" content="profiles of "?>high
            location<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151508+1000"?>
            profiles<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151505+1000" content="s"?>
            (most often along road centrelines) and low locations (most often the inverts of
            gutters). The trapped low points in road networks require
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151526+1000" content="the "?>provision
            of sag pits
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151533+1000" content="which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151533+1000"?>that<?oxy_insert_end?>
            will usually inform the required network of conveyance infrastructure (pipes)
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151539+1000" content="that"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151539+1000"?>and<?oxy_insert_end?>
            can be realised by ‘joining up the dots’ between pits as shown in <xref
                linkend="b9_ch5_f_hqvt5"/>.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_hqvt5">
            <title>A typical configuration of a conveyance network</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9035.bmp"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>The configuration of an urban drainage network is demonstrated in a simple example of
            a single street in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_sa5dh"/>.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_sa5dh">
            <title>A simple example of a stormwater conveyance network</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9036.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_sa5dh"/> indicates the location of inlet pits at the top of a
            conveyance network.
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151618+1000" content="The street gutters are part of the conveyance network and are utilised to transport stormwater towards inlet pits that are situated at intervals to ensure that acceptable flows are carried in gutters. The width and depth of flows in gutters are limited to allow unimpeded access for pedestrians and vehicles. A maximum width of gutter flow of 2 m to 2.5 m with a maximum flow depth of 150 mm is generally acceptable. Local authorities will provide guidance on these values. Locations of inlet pits to ensure adequate conveyance of stormwater may also be determined from percentages of stormwater runoff captured by each pit, and the depth of flow and the velocity-depth product of flows in the road gutter."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151618+1000"?>The
            street gutters are part of conveyance network and are used to transport stormwater
            towards inlet pits situated at regular intervals to ensure acceptable flows are carried
            into gutters. The width and depth of flows in gutters are limited to allow unimpeded
            access to pedestrians and vehicles. A maximum gutter flow width between 2 m and 2.5 m
            with a maximum flow depth of 150 mm is generally acceptable. Local authorities will
            provide guidance on these values. Percentage of stormwater runoff captured by each pit,
            the depth of flow, and the velocity-depth product of flows in the road gutter will
            determine the inlet pit locations to ensure adequate conveyance of stormwater.
            <?oxy_insert_end?></para>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151718+1000" content="A designer would, typically, prefer to collect all stormwater"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151718+1000"?>A
            designer typically prefers collecting all stormwater<?oxy_insert_end?> runoff from the
            upper side of the street as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_sa5dh"/> with an inlet pit
            at Point D
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151728+1000" content="which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151729+1000"?>that<?oxy_insert_end?>
            avoids the need for conveyance branch in the street. This possibility is evaluated by
            establishing a trial location (A) where stormwater runoff from the corresponding
            catchment is calculated and the corresponding width of gutter flow is estimated. The
            width of flows will increase along the gutter length as the areas of contributing
            catchments increase. A pit must be located whenever any of the criterion limits (such as
            flow width,
            depth<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151745+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            or velocity-depth product) are reached. Note that the design process is about limiting
            surface flows.</para>
        <para>Capture of all stormwater runoff at inlet pit B reduces surface flow to zero
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151823+1000"?>by
            <?oxy_insert_end?>just downstream<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151826+1000"?>ing<?oxy_insert_end?>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151831+1000" content="of "?>the
            pit<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151834+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            with surface flows increasing again along the gutter due to lateral inflows from the
            catchment. However, it is unlikely that on-grade pits will capture all stormwater runoff
            from catchment areas during minor storm events
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151843+1000" content="which"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151843+1000"?>that<?oxy_insert_end?>
            create bypass flows downstream of the pit. This is shown at inlet pit C where the
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151915+1000" content="width of "?>flow<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151916+1000" content="s"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151920+1000"?>
            width<?oxy_insert_end?> increases and
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151931+1000" content="is reduced"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151931+1000"?>reduces<?oxy_insert_end?>
            due to the pit with a
            bypass<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T151955+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            and some width of flow just downstream of the pit. The flow widths along the gutter will
            typically follow a saw-tooth pattern.</para>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_sa5dh"/> also highlights that an inlet pit must be located
            upstream of a tangent point at an intersection to prevent excessive surface flows at the
            kerb return. Bypass flows from this inlet pit are collected at inlet pit D.
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152003+1000" content="The o"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152003+1000"?>O<?oxy_insert_end?>ther
            pits at the intersection are located along the path of surface overflows to collect both
            minor and major overflows. This configuration of inlet structures (pits) allows
            pedestrians to cross
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152010+1000" content="at "?>street
            corners without being exposed to large widths of flows.</para>
        <para>The location of inlet pits in the conveyance network may also be driven by a need to
            provide an inlet at a significant location, such as near a school with street crossings
            or at a change in road alignment. Aspects of good design practice include location of
            inlet pits upstream of driveways and avoidance of clashes with other services. A
            conveyance network also includes additional pipe connections from private property that
            should be incorporated in the design or analysis of
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152020+1000" content="the "?>conveyance
            network for the street. This may include directly connected pipes from sources such as
            inter-allotment drainage, onsite volume management systems (such as onsite detention and
            rainwater tanks),
            or<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152025+1000" content=" from"?> major
            commercial developments. The first inlet pit in the conveyance network for the street
            may<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152030+1000" content=" actually"?>
            be receiving considerable pipe flow from upstream private property.</para>
        <para>The designer needs to decide on the density of inlet pits in the conveyance network.
            This decision will typically be guided by the local authority. For example, the two
            arrangements of inlet pits at an intersection may be acceptable in two different
            scenarios as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_64v37"/>.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_64v37">
            <title>Example of alternative configurations of inlet pits at a road
                intersection</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9037.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_64v37"/>
            demonstrates<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152114+1000" content=" the"?>
            different arrangements that may be required at an intersection that could use two or
            four inlet pits. The decision about
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152123+1000" content="the configuration of "?>inlet
            pits <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152128+1000"?>configuration
            <?oxy_insert_end?>is dependent on the magnitudes and consequences of the flows that may
            bypass the inlet pits. In a densely-developed area, where overflows or bypass flows may
            cause nuisance and damage, a greater number of inlet pits will be preferred. Fewer inlet
            pits can be used in a lower density development where surface flows are more easily
            managed and the consequences of overflows or bypass flows are small.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_jkekw">
        <title>Design of Conveyance Networks with Computer Models</title>
        <para>Design of urban stormwater conveyance networks has a long history in Australia. Hand
            calculations using the urban Rational Method was discussed in the 1958, 1977 and 1987
            editions of ARR as the most utilised method for estimation of stormwater inflows to
            conveyance or drainage networks. There is significant ongoing concern
            about<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152148+1000" content=" the"?>
            reliable characterisation
            of<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152141+1000" content=" the"?>
            parameters (such as runoff co-efficient and time of concentration) underpinning the
            Rational Method due to insufficient rainfall runoff observations in urban areas
                <citation>b9_c5_r1</citation>.
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152156+1000" type="split"?></para>
        <para><?oxy_insert_end?>A transition into the computer age heralded the design and analysis
            of urban conveyance networks using computers to operate drainage software or spreadsheet
            manipulation that often implemented the Rational Method. The sizing of conveyance
            infrastructure was based on estimates of peak flows. Increases in computing power
            allowed greater access to software that integrated hydrology and hydraulics to more
            accurately analyse
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152203+1000" content="or"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152203+1000"?>and<?oxy_insert_end?>
            design conveyance networks using hydrograph methods. Additional details about urban
            modelling approaches are provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/>.</para>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152211+1000" content="The c"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152211+1000"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?>haracteristics
            of contemporary urban stormwater management have evolved to be different to the
            objectives and design solutions for urban stormwater drainage or conveyance networks as
            envisaged in 1987 <citation>b9_c5_r2</citation>. Since the 19th
            century<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152228+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152220+1000" content=" the"?>
            Rational Method and hand calculations has evolved into modern rainfall runoff models
            (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). The catchment area has been subdivided into
            sub-catchments. Average rainfall intensity derived from storm bursts
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152238+1000" content="has been"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152238+1000"?>is<?oxy_insert_end?>
            modernised to include temporal patterns, spatial variation, relationships between
            different burst rainfall depths and durations, and
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152244+1000" content="the "?>capture
            of partial areas effects. The runoff coefficient for estimation of stormwater runoff
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152249+1000" content="has been"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152249+1000"?>is<?oxy_insert_end?>
            replaced with processes that account for the degree of urbanisation and spatial
            distribution of different land uses, addition of loss models to determine rainfall
            excess, accounting for pervious and directly or indirectly connected impervious
            surfaces, and inclusion of depression storages. </para>
        <para>Rainfall runoff models have also incorporated connective components including:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>the shape of drainage networks; </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>addition of drainage network conveyance, travel times and system storages;
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152325+1000" content="a "?>separation
                    of minor and major systems; </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>response times of different components (such as roads and gutters); </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>bypasses of drainage pits and storages in sag pits. </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>These evolving models account for modern urban features
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152331+1000" content="that include"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152331+1000"?>including<?oxy_insert_end?>
            distributed storages such as rainwater tanks, bio-retention and on-site detention;
            detention basins and the spatial distribution of urban features (see <xref
                linkend="b9_ch4"/>). Modern design criteria
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152345+1000" content="may "?>include
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152352+1000" content="analysis of the "?>volumes,
            timing and frequency
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152359+1000"?>analysis
            <?oxy_insert_end?>of stormwater runoff to determine peak flow rates, water quality and
            requirements<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152415+1000"?>. This
            is done<?oxy_insert_end?> to mimic natural regimes of volumetric flows to protect
            waterway health <citation>b9_c5_r3, b9_c5_r4</citation>. Management of
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152432+1000" content="the volume of"?>
            stormwater runoff
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152436+1000"?>volume
            <?oxy_insert_end?>and the frequency of runoff events from urban catchments
            is<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152447+1000" content=" now"?> seen
            as a key design objective to mitigate downstream flooding and
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152452+1000" content="also to "?>protect
            the health of urban waterways. </para>
        <para>Predictions of peak stormwater flows using
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152456+1000" content="the "?>Rational
            Method may not adequately represent
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152505+1000" content="the "?>fundamental
            processes occurring within contemporary urban catchments <citation>b9_c5_r1</citation>.
            This concern is particularly relevant to modern stormwater management methods, such as
            Water Sensitive Urban Design (WSUD),
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152514+1000" content="that"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152514+1000"?>which<?oxy_insert_end?>
            include<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152516+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>
            cascading integrated solutions involving retention, slow drainage via vegetation,
            harvesting and reuse of stormwater and the disconnection of impervious surfaces. These
            distributed solutions within catchments alter runoff volume and timing in a variable
            manner throughout a catchment (see <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>). These dynamics
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152552+1000"?>are usually
            discovered through
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152550+1000" content="are more likely to be revealed by"?>
            advanced analysis methods. Importantly<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152631+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152635+1000" content="the "?>provision
            of optimum designs for urban stormwater management is dependent on testing solutions
            across the full range of urban dynamics.
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152647+1000" content="The l"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152647+1000"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?>imited
            urban data available for
            characteri<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152652+1000" content="z"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152652+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>ing
            the parameters underpinning the urban Rational Method for average urban conditions
            remains a challenge.</para>
        <para>The design procedure using computer models is typically implemented more easily and
            accurately than the simpler design methods.
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152659+1000" content="A"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152659+1000"?>One
            of the<?oxy_insert_end?> main
            advantage<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152705+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>
            is the ability of a computer model to rapidly perform design procedures once a system is
            set up and the necessary data is entered. In addition,
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152710+1000" content="the "?>use of
            computer software allows
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152715+1000" content="the "?>simultaneous
            analysis of
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152721+1000" content="both "?>minor
            and major storm events to adequately size inlet structures and conveyance infrastructure<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152728+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152733+1000" content="to ensure"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152733+1000"?>ensuring<?oxy_insert_end?>
            safe overland flow outcomes. </para>
        <para>The procedures for
            design<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152749+1000"?>ing
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152752+1000" content=" of "?>conveyance
            networks have evolved from simplifying assumptions required for hand
            calculations<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152759+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            such as assuming that pipes are flowing full but not under pressure. Modern methods
            include more calculations and checks, and can apply unsteady flow hydraulic simulations
            throughout conveyance networks. These complex calculations are implemented using
            computers. The amount of calculations is now so large that simple numerical checks using
            hand calculations are not possible.
            However<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152858+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            ‘sanity checks’ can (and should) be made to compare results from models using simplified
            procedures such as estimating flowrates per unit area. These simple checks will provide
            estimates that are different to the results produced by computer
            models<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152904+1000"?>,
            however,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152912+1000" content=" but"?>
            this process should assist in avoiding gross errors.</para>
        <para> Peak flowrates and hydrographs calculated by rainfall-runoff models are inputs to
            hydraulic models that determine the characteristics (elevations, depths, widths and
            velocities) of stormwater flows throughout catchments. Hydraulic modelling is based on
            physics and requires that
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152920+1000" content="the "?>geometry
            of components of a conveyance network should be carefully defined. Key hydraulic
            concepts such as Continuity, Conservation of Mass, Energy, and the Bernoulli's Equation,
            are covered in <xref linkend="b6_ch2"/>. The Friction Equations including
            Darcy-Weisbach, the Manning and the Colebrook-White Equations (<xref linkend="b6_ch2"/>)
            are all important considerations for
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152927+1000" content="the "?>hydraulics
            design of conveyance networks.</para>
        <para>A range of hydraulic models can be used to design conveyance networks. The performance
            of the models can be illustrated by
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152932+1000" content="h"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152932+1000"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?>ydraulic
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152936+1000" content="g"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152936+1000"?>G<?oxy_insert_end?>rade
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152940+1000" content="l"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152940+1000"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?>ines
            (HGL) and
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152948+1000"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?>energy
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152951+1000" content="g"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152951+1000"?>G<?oxy_insert_end?>rade
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152954+1000" content="l"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T152954+1000"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?>ines
            (EGL, also called total energy line,
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153010+1000" content="TEL"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153010+1000"?><?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180921T122131+1000" comment="Does this needs an expansion? "?>TEL<?oxy_comment_end?><?oxy_insert_end?>).
            These grade lines are described in books on fluid mechanics and
            hydraulics<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153136+1000" content=" and"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153136+1000"?>
            and<?oxy_insert_end?> are
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153111+1000"?>useful
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153107+1000" content="a most useful tool"?>
            for understanding flow phenomena.</para>
        <para> The design of conveyance infrastructure is highly dependent on the
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153149+1000" content="capacity of "?>inlet
            structures<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153201+1000"?>'s
            capacity<?oxy_insert_end?>.
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153212+1000"?>After
            i<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153215+1000" content="I"?>nlet
            structures (pits) are
            chosen<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153225+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153233+1000" content=" and then"?>
            surcharges from each structure are calculated<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153249+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153255+1000" content="which determines"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153255+1000"?>determining<?oxy_insert_end?>
            the possible cumulative surface flows throughout
            sub-catchments.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153313+1000"?>
            This is followed by checcking if<?oxy_insert_end?>
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153337+1000" content="A check is made to see whether "?>the
            hydraulic characteristics of surcharges exceed performance objectives for the network
            (such as safety and access criteria). If the performance objectives are exceeded, the
            size of inlet structures
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153353+1000" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153353+1000"?>needs
            to be <?oxy_insert_end?> increased using the next largest inlet structures and
            calculations proceed. During the design of inflows and associated dimensions of inlet
            structures, conveyance infrastructure (pipes) are also sized to ensure that the
            performance objectives are met. This process continues until a satisfactory level of
            surface flow is reached.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_wtcce">
        <title>Inlet Structures</title>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153422+1000" content="The performance of urban conveyance networks is dependent on the effectiveness of the inlet structures (pits) that capture stormwater runoff at regular intervals throughout the network. Relationships for the capacity of inlet structures determine the magnitudes of bypass flows and are an essential part of the design of conveyance networks. Designers should be concerned that flow widths and depths are within appropriate limits, both upstream and downstream of an inlet structure."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153422+1000"?>Performance
            of urban conveyance networks is dependent on the effectiveness of the inlet structures
            (pits) that capture stormwater runoff at regular intervals throughout the network.
            Capacity of inlet structures' relationship determines the magnitude of bypass flows.
            This is an essential part of conveyance networks design. Designers should be concerned
            that flow widths and depths are within appropriate limits, both upstream and downstream
            of an inlet structure.<?oxy_insert_end?>
        </para>
        <para>Designers need to consider that the effectiveness of inflow structures is impacted by
            the inflow of stormwater through grates or kerb inlets, and by the energy losses or
            pressure changes that are created by inlet structures (see <xref
                linkend="b9_ch5_f_chyg6"/>).
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153459+1000"?>Historically,
            p<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153503+1000" content="P"?>it
            losses
            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153514+1000" content="have been historically"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153514+1000"?>were<?oxy_insert_end?>
            simplified as a single simple coefficient that approximates the reality of entry losses
            to the pit, losses within the pit and exit losses from the pit. A simple single
            coefficient is generally used for many different types of inlet structures.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_chyg6">
            <title>Idealised hydraulic issues impacting on inlet structures</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9026.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_g4ltk">
            <title>Types of inlet structures</title>
            <para>A majority of urban stormwater runoff enters conveyance networks via inlet
                structures located in gutters and medians of roads. These inlet structures or
                drainage pits are classified by shape or configuration, and are also defined by
                location on a slope (on-grade pits) or in a depression (sag pits), as shown in <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_f_90esm"/>. On-grade and sag inlet structures are subject to
                different hydraulic processes. The behaviour of on-grade pits links inlet capacities
                to approaching flowrates and resulting bypass flows. Performance of sag pits is
                dependent on stormwater inflows and depths of ponded water over pits which cannot
                escape without passing over footpaths or crowns of roads.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_90esm">
                <title>Basic types of inlet structures</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9027.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>It is desirable for an inlet structure to maximise collection of stormwater
                runoff. However this objective must also in include the safety and convenience of
                pedestrians, cyclists and motorists, and costs of infrastructure. Open pit
                structures that may provide the greatest inlet capacity are unacceptable in most
                environments. The design of inlet structures must not permit children to enter the
                pit or the conveyance network. </para>
            <para>Grates and kerb inlet pits (also referred to as side entries or lintels) are
                typical inlet structures that are deployed either separately or in combination.
                Capacities of inlet structures can be improved by providing extensions to kerb
                inlets, deflectors (ribs or grooves that direct water into an inlet), depressed
                grates and gutters, or clusters of inlet structures that include adjacent
                installation of two or three standard pits. Grates and depressions of inlet
                structures should not be hazardous to road users, including cyclists, and their use
                should be avoided on busy narrow roads. Aspects of inlet structures for bicycle
                safety are discussed by the U.S. Federal Highway Administration
                    <citation>b9_c5_r5</citation>.</para>
            <para>There is limited information or simple relationships available for the capacity of
                many types of inlet structures. Many investigations of pit entry capacities have
                utilised hydraulic models. A range of significant historical studies were published
                by <citation>b9_c5_r5+1</citation>, the <citation>b9_c5_r36+1</citation>,
                    <citation>b9_c5_r6+1</citation> and <citation>b9_c5_r7+1</citation>. More
                general information about capacities of inlet structure are provided by
                    <citation>b9_c5_r8+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c5_r9+1</citation>,
                    <citation>b9_c5_r7+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c5_r35+1</citation>, and
                    <citation>b9_c5_r10+1</citation>.</para>
            <para>More recent laboratory experiments have examined capacities of different inlet
                structures at the Manly Hydraulics Laboratory in NSW and at the University of South
                Australia. The relationships obtained from laboratory tests do not extend to
                flowrates that may occur in extreme flood events such as 1% AEP or probable maximum
                floods. However, these relationships are still useful for most design problems as
                inlet structures in urban areas are predominantly used to admit inflows from minor
                or more frequent events into conveyance networks. </para>
            <para> The US Federal Highway Administration <citation>b9_c5_r11</citation> has
                published the general procedure for determining inflow capacities of on-grade pits
                in their Hydraulic Engineering Circular No. 22 (HEC-22). The efficiency of various
                grate types and impacts on inlet capacities for a range of approach grades and
                velocities are important considerations for urban conveyance networks. In addition
                to grate and kerb inlets, the capacities of slotted drain inlet structures are also
                relevant for locations where interception of wide sheet flow is desirable and low
                sediment and debris is expected. The HEC-22 pit inlet procedures are a useful source
                of information to aid design of inlet structures.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_b5ju4">
            <title>Inlet Capacities</title>
            <para>The hydraulic behaviour of on-grade and sag pits is quite different. These
                differences are discussed below.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Sag inlet pits </emphasis></para>
            <para>The capacities of sag pits are generally independent of upstream gutter slopes and
                are governed by weir and orifice equations which are dependent on the depth of
                ponding. The weir equations apply to flows that enter the pit at its edges or at the
                edges of bars in a grate. Alternatively orifice equations are applied when water
                ponds above the inlet structure at depths exceeding 0.2 m. The depth of ponding
                increases to a threshold level and stormwater will overflow as bypass flow by
                passing over a ‘weir‘ such as a road crown or driveway hump or wall.</para>
            <para>The approach and cross-fall grades of roads can affect the availability of storage
                volumes surrounding sag pits which can indirectly affect the overall behaviour of
                sag pits. These issues can be considered using hydrodynamic analysis of sag pits as
                small detention structures. Sag pits must have
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153547+1000" content="sufficient"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153551+1000"?>enough<?oxy_insert_end?>
                inflow capacity to accept the total inflows of stormwater runoff to avoid
                undesirable ponding of stormwater in intersections to limit obstruction to turning
                traffic, onto footpaths, into adjacent private properties or basement car parks, or
                over the crown of a road during a minor storm.</para>
            <para>Basic calculations for determining approximate inlet relationships for grated sag
                pits were derived by <citation>b9_c5_r8+1</citation>. However, it is preferable to
                utilise the HEC 22 procedures rather than the sag pit <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_33eks"
                /> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_z20vu"/> when side entry inlet relationships are
                required. </para>
            <para>For a grate,</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_33eks">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <semantics>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>Q</mi>
                                <mi>i</mi>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>=</mo>
                            <mi>B</mi>
                            <mi>F</mi>
                            <mo>×</mo>
                            <mn>1.66</mn>
                            <mi>P</mi>
                            <msup>
                                <mi>d</mi>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mn>1.5</mn>
                                </mrow>
                            </msup>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext>up to about 0</mtext>
                            <mtext>.12 m of ponding (d &lt; 0</mtext>
                            <mtext>.12)</mtext>
                        </mrow>
                    </semantics>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>or</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_z20vu">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <semantics>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>Q</mi>
                                <mi>i</mi>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>=</mo>
                            <mi>B</mi>
                            <mi>F</mi>
                            <mo>×</mo>
                            <mn>0.67</mn>
                            <mi>A</mi>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mo stretchy="false">(</mo>
                                    <mn>2</mn>
                                    <mi>g</mi>
                                    <mi>d</mi>
                                    <mo stretchy="false">)</mo>
                                </mrow>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mn>0.5</mn>
                                </mrow>
                            </msup>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext> </mtext>
                            <mtext>over 0</mtext>
                            <mtext>.43 m of ponding (d &gt; 0</mtext>
                            <mtext>.43)</mtext>
                        </mrow>
                    </semantics>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where </para>
            <para><emphasis role="italic">Q<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis> is the inlet flowrate
                    (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s),</para>
            <para><emphasis role="italic">BF</emphasis> is the blockage factor</para>
            <para><emphasis role="italic">d</emphasis> is the average depth of ponding (m),</para>
            <para><emphasis role="italic">P</emphasis> is the perimeter length of the pit excluding
                the section against the kerb (m) (bars can be disregarded),</para>
            <para><emphasis role="italic">A</emphasis> is the clear opening of the grate (m<superscript>2</superscript>), i.e. total area minus area of bars, and</para>
            <para><emphasis role="italic">g</emphasis> is acceleration due to gravity (approximately
                9.8 m/s<superscript>2</superscript>).</para>
            <para>The relationship for inlet capacity between depths of 0.12 and 0.43 is described
                by ARR 1987 as indefinite and <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_33eks"/> was recommended in
                that situation. For an undepressed inlet structure, the following relationships are
                recommended:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_bpw56">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <msub>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mi>i</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mi>B</mi>
                    <mi>F</mi>
                    <mtext> x </mtext>
                    <mn>1.66</mn>
                    <mi>P</mi>
                    <msup>
                        <mi>d</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>1.5</mn>
                        </mrow>
                    </msup>
                    <mtext>                               for ponding up to 1</mtext>
                    <mtext>.4 times the height of the inlet </mtext>
                    <mi>h</mi>
                    <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>d</mi>
                            <mo>≤</mo>
                            <mn>1.4</mn>
                            <mi>h</mi>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>or</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_97bt4">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <msub>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mi>i</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mi>B</mi>
                    <mi>F</mi>
                    <mtext> x </mtext>
                    <mn>1.67</mn>
                    <mi>A</mi>
                    <msup>
                        <mrow>
                            <mo>(</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                                <mi>g</mi>
                                <mn>9</mn>
                                <mi>d</mi>
                                <mo>−</mo>
                                <mfrac>
                                    <mi>h</mi>
                                    <mn>2</mn>
                                </mfrac>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>1.5</mn>
                        </mrow>
                    </msup>
                    <mtext>             for ponding greater than 1</mtext>
                    <mtext>.4</mtext>
                    <mi>h</mi>
                    <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>d</mi>
                            <mo>&gt;</mo>
                            <mn>1.4</mn>
                            <mi>h</mi>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where Qi is the inlet flowrate (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s),</para>
            <para> h is the height of the inlet</para>
            <para> BF is the blockage factor</para>
            <para> d is the average depth of ponding (m)</para>
            <para> L is the inlet width (m),</para>
            <para> A is the clear area of the opening (m<superscript>2</superscript>), and </para>
            <para> g is acceleration due to gravity (m<superscript>2</superscript>/s).</para>
            <para>Charts of the inlet capacity of depressed kerb inlets at sag points are provided
                by <citation>b9_c5_r8+1</citation> and in <citation>b9_c5_r11</citation>.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">On-Grade inlet pits</emphasis></para>
            <para>Calculation of relationships for inlet capacity of on-grade pits is more complex
                than for sag pits as several factors can change the capacity of inlets. These
                factors include:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>grade of the approach gutter (or channel) which will vary flow
                        velocity;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>road cross-fall which impacts the flow width and consequently the maximum
                        allowable flow depth at the inlet;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>roughness of the gutter and road pavement (or channel);</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>efficiency of the grate; and</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>entry conditions leading into the pit chamber such as gutter depressions
                            (<xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_2ifwh"/>) and the angle of the throat (<xref
                            linkend="b9_ch5_f_7uzyl"/>).</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_2ifwh">
                <title>Kerb inlet gutter depressions from HEC-22</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9028.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_7uzyl">
                <title>Kerb inlet throat angles from HEC-22</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9029.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The basic calculations to determine approximate relationships for inlet capacities
                of grate, side entry and combination inlets are provided by
                    <citation>b9_c5_r8+1</citation>. However, <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_bpw56"/> and
                    <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_97bt4"/> should not be used in preference to HEC 22
                procedures which have been hydraulically tested, and where the efficiency of various
                grate types is provided along with calculations for throat entry conditions. As an
                illustration, typical relationships for 1 m and 2 m on-grade kerb inlets are shown
                in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_2vdnh"/> that were derived using the HEC 22
                procedures.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_2vdnh">
                <title>Inlet capacities for on-grade pits</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9086.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Additional Information</emphasis></para>
            <para>Many different types of inlet structures are used across Australia and this
                chapter has only discussed some of the configurations. It is recommended that local
                capacity relationships, knowledge and experience, and types of inlet structures
                should be employed in designs for urban stormwater conveyance networks. In the
                absence of mandated design procedures that may be provided by a local authority,
                preferences should be given to local knowledge and experience, and to laboratory
                based methods. The designer and local authority should also accept first principles
                hydraulic analysis and evolving science in the selection of inlet capacities. </para>
            <para>Additional resources available to the designer include those provided local
                authorities such as VicRoads, the <citation>b9_c5_r12</citation> and from older
                resources including the <citation>b9_c5_r13+1</citation>, the
                    <citation>b9_c5_r34+1</citation> and the
                <citation>b9_c5_r31+1</citation>.</para>
            <para>The usual pit entry capacity relationships may not be adequate for analysis of
                conveyance networks subject to major rainfall events. In these situations, larger
                depths of surface flows, velocities and loads of debris may occur, and the inlet
                capacities of pits will be reduced (see <xref linkend="b6_ch6"/> for additional
                discussion). A blockage factor of 50% is generally applied for sag pits for minor
                and major systems in situations when experimental results or observations are not
                available. The blockage factor for on-grade pits can vary from 0% and 20% in
                response to local conditions. Higher blockage factors are often applied for events
                rarer than the 1% AEP. Additional advice on blockage factors is provided by
                    <citation>b9_c5_r43+1</citation> as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_t_oe842"/>.
                Higher blockage factors are often applied for events rarer than the 1% AEP.</para>
            <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch5_t_oe842">
                <caption>Suggested design and severe blockage conditions for inlet pits
                        <citation>b9_c5_r43</citation></caption>
                <col width="25%"/>
                <col width="25%"/>
                <col width="25%"/>
                <col width="25%"/>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td colspan="2" rowspan="2">Type of structure</td>
                        <td colspan="2">Blockage conditions</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Design blockage</td>
                        <td>Severe blockage</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="3"/>
                        <td>Kerb inlet only</td>
                        <td>0/20%</td>
                        <td rowspan="3">100% (all cases)</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Grated inlet only</td>
                        <td>0/50%</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Combined inlets</td>
                        <td>Capacity of kerb opening with 100% blockage of grate</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="4">On grade kerb inlets</td>
                        <td>Kerb inlet only</td>
                        <td>0/20%</td>
                        <td rowspan="4">100% (all cases)</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Grated inlet only (longitudinal bars)</td>
                        <td>0/40%</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Grated inlet only (transverse bars)</td>
                        <td>0/50%</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Combined inlets</td>
                        <td>10% blockage of combined inlet capacity on continuous grade</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <para>Ultimately relationships for the capacity of inlet structures determine the
                magnitudes of bypass flows and are an essential consideration in the design of
                conveyance networks. Designers must be concerned that flow widths, depths and
                product of depths and velocities are within appropriate limits at locations upstream
                and downstream of an inlet structure. These factors can be controlled by the careful
                location of inlet structures and by limiting bypass flows using infrastructure with
                sufficient inlet capacities.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_3wuje">
            <title>Energy losses</title>
            <para>Significant pressure losses may be created by inlet structures and junctions in
                conveyance networks. Hydraulic losses are generally reduced when open channel flows
                occur in conveyance infrastructure (pipes) and benching or smooth transitioning is
                provided within inlet structures. Higher losses occur at inlet structures when
                conveyance infrastructures (pipes) are full and surcharging in response to pressure
                flows. These losses at pits are offset by the increased capacity of pressurised
                pipes and the entire pressurised conveyance network may cope with greater flowrates.
                Energy losses at inlet structures are expressed as a function of the velocity
                    <emphasis role="italic">V<subscript>0</subscript></emphasis> in the outlet or downstream pipe:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_y2bb7">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <msub>
                        <mi>h</mi>
                        <mi>L</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                    <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>V</mi>
                                <mn>0</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow/>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mi>g</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where</para>
            <para>h<subscript>L</subscript> is the loss in m,</para>
            <para>k is a dimensionless energy loss
                coefficient, and </para>
            <para>g is acceleration due to gravity
                (m/s<superscript>2</superscript>).</para>
            <para>This energy loss at the inlet structure creates a change in the total energy line
                (TEL) as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_y8mnd"/>. The associated change in the
                hydraulic grade line (HGL) is likely to be different in response to different pipe
                diameters and flowrates upstream and downstream of the structure. The position of
                the HGL is important to designers as it determines the location of the water surface
                and the degree of surcharge or overflow which may occur at that location in the
                conveyance network.</para>
            <para>The change in pressure head is estimated as</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_3xvcw">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mi>Δ</mi>
                    <mi>P</mi>
                    <mo>/</mo>
                    <mi>γ</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>k</mi>
                        <mi>u</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                    <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>V</mi>
                                <mn>0</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow/>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mi>g</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where </para>
            <para>ΔP/γ is the pressure head change (m) relating to a change of pressure of ΔP kN /
                    m<superscript>2</superscript> and the specific weight of water
                    kN/m<superscript>3</superscript>, and</para>
            <para> k<subscript>u</subscript> is a dimensionless coefficient of change in pressure.</para>
            <para>A similar relationship can be applied to water levels within inlet structures
                which may be slightly higher than the HGL level dueto the conversion of some kinetic
                energy to pressure energy when stormwater flows through a pit:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_zj482">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mi>W</mi>
                    <mi>S</mi>
                    <mi>E</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>k</mi>
                        <mi>w</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                    <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>V</mi>
                                <mn>0</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow/>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mi>g</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where </para>
            <para>WSE is the elevation of the pit water surface (m) relative to the downstream HGL
                elevation, and k<subscript>w</subscript> is a dimensionless coefficient.</para>
            <para>These effects are illustrated in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_y8mnd"/>. </para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_y8mnd">
                <title>Idealised grade lines at an inlet structure</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9030.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The parameters <emphasis role="italic">k<subscript>u</subscript></emphasis> and
                    <emphasis role="italic">k<subscript>w</subscript></emphasis> are similar for
                most configurations of inlet structures and the water level in a pit can be assumed
                to coincide with the HGL level. The arrangement of grade lines in <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_f_y8mnd"/> is an idealised situation that assumes all changes
                occur at the centreline of the inlet structure. Losses
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153648+1000" content="actually "?>occur
                across the structure and immediately downstream in the conveyance infrastructure.
                The convention in measurement of the performance of inlet structures is to project
                grade lines (measured by manometers in the upstream and downstream pipes) forwards
                or backwards to the pit centreline and to accept the difference as the overall loss
                or pressure change.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Available Methods of Determining Pressure Loss Coefficient
                    k</emphasis><emphasis role="bold"><subscript>u</subscript></emphasis></para>
            <para>Studies using hydraulic models can be used to derive reliable values of energy
                losses and pressure changes for different types of pits and junctions. A significant
                study by <citation>b9_c5_r14+1</citation> dealt with pipes flowing full and produced
                a set of design aids for a selected configuration of inlet structures which are now
                called “Missouri Charts”. <citation>b9_c5_r15+1</citation>;
                    <citation>b9_c5_r16+1</citation> produced information on other configurations.
                The charts are complex and provide many possible geometric configurations of inlet
                structures. Careful judgement is required to select the appropriate chart for
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153700+1000" content="a particular "?>configuration
                of a structure, and in practice, iterative calculations are required to converge to
                a suitable value of the pressure loss coefficient.</para>
            <para>This iterative process can be quite time consuming for large conveyance networks.
                Attempts have been made to replace dependence on charts with semi-analytical
                methods. These range from relatively simple methods suggested by
                    <citation>b9_c5_r10+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c5_r33+1</citation> and
                    <citation>b9_c5_r17+1</citation> to more in-depth methods suggested by
                    <citation>b9_c5_r18+1</citation> and the US FHWA HEC-22 procedure from which the
                algorithm described by <citation>b9_c5_r19+1</citation> and
                    <citation>b9_c5_r20+1</citation> has been developed. The FHWA HEC-22 procedure
                was developed using research and laboratory efforts improving the methodologies of
                the ‘Corrective Coefficient Energy-Loss Method’ <citation>b9_c5_r40</citation> and
                the ‘Composite Energy Loss Method” <citation>b9_c5_r21+1</citation>. It is also the
                only method which considers part-full and full pipe flow, drops in pits and other
                situations.</para>
            <para>A summary paper by <citation>b9_c5_r22+1</citation> compared the different
                algorithms and could not find significant differences which suggested that no single
                method was superior. However, the information indicated that a viable algorithm can
                be developed, and that further testing and development is required for the methods
                to acceptably match the full range of configurations of inlet structures provided by
                the <citation>b9_c5_r16+1</citation>. The FHWA algorithm appears to provide a
                significant advance in the determination of head losses and pit pressure changes in
                stormwater conveyance networks. Comparisons with alternative algorithms and
                experimental data indicated that simpler methods may provide equivalent results for
                losses.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Determining Pit Pressure Losses in
                Practice</emphasis></para>
            <para>Determining pressure changes in practice is complex due to the many possible
                geometric configurations of inlet structures. Geometric configurations of pits can
                vary according to:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>number of pipes entering pits (0, 1, 2, 3 or more);</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>horizontal change of direction at the pit;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>vertical drop in the pit between inlet and outlet pipes;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>ratios of incoming and outgoing pipe diameters;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153730+1000" content="a number of"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153730+1000"?>several<?oxy_insert_end?>
                        secondary factors, including slopes of pipes, shape and size of inlet
                        structure, depths of sumps in the structure below the invert of the outgoing
                        pipe, streamlining (or benching) of the pit and the entrance to the outlet
                        pipe, and location of the confluence of the incoming pipes.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>Variances in flows are impacted by:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>magnitudes of flow and velocity;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>ratios of grate flow entering the top of structures compared to the
                        outflow; and</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>tailwater levels.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>The design calculations typically need to be repeated to achieve converging
                values. When designing to satisfy a freeboard requirement, revised coefficients may
                lead to circular alteration of pit and pipe inlet capacities which requires the
                designer to intervene.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Initial Estimates of </emphasis><emphasis role="bold">k<subscript>u</subscript></emphasis><emphasis role="bold"> before Commencing Iterative
                    Calculations</emphasis></para>
            <para>An analysis of the hydraulic grade line of a pipe requires an estimated value of
                k<subscript>u</subscript> at each inlet structure. Some government authorities may provide suggested values
                and experienced designers are likely to have developed ‘rule-of-thumb’ methods for
                determining these initial estimates of k<subscript>u</subscript>. Engineers are encouraged to use these
                methods in hydraulic design wherever the methods have proven to be effective.</para>
            <para>Guidance for initial estimates of k<subscript>u</subscript> is provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_d9yrz"
                /> for a range of common pit configurations. These are not absolute or recommended
                values for final analysis of a network and are only indicative starting points of
                iterations required to converge to a final value. These estimations assume shallow
                pipes with typical minimum covers and no increases in outlet pipe diameters. Deeper
                inlet structures may increase values of k<subscript>u</subscript> and increases in outlet pipe diameters
                may reduce values of k<subscript>u</subscript>.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_d9yrz">
                <title>Approximate pressure
                    change<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153751+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>
                    coefficients, k<subscript>u</subscript>, for inlet structures</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9087.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Simplified Approach</emphasis></para>
            <para>As discussed earlier, simplified design methods are available such as those
                presented by <citation>b9_c5_r17+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c5_r23+1</citation>, and
                    <citation>b9_c5_r10+1</citation>. Although these simpler methods may provide
                similar results to more complex semi-analytical methods, further laboratory research
                and development was recommended to account for the full range of pit configurations
                considered by the original Missouri Charts and by <citation>b9_c5_r15+1</citation>.
                Whilst simplified design methods may be considered for use during simple,
                non-critical pit and pipe network designs, use of Missouri Charts and Hare’s results
                is preferred. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Recommended Approach</emphasis></para>
            <para>The Missouri Charts <citation>b9_c5_r14</citation> and the results from
                    <citation>b9_c5_r15+1</citation> remain widely accepted and are relevant to an
                estimated 85% of the possible configurations of inlet structures. The example charts
                presented in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_yxn1u"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_0tx8n"/>
                are based on this information <citation>b9_c5_r12</citation>. The first chart (<xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_f_yxn1u"/>) was derived from the original Missouri Chart 2 with
                modification from the <citation>b9_c5_r32+1</citation> for an inlet structure with
                grate flow only. The pressure change coefficient k<subscript>u</subscript> depends
                on the submergence ratio S/D<subscript>0</subscript> and iterative calculations are
                required.</para>
            <para>The second example chart (<xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_0tx8n"/>) was modified from the
                Missouri Chart 4 to include the results from<citation>b9_c5_r15</citation>. The
                inlet structure accommodates flows straight through the pit for a submergence ratio
                    S/D<subscript>0</subscript> of 2.5 and
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153812+1000" content="also "?>considers
                inflows through grates. Here k<subscript>u</subscript> depends on the ratio Du/Do
                and provides flow ratios Qg/Qo ranging from 0 to 0.5. A correction factor needs to
                be added from <xref linkend="b9_ch5_t_x2nkl"/> when the submergence ratio
                    S/D<subscript>0</subscript> does not equal 2.5. </para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_yxn1u">
                <title>Pressure change coefficient chart <citation>b9_c5_r12</citation></title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9031a.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_0tx8n">
                <title>Pressure change coefficient chart <citation>b9_c5_r12</citation></title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9031b.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <table frame="void" xml:id="b9_ch5_t_x2nkl">
                <caption>Correction factors for k<subscript>u</subscript> and
                        k<subscript>w</subscript> for submergence ratios
                        (S/D<subscript>0</subscript>) not equal to 2.5
                        <citation>b9_c5_r12</citation></caption>
                <col width="14%"/>
                <col width="14%"/>
                <col width="14%"/>
                <col width="14%"/>
                <col width="14%"/>
                <col width="14%"/>
                <col width="14%"/>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="2"><emphasis role="bold">S/D<subscript>0</subscript></emphasis></td>
                        <td colspan="6"><emphasis role="bold">Q<subscript>g</subscript>/Q<subscript>0</subscript></emphasis></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.10</td>
                        <td>0.20</td>
                        <td>0.30</td>
                        <td>0.40</td>
                        <td>0.50</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>1.5</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.11</td>
                        <td>0.22</td>
                        <td>0.33</td>
                        <td>0.44</td>
                        <td>0.55</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2.0</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.04</td>
                        <td>0.08</td>
                        <td>0.12</td>
                        <td>0.16</td>
                        <td>0.20</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2.5</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>3.0</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>-0.03</td>
                        <td>-0.06</td>
                        <td>-0.09</td>
                        <td>-0.12</td>
                        <td>-0.15</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>3.5</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>-0.04</td>
                        <td>-0.08</td>
                        <td>-0.12</td>
                        <td>-0.16</td>
                        <td>-0.20</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>4.0</td>
                        <td>0.00</td>
                        <td>-0.05</td>
                        <td>-0.10</td>
                        <td>-0.15</td>
                        <td>-0.20</td>
                        <td>-0.25</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <para>Additional influencing factors become apparent as configurations of inlet
                structure become more complex; such as interpolation coefficients for intermediate
                grate flow ratios, presence of deflectors and additional lateral or sideline pipes.
                The second chart (<xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_0tx8n"/>) shows that k<subscript>u</subscript> can be negative in
                situations where the outlet pipe is larger than the inlet pipe and “pressure
                recovery” occurs due to the lower downstream flow velocities than the upstream
                inflow velocities.</para>
            <para>Large energy losses and pressure changes can be avoided by attention to simple
                rules in detailed design and construction. One principle is to ensure that jets of
                water emerging from inlet pipes do not impinge directly on pit walls. Wherever
                possible the stormwater jets from inflow should be directed into outlet pipes.
                    <citation>b9_c5_r16+1</citation> states that changes of flow direction should
                generally occur on the downstream face of pits, rather than at the upstream face or
                centre. Losses may be reduced by use of curved pipelines, precast bends and slope
                junction fittings at changes of flow direction. Typical loss factors for these
                fittings are:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>tee – k = 1.15 for energy loss expression kV<superscript>2</superscript>/
                        2g</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>90° double mitre bend – k = 0.47</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>60° double mitre bend – k = 0.25</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>45° single mitre bend – k = 0.34</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>22° single mitre bend – k = 0.12</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Benching</emphasis></para>
            <para>The recommended Missouri Charts do not include the effect of benching to reduce
                energy losses. Potential decreases in pressure change coefficients
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153841+1000" content="as a result of"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153841+1000"?>due
                to<?oxy_insert_end?> benching are provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_m3u9s"
                    />(<citation>b9_c5_r12+1</citation> Table 7.16.4).</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_m3u9s">
                <title>Decrease in pressure change coefficient as a result of benching
                        <citation>b9_c5_r12</citation>
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9134.PNG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Computer Models</emphasis></para>
            <para>Various procedures have been implemented in computer software. Some unsteady flow
                computer programs allow for pressure losses in rather simplistic ways, such as
                increasing pipe friction factors to include estimated pressure losses. Other complex
                procedures employed by computer software include:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>iterative processes based on Missouri Charts, geometry and hydraulic
                        results,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>semi-analytical algorithm based approaches, and</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>numerical methods.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_iy2cb">
        <title>Conveyance Infrastructure</title>
        <para>Urban conveyance networks collect rainfall runoff from urban surfaces (properties and
            adjacent roads) and utilise gutters, road surfaces, pipes, culverts and channels to
            convey stormwater to downstream infrastructure or receiving waters. This section
            discusses the design of conveyance infrastructure. </para>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_b6o76">
            <title>Hydraulic Models to Define Flow Characteristics</title>
            <para>The complexity of conveyance networks requires that simple calculations based on
                energy gradients are often replaced by more complex procedures. Rainfall runoff is
                collected at multiple entry points (inlet structures) and accumulates throughout the
                conveyance network. The necessary calculations combine these inflows and route them
                throughout a network by determining the water depths and velocities in the
                conveyance infrastructure. Simpler methods or models can do this for steady flows
                with unchanging flowrates whereas more complex models are required for unsteady and
                time-varying flowrates. Hydraulic grade lines (HGL) and energy grade lines (EGL) can
                be used to define flow depths, pressures and energies in conveyance networks as
                shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_bfuec"/>. Hydraulic models must allow for overflows
                when water levels exceed limits or pass over barriers. Additional information about
                hydraulic models is provided in <xref linkend="book6"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch6"
                />.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_bfuec">
                <title>Schematic of three hydraulic models of conveyance networks</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9025.bmp"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_bfuec"/> (a) demonstrates a simple model that accepts peak
                inflows derived from a hydrological model. It is assumed that steady flows occur in
                each pipe reach or link. Hydraulic grade lines are assumed to be located at the
                obvert (upper inside surface) of pipes and the flow condition is described as
                “flowing full but not under pressure”. Allowances for local losses are provided by a
                small drop (up to 90 mm, depending on change of flow direction) within inlet
                structures. The capacity of pipes can be calculated easily by applying a friction
                formula such as the Manning Equation and accounting for the grade of the pipe. The
                conveyance network is assumed to behave as a network of open channels and no
                allowance is made for upstream or downstream surcharges. </para>
            <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_bfuec"/> (b) shows a second approach to hydraulic analysis
                that also assumes steady-state conditions where peak flows occur as pressure flows
                in pipes and the HGL is located above or along the pipe obvert. This method includes
                energy losses and pressure changes at inlet structures that are likely to be greater
                than open channel flow assumptions where water levels are below pipe obverts.
                Capacity of pipes is also dependent on downstream water levels which may create
                backwater effects on flows in pipes.</para>
            <para>These methods accept peak flow from hydrological models and assume that peak flows
                occur simultaneously throughout the conveyance network. Flowrates are constant
                within each link and the calculated HGLs and EGLs represent upper envelopes of these
                flows. This process will usually estimate lower pipe capacities than unsteady flow
                assumptions.</para>
            <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_bfuec"/> (c) presents unsteady flow processes that are
                created by the inflow to the conveyance network of full hydrographs typically
                generated in computer models and real rainfall depths and patterns. The simulations
                account for the changes in water levels and flow characteristics in pipes and the
                network throughout storm events. These processes include dynamic effects such as
                fast-travelling waves generated by changes in flow conditions that can create shock
                losses in the conveyance network. This model is applied using computers that process
                and solve finite difference computations. A steady flow system is assumed to be
                independent of time and only requires one set of calculations. However calculations
                in computer models of unsteady flows are repeated for many time steps and pipe
                reaches are divided into several sections during the calculation processes. </para>
            <para>All three hydraulic models can be utilised for design and analysis. The first and
                simplest method can be used for design of small networks where downstream conditions
                may ultimately be varied to account for the actual behaviour of the conveyance
                network. These adjustments may not be possible for design of a fixed conveyance
                network, and the estimated capacities and impacts of conveyance network may be
                incorrect.</para>
            <para>The assumed steady-state flows and a connected hydraulic grade line throughout a
                network of the second method is more suitable for basic design and analysis tasks.
                This method is likely to provide more efficient designs as it more closely
                reproduces real behaviour and allows for surcharging of pits and pressure flows.
                This process may be used as a checking procedure by working backwards from the
                receiving water level towards the top of the catchment. </para>
            <para>This model was presented by ARR 1987 <citation>arr_1987</citation> as the
                preferred hand calculation method for hydraulic design of simple pipe networks.
                Calculations typically involve two iterations for a conveyance network. The first
                iteration commences at the top of the catchment, accumulating the flows arriving at
                each inlet structure, and allows for possible bypass flows at pits. The calculated
                flows through the conveyance network are used to determine the sizes of pipes and
                the invert levels at their ends whilst ensuring that HGLs do not rise above a limit,
                usually 0.15 m below the surface level of inlet structures. This design procedure
                involves a series of trials with increasing pipe sizes selected from the
                commercially available diameters. The smallest commercially available pipe diameters
                that meet the design requirements are typically selected.</para>
            <para>The iteration of the calculations
                commence<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153918+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?>
                at the outlet using a set tailwater level and project the HGLs upward towards the
                top of the catchment by considering the HGL slope due to pipe friction and the local
                pressure changes at each inlet structure. The previously calculated flowrates, pipe
                diameters and water levels in pits can be used in design charts such as the Missouri
                and Hare charts to determine local pressure changes at pits (see <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_s_wtcce"/>). When the upstream process of calculations
                reach<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153925+1000"?>es<?oxy_insert_end?>
                an inlet structure with two or more pipe branches, the calculations progress
                separately and upstream in each branch.</para>
            <para>This projection process can
                <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153932+1000"?>be
                <?oxy_insert_end?>employed
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153936+1000" content="for"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153936+1000"?>to<?oxy_insert_end?>
                part-full pipe flows, and
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153944+1000" content="for"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153944+1000"?>to<?oxy_insert_end?>
                pressurised and full-pipe flows.
                However<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T153948+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
                the straight water surface profiles assumed for part-full flows will not be exact. A
                more accurate procedure is to project water surfaces upstream using the
                gradually-varied flow methods commonly called backwater curve computations.</para>
            <para>Some designers of conveyance networks are still using the simple, steady flow
                procedures. However the unsteady flow models produce more realistic behaviours in
                response to hydrographs and flow volumes that are essential for analysis volume
                sensitive systems that include volume management facilities (see <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch4"/>). Modelling using unsteady hydraulic (and hydrology)
                assumptions is the preferred method for detailed analysis of conveyance networks
                that need to respond to strict constraints and where realistic modelling of network
                behaviour is needed. This approach is also essential for analysis of existing
                conveyance networks to replicate an existing deficit in performance or to reproduce
                a known flooding problem. There are many software products currently available that
                can be utilised for these types of analysis and design (see <xref linkend="b9_ch6"
                />).</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_fm486">
            <title>Overland Flow</title>
            <para>Conveyance networks receive and include overland flows. Overland flow is conveyed
                as sheet flow across land surfaces or in an overland flow path within a channel or
                swale. Sheet flow is typically produced when rainfall exceeds the volume of
                depression storages and infiltration capacity of a catchment resulting in overland
                flows travelling towards a receiving watercourse or an inlet structure in a
                conveyance network. Overland flows can also be escaping floodwater when the capacity
                of a conveyance network or watercourse is exceeded.</para>
            <para>Overland flow paths typically convey stormwater when the capacity of the minor
                conveyance network is exceeded as bypass flows between inlet structures along a kerb
                and gutter in a street, along swales in rural or grassed areas, or sometimes
                undesirably through private property. Calculations for overland flows are similar to
                open channels in that they
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154059+1000" content="can be"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154059+1000"?>are<?oxy_insert_end?>
                defined as
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154110+1000" content="a number of"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154110+1000"?>several<?oxy_insert_end?>
                different channel sections with constant cross-sections and slopes. However a key
                difference between overland flow paths and open channels is that overland flow paths
                are typically limited to shallower flow depths to meet safe design criteria. Open
                channels typically convey stormwater at greater depths and flowrates.<anchor
                    xml:id="_Toc421879435"/></para>
            <para>Urban stormwater management may combine buffer strips or vegetated swales or
                bioretention with overland flow paths as cost effective methods to facilitate
                attenuation of flows and removal of pollutants. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Limitations of depth and width of overland
                flows</emphasis></para>
            <para>The depths, widths and velocities of overland flows should be limited to meet
                objectives for safety and erosion. A range of conditions may be applied when a
                cross-section of a road is to be used to convey major and minor flows and the
                limiting factor is deemed to be the most restrictive criteria. These criteria
                include risks to pedestrians, particularly children, and the importance of the road
                for transport purposes. The following conditions should apply when guidance from a
                consent authority is not available:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The depth of stormwater flows at the kerb (d<subscript>g</subscript>)
                        should be limited to the lower side of a street to prevent uncontrolled
                        overflows from entering properties. For streets with 150 mm high kerbs and a
                        footpath with a substantial slope towards the gutter, a suitable limiting
                        depth may be 200 mm or to the height of a water-excluding hump on a driveway
                        plus an appropriate freeboard. In
                        addition<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154156+1000"?>,
                        a carriageway should not exceed the<?oxy_insert_end?>
                        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154212+1000" content="a"?>
                        maximum
                        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154144+1000" content="width of flow should not be exceeded in the carriageway"?>.
                        Greater depths may be tolerated where a street is significantly lower than
                        the land on both sides and in tropical areas with high rainfalls. A suitable
                        freeboard should apply to floor levels of habitable rooms in properties
                        adjoining the road.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The product of depth and velocity (d<subscript>g</subscript>.V), with V
                        being the average velocity in the gutter, should not exceed 0.4
                            m<superscript>2</superscript>/s for safety of pedestrians, 0.3
                            m<superscript>2</superscript>/s for stability of parked vehicles
                        (depending on size), or as directed by the consent authority (see <xref
                            linkend="b9_ch8"/>).</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Depths of stormwater flows should not exceed the height of the crown of
                        the road during minor storms or where flows are to be contained on one side
                        of a street. This includes locations that include ponding of stormwater such
                        as at sag pits. Depending on the importance of the road (local, collector,
                        arterial) and the importance of access, limits on width of flow of 2 to 2.5
                        m are typical.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Widths of flows may be limited to allow clear lanes in the centre of a
                        road for passage of vehicles. Flow depths should not exceed the height of
                        the crown of a road by more than 50 mm for major overland flow paths not
                        considered part of the trunk drainage system and in new development areas.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Dimensions of Flow</emphasis></para>
            <para>The Manning Equation can be used to calculate flows in trapezoidal style overland
                flow paths. Sheet flow is commonly estimated using a version of the kinematic wave
                equation for flow distances up to 130 m and then sheet flows are then concentrated
                into some form of gully or defined overland flow path
                <citation>b9_c5_r11</citation>. </para>
            <para>Equations for road gutters can be extended to calculate flows along full road
                cross-sections during major events. For a given flowrate, the normal depth
                corresponding to steady, established flow can be found by simple iterative
                calculations using a friction formula such as the Manning Equation. Although these
                assumptions may not be entirely valid, the errors involved may be generally
                acceptable.</para>
            <para>Design charts of the flow capacities of roadway cross-sections can be prepared
                using <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_dzy0v"/>. Allowable zones are defined by various
                limiting conditions and criteria as shown by the example in <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_f_9snjh"/>.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_9snjh">
                <title>Flow capacity chart for one side of an 8 m carriageway with 3%
                    cross-fall</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9088.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Gutter and Roadway Flow Equation</emphasis></para>
            <para>The following general equation developed by the U.S. Bureau of Public Roads
                    <citation>b9_c5_r8</citation> is recommended to determine flows in streets. With
                reference to <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_s9bk8"/> (a), the equation is:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_dzy0v">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mi>Q</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>A</mi>
                            <mi>B</mi>
                            <mi>C</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>−</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>D</mi>
                            <mi>B</mi>
                            <mi>F</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>−</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>D</mi>
                            <mi>E</mi>
                            <mi>F</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>−</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>G</mi>
                            <mi>E</mi>
                            <mi>H</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mn>0.375</mn>
                    <mi>F</mi>
                    <mrow>
                        <mo>[</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>Z</mi>
                                                <mi>g</mi>
                                            </msub>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>/</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>n</mi>
                                                <mi>g</mi>
                                            </msub>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>.</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <msubsup>
                                        <mi>d</mi>
                                        <mi>g</mi>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mrow>
                                                <mn>8</mn>
                                                <mo>/</mo>
                                                <mn>3</mn>
                                            </mrow>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </msubsup>
                                    <mo>−</mo>
                                    <msubsup>
                                        <mi>d</mi>
                                        <mi>p</mi>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mrow>
                                                <mn>8</mn>
                                                <mo>/</mo>
                                                <mn>3</mn>
                                            </mrow>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </msubsup>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>Z</mi>
                                                <mi>p</mi>
                                            </msub>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>/</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>n</mi>
                                                <mi>p</mi>
                                            </msub>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>.</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <msubsup>
                                        <mi>d</mi>
                                        <mi>p</mi>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mrow>
                                                <mn>8</mn>
                                                <mo>/</mo>
                                                <mn>3</mn>
                                            </mrow>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </msubsup>
                                    <mo>−</mo>
                                    <msubsup>
                                        <mi>d</mi>
                                        <mi>c</mi>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mrow>
                                                <mn>8</mn>
                                                <mo>/</mo>
                                                <mn>3</mn>
                                            </mrow>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </msubsup>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>]</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                    <msubsup>
                        <mi>S</mi>
                        <mn>0</mn>
                        <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                                <mo>/</mo>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                    </msubsup>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where Q (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s) is the total flowrate which is estimated
                by dividing the section as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_s9bk8"/>(a) and applying
                the equation by <citation>b9_c5_r29+1</citation> for a triangular channel with a
                single cross-fall:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_v944u">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mi>Q</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mn>0.375</mn>
                    <mi>F</mi>
                    <msup>
                        <mi>d</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                                <mn>8</mn>
                                <mo>/</mo>
                                <mn>3</mn>
                            </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                    </msup>
                    <msubsup>
                        <mi>S</mi>
                        <mn>0</mn>
                        <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                                <mo>/</mo>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                    </msubsup>
                    <mrow>
                        <mi>Z</mi>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>and: </para>
            <para>F is a flow correction factor,</para>
            <para>Z<subscript>g</subscript> and
                    Z<subscript>p</subscript> are the reciprocals of the gutter and pavement
                cross-slopes (m/m),</para>
            <para>n<subscript>g</subscript> and n<subscript>p</subscript> are the
                corresponding Manning's roughness coefficients,</para>
            <para>d<subscript>g</subscript> and
                    d<subscript>p</subscript> are the greatest gutter and pavement depths (m),</para>
            <para>d<subscript>c</subscript> is the depth of water on the road crown, and</para>
            <para>S<subscript>0</subscript> is the longitudinal slope (m/m).</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_s9bk8">
                <title>Gutter flow characteristics.</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9032.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para><xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_dzy0v"/> can be applied in simplified form when flows are
                contained in a gutter or on one side of a road. <citation>b9_c5_r24+1</citation>
                estimated values for F of about 0.9 for simple triangular channels and 0.8 for
                gutter sections of the type shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_s9bk8"/> (a). These
                assumptions may be used in the absence of more precise information. Typical values
                of n are 0.012 for concrete, 0.014 for asphalt, 0.018 for flush seal and 0.025 for
                stone pitchers <citation>b9_c5_r25</citation>.</para>
            <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154325+1000" content="The face of the kerb can be considered to be vertical in situations where the face of a kerb is relatively steep"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154325+1000"?>Consider
                the face of the kerb to be vertical in situations where the face of a kerb is
                relatively steep<?oxy_insert_end?>. <xref linkend="b9_ch5_e_dzy0v"/> can be applied
                to “lay-back” kerbs with sloping faces by assuming that zg is equal to w/dg as
                defined in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_s9bk8"/> (b). </para>
            <para>Open channel flow equations, such as the Manning Equation, can also be used to
                determine flows in lined gutters or unlined drains or swales.</para>
            <para>Flow depths and widths for a specified flowrate can be determined using <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_e_dzy0v"/>. Velocities are estimated by dividing the flowrate by
                the corresponding flow area. Travel times for stormwater conveyance can be derived
                by dividing gutter length by flow velocity. Distributed lateral inflows as shown in
                    <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_s9bk8"/> (c) can generate flowrates and characteristics
                such as width, depth and velocity that vary along a gutter. In this situation the
                average flow velocity occurs at about 60% of the distance along the gutter towards
                the inlet structure. Gutter flow calculations that use of the total flow arriving an
                inlet structure will overestimate velocities impacting on the structure.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Other Considerations</emphasis></para>
            <para>Gutter flow times depend on flowrates and it is necessary to specify a
                time<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154339+1000" content=" in order"?>
                to estimate a flowrate. A set of iterative calculations are required. In these
                calculations, a velocity or time is
                assumed<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154347+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
                and a flowrate calculated. Then a check is undertaken to determine whether the total
                time of flow in the overland and gutter flow paths agrees with the original
                assumption. </para>
            <para>A precise calculation of gutter flows must allow for concentrated inflows such as
                bypass flows from an upstream pit at the upper end of the gutter or an outflow from
                a large site at some point along the gutter. A representative design flowrate must
                be estimated to permit calculation of the average velocity and travel time.</para>
            <para>Parked vehicles and driveways may interrupt and widen surface flows. The limited
                experimental evidence available suggests that these effects are localised. Allowance
                for this effect may be needed for streets where close parking of vehicles is likely
                but specific allowance does not appear necessary at other locations. The design
                process should account for possible future alterations to gutter and road profiles
                including resurfacing of roads. Effects of possible pit blockages must be assessed
                at locations where overflows may cause significant damage. </para>
            <para>Aquaplaning or hydroplaning is also an important consideration, especially for
                highway drainage. This occurs when the tyre’s inability to shed water from the
                contact patch is exceeded, resulting in a layer of water building between the tyre
                and road surface leading to a loss of traction that prevents the vehicle from
                responding to control inputs. Although aquaplaning is dependent on other geometric
                factors of road design, adequate sizing and placement of inlet structures and cross
                culvert drainage systems is also a significant factor in reducing the risk of sheet
                flow occurring on roads. For guidance on aquaplaning, or highway drainage in
                general, refer to sources such as Austroads, road transport authority guidelines for
                each state and territory, the FHWA or UK Highway Agency.</para>
            <para>It is also important to consider the longevity of an overland flow path and this
                is especially relevant for flow paths through private property. Blockages are likely
                to occur due to lack of maintenance, or by post construction modifications such as
                from garden beds and mulch, or by modifications designed to enclose domestic
                pets.</para>
            <para>It is often necessary to locate structures within minor overland flow paths
                including property fencing, sound-control barriers and above ground services. When
                designing overland flow paths that may contain these types of structures it is
                important to consider the potential for flows to be redirected by these barriers. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_v5jj0">
            <title>The Hydraulic Grade Line (HGL) and Energy Grade Line (EGL)</title>
            <para>The hydraulic (HGL) and energy grade line (EGL) concepts are derived from the
                Bernoulli Equation and assist with the analysis of complex flow problems. The HGL is
                determined by plotting the relationship for pressure head <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="block">
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                            <m:mo>/</m:mo>
                            <m:mi>&#x03B3;</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                </inlineequation> and height above an arbitrary datum z at key locations in a
                conveyance network using the following equation:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_6uqjh">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mi>H</mi>
                    <mi>G</mi>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mrow>
                        <mi>P</mi>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>γ</mi>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mi>z</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>Where P is pressure and <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="block">
                        <m:mi>&#x03B3;</m:mi>
                    </m:math>
                </inlineequation> is specific density of water.</para>
            <para>Similarly, the EGL adds the velocity head V<superscript>2</superscript>/2g to the HGL to provide a
                relationship for EGL that can be derived at key locations in the conveyance
                network:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_xi35t">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                    <mrow>
                        <mi>E</mi>
                        <mi>G</mi>
                        <mi>L</mi>
                        <mo>=</mo>
                        <msup>
                            <mi>V</mi>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                        </msup>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                        <mi>g</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>P</mi>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mi>&#x03B3;</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>z</mi>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>Where V is the average velocity in a conduit and g is gravity.</para>
            <para>The vertical distance to point (such as the centre of a conduit) below the HGL
                represents the pressure head or pressure energy at a point. Negative heads or
                partial vacuums may occur at siphons and the conduit is above the HGL. The HGL
                coincides with the water surface for open channel flows, except at points such as
                brinks of weirs where non-hydrostatic conditions prevail. Water rises to the level
                of the HGL in an inlet structure (pit) that acts as a vertical riser. </para>
            <para>The EGL is located above the HGL and represents the total energy (velocity +
                pressure + potential) available to the flow that is expressed as a height (metres)
                equivalent to flow energy per unit weight in joules (or newton-metres) per
                newton.</para>
            <para>Grade lines typically slope downwards in the direction of flow in conveyance
                networks and slope represents energy losses due to pipe friction. The HGL and EGL
                are parallel for steady flows. The grade lines generally have a different slope to
                the pipe in closed conduits under pressure (with the HGL above the pipe). The
                grade-lines are parallel to open channels that are subject to steady and uniform
                flows since the friction loss equals the potential energy loss represented by the
                slope of the conduit.</para>
            <para>Changes in the shape or direction of conduits create turbulence and local losses
                that are represented as sharp drops in EGLs. Significant energy losses are typically
                assumed to act at the centre of inlet structures in analysis of conveyance networks.
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154433+1000" content="The HGL is also assumed to change at the centre of inlet structures as illustrated"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154433+1000"?>The
                assumption here is that HGL will change at the centre of inlet structures as
                illustrated<?oxy_insert_end?> in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_4oxnb"/>. These assumptions
                differ from the actual location of losses at the entry and exit of inlet structures
                (pits).</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_4oxnb">
                <title>Flow behaviour in a surcharged pipe system showing Energy Grade Lines and
                    Hydraulic Grade Lines</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9021.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_5ut3i">
            <title>Flows through conveyance networks</title>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Local Losses</emphasis></para>
            <para>Changes in the shape or direction of conduits can create turbulence and local
                losses that are represented as sharp drops in the EGL. Losses occur at locations
                such as entrances and exits to pits, pipe bends, and at contractions, expansions,
                junctions, and valves in conveyance networks. Except for expansions and contractions
                of conduits, these losses have the following relationship:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_hqyny">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mi>h</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                    <mfrac>
                        <mrow>
                            <msup>
                                <mi>V</mi>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                        </mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mi>g</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mfrac>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where h is the loss in m, and k is a loss coefficient multiplied by the velocity
                head of the downstream flow.</para>
            <para>The loss factor k is dependent on the geometry of entrances to a conduit. A
                square-edged entrance will usually have a factor of k<subscript>e</subscript> = 0.5
                and for a rounded entrance the factor is approximately 0.2. The factor at a pipe
                exit k<subscript>exit</subscript> is usually 1.0 as it is assumed the entire kinetic energy of flows will
                be lost as the pipe discharges into a larger body of water or atmosphere.</para>
            <para>The losses at bends depend on the radius of the bend and have a typical value of
                    k<subscript>b</subscript> = 0.5. Contractions in conduits (decreases in pipe
                diameter) are subject to low levels of losses with a typical factor k<subscript>c</subscript> of 0.05.
                Expansions in conduits (increases in diameter) generate higher losses h<subscript>L</subscript> that are
                dependent on the upstream V<subscript>u</subscript> and downstream
                    V<subscript>d</subscript> velocities:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_i3kr3">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <msub>
                        <mi>h</mi>
                        <mi>L</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>K</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mi>exp</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                    <mfrac>
                        <mrow>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>V</mi>
                                                <mi>u</mi>
                                            </msub>
                                            <mo>−</mo>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>V</mi>
                                                <mi>d</mi>
                                            </msub>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                        </mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mi>g</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mfrac>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where k<subscript>exp</subscript> is about 1.0 for abrupt pipe expansions. </para>
            <para>Valves have variable loss factors which can become very large as the valve
                closes.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Full flows in conduits</emphasis></para>
            <para>The estimation of flowrates through conveyance networks that are flowing full is
                made by relating the available energy or head to the losses as expressed by the
                velocity head. The following calculation shows how flowrates can be determined from
                the available head and the assumed energy losses along a 300 mm pipe discharging
                from a reservoir as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_jk53i"/>. </para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_jk53i">
                <title>Example of Full Flows in a Pipe</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9022.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The pipe diameter reduces from 300 mm to 200 mm at the middle of the pipe branch.
                The energy loss at the following expansion is assumed to be 0.5 times the velocity
                head in the downstream pipe and all friction values (f) in the Darcy-Weisbach
                Equation are set at 0.02. </para>
            <para>The water level in the reservoir is 57.0 m above a height datum and the total head
                available is 57.0 - 46.0 = 11.0 m. The various losses are all functions of the
                velocity heads in the pipes. Since V<subscript>3</subscript> =
                    V<subscript>1</subscript> and <inlineequation>
                    <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                        <msub>
                            <mi>V</mi>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>=</mo>
                        <msub>
                            <mi>V</mi>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>.</mo>
                        <mfrac>
                            <mrow>
                                <msub>
                                    <mi>A</mi>
                                    <mn>1</mn>
                                </msub>
                            </mrow>
                            <mrow>
                                <msub>
                                    <mi>A</mi>
                                    <mn>2</mn>
                                </msub>
                            </mrow>
                        </mfrac>
                        <mo>=</mo>
                        <msub>
                            <mi>V</mi>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>.</mo>
                        <msup>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mfrac>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>D</mi>
                                                <mn>1</mn>
                                            </msub>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <msub>
                                                <mi>D</mi>
                                                <mn>2</mn>
                                            </msub>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </mfrac>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                        </msup>
                    </math>
                </inlineequation>, the sum of the losses will be:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_7v0vx">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>k</mi>
                                <mi>e</mi>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <msub>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mi>f</mi>
                                            <mo>.</mo>
                                            <mfrac>
                                                <mi>L</mi>
                                                <mi>D</mi>
                                            </mfrac>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>k</mi>
                                <mi>c</mi>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <msub>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mi>f</mi>
                                            <mo>.</mo>
                                            <mfrac>
                                                <mi>L</mi>
                                                <mi>D</mi>
                                            </mfrac>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>.</mo>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mfrac>
                                                <mrow>
                                                  <msub>
                                                  <mi>D</mi>
                                                  <mn>2</mn>
                                                  </msub>
                                                </mrow>
                                                <mrow>
                                                  <msub>
                                                  <mi>D</mi>
                                                  <mn>1</mn>
                                                  </msub>
                                                </mrow>
                                            </mfrac>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mn>4</mn>
                            </msup>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>k</mi>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mi>exp</mi>
                                </mrow>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <msub>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mi>f</mi>
                                            <mo>.</mo>
                                            <mfrac>
                                                <mi>L</mi>
                                                <mi>D</mi>
                                            </mfrac>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mn>3</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>k</mi>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mi>e</mi>
                                    <mi>x</mi>
                                    <mi>i</mi>
                                    <mi>t</mi>
                                </mrow>
                            </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mfrac>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>V</mi>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow/>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                        </mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mi>g</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mfrac>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mn>11</mn>
                    <mtext> m</mtext>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_e1iv5">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>0.5</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mn>0.02.</mn>
                                    <mfrac>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mn>430</mn>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mn>0.3</mn>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </mfrac>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mn>0.1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mn>0.02.</mn>
                                    <mfrac>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mn>55</mn>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mn>0.2</mn>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </mfrac>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>.</mo>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mfrac>
                                                <mrow>
                                                  <mn>0.3</mn>
                                                </mrow>
                                                <mrow>
                                                  <mn>0.2</mn>
                                                </mrow>
                                            </mfrac>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mrow>
                                <mn>4</mn>
                            </msup>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mn>0.5</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mn>0.02.</mn>
                                    <mfrac>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mn>385</mn>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mn>0.3</mn>
                                        </mrow>
                                    </mfrac>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mn>1.0</mn>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mfrac>
                        <mrow>
                            <msub>
                                <mi>V</mi>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                            </msub>
                            <msup>
                                <mrow/>
                                <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                        </mrow>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mi>g</mi>
                        </mrow>
                    </mfrac>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mn>11</mn>
                    <mtext> m</mtext>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_4thr9">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                    <mtable columnalign="left">
                        <mtr>
                            <mtd>
                                <mtext>Thus,&#x00A0;</mtext>
                            </mtd>
                        </mtr>
                        <mtr>
                            <mtd>
                                <mn>84.28</mn>
                                <mo>&#x22C5;</mo>
                                <mfrac>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <msub>
                                            <mi>V</mi>
                                            <mn>1</mn>
                                        </msub>
                                        <msup>
                                            <mrow/>
                                            <mn>2</mn>
                                        </msup>
                                    </mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mn>2</mn>
                                        <mi>g</mi>
                                    </mrow>
                                </mfrac>
                                <mo>=</mo>
                                <mtext>11&#x00A0;m,&#x00A0;</mtext>
                            </mtd>
                        </mtr>
                        <mtr>
                            <mtd>
                                <msub>
                                    <mi>V</mi>
                                    <mn>1</mn>
                                </msub>
                                <mo>=</mo>
                                <msup>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mfrac>
                                                <mrow>
                                                  <mn>11.0</mn>
                                                  <mo>&#x00D7;</mo>
                                                  <mn>19.60</mn>
                                                </mrow>
                                                <mrow>
                                                  <mn>84.28</mn>
                                                </mrow>
                                            </mfrac>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mn>0.5</mn>
                                    </mrow>
                                </msup>
                            </mtd>
                        </mtr>
                        <mtr>
                            <mtd>
                                <mo>=</mo>
                                <mn>1.60</mn>
                                <mtext>&#x00A0;m/s&#x00A0;and&#x00A0;</mtext>
                            </mtd>
                        </mtr>
                        <mtr>
                            <mtd>
                                <mi>Q</mi>
                                <mo>=</mo>
                                <msub>
                                    <mi>V</mi>
                                    <mn>1</mn>
                                </msub>
                                <msub>
                                    <mi>A</mi>
                                    <mn>1</mn>
                                </msub>
                            </mtd>
                        </mtr>
                        <mtr>
                            <mtd>
                                <mo>=</mo>
                                <mfrac bevelled="true">
                                    <mi>&#x03C0;</mi>
                                    <mn>4</mn>
                                </mfrac>
                                <mo>&#x22C5;</mo>
                                <msup>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mo>(</mo>
                                        <mrow>
                                            <mn>0.3</mn>
                                        </mrow>
                                        <mo>)</mo>
                                    </mrow>
                                    <mn>2</mn>
                                </msup>
                                <mo>&#x22C5;</mo>
                                <mn>1.60</mn>
                            </mtd>
                        </mtr>
                        <mtr>
                            <mtd>
                                <mo>=</mo>
                                <mn>0.113</mn>
                                <msup>
                                    <mtext>&#x00A0;m</mtext>
                                    <mn>3</mn>
                                </msup>
                                <mtext>/s</mtext>
                            </mtd>
                        </mtr>
                    </mtable>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>The Manning Equation can also be used with friction losses expressed by  since
                slope of the energy gradeline is S = h<superscript>f</superscript>/L. </para>
            <para>Equations using conservation of mass, energy and momentum can be constructed to
                describe the state of an entire conveyance network that includes multiple pipes and
                inlet structures. These equations are solved to provide information about the
                pressures and velocities throughout a conveyance network which can be visualised as
                EGLs and HGLs. More complex partial differential equations are required to cope with
                unsteady flows that change with time.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Conduits flowing partially full</emphasis></para>
            <para>Conduits that are flowing partially full in stormwater conveyance networks can
                exhibit complex behaviours. A maximum flow capacity is
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154447+1000" content="actually "?>achieved
                when conduits are operating at less than full flows. However it is not good practice
                to design conduits with partial flows as disturbances may eliminate free surfaces in
                conduits and cause a transition to pressurized full flows that may lead to
                surcharges.</para>
            <para>This assumes that flows in conduits are open channel flows with atmospheric
                pressure at the surface. Submergence at the entrance and tailwater levels affecting
                the outlet of conduits generates further complications. In addition, large air
                bubbles and air pockets can occur in conduits that operate in partially full
                conditions resulting in pressures that can be above or below atmospheric pressure.
                The theory of open channel hydraulics is addressed in <xref linkend="book6"
                />.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Complex Procedures</emphasis></para>
            <para>A more complex and correct procedure for analysis of conveyance networks is to
                apply partial differential equations of unsteady flow varying in space (the distance
                along a conduit) x and time t that is defined as steps or intervals. These numerical
                models divide river, channel or pipe reaches into segments and define the transfer
                of mass and momentum between adjacent segments using the <emphasis role="italic"
                    >Saint Venant Equations</emphasis> for conservation of mass and momentum in
                unsteady flows as described in <xref linkend="b6_ch2"/>. The equations must be
                solved iteratively using finite difference or finite element models and matrix
                calculations that may require longer computing times. </para>
            <para>These more complex calculation processes are quite different from water surface
                projection methods such as the ‘standard step’ procedure. <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154525+1000" content="Nevertheless the same outputs are produced such the HGL levels at points along a conduit and at different times during a flow event."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154525+1000"?>
                <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaCK" timestamp="20180921T134749+1000" comment="This sentence does not seem complete. Please check. "?>Nevertheless
                the same outputs are produced such that the HGL levels points along a conduit and at
                different times during a flow event.<?oxy_insert_end?>
                <?oxy_comment_end?>The equations allow for pipe friction and local losses, and also
                incorporate pressure changes at inlet pits and junctions.</para>
            <para>Modelling of urban conveyance networks is typically carried out using a range of
                computer software packages that provide different levels of rigour or precision
                which involve trade-offs between speed and accuracy. However the designer should be
                aware of other important considerations such as stability.
                <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154552+1000" content="Unlikely"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154552+1000"?>It
                is unlikely that<?oxy_insert_end?> high or low pressures, water levels, and
                flowrates are generated when iterative calculations become unstable. The usual way
                of achieving stable results with a computer model is to choose a shorter time step
                or adjustment of factors affecting the relative time steps in space and time. Small
                errors in volumes or flows (typically &lt; 1%) can be accepted in order to achieve
                faster running times.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Priessmann Slot</emphasis></para>
            <para>Methods of analysis must allow for flows that change from partially full to full
                conduit flows and back again. Modelling procedures that account for unsteady flow
                regimes employ the Priessmann Slot assumption. This mixed flow problem is simplified
                by the addition of a hypothetical slot in the pipe which allows the depth of flow to
                exceed the pipe diameter and provides pressurized flow effects <citation>b9_c5_r26,
                    b9_c5_r27</citation>. The width of the slot must not be too wide to
                significantly impact on continuity and should be determined to ensure that the
                gravity wave speed equals the pressure wave speed. </para>
            <para>The hypothetical slot allows the analysis of the conveyance network to be treated
                as an open channel flow problem. However, a limitation of this approach is that it
                cannot accurately simulate the formation and impact of air pockets or negative
                pressures results from shocks. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Outlet Structures</emphasis></para>
            <para>Regardless of whether flow within the conduit is full or part full, suitable
                transition is required at the end of a conveyance conduit, where flow discharges to
                the receiving environment. The transition structure, or outlet structure should
                accommodate potential for high velocity and/or turbulent flow. This can be achieved
                through armouring of the surface using material such as rock or
                concrete<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154635+1000" content=" and"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154635+1000"?>,
                along with<?oxy_insert_end?> gradual transition of geometry from that of the
                conduit, to that of the receiving channel or basin. Energy dissipation and/or flow
                dispersion can be achieved at the same time using appropriate outlet structure
                design. This is particularly necessary where stormwater settlement processes are
                expected in a receiving basin structure such as a
                bio<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154647+1000" content="-"?>retention
                basin or constructed wetland. </para>
            <para>The outlet structure may also represent an opportunity for removal of
                gross-pollutants prior to stormwater passing into a receiving channel or structure.
                This can be achieved using various forms of screens, baskets and mechanical filters.
                The impact of these structures, whether clear, partially blocked or fully blocked on
                the hydraulic performance of the conveyance infrastructure needs careful assessment
                at the design stage.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="b9_ch5_s_3llvr">
            <title>Culverts</title>
            <para>The simplest conveyance network is a single-pipe culvert which is a common
                component of highway and railway networks that is located wherever an embankment
                crosses a waterway or drainage path. These transport crossings may only involve a
                single pipe (or multiple parallel pipes). However, the hydraulic calculations can be
                complicated. Culvert hydraulics are comprehensively described by
                    <citation>b9_c5_r28+1</citation>. The treatment of culvert hydraulics (or
                headwalls) is divided by two flow conditions:</para>
            <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
                <listitem><para>Inlet controls – dependent on the orifice effect at the culvert entrance, and</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>Outlet controls – dependent on full, pressurised flow conditions through the pipe or on high
                        tailwater levels.</para></listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
            
            <para>Multiple culverts may be connected by pits or junctions in a similar manner as a
                large conveyance network (see <xref linkend="b9_ch5_s_5ut3i"/>)</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Inlet Control</emphasis></para>
            <para>Inlet conditions for culverts are created by the vena contracta effects shown in
                    <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_h9l8m"/>. </para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_h9l8m">
                <title>Vena contracta or contraction at a culvert entrance</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9089.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The streamlines of flows entering a culvert cannot turn abruptly and the curvature
                of flows continues into the culvert creating a jet with a diameter less than that of
                the culvert. This process reduces the available cross-sectional area of flows and
                the overall flowrate. The ratio between the jet and the pipe diameters is 0.6 for a
                square-edged entrance. Values for other entrance types are shown in <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_f_c8cfh"/>. </para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_c8cfh">
                <title>Orifice coefficients <citation>b9_c5_r42</citation></title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9090.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The correction coefficient for the reduced area is Cc and Cv is the factor for the
                velocity being less that the theoretical value of V = √ 2gh where h is the pressure
                head on the orifice (m) and g is the acceleration due to gravity (m/s<superscript>2</superscript>). The overall
                correction coefficient is C = Cc.Cv.</para>
            <para>The general case of inlet control is presented in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_dwacx"/>
                where it is observed that the culvert barrel has a greater capacity than the
                entrance as it is flowing partially full. As indicated, <xref
                    linkend="b9_ch5_f_c8cfh"/> shows that the capacity of the culvert can be
                improved by modifying the entrance by rounding sharp edges and changing the
                streamlines. These improvements may be useful in situations when additional capacity
                is required.</para>
            <para>The general equation governing orifice flow for a circular pipe is:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_bpt6l">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mrow>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mo>=</mo>
                        <mi>V</mi>
                        <mi>A</mi>
                        <mo>=</mo>
                        <mi>C</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mo>(</mo>
                            <mrow>
                                <mfrac>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mi>π</mi>
                                        <msup>
                                            <mi>D</mi>
                                            <mn>2</mn>
                                        </msup>
                                    </mrow>
                                    <mn>4</mn>
                                </mfrac>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                        <msup>
                            <mrow>
                                <mrow>
                                    <mo>(</mo>
                                    <mrow>
                                        <mn>2</mn>
                                        <mi>g</mi>
                                        <mi>h</mi>
                                    </mrow>
                                    <mo>)</mo>
                                </mrow>
                            </mrow>
                            <mrow>
                                <mn>0.5</mn>
                            </mrow>
                        </msup>
                    </mrow>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where C is the correction factor (dimensionless),</para>
            <para>D is the pipe diameter (mm),</para>
            <para>h is the head on the orifice, usually taken from the upstream water surface to the
                centre of the orifice (m), and</para>
            <para>g is gravitational acceleration (9.8
                    m/s<superscript>2</superscript>).</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_dwacx">
                <title>Example of inlet control  <citation>b9_c5_r41</citation></title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9091.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The hydraulics is more complicated when the entrance to the culvert is not
                completely submerged. This may involve three different states depending on the
                headwater height above the invert HW and the culvert diameter or height D:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Partially full flow for HW &lt; 0.8D is a weir type flow as water pours
                        into the pipe.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Partially full flow with 0.8 &lt; HW &lt; 1.2D is similar to weir
                        flow,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Fully submerged inlet flow for HW &gt; 1.2D is an orifice flow.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>The stated limits of 0.8D and 1.2D are approximate. These three zones lead to the
                behaviour demonstrated in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_htvy0"/> where the inlet control
                relationship changes depending on the headwater elevation. It is also possible to
                have two different flowrates at the same water elevation which depends on whether
                the culvert is operating as an inlet or outlet controlled system. These states can
                also depend on whether flows are increasing or decreasing.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_htvy0">
                <title>Inlet control versus elevation of headwaters
                    <citation>b9_c5_r41</citation></title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9092.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>A range of design aids are generally available in the form of nomographs used to
                calculate headwater levels for various situations involving circular, box and other
                types of culverts. A better approach is to use computer software to model culvert
                hydraulics.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Outlet controls</emphasis></para>
            <para>Outlet control occurs when a culvert is not capable of conveying as much flow as
                the inlet can accept. The controlling section is generally at the culvert exit where
                subcritical or pressurised flow conditions are occurring or further downstream of
                the culvert due to tailwater conditions. Two
                outlet<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154728+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181003T154728+1000" content=" "?>controlled
                situations are provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_wwdiq"/>. The difference between
                upstream headwater and the tailwater levels drives the flows through the culvert.
                Energy losses are added and equated to the available head.</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_wwdiq">
                <title>Example of outlet control situations <citation>b9_c5_r41</citation></title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9093.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>These calculations involve backwards projection of the HGL that commences at the
                tailwater level if this submerges the outlet. Different computer models make various
                assumptions for free outfalls. It is assumed that the level will be half way between
                the pipe obvert and the critical depth, and it is necessary to determine that
                critical depth from nomographs or equations. However other computer models assume
                that it is the lower of (a) the critical depth and (b) the normal depth.</para>
            <para>A weir equation is applied to allow for overtopping of road embankments:</para>
            <equation xml:id="b9_ch5_e_q3jok">
                <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                    <mi>Q</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>C</mi>
                        <mi>w</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <msub>
                        <mi>L</mi>
                        <mi>w</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <msup>
                        <mi>H</mi>
                        <mrow>
                            <mn>1.5</mn>
                        </mrow>
                    </msup>
                </math>
            </equation>
            <para>where C<subscript>w</subscript> is a weir coefficient, depending on the weir shape
                    (<xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_wzmrw"/>),</para>
            <para>L<subscript>w</subscript> is the width or
                length of the weir perpendicular to the direction of flow, and</para>
            <para>h is the height of
                water above the weir crest (m).</para>
            <figure xml:id="b9_ch5_f_wzmrw">
                <title>Shapes of weir crests <citation>b9_c5_r30</citation></title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9094.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Culvert and overflow weir outflows can be combined into a composite relationship
                as shown in <xref linkend="b9_ch5_f_htvy0"/>. This calculation should account for
                inlet and outlet controls and usually the most conservative relationship that
                provides the lowest flowrate for a given depth is accepted.</para>
            <para>The real behaviour of a culvert is more complex and involves a phenomenon called
                'priming'. As upstream water levels rise, culverts tend to remain under inlet
                control until they run full. As upstream water levels decline, culverts tend to
                remain at full flows in an outlet control configuration until there is a sudden
                reversion to inlet control and decline in headwater level.</para>
            <para>Since culverts are often used as outlets for detention basins and conveyance
                networks. The relationships presented above can be applied to specify the elevation
                and discharge relationships needed for routing of flows through volume management
                facilities.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
        <xi:fallback>
            <para>No included references yet...</para>
        </xi:fallback>
    </xi:include>
 </chapter>

<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>