<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b2_ch6"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Continuous Rainfall Simulation</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/sharma_ashish.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/srikanthan_r.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/mehrotra_raj.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/westra_seth.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/lambert_martin.xml"/>
    
  </info>

  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>

      <td>2</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>

      <td>6</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>

      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>General</td>

      <td>Integration of different methods required</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_ly1qa">
    <title>Use of Continuous Simulation for Design Flood Estimation</title>

    <para>Design floods can be estimated based on either historical flood data
    using at-site Flood Frequency Analysis or Regional Flood Frequency
    Analysis, or derived using rainfall data and a suitable hydrologic model
    to simulate flows. When using the latter, two options exist. The first is
    the event-based approach which converts the design rainfall storm to a
    corresponding design flood using a hydrologic model. The second is the
    continuous simulation approach, which converts a continuous rainfall time
    series to a flow time series using a hydrologic model, followed by the
    application of a frequency analysis on the flows to estimate the design
    flood. The generation of the rainfall time series for this latter approach
    is the focus of the current chapter.</para>

    <para>While a clear case is often present when deciding between a flood
    frequency and an event-based approach for estimating the design flood, it
    is less clear when a continuous simulation approach should be used in
    place of an event-based approach. In general, the primary benefits of
    continuous simulation approaches arise when the relationship between the
    catchment’s antecedent moisture stores and the flood-producing rainfall
    event are not independent of each other, or change over time [<emphasis
    role="italic">Blazkova and Beven</emphasis>, 2002; <emphasis
    role="italic">W Boughton and Droop</emphasis>, 2003; <emphasis
    role="italic">Cameron et al.</emphasis>, 2000; <emphasis
    role="italic">Lamb and Kay</emphasis>, 2004]. Continuous simulation allows
    an explicit representation of the joint probability of antecedent moisture
    conditions and flood-producing rainfall data, which can be challenging for
    event-based approaches. Therefore key areas where continuous simulation
    approaches are likely to be useful include the following:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchments with large moisture stores having significant
        relation between antecedent rainfall and the annual maximum flood
        [<emphasis role="italic">Pathiraja et al.</emphasis>, 2012];</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Examining the joint probability of flooding arising from the
        confluences of streams which are subject varying spatial rainfall
        distributions.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Situations where the relationship between historical antecedent
        conditions and flood-producing rainfall are not representative of the
        design period. This is may occur as a result of climate change, but
        may also be relevant when calibrating over a period that is
        over-represented in terms of El Niño or La Niña events (e.g.
        [<emphasis role="italic">Pui et al.</emphasis>, 2011] [<emphasis
        role="italic">Das et al.</emphasis>, 2012; <emphasis role="italic">Pui
        et al.</emphasis>, 2012; <emphasis role="italic">Steinschneider and
        Lall</emphasis>, 2015] [<emphasis role="italic">Micevski and
        </emphasis><emphasis role="italic">Kuczera</emphasis>, 2009]).</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Situations requiring a quantification of uncertainty of flood
        quantities, where continuous simulation approaches can provide a
        natural method for representing the dependence between flood-producing
        rainfall and the antecedent conditions.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Situations where the initial level of flood and reservoir
        storages are unknown and these influence the resulting downstream
        flood flows.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>When using a virtual laboratory to test proposed simpler event
        based approaches.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Consider the example in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_ihzwo"/> which uses
    data for a South Australian catchment to illustrate the workings of the
    three approaches used for design flood estimation. While the figure uses
    the 90-day antecedent rainfall to illustrate its relation with the extreme
    rain, similar joint relationships could exist between antecedent rainfall
    for longer periods, or other more subtle rainfall characteristics that are
    difficult to summarise using a simple metric.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_ihzwo">
      <title>Illustrative flood events for a typical Australian catchment,
      with rainfall from Scott Creek in South Australia</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2001.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>The first two panels illustrate the working of a flood-frequency or
    event based modelling approach for design flood estimation. The last panel
    illustrates a continuous simulation model that attempts to capture the
    strong relationship in extreme rainfall with the 90-day Antecedent
    rain.</para>

    <para>As highlighted in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_ihzwo"/>, continuous
    simulation approaches for design flood estimation require continuous
    rainfall sequences as the primary data input. Although continuous rainfall
    data exist in some locations for periods of several decades or longer, for
    most locations in Australia the continuous data is either unavailable, too
    short or of insufficient quality to support continuous rainfall-runoff
    modelling. This chapter therefore presents the basis and techniques for
    stochastically generating continuous rainfall records in a catchment. Also
    discussed are:</para>

    <para><orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para>generic issues regarding the accuracy of rainfall observations
          and methods for identifying errors in rainfall time series,</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>approaches for infilling rainfall data at a point
          location,</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>when to generate multi-site data as compared to lumped or
          single site rainfall,</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>approaches for generating data at locations where rainfall
          records are not available, and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>implications of nonstationarity in the rainfall record as a
          result of urbanization and climate change.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>

    <para>The next section discusses the approaches used to prepare rainfall
    data for use in stochastic generation or other modelling studies. This is
    followed by a conceptual framework that underlies stochastic rainfall
    generation at point or multiple locations. Alternatives for generation of
    daily rainfall are discussed next, followed by alternatives for
    disaggregation of daily rainfall to sub-daily time scales. Alternatives
    that generate continuous rainfall sequences without reference to a daily
    total at point and multiple locations conclude the presentation. Worked
    examples illustrating the applications of some of the models presented are
    included to assist with practical implementations.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_jccfb">
    <title>Rainfall Data Preparation</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_o2j9k">
      <title>Errors in rainfall measurements</title>

      <para>Stochastic rainfall generation aims to generate continuous
      rainfall sequences that are representative of the underlying climate.
      Hence it is important that the observed rainfall is a true
      representation of the underlying climate, and is not influenced by
      potential measurement or sampling inaccuracies that may lead to biased
      rainfall sequences. Hence the first step of stochastic rainfall
      generation is to identify and correct for noticeable errors in the
      observed rainfall record.</para>

      <para>Rainfall measurements can be susceptible to a range of
      errors:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Effect of wind, wetting, evaporation and
          splashing on daily rainfall measurements – The World Meteorological
          Organisation [</emphasis> <emphasis role="italic">WMO</emphasis> ,
          1994] states that these factors can result in the measured daily
          rainfall being less than the true rainfall by anywhere between three
          and 30%.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Errors in tipping bucket
          measurements</emphasis> – Tipping bucket raingauges are the
          preferred means of continuous rainfall measurement over the world.
          While reasonably accurate at low rainfall intensities, tipping
          bucket raingauges can underestimate the rainfall when intensities
          are high due to the water lost as a result of the tipping motion of
          the raingauge. Typical errors for intensities greater than
          200mm/hour can range from 10-15% of the true rainfall [ <emphasis
          role="italic">La Barbera et al.</emphasis> , 2002]. A simple model
          for characterising gauge measurement errors was proposed by
          <emphasis role="italic">Ciach</emphasis> , 2003], marking them
          inversely proportional to the measured rainfall intensity.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Homogeneity of rainfall
          measurements</emphasis> - The double mass curve is a commonly used
          technique to identify and correct for changes in the exposure or
          location of the gauge, changes in the manner in which data is
          collected, or any other changes that result in a systematic bias in
          the measurements compared to the general trend in nearby locations.
          An example of such change is illustrated in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch6_f_ozunq"/> for a hypothetical rainfall record, where
          the change appears to have occurred around 1955 with the slope of
          the mass curve changing from 0.95 to 0.75 from that point onwards.
          Changes such as those illustrated in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch6_f_ozunq"/> should be investigated in greater detail
          and corrective measures (e.g. multiplicative scaling) may need to be
          used. Note that similar comparative checks can also be used in the
          context of identifying ‘odd’ raingauge locations from the regional
          average (slope of the double mass curve will be significantly
          different to 1).</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_ozunq">
            <title>Double Mass Curve analysis for rainfall at Station A (from
            [WMO, 1994])</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2002.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Homogeneity of gridded
          rainfall</emphasis> – An important source of error in gridded
          rainfall data is related to the use of varying number of rain gauges
          over time in the process of reconstructing records. A recent paper
          looking at the extent of this variability in the context of radar
          rainfall estimation expressed this as a function of the grid size
          and the density of gauges within the grid. Using daily gauge data
          for Sydney, the coefficient of variation of the of the rainfall for
          a 1km x1km grid cell having a single gauge was estimated as 1.35,
          with reductions in this value as more gauge were included, and
          increases when extended to larger grid sizes. This error was found
          to be considerably larger than the measurement error discussed
          before [ <emphasis role="italic">Ciach</emphasis> , 2003]. While
          there is no clear way of addressing this error, its variation over
          time can be factored in the specification of any model that is
          developed using this as inputs [ <emphasis role="italic">Chowdhury
          and Sharma</emphasis> , 2007].</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Effect of untagged multi-day
          accumulations in daily rainfall data</emphasis> – As nearly a third
          of the long-term daily rainfall records are recorded at post offices
          and other public buildings, the occurrence of multi-day readings
          (representing Saturday to Monday) recorded on the first working day
          after the weekend is frequent. An example of one such station is
          illustrated in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_d6lnp"/>. Viney and Bates
          [2004] outline a hypothesis test for identifying the periods in a
          rainfall record that reflect significant multi-day accumulations.
          While there is no simple corrective procedure that can be employed,
          common-sense alternatives such as comparing with data at nearby
          locations (after ascertaining that they do not suffer from the same
          problem), and using the persistence structure of the non-accumulated
          data to disaggregate the accumulated values, should be adopted. It
          should be noted that while such accumulations may not affect
          calculations in yield or water balance studies, their implications
          in flood estimation studies can be significant.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_d6lnp">
        <title>Total rainfall amounts for rainfall station 009557 over the
        period 1956-1962 (from [Viney<emphasis role="italic">
        </emphasis>and<emphasis role="italic"> </emphasis>Bates,
        2004])</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2003.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_zjdnw">
      <title>Options for catchments with no rainfall records</title>

      <para>One of the advantages of event-based approaches for design flood
      estimation, is the availability of design rainfall data in different
      parts of Australia. These data are derived through spatial interpolation
      of IFD parameters, with assumptions on the changes one would expect from
      gauged to ungauged locations. In contrast, continuous simulation either
      requires observed rainfall time series at each location of interest, or
      a procedure to generate such series based on data from nearby locations.
      For situations where observed rainfall data are not available, the
      following alternatives can be considered:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Use of gridded rainfall
          products</emphasis> . Given the need to use catchment averages of
          rainfall and potential evapotranspiration in a range of hydrologic
          studies, datasets of gridded rainfall and temperature have been
          produced for Australia and elsewhere. Two gridded datasets used
          routinely in Australia are the SILO and the AWAP daily rainfall
          5kmx5km gridded datasets. The SILO project [<emphasis
          role="italic">Jeffrey et al.</emphasis> , 2001] by the Queensland
          Centre for Climate Applications, Department of Natural Resources,
          aimed to develop a comprehensive archive of key meteorological
          variables (Maximum and Minimum Temperature, Rainfall, Class-A pan
          Evaporation, Solar Radiation and Vapour Pressure) through
          interpolation on a 0.05° grid extending from latitude 10°S to 44°S
          and longitude 112°E to 154°E. The project has also resulted in a
          patched daily rainfall series at 4600 locations extending back to
          1890. In addition, the Australian Water Availability Project (AWAP)
          dataset was produced by the CSIRO and the Australian Bureau of
          Meteorology [<emphasis role="italic">D Jones et al.</emphasis> ,
          2009] at the same resolution using a different averaging procedure.
          These datasets have been compared [<emphasis role="italic">Beesley
          et al.</emphasis> , 2009] and found to be similar in many respects,
          while still resulting in a dampening of high extremes due to
          averaging, as well as a oversimulation of the number of wet days in
          a year. Similar biases occur in the representation of persistence
          attributes, possibly distorting the specification of antecedent
          conditions prior to large rainfall events. Care must be taken when
          using such datasets, especially if the intention is to simulate flow
          extremes for the catchment.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Use of radar or satellite derived
          rainfall measurements</emphasis> . While the above mentioned gridded
          data are based on spatial interpolation of gauged rainfall alone,
          another option that has been pursued with success is to combine
          gauge and remotely sensed rainfall, which is known to improve
          accuracy especially in remote locations with limited gauge coverage.
          Examples of approaches that have produced and assessed such combined
          datasets include [<emphasis role="italic">Chappell et al.</emphasis>
          , 2013]. While they suffer from the same problems as other gridded
          datasets, the advantages they offer in remote locations should be
          taken into consideration.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Use of statistical interpolation
          techniques based on nearby daily and sub-daily gauge
          records</emphasis> . We refer readers to the alternatives for
          continuous simulation at ungauged locations presents later in the
          chapter. These alternatives use separate approaches for daily and
          sub-daily continuous generation at ungauged locations. The daily
          alternative amounts to identifying nearby gauges that “mirror” key
          characteristics that would be expected of daily rainfall at the
          location of interest. These nearby gauge records are then
          transformed to the current location by adjusting for any difference
          in their annual mean. Each nearby gauge is assigned a probability
          depending on how “similar” it may be to the location of interest,
          which allows characterisation of the uncertainty associated with
          this procedure. In the sub-daily case, a second step is adopted.
          Once the daily record has been generated, it is disaggregated using
          data on sub-daily fragments based on a different set of
          characteristics that define the subdaily climate of the location.
          More details on these procedures are presented later.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_sx0j3">
      <title>Missing rainfall observations</title>

      <para>Rainfall records often contain missing observations that need to
      be filled using appropriate techniques. This problem is often compounded
      when records from multiple sites are to be used for analysis. The World
      Meteorological Organisation [<emphasis role="italic">WMO</emphasis>,
      1994] expresses caution against filling more than 10% of the rainfall
      records as the aggregate rainfall information may be influenced by
      interpretation. Some of the methods recommended for filling short gaps
      in the rainfall record are as follows:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Normal Ratio Method</emphasis> – This
          method estimates the missing rainfall <inlineequation>
              <m:math display="inline">
                <m:mover>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                </m:mover>
              </m:math>
            </inlineequation> at gauge <inlineequation>
              <m:math display="inline">
                <m:mi>g</m:mi>
              </m:math>
            </inlineequation> as a weighted average of the measured rainfall
          at nearby raingauges:</para>

          <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_w6epo">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mover>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                </m:mover>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mfrac>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:munderover>
                      <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>G</m:mi>
                    </m:munderover>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mover>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>─</m:mo>
                        </m:mover>

                        <m:mover>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>─</m:mo>
                        </m:mover>
                      </m:mfrac>

                      <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>G</m:mi>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>where <emphasis role="italic">G</emphasis> represent the total
      number of raingauges, <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mover>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                <m:mi>g</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>─</m:mo>
            </m:mover>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> and <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mover>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>─</m:mo>
            </m:mover>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> the average annual rainfall at gauges <emphasis
      role="italic">g</emphasis> and <emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis>
      respectively, and <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>P</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> the rainfall at gauge <emphasis
      role="italic">i</emphasis> for the time period being filled. Care must
      be taken to ensure that the “host” raingauges have similar climatic
      conditions as the gauge where the missing observations are being
      infilled.</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Quadrant Method</emphasis> – This method
          is related to the Normal Ratio method, but aims to account for the
          proximity of the raingauges to the target location. The missing
          rainfall <inlineequation>
              <m:math display="inline">
                <m:mover>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                </m:mover>
              </m:math>
            </inlineequation> at gauge <emphasis role="italic">g</emphasis> is
          estimated as a weighted average of observations at four raingauges,
          one in each quadrant using north-south and east-west lines that
          intersect the location of gauge <emphasis role="italic">g</emphasis>
          . The rainfall is estimated as:</para>

          <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_r09n1">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mover>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                </m:mover>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mfrac>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:munderover>
                      <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>4</m:mi>
                    </m:munderover>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                        <m:msubsup>
                          <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:msubsup>
                      </m:mfrac>

                      <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:munderover>
                      <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>4</m:mi>
                    </m:munderover>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                        <m:msubsup>
                          <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:msubsup>
                      </m:mfrac>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>where <emphasis role="italic">d<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis>
      is the Euclidean distance between gauges <emphasis
      role="italic">i</emphasis> and <emphasis
      role="italic">g</emphasis>.</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Isohyetal Method</emphasis> – This
          method involves drawing isohyets (lines of equal rainfall) for the
          storm duration over the network of raingauges available, and
          inferring the rainfall at the missing raingauge by interpolation.
          The accuracy of the Isohyetal method depends significantly on the
          number of raingauges used and the interpolation algorithm being used
          to construct the isohyets.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Copula based interpolation</emphasis> –
          In a recent paper, [<emphasis role="italic">András Bárdossy and
          Pegram</emphasis> , 2014] presented an alternative for interpolating
          existing data to infill missing values at a station of interest.
          They used a copula-based specification of the conditional
          probability distribution of the missing rainfall based on values at
          nearby gauges. They compared their approach with both regression and
          other spatial interpolation based alternatives, and found it to
          perform better using daily rainfall data from South Africa. Another
          advantage argued for their approach is the fact that it can include
          conditioning on exogenous variables which could include atmospheric
          fields that are common to all stations in the area of interest,
          thereby allowing additional information on the nature of
          precipitation.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The above methods are fairly intuitive and modifications of the
      basic logic outlined are common. For instance, in situations where data
      from nearby raingauges are hard to find, the interpolation is often from
      previous years of record at the same raingauge, the period being chosen
      to represent the same season and similar antecedent rainfall
      conditions.</para>

      <para>All the methods suggested above ought to be used with care, with
      consideration for the distributional changes that occur as a result of
      the interpolation. For instance, if the stations used for spatial
      averaging are at significant distances to the station where the
      interpolation is required, then the interpolated rainfall is likely to
      be ‘smoother’ than the rainfall that would have occurred at that
      location, potentially leading to an overestimation of wet days and an
      underestimation of peak rainfall. Similarly, if the interpolation is
      performed at each time step independently, the dependence of rainfall
      from one time to the next may not be accurately represented. These
      considerations attain importance particularly when short time steps
      (daily and sub-daily) are considered, and when the missing periods are a
      significant portion of the overall record.</para>

      <para>Missing data within historical rainfall records can be a serious
      problem, the amount of which can affect the type of model structure
      considered. Few researchers explain adequately how this is dealt with.
      Cowpertwait (1991a) described a replacement strategy to handle missing
      data but it is not apparent that this approach will be adequate with
      significant missing or rejected data. Katz and Parlange (1995) and
      Gyasi-Agyei (1999) ignore and discard months with any missing data. As a
      result, valuable information could be lost, particularly if there is
      limited data in the first place. For some months of the year Gyasi-Agyei
      (1999) discarded up to half of the available data. With an event-based
      approach, discarding storm events or inter-event times containing
      missing intervals should introduce no significant bias into the
      calibration, provided the occurrence of this corrupted data is random.
      Therefore, if part of a month of data is missing it does not invalidate
      the remaining good quality data in that month.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_e1id1">
    <title>Stochastic Rainfall Generation Philosophy</title>

    <para>Stochastic generation of daily or sub-daily rainfall sequences
    requires the specification of a probabilistic model of rainfall over time.
    Such a probability model should account for the following features of
    daily or sub-daily rainfall:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The significant probability mass for zero values (no
        rain);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The seasonality of a range of rainfall statistics, including
        wet/dry days, averages and extremes;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The low-frequency variability, which causes below- or
        above-average rainfall to persist for multiple consecutive
        years;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The short-range (day-to-day and within-day) persistence of wet
        and dry periods;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The highly skewed distribution of rainfall, with the rainfall
        features often of most interest in a flood estimation context being
        located at the tail of the distribution.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Simulation of these aspects of rainfall requires careful formulation
    of the rainfall generation model, often by using conditional variables
    that enforce this variability at multiple timescales.</para>

    <para>Finally, although the current chapter does not discuss the case of
    stochastic generation at multiple locations, this added consideration
    would require the specification of multivariate conditional probability
    distributions characterising both the temporal evolution of the process,
    as well its links in space.</para>

    <para>In general, single-site rainfall generation approaches fall into the
    following categories:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Daily rainfall generation</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Sub-daily rainfall generation</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Sub-daily rainfall generation through disaggregation of daily
        rainfall</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>Many alternative models exist for each of these categories, as do
    their extensions to ungauged or partly gauged locations. Readers are
    referred to [<emphasis role="italic">Sharma and Mehrotra</emphasis>, 2010]
    for a review on these alternatives. A subset of these alternatives is
    discussed below. It should be noted that some of the sub-daily models
    simulate daily rainfall very well when aggregated to daily (See Frost et
    al. 2004)</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_xlggl">
    <title>Rainfall Generation Models</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_t0yv2">
      <title>Daily Rainfall Generation</title>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_zrgot">
        <title>Overview of daily rainfall generation techniques</title>

        <para>Generation of daily rainfall sequences requires the formulation
        of procedures for generating rainfall occurrences (wet or dry) and
        amounts (for the wet days). As rainfall occurs in bursts, it is
        important to represent the day-to-day persistence in the rainfall.
        This can be accomplished by assuming rainfall is a Markovian process,
        with the nature of persistence defined by the order of Markovian
        dependence. A first-order Markovian process assumes rainfall depends
        only on the rainfall (amount or occurrence) on the previous
        day.</para>

        <para>Assuming first or low-order dependence can result in the number
        of wet days in a year being similar from one year to the next. This is
        contrary to the nature of rainfall in Australia and elsewhere, with
        considerable variations from one year to the next often modulated by
        low-frequency climatic anomalies such as the El Nino Southern
        Oscillation (ENSO) phenomenon. This inability of rainfall generation
        models to simulate observed variability at aggregated (annual or
        longer) scales is referred to as “over-dispersion”[<emphasis
        role="italic">Katz and Parlange</emphasis>, 1998].</para>

        <para>In addition to the representation of persistence, a rainfall
        generation model needs to also allow for seasonal variation. This is
        often accomplished by allowing model parameters to be estimated on a
        seasonal or monthly basis. While these distributions are characterised
        by sample parameter estimates at locations with sufficient
        observational records, these can also be regionalised for use in
        ungauged locations.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch6_t_04g6n"/> (adapted from [<emphasis
        role="italic">Sharma and Mehrotra</emphasis>, 2010]) summarise the
        approaches used for generation of daily rainfall. The higher-order
        Markov approaches listed are especially relevant for Australia, given
        the significant low-frequency variability that characterises
        Australian rainfall. Mis-representation of this variability can have
        serious implications in the representation of pre-burst antecedent
        conditions, as well as the relationship between the rainfall extremes
        and the longer-range antecedent rainfall, given both are known to be
        modulated by climatic anomalies responsible for such variability in
        rainfall time series. <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_04g6n">
            <caption>A summary of alternative methods for stochastic
            generation of daily rainfall</caption>

            <col width="33%"/>

            <col width="33%"/>

            <col width="33%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Model</th>

                <th>Description/Advantages/Drawbacks</th>

                <th>References</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <th colspan="3">Daily rainfall occurrence generation</th>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Low order Markov chain models</td>

                <td>Based on wet days probabilities. For some regions
                generates rainfall series with too few long dry spells.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Buishand</emphasis>, 1977;
                <emphasis role="italic">Caskey</emphasis>, 1963; <emphasis
                role="italic">Feyerherm and Bark</emphasis>, 1965; 1967;
                <emphasis role="italic">Gabriel and Neumann</emphasis>, 1962;
                <emphasis role="italic">Hopkins and Robillard</emphasis>,
                1964; <emphasis role="italic">Racsko et al.</emphasis>, 1991;
                <emphasis role="italic">Selvalingam and Miura</emphasis>,
                1978; <emphasis role="italic">Stern and Coe</emphasis>, 1984;
                <emphasis role="italic">Wilks</emphasis>, 1998]; [<emphasis
                role="italic">Chapman</emphasis>, 1997]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Higher order Markov chain models</td>

                <td>Based on wet day probabilities of few consecutive days.
                The approach increases the length of the Markov model’s
                ‘memory’ of antecedent wet and dry days. The number of
                parameters (i.e., transition probabilities) required increases
                exponentially as the order increases, being 2k for a <emphasis
                role="italic">k</emphasis>th-order chain. These models
                improves the representation of observed inter- annual variance
                in the simulations but still fell short of observed climatic
                variability on average.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Coe and Stern</emphasis>, 1982;
                <emphasis role="italic">Dennett et al.</emphasis>, 1983;
                <emphasis role="italic">Gates and Tong</emphasis>, 1976;
                <emphasis role="italic">P G Jones and Thornton</emphasis>,
                1997; <emphasis role="italic">R. Mehrotra and
                Sharma</emphasis>, 2007a; b; <emphasis role="italic">Raj
                Mehrotra et al.</emphasis>, 2012; <emphasis
                role="italic">Pegram</emphasis>, 1980; <emphasis
                role="italic">Singh and Kripalani</emphasis>, 1986]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>‘hybrid-order’ Markov models</td>

                <td>The Markov ‘memory’ extends further back in time for the
                dry spells only.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Stern and Coe</emphasis>, 1984;
                <emphasis role="italic">Wilks</emphasis>, 1999b]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td rowspan="2">Alternating renewal process based models</td>

                <td>These spell-length models operate by fitting probability
                distributions to observed relative frequencies of wet and
                dry-spell lengths. The approach may not be suited in arid
                regions or in cases with less than 25 years of
                observations.</td>

                <td><para>[<emphasis role="italic">Buishand</emphasis>, 1977;
                <emphasis role="italic">Racsko et al.</emphasis>, 1991;
                <emphasis role="italic">Roldan and Woolhiser</emphasis>, 1982;
                <emphasis role="italic">Wilks</emphasis>, 1999b; <emphasis
                role="italic">David A. Woolhiser</emphasis>, 1992]</para>
                <para>Heneker et al. 2001</para></td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Non-parametric wet-dry spell length models</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Lall et al.</emphasis>, 1996;
                <emphasis role="italic">Sharma and Lall</emphasis>, 1999]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <th colspan="3">Daily rainfall generation including
                amount</th>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Parametric precipitation amounts models</td>

                <td>Based on some distribution like a two parameter gamma
                distribution, exponential and mixed exponential distribution.
                These models assume that precipitation amounts on wet days are
                independent, and follow the same distribution.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Wilks</emphasis>,
                1999a][<emphasis role="italic">Coe and Stern</emphasis>, 1982;
                <emphasis role="italic">Richardson</emphasis>, 1981; <emphasis
                role="italic">David A. Woolhiser and Pegram</emphasis>, 1979;
                <emphasis role="italic">David A. Woolhiser and
                Roldán</emphasis>, 1982; <emphasis role="italic">D. A.
                Woolhiser and Roldán</emphasis>, 1986]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Wet spell based precipitation amount models</td>

                <td>These models allow different probability distributions for
                precipitation amounts depending on that day’s position in a
                wet spell (separate models for start, mid and end of a wet
                spell).</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Chapman</emphasis>,
                1997][<emphasis role="italic">Buishand</emphasis>,
                1977][<emphasis role="italic">Wilks</emphasis>,
                1999a][<emphasis role="italic">Chin and Miller</emphasis>,
                1980; <emphasis role="italic">Cole and Sherriff</emphasis>,
                1972]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Nonparametric precipitation amount models</td>

                <td>A nonparametric kernel density estimation based procedure
                is used to simulate the rainfall conditional on previous time
                step value of rainfall and/or other variables</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Harrold et al.</emphasis>, 2003b;
                <emphasis role="italic">R. Mehrotra and Sharma</emphasis>,
                2006; <emphasis role="italic">Oriani et al.</emphasis>,
                2014]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Multistate Markov models</td>

                <td>These Markov models simulate both precipitation occurrence
                and amounts, by defining different ranges of precipitation
                amounts as constituting distinct states. The outcome of this
                approach depends on the choice of the number of states, their
                ranges and on the distributions used for wet-day amounts in
                any given state. These models involve comparatively large
                numbers of parameters, and thus require quite long data
                records in order to be estimated well.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">W C Boughton</emphasis>,
                1999][<emphasis role="italic">Gregory et al.</emphasis>, 1993;
                <emphasis role="italic">Haan et al.</emphasis>, 1976;
                <emphasis role="italic">McMahon and Srikanthan</emphasis>,
                1983; <emphasis role="italic">R. Srikanthan and
                McMahon</emphasis>, 1985]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Cluster based point processes models</td>

                <td>Rainfall process is described using cluster of rectangular
                pulses. In the approach, storms arrive according to a Poisson
                process and are represented by clusters of rainfall cells
                temporally displaced from the storm centre.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Evin and Favre</emphasis>, 2012;
                <emphasis role="italic">Kavvas and Delleur</emphasis>, 1981;
                <emphasis role="italic">D Kim et al.</emphasis>, 2014;
                <emphasis role="italic">Leblois and Creutin</emphasis>, 2013;
                <emphasis role="italic">Leonard et al.</emphasis>, 2008;
                <emphasis role="italic">Onof et al.</emphasis>, 2000;
                <emphasis role="italic">Ramirez and Bras</emphasis>, 1985;
                <emphasis role="italic">Ignacio Rodriguez-Iturbe et
                al.</emphasis>, 1984; <emphasis role="italic">I.
                Rodriguez-Iturbe et al.</emphasis>, 1987; 1988; <emphasis
                role="italic">Waymire and Gupta</emphasis>, 1981a; b;
                <emphasis role="italic">Wheater et al.</emphasis>, 2000]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Copula theory based models</td>

                <td>Multivariate copulas are used to describe the spatial
                structure of rainfall amounts and occurrences</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">A. Bárdossy and
                Pegram</emphasis>, 2009; <emphasis
                role="italic">Serinaldi</emphasis>, 2009]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Multifractal simulation techniques</td>

                <td>These models characterize rainfall by scale invariant
                (scaling) and fractal properties.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Seed et al.</emphasis>,
                1999][<emphasis role="italic">Merab Menabde et al.</emphasis>,
                1997][<emphasis role="italic">Jha et al.</emphasis>,
                2015]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Conditioning on covariates</td>

                <td>Monthly statistics of rainfall, long-range forecasts of
                the monthly statistics, random numbers or a ‘hidden’ mixture
                approach to capture some interannual variability.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">P G Jones and
                Thornton</emphasis>, 1997][<emphasis role="italic">Katz et
                al.</emphasis>, 2003][<emphasis
                role="italic">Wilks</emphasis>, 1999b]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Conditioning on previous time history of simulated
                rainfall</td>

                <td>Rainfall occurrences and amounts are simulated conditional
                on the recent past rainfall behaviour.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Harrold et al.</emphasis>, 2003a;
                b; <emphasis role="italic">R. Mehrotra and Sharma</emphasis>,
                2007a; b; <emphasis role="italic">Sharma and
                O'Neill</emphasis>, 2002]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Conditioning on some aspect of large-scale atmospheric
                circulation/weather patterns</td>

                <td>Using the Lamb Weather Type weather classification,
                monthly Southern Oscillation Index (SOI), North Atlantic
                Oscillation Index (NAOI), North Atlantic sea surface
                temperature (SST) anomalies and other atmospheric
                predictors.</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Katz and Parlange</emphasis>,
                1998]Hay <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>.
                (1991)[<emphasis role="italic">Charles et al.</emphasis>,
                1999; <emphasis role="italic">Hughes and Guttorp</emphasis>,
                1994][<emphasis role="italic">David A. Woolhiser</emphasis>,
                1992][<emphasis role="italic">Wilby et al.</emphasis>,
                1998][<emphasis role="italic">D Kim et al.</emphasis>,
                2014][<emphasis role="italic">Bardossy and Plate</emphasis>,
                1992; <emphasis role="italic">Serinaldi and Kilsby</emphasis>,
                2014; <emphasis role="italic">Wallis and Griffiths</emphasis>,
                1997][<emphasis role="italic">D Kim et al.</emphasis>, 2014;
                <emphasis role="italic">Y Kim et al.</emphasis>, 2012;
                <emphasis role="italic">Kleiber et al.</emphasis>,
                2012][<emphasis role="italic">Carey-Smith et al.</emphasis>,
                2014; <emphasis role="italic">Heaps et al.</emphasis>,
                2015]</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Model nesting at multiple time scales</td>

                <td>Rainfall amounts are adjusted at monthly/seasonal and
                annual time scales to maintain the desired variability at
                higher time scales</td>

                <td>[<emphasis role="italic">W C Boughton</emphasis>,
                1999][<emphasis role="italic">R. Srikanthan and
                Pegram</emphasis>, 2009][<emphasis role="italic">Wang and
                Nathan</emphasis>, 2007], Lambert et al. (2003), Thyer and
                Kuczera (2003a, 2003b)</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <para>The daily generation models in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_t_04g6n"/>
        are often formulated using high quality observed rainfall records, and
        then regionalised for use anywhere. Regionalisation of a rainfall
        generation model is accomplished either by interpolating model
        parameters for use at ungauged locations, or by sampling data from
        other locations as representative for the location of interest. In the
        discussion that follows, two methods - the regionalised Nested
        Transition Probability Model (N-TPM) and the Regionalised Modified
        Markov Model (RMMM), are summarised due to their widespread use in
        Australia and the availability of software to facilitate
        implementation within the country.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_egx9g">
        <title>Nested Transition Probability Matrix approach (N-TPM)</title>

        <para>The Transition Probability Model (TPM) offers a simple and
        effective characterisation of Markov order-one persistence in the
        daily rainfall generation process [<emphasis
        role="italic">Ratnasingham Srikanthan et al.</emphasis>, 2003]. In the
        TPM, the daily rainfalls are divided into a maximum of seven states.
        State 1 is dry (no rainfall) and the other states are wet. The
        rainfall amounts in the largest state are generated using a Gamma
        distribution. The model operates by estimating the transition
        probability of sampling a state given the state of the preceding time
        step. Hence, if seven states are used, a 7x7 transition probability
        matrix needs to be estimated from the data. As only Markov order-one
        dependence is assumed, a correction is needed to ensure that simulated
        rainfall exhibits sufficient variability at an annual time scale. This
        correction occurs by re-scaling of the daily rainfall amounts, thereby
        inflating the variability of rain on each day, while keeping the
        fraction of wet days in a year constant.</para>

        <para>The TPM has been applied in a number of studies, and exists in a
        regionalised form for use anywhere in Australia. The computer program
        for the TPM can be obtained from the Stochastic Climate Library as
        part of the e-Water Toolkit (<link
        xlink:href="http://toolkit.net.au/Tools/SCL">http://toolkit.net.au/Tools/SCL</link>
        ). Parameters for major city centres and recommendations for ungauged
        locations are provided within the software. <xref
        linkend="b2_ch6_t_1n4n0"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch6_t_6gzdy"/>
        present the number of states and the rainfall amount associated with
        highest state used for major city centres in Australia. If the number
        of states is less than seven the upper limit of the last state is
        infinite. <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_cvuvq"/> provides regional extents
        that are used in applying the method to other locations not included
        in the tables.</para>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_1n4n0">
            <caption>Number of states used for different rainfall stations in
            the Transition Probability Model [<emphasis
            role="italic">Ratnasingham Srikanthan et al.</emphasis>,
            2003]</caption>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <col width="6%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Station</th>

                <th><para>Latitude °S</para></th>

                <th><para>Longitude</para> <para> °E</para></th>

                <th>J</th>

                <th>F</th>

                <th>M</th>

                <th>A</th>

                <th>M</th>

                <th>J</th>

                <th>J</th>

                <th>A</th>

                <th>S</th>

                <th>O</th>

                <th>N</th>

                <th>D</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Melbourne</td>

                <td>37 49</td>

                <td>144 58</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Lerderderg</td>

                <td>37 30</td>

                <td>144 22</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Monto</td>

                <td>24 51</td>

                <td>151 01</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Cowra</td>

                <td>33 49</td>

                <td>148 42</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Adelaide</td>

                <td>34 56</td>

                <td>138 35</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Perth</td>

                <td>31 57</td>

                <td>115 51</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Sydney</td>

                <td>33 52</td>

                <td>151 12</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Brisbane</td>

                <td>27 28</td>

                <td>121 06</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Mackay</td>

                <td>21 06</td>

                <td>149 06</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Kalgoorlie</td>

                <td>30 47</td>

                <td>21 27</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Alice Springs</td>

                <td>23 49</td>

                <td>133 53</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Onslow</td>

                <td>21 40</td>

                <td>115 07</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>4</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Bamboo Springs</td>

                <td>22 03</td>

                <td>119 38</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>6</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>5</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Broome</td>

                <td>17 57</td>

                <td>122 15</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>4</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Darwin</td>

                <td>12 27</td>

                <td>130 48</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>2</td>

                <td>3</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>

                <td>7</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_cvuvq">
          <title>Location of the rainfall stations in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch6_t_04g6n"/> for the Transition Probability model
          [Ratnasingham Srikanthan et al.<emphasis>, 2003]</emphasis></title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2004.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_6gzdy">
            <caption>State boundaries for rainfall amounts in the TPM
            model</caption>

            <col width="50%"/>

            <col width="50%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>State Number</th>

                <th>Upper state boundary limit (mm)</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>1</td>

                <td>0.0</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>2</td>

                <td>0.9</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>3</td>

                <td>2.9</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>4</td>

                <td>6.9</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>5</td>

                <td>14.9</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>6</td>

                <td>30.9</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>7</td>

                <td>CHECKK</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <para>As the TPM requires a correction for the mis-representation of
        low-frequency variability, several alternatives have been developed to
        address this limitation. The Nested TPM [<emphasis role="italic">R.
        Srikanthan and Pegram</emphasis>, 2009] operates by aggregating the
        sequences of rainfall from the TPM to first a monthly and then to an
        annual time scale. Once aggregated, rainfall is modelled as a Markov
        order-one process at the aggregated time scale, accounting for the
        lag-one autocorrelation and variability that is manifested in the
        aggregated process. This offers an effective means of correcting
        variability in rainfall across a range of time scales, making the
        generated series more useable for hydrological applications. As with
        the TPM, the computer program for the Nested TPM can be obtained from
        the Stochastic Climate Library as part of the e-Water Toolkit (<link
        xlink:href="http://toolkit.net.au/Tools/SCL">http://toolkit.net.au/Tools/SCL</link>
        ).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_ujl47">
        <title>Regionalized Modified Markov Model (RMMM)</title>

        <para>The Regionalized Modified Markov Model (RMMM) offers a
        nonparametric basis for daily rainfall generation at any location in
        Australia in a manner that ensures generated sequences mimic observed
        rainfall in its representation of distributional features as well as
        low-frequency variability. The RMMM is a regionalised version of the
        Modified Markov Model (MMM) [<emphasis role="italic">R. Mehrotra and
        Sharma</emphasis>, 2007a] which simulates rainfall by characterising
        the rainfall occurrence by a variable-order Markovian process that is
        designed to simulate low-frequency variability. This variable-order
        Markov process is defined by assuming that daily rainfall occurrence
        depends on the rainfall state on the previous day as well as the
        aggregated rainfall for the past 30 and 365 days. The use of the
        aggregated rainfall conditioning variables allows the generated
        sequences to reflect the dependence there exists in observed rainfall
        across different temporal scales. Furthermore, use of aggregated
        variables allows invoking of the Central Limit Theorem and
        approximating their probability distribution as a Gaussian
        distribution, thereby simplifying parameter estimation and
        implementation. As a result of using the aggregated variables, the
        number of wet days in a year exhibit variability that is consistent
        with the observed record, in contrast to the Nested TPM approach that
        offers similar variability with rainfall amounts alone. Once the
        rainfall occurrences have been generated, rainfall amounts are
        generated using a nonparametric kernel density estimation
        approach.</para>

        <para>The algorithm for generating daily rainfall using the MMM is
        presented in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_gfdnjfsd"/> below.</para>

        <para><sidebar xml:id="b2_ch6_f_gfdnjfsd">
            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>For all calendar days of the year calculate the
                transition probabilities of the standard first order Markov
                model using the observations falling within the moving window
                of 31 days centered on each day. Denote these transition
                probabilities as p11 for previous day being wet and p01 for
                previous day being dry.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Also estimate the means, variances and covariances of
                the higher time scale predictor variables separately for
                occasions when current day is wet/day and previous day is
                wet/dry. (Mehrotra and Sharma (2007), identified 2 variables
                namely, previous 30 and 365 days wetness state)</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Consider a day. Ascertain appropriate critical
                transition probability to the day t based on previous day’s
                rainfall state of the generated series. If previous day is
                wet, assign critical probability p as p11 otherwise assign
                p01.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Calculate the values of the 30 and 365 days wetness
                state for the day t and the available generated sequence (Jo).
                To have values of wetness state in the beginning of the
                simulation randomly pickup a year from the historical record
                and calculate values of 30 and 365 days wetness states.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Modify the critical transition probability p of step 3
                using the following equation and, conditional means,
                variances, covariances and tth day value of higher time scale
                predictors for the generated day t. Denote the modified
                transition probability as <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mover>
                        <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                        <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                      </m:mover>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation>.</para>

                <informalequation>
                  <m:math display="block">
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mover>
                        <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                        <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                      </m:mover>

                      <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>1i</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>

                        <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                        <m:mfrac>
                          <m:mfrac>
                            <m:msup>
                              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                  <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mfrac>
                                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                        <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                                      </m:mfrac>

                                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                      <m:mfenced>
                                        <m:mrow>
                                          <m:msub>
                                            <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                                            <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                          </m:msub>

                                          <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                          <m:msub>
                                            <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                                            <m:mrow>
                                              <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                              <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                          </m:msub>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                      </m:mfenced>
                                    </m:mrow>

                                    <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:msubsup>
                                        <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                                        <m:mrow>
                                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                          <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                        </m:mrow>

                                        <m:mi>-1</m:mi>
                                      </m:msubsup>

                                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                      <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mfenced>
                                          <m:mrow>
                                            <m:msub>
                                              <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                                              <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                            </m:msub>

                                            <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                            <m:msub>
                                              <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                                              <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                              </m:mrow>
                                            </m:msub>
                                          </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mfenced>

                                        <m:mo>’</m:mo>
                                      </m:mrow>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                  </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mo>}</m:mo>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:msup>

                            <m:msqrt>
                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>det</m:mi>

                                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                <m:mfenced>
                                  <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                  </m:msub>
                                </m:mfenced>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:msqrt>
                          </m:mfrac>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mfrac>
                                  <m:msup>
                                    <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                                      <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                        <m:mrow>
                                          <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mfrac>
                                              <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                              <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                                            </m:mfrac>

                                            <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                            <m:mfenced>
                                              <m:mrow>
                                                <m:msub>
                                                  <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                                                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                                </m:msub>

                                                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                                <m:msub>
                                                  <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                                                  <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                                  </m:mrow>
                                                </m:msub>
                                              </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mfenced>
                                          </m:mrow>

                                          <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                                          <m:mrow>
                                            <m:msubsup>
                                              <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                                              <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                              </m:mrow>

                                              <m:mi>-1</m:mi>
                                            </m:msubsup>

                                            <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                            <m:mrow>
                                              <m:mfenced>
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                  <m:msub>
                                                    <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                                                    <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                                  </m:msub>

                                                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                                  <m:msub>
                                                    <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                  </m:msub>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                              </m:mfenced>

                                              <m:mo>’</m:mo>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                          </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                      </m:mrow>

                                      <m:mo>}</m:mo>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                  </m:msup>

                                  <m:msqrt>
                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mi>det</m:mi>

                                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                      <m:mfenced>
                                        <m:msub>
                                          <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                                          <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                          </m:mrow>
                                        </m:msub>
                                      </m:mfenced>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                  </m:msqrt>
                                </m:mfrac>

                                <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                                <m:msub>
                                  <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                                  <m:mi>1i</m:mi>
                                </m:msub>
                              </m:mrow>

                              <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mfrac>
                                  <m:msup>
                                    <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                                      <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                        <m:mrow>
                                          <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mfrac>
                                              <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                              <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                                            </m:mfrac>

                                            <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                            <m:mfenced>
                                              <m:mrow>
                                                <m:msub>
                                                  <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                                                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                                </m:msub>

                                                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                                <m:msub>
                                                  <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                                                  <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                                  </m:mrow>
                                                </m:msub>
                                              </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mfenced>
                                          </m:mrow>

                                          <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                                          <m:mrow>
                                            <m:msubsup>
                                              <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                                              <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                              </m:mrow>

                                              <m:mi>-1</m:mi>
                                            </m:msubsup>

                                            <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                            <m:mrow>
                                              <m:mfenced>
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                  <m:msub>
                                                    <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                                                    <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                                  </m:msub>

                                                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                                  <m:msub>
                                                    <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                  </m:msub>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                              </m:mfenced>

                                              <m:mo>’</m:mo>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                          </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                      </m:mrow>

                                      <m:mo>}</m:mo>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                  </m:msup>

                                  <m:msqrt>
                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mi>det</m:mi>

                                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                      <m:mfenced>
                                        <m:msub>
                                          <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                                          <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                          </m:mrow>
                                        </m:msub>
                                      </m:mfenced>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                  </m:msqrt>
                                </m:mfrac>

                                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                                <m:mfenced>
                                  <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                                    <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                    <m:msub>
                                      <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                                      <m:mi>1i</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                  </m:mrow>
                                </m:mfenced>
                              </m:mrow>

                              <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mfrac>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:math>
                </informalequation>

                <para>where <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> is the predictor set at time t, the
                <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> parameters represent the mean
                <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                        <m:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators="|">
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>J</m:mi>

                                <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                              <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>

                            <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>J</m:mi>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                  <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mfenced>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> and <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> is the corresponding variance-covariance
                matrix. Similarly, <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>0</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> and <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>V</m:mi>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>0</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> represent, respectively, the mean vector
                and the variance-covariance matrix of <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> when <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>J</m:mi>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                              <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                              <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> and <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>J</m:mi>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation>. The <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>1i</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> parameters represent the baseline
                transition probabilities of the first order Markov model
                defined by <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                        <m:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators="|">
                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>J</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>

                            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>J</m:mi>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                                <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:msub>

                            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mfenced>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> and <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>det</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                        <m:mfenced>
                          <m:mi/>
                        </m:mfenced>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> represents the determinant
                operation.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Compare <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mover>
                        <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                        <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                      </m:mover>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> with the uniform random variate
                <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>

                        <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                        <m:mfenced>
                          <m:mi>k</m:mi>
                        </m:mfenced>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> for station k. If <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                          <m:mfenced>
                            <m:mi>k</m:mi>
                          </m:mfenced>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>≤</m:mo>

                        <m:mover>
                          <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                          <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
                        </m:mover>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> , assign rainfall occurrence,
                <inlineequation>
                    <m:math display="inline">
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>Jo</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:math>
                  </inlineequation> for the day <emphasis>t</emphasis> as 1
                otherwise zero.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Move to the next date in the generated sequence and
                repeat steps 2-5 until the desired length of generated
                sequence is obtained.</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sidebar></para>

        <para>Box 5. Algorithm for step-wise daily rainfall generation using
        MMM [<emphasis role="italic">R. Mehrotra and Sharma</emphasis>,
        2007a]</para>

        <para>Readers are referred to [<emphasis role="italic">R. Mehrotra and
        Sharma</emphasis>, 2007a] for details of the MMM rainfall generation
        algorithm. A R-package to generate daily rainfall at multiple
        locations given observed rainfall time series has been developed
        [<emphasis role="italic">R. Mehrotra et al.</emphasis>, 2015] and is
        available for download from Hydrology@UNSW Software website (<link
        xlink:href="http://www.hydrology.unsw.edu.au/download/software/multisite-rainfall-simulator">http://www.hydrology.unsw.edu.au/download/software/multisite-rainfall-simulator</link>).
        The package exists as a Multi-site Rainfall Simulator (abbreviated
        MRS), offering the capability to generate rainfall at multiple
        locations of interest while maintaining their spatial dependence
        attributes in sequences, but simplifies to the MMM when used to
        generate rainfall for a single location.</para>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_m2q83">
          <title>Regionalisation</title>

          <para>The MMM as described above requires a representative sample of
          daily rainfall for generation to proceed. This restricts its
          application only to locations having long-length observed records.
          An attempt to regionalise the MMM was presented in [<emphasis
          role="italic">Raj Mehrotra et al.</emphasis>, 2012], using a similar
          approach to the regionalised sub-daily generation model [<emphasis
          role="italic">Seth Westra et al.</emphasis>, 2012] described later.
          Unlike the regionalised version of the Nested TPM presented earlier,
          here the regionalisation involved identifying rainfall records for
          locations deemed ‘similar’ to the target, followed by rescaling to
          adjust for changed climatology, and then pooling to take account of
          relative similarities each nearby location bears to the target
          location. This pooled record was then used as the basis for
          generating the daily rainfall sequences.</para>

          <para>As the regionalised approach relies on using data from nearby
          rainfall stations, it is necessary to: (1) identify metrics to
          determine whether two stations are ‘similar’; and (2) predict the
          probability that stations within a ‘neighbourhood’ of the target
          site are similar by regressing against physiographic indicators such
          as the difference in latitude, longitude, elevation and relative
          distance to coast between station pairs. The relative distance to
          coast is obtained by dividing the difference in distance to coast
          between two stations by the distance to coast of the target site.
          This is done to account for the fact that the relative influence of
          distance to coast is likely to be greater for two stations having
          greater proximity to the coastline.</para>

          <para>‘Similarity’ between any two sites was assessed based on the
          similarity in the bivariate probability distributions of a
          daily-scale attribute of interest, and the annual rainfall total.
          <xref linkend="b2_ch6_t_6gzdy"/> outlines the attributes used in
          formulation of the RMMM. Each of the attributes listed were used to
          define similarity between stations based on a 2-sample,
          2-dimensional Kolgomorov-Smirnov test [<emphasis
          role="italic">Fasano and Franceschini</emphasis>, 1987]. The
          resulting classification of similarity (‘1’ for similar and ‘0’ for
          dis-similar) for each attribute was pooled in a logistic regression
          framework, using the difference in latitude for the two stations,
          difference in longitude, and difference in the relative distance to
          coast as covariates.</para>

          <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_v3e2v">
              <caption>Daily scale attributes used to define similarity
              between locations. Each of these variables were estimated for
              each location and each year of record, and then paired to assess
              the best basis for defining ‘similarity’ between stations. Using
              2708 separate rain gauge stations with at least 25 years of
              data, this resulted in a total of 3,665,278 station
              pairs</caption>

              <col width="50%"/>

              <col width="50%"/>

              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Daily Maxima</td>

                  <td>Daily Maximum rainfall for DJF, MAM, JJA, SON</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>7-day Maxima</td>

                  <td>Maximum 7-day total rainfall for each season</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Wet/Dry spell lengths</td>

                  <td>Maximum Wet/Dry spell length for each season</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Rainfall Amount per spell</td>

                  <td>Total Rainfall in maximum wet spell for each season</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Daily Averages</td>

                  <td><itemizedlist>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Average rainfall amount per wet day for
                        year</para>
                      </listitem>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Average rainfall amount per day (wet or dry) for
                        each season</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>Number of wet days</td>

                  <td/>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table></para>

          <para>This logistic regression framework can then be used to
          determine the similarity between any two stations for the attribute
          of interest. Thereby, for a given target location where rainfall is
          to be generated, one can now rank stations with data from
          most-similar to least-similar for each attribute. The approach
          adopted in RMMM is to form an average rank using all attributes for
          all nearby stations, and use the lowest <emphasis
          role="italic">S</emphasis> ranks to identify the stations to use as
          the basis of rainfall generation. To account for the relative
          similarity across these <emphasis role="italic">S</emphasis>
          stations, each station is selected with a probability equal
          to:</para>

          <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_9t9fk">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>w</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mfrac>
                  <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mfrac>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:munderover>
                      <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>k</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                    </m:munderover>

                    <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>k</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mfrac>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>

          <para>where w<subscript>i</subscript> represents the weight
          associated with the <emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis>th station
          and r<subscript>i</subscript> the rank associated with that station,
          used as the basis for probabilistically selecting nearby stations in
          the modified Markov model. Lower-ranked stations, which, by
          definition have rainfall attributes which are most statistically
          similar to the target site, attain higher weight and therefore a
          higher probability of being used in MMM. This rationale is
          summarised in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_dg0kh"/> below.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_dg0kh">
            <title>Identification of “similar” locations for daily rainfall
            generation using RMMM</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2006.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>Once the ‘similar’ <emphasis role="italic">S</emphasis>
          stations have been identified, the generation of rainfall sequences
          at the target location proceeds as per the generation algorithm for
          MMM in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_gfdnjfsd"/>, with the inclusion of
          two additional steps. The first of these steps involves a re-scaling
          of the “similar” locations identified as described in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch6_f_dg0kh"/>. The second of these steps is a
          probabilistic selection of the “similar” locations, based on the
          weights associated with each location. These steps are summarised in
          <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_kqjty"/>.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_kqjty">
            <title>Algorithm for generation of daily rainfall sequences using
            the RMMM approach.</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2007.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>It should be noted that the low-frequency variable states (30-
          and 365-day wetness states in MMM) are ascertained based on the
          generated sequence, and hence represent the probabilistic average
          from the collation of the locations that have been selected as
          “similar” for the generation procedure. The software first
          identified “similar locations to the target location of interest,
          and then estimates the parameters of the MMM for these locations. As
          the criterion for selecting “similar” locations is defined as a
          function of differences in latitude, longitude, elevation and
          rescaled distances from the coast, a new location with daily
          observations can be included for the procedure to work. The
          parameters of the logistic regression model have been ascertained
          using high quality daily rainfall observations, and will be updated
          with significant updates in the daily rainfall datasets available in
          Australia.</para>

          <para>It should also be noted that use of actual rainfall data from
          similar locations is followed by a rescaling approach to account for
          changed climatology results in maximal use of observed rainfall. The
          use of MMM has been shown to produce generated rainfall with
          low-frequency variability and extremes that are consistent with
          observations. Given not one but multiple similar locations are used,
          the likelihood of over-sampling rainfall attributes from a
          misclassified similar location is reduced. An assessment by
          [<emphasis role="italic">Raj Mehrotra et al.</emphasis>, 2012]
          indicates that the method is able to capture the important
          attributes that define daily rainfall in both gauged and ungauged
          locations in Australia.</para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_1jn8s">
      <title>Sub-daily Rainfall Generation</title>

      <para>While considerable work has been done on generation of daily
      rainfall sequences, for design flood estimation, information is often
      required at a sub-daily time scale. Sub-daily rainfall sequences are
      generated using two sets of approaches. In the first case, rainfall is
      generated assuming a model formulated based on sub-daily rainfall
      observations. In the second case, sub-daily rainfall is generated
      conditional to daily rainfall through a disaggregation algorithm, the
      aim being to utilise the value of the much longer daily rainfall data
      and adopt a sensible approach to convert it to finer time steps. <xref
      linkend="b2_ch6_t_2izo5"/> summarises many of the sub-daily rainfall
      generation approaches available in the literature.</para>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_2izo5">
          <caption>Commonly used sub-daily rainfall generation
          models</caption>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Model</th>

              <th>Description/Advantages/Drawbacks</th>

              <th>References</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Poisson cluster process based models</td>

              <td>Represents rainfall events as clusters of rain cells where
              each cell is considered a pulse with a random duration and
              random intensity. A Rainfall generation model, however, can also
              be used for rainfall disaggregation.</td>

              <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Cowpertwait</emphasis>, 2010;
              <emphasis role="italic">Cowpertwait et al.</emphasis>, 2002;
              <emphasis role="italic">Leonard et al.</emphasis>,
              2008][<emphasis role="italic">Koutsoyiannis et al.</emphasis>,
              2003; <emphasis role="italic">Onof and Townend</emphasis>, 2004;
              <emphasis role="italic">Wheater et al.</emphasis>,
              2000][<emphasis role="italic">Gyasi-Agyei</emphasis>,
              2013][<emphasis role="italic">I. Rodriguez-Iturbe et
              al.</emphasis>, 1987; 1988][<emphasis
              role="italic">Eagleson</emphasis>, 1978; <emphasis
              role="italic">Heneker et al.</emphasis>, 2001; <emphasis
              role="italic">Koutsoyiannis and Pachakis</emphasis>, 1996;
              <emphasis role="italic">M. Menabde and Sivapalan</emphasis>,
              2000]</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Scale invariance theory based models</td>

              <td>Utilises the moment scaling function and an appropriate
              probability distribution for the weights.</td>

              <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Waymire and Gupta</emphasis>,
              1981a][<emphasis role="italic">Merab Menabde et al.</emphasis>,
              1997; <emphasis role="italic">Seed et al.</emphasis>,
              1999][<emphasis role="italic">de Lima and Grasman</emphasis>,
              1999; <emphasis role="italic">Deidda et al.</emphasis>, 1999;
              <emphasis role="italic">Gupta and Waymire</emphasis>, 1993;
              <emphasis role="italic">Lovejoy and Schertzer</emphasis>, 1990;
              <emphasis role="italic">Molnar and Burlando</emphasis>, 2005;
              <emphasis role="italic">Olsson and Berndtsson</emphasis>, 1998;
              <emphasis role="italic">Over and Gupta</emphasis>, 1996;
              <emphasis role="italic">Schertzer and Lovejoy</emphasis>, 1987;
              <emphasis role="italic">Sivakumar et al.</emphasis>, 2001]</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Parametric and non-parametric stochastic disaggregation
              models</td>

              <td>Based on disaggregation of daily rainfall based on
              distribution of sub-daily rainfall statistics/ rainfall
              values.</td>

              <td>[<emphasis role="italic">Arnold and Williams</emphasis>,
              1989; <emphasis role="italic">Connolly et al.</emphasis>, 1998;
              <emphasis role="italic">Cowpertwait et al.</emphasis>, 1996;
              <emphasis role="italic">Econopouly et al.</emphasis>, 1990;
              <emphasis role="italic">Hershenhorn and Woolhiser</emphasis>,
              1987; <emphasis role="italic">Sharma and Srikanthan</emphasis>,
              2006; <emphasis role="italic">Seth Westra et al.</emphasis>,
              2012][<emphasis role="italic">Koutsoyiannis</emphasis>, 2001;
              <emphasis role="italic">Koutsoyiannis and Onof</emphasis>,
              2000]</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>

      <para>We discuss next two approaches recommended for use in Australia.
      Both approaches exist in a regionalised form and can be adopted at any
      location within the country. The first of these approaches represents a
      sub-daily rainfall generator that is calibrated using sub-daily data and
      parameters regionalised for use anywhere, while the second is a daily to
      sub-daily disaggregation approach that relies on either the observed
      daily rainfall or a generated daily rainfall sequence to convert to a
      sub-daily scale.</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_jsbvo">
        <title>Disaggregated Rainfall Intensity Pulse (DRIP)</title>

        <para>Also known as ‘alternating renewal’ or ‘profile-based’ models,
        event-based models break the rainfall process into a series of events
        characterised by inter-arrival time, storm duration and mean storm
        intensity. Early work on such models by [<emphasis
        role="italic">Eagleson</emphasis>, 1978] involved simulating rainfall
        arrivals using a Poisson distribution, the time between events and the
        event duration using an exponential distribution, and the storm event
        depth using a gamma distribution. Since this time these models have
        undergone significant development, including the elucidation of the
        self-similarity concept, in which storms are found to exhibit similar
        internal structure despite differing durations and storm depths, thus
        providing a basis for the disaggregation of storm events into
        within-storm temporal patterns [<emphasis role="italic">Koutsoyiannis
        et al.</emphasis>, 2003][<emphasis role="italic">Garcia-Guzman and
        Aranda-Oliver</emphasis>, 1993], and the development of a generalised
        exponential distribution for representing inter-storm and storm
        durations [<emphasis role="italic">Lambert and Kuczera</emphasis>,
        1998].</para>

        <para>The Disaggregated Rectangular Intensity Pulse (DRIP) model was
        developed by [<emphasis role="italic">Heneker et al.</emphasis>, 2001]
        with the view to addressing several perceived deficiencies in existing
        event-based models, particularly with regard to the simulation of
        extreme rainfall and aggregation statistics. The DRIP modelling
        process is divided into two stages. The generation stage (<emphasis
        role="bold"><xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_0rmsb"/>a</emphasis>) is
        represented by three random variables: dry spell or inter-event time
        <emphasis role="italic">ta</emphasis>, the wet spell or storm duration
        <emphasis role="italic">td</emphasis>, and the average intensity
        <emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis>, with <emphasis
        role="italic">ta</emphasis> and <emphasis
        role="italic">td</emphasis>both described by a generalised exponential
        distribution and the intensity (<emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis>)
        described by a generalised Pareto distribution. In the second stage,
        the individual events are disaggregated through a constrained random
        walk (<xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_0rmsb"/><emphasis
        role="bold">b</emphasis>) to represent the rainfall temporal pattern
        for each event.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_0rmsb">
          <title>The Disaggregated Rectangular Intensity Pulse model
          (extracted from Heneker<emphasis role="italic"><emphasis
          role="bold"> </emphasis></emphasis>et al, 2001)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2008.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The random walk through a nondimensional time-depth space is
        illustrated in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_ozunq"/>. This is then used to
        disaggregate the rectangular pulse to time steps of the order of six
        or fewer minutes. Time during the storm is non-dimensionalised by
        <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>τ</m:mi>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> where t is the time since the start of the storm
        and depth is non-dimensionalised by <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                    <m:mfenced>
                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                    </m:mfenced>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> where <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                <m:mfenced>
                  <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                </m:mfenced>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the cumulative rainfall up to time t. The
        random walk progresses in discrete time intervals <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>Δ</m:mi>

                <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                <m:mi>τ</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> from coordinate (0,0) to (1,1) in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch6_f_lrnm4"/>, always with a non-negative slope. There
        are two possibilities for a jump from <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mi>τ</m:mi>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> to <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>τ</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>Δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>τ</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation>:</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>An internal dry spell (represented by a horizontal segment
            in Figure <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_lrnm4"/>) whose probability of
            occurrence is defined by a probability distribution; or</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A rainburst (represented by a sloping segment in Figure
            <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_lrnm4"/>) whose nondimemsional depth
            <inlineequation>
                <m:math display="inline">
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>Δ</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>δ</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:math>
              </inlineequation> is sampled from a probability
            distribution.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_lrnm4">
          <title>Schematic of non-dimensional random walk used in DRIP
          disaggregate pulses.</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2052.PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>To fit a probability distribution to the observed inter-event
        time <emphasis role="italic">ta</emphasis> and storm duration
        <emphasis role="italic">td</emphasis>populations, a procedure was
        employed to extract independent events from the continuous historical
        record. After analysis of correlation results, Heneker <emphasis
        role="italic">et al.</emphasis> (2001) adopted a minimum inter-event
        time of 2 hours to distinguish independent storms and inter-storm
        periods. This value provides a balance between ensuring consecutive
        events are sufficiently independent and the need to have as much
        calibration storm data as possible within a fixed length historical
        record. While different minimum inter-event times have been reported
        (e.g. Grace and Eagleson (1967), Sariahmed and Kisiel (1968),
        Koutsoyiannis and Xanthopoulos (1990), Heneker <emphasis
        role="italic">et al.</emphasis> (2001)), Heneker <emphasis
        role="italic">et al.</emphasis> (2001) showed that 2 hours was shown
        to assure independence of storm events across numerous Australian
        sites.</para>

        <para>The generalised exponential distribution developed by Lambert
        and Kuczera (1998) was used to model the distributions of inter-event
        time and storm duration. The generalised exponential distribution
        takes the form</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_98jj4">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                <m:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators="|">
                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mfenced>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                  <m:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators="|">
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>≤</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mfenced>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                      <m:msup>
                        <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>g</m:mi>

                                <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                              <m:mfenced>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                                  <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                                    <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                  </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:mfenced>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:msup>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>&gt;</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where <emphasis role="italic">X</emphasis> is an independently
        distributed random variable and <emphasis role="italic">qt
        </emphasis>is a parameter vector which may be dependent on<emphasis
        role="italic">t</emphasis> defined as the time at the start of the
        storm or inter-event time, and <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>g</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                <m:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators="|">
                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mfenced>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is a kernel function. The kernel chosen by Heneker
        <emphasis role="italic">et al.</emphasis> (2001) to best fit the data
        was a combination of functions based on the Generalised Pareto
        Distribution (Rosjberg <emphasis role="italic">et al.</emphasis> 1992)
        and the power law</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_0s5tn">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                      <m:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators="|">
                        <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                      </m:mfenced>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>g</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                  <m:mfenced>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mfenced>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mfrac>

                    <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>log</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>e</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>

                            <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                            <m:mfrac>
                              <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                                <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                              </m:msub>
                            </m:mfrac>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>3</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>

                    <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                    <m:msup>
                      <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>4</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:msup>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>&lt;</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>0</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>

                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>3</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>4</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>&gt;</m:mo>

                <m:mi>0</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>The parameter vector <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                <m:mi>t</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is estimated using maximum likelihood techniques.
        The DRIP parameters are usually calibrated for each month of the year
        to capture seasonal variability in the rainfall process. <xref
        linkend="b2_ch6_f_5bb77"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_o1tcc"/>
        illustrate observed and fitted probability distributions for
        inter-event and storm durations for Melbourne for select months and
        demonstrate the good fit typically achieved by the generalized
        exponential distribution. Noting that exponentially distributed data
        would plot as a straight line in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_5bb77"/> and
        <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_o1tcc"/>, the use of an exponential
        distribution for inter-event and storm durations would be clearly
        inappropriate. A detailed comparison of the DRIP model with other
        point process models is given in Frost et al. (2004)</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_5bb77">
          <title>Heneker <emphasis role="italic">et al.</emphasis>(2001) model
          fitted to monthly inter-event time data for Melbourne in
          January</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2053.PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_o1tcc">
          <title>Heneker<emphasis role="italic"> et al.</emphasis>(2001) model
          fitted to monthly storm duration data for Melbourne in May</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2054.PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>Recently, DRIP has been extended to any location where
        sufficient daily data is available, thus greatly augmenting the domain
        of the approach. The basis of this regionalisation is a
        ‘master-target’ scaling relationship in which model calibration is
        undertaken at a ‘master’ site with a long pluviograph record which is
        then updated and scaled to the ‘target’ site of interest using the
        information from either a short pluviograph or daily rainfall record
        (Jennings <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>, 2009), with
        testing providing encouraging results for separations of up to 190 km
        between the master and the target.</para>

        <para>The software for DRIP is available via the Stochastic Climate
        Library as part of the e-Water Toolkit (<link
        xlink:href="http://toolkit.net.au/Tools/DRIP">http://toolkit.net.au/Tools/DRIP</link>
        ).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_rnlni">
        <title>Regionalized Method of Fragments (RMOF)</title>

        <para>The regionalised method of fragments offers a mechanism to
        disaggregate observed or generated daily rainfall sequences to a
        sub-daily time scale. The disaggregation rationale for the method is
        patterned after the Method of Fragments [<emphasis role="italic">W C
        Boughton</emphasis>, 1999] that resamples the observed near-continuous
        fractions (or fragments) of daily accumulated rainfall for use with
        any daily total that is closest in magnitude. This approach assumes
        that the sub-daily rainfall structure depends solely on the daily
        rainfall, an assumption that can lead to discontinuities in the
        generated sub-daily sequences between two adjacent days. Taking this
        on board, [<emphasis role="italic">Seth Westra et al.</emphasis>,
        2012] modified the basic Method of Fragments approach in two ways. The
        first modification was to the traditional fragments approach to work
        at ungauged locations. The second modification was the use of a
        “state-based” conditioning approach [<emphasis role="italic">Sharma
        and Srikanthan</emphasis>, 2006] that makes use of information about
        the state of rainfall on the preceding and the next day, in an attempt
        to reduce the disconnect in sub-daily rainfall attributes across daily
        boundaries.</para>

        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_byzkg"/> illustrates the rationale
        behind the regionalised version of the state-based Method of Fragments
        procedure used in [<emphasis role="italic">Seth Westra et
        al.</emphasis>, 2012]. Here, I(Rt) represents the state (wet or dry)
        of the rainfall on day t. Conditioning the selection of a “similar”
        day in the historical record involves selecting from a subset of days
        that (a) fall within a calendar window representative of the season
        (chosen equal to +/-15 days in [<emphasis role="italic">Seth Westra et
        al.</emphasis>, 2012]), and (b) represent the same state
        (I(Rt-1),I(Rt=1),I(Rt+1)). Once these subsets of days are identified,
        they are ranked based on their similarity with the rainfall amount
        that is sought to be disaggregated. This forms the sample of days the
        fragments can be resampled from. Resampling proceeds probabilistically
        using the k-nn resampling approach of [<emphasis role="italic">Lall
        and Sharma</emphasis>, 1996]. Once the fragments have been resampled,
        they are scaled back to rainfall amounts by multiplication with the
        daily rainfall total for the day being disaggregated.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_byzkg">
          <title>Illustration of the state-based method of fragments algorithm
          used in the Regionalised Method of Fragments sub-daily rainfall
          generation procedure. A sub-daily time-step of 6-minutes is used in
          this illustration, although no change in the procedure is needed if
          an alternate sub-daily time-step is to be adopted</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2009.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The logic used to regionalise the method is similar to that
        adopted in case of the Regionalised Modified Markov Model (RMMM)
        earlier. Here, the importance of regionalisation is all the more given
        the paucity of sub-daily rainfall records in most parts of Australia
        (and the world). However, here the aim of the regionalisation is not
        to identify locations having similar rainfall attributes as the
        target, but a similar daily to sub-daily disaggregation relationships.
        As with the daily rainfall generation, a range of criteria were used
        to characterise this relationship. These are listed in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch6_t_sgsgw"/> below.</para>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_sgsgw">
            <caption>Sub-daily attributes used to define similarity between
            locations. Each of these variables were estimated for each
            location, and then paired to assess the best basis for defining
            ‘similarity’ between stations.</caption>

            <col width="50%"/>

            <col width="50%"/>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Maximum sub-daily Intensity</td>

                <td>Maximum Intensity Fraction for each day for 6, 12, 30, 60,
                120, 180 and 360 minute durations</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Fraction of zeroes</td>

                <td>Fraction of zero rainfall time-steps within each day at a
                6-minute time scale.</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Timing of Maximum Intensity</td>

                <td>The timing associated with the maximum intensity fraction
                for the day for 6, 12, 30, 60, 120, 180 and 360 minute time
                steps</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <para>Using 232 separate rain gauge stations with at least 30 years of
        data, a total of 26796 station pairs were formulated for each
        attribute. The similarity in each attribute across each pair was then
        assessed using a 2-sample 2-dimensional Kolmogorov Smirnov test. Using
        a significance level of 5%, this allowed the identification of pairs
        where the attributes were similar. This then allowed the
        identification of covariates that could be used to distinguish
        “similar” locations to allow the regionalisation to proceed. Use of
        attributes pertaining to the maximum sub-daily fractions at multiple
        durations, as well as the timing of the maximum, allowed similarity to
        be defined taking both diurnal pattern characterisation and rainfall
        magnitudes into account. The use of fraction of zeroes allowed
        distinction between locations having dominantly convective extremes
        from those that were spread over the day.</para>

        <para>The results of the significance testing described above were
        used as the basis for formulating a logistic regression relationship
        for each attribute, with regression coefficients being allowed to vary
        with season. The predictor variables found to be significant in
        defining the relationship were the differences in latitude, longitude,
        elevation and the relative distance to the coast. Based on this
        relationship, given any location in Australia, the user can identify a
        subset of sub-daily locations having attributes that are most similar
        to the target location sequences are needed at. This information is
        expressed as a probability, which is then used to identify a defined
        number of sub-daily locations for use in the RMOF procedure.</para>

        <para>The logistic regression of the binomial (0 for insignificant and
        1 for a significant test outcome) response for each sub-daily
        attribute can be expressed as:</para>

        <para>(4)</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_2nut3">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>Pr</m:mi>

                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                <m:mfenced>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>u</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfenced>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>logit</m:mi>

                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>

                <m:mfenced>
                  <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                </m:mfenced>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mfrac>
                <m:msup>
                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                </m:msup>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                  </m:msup>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mfrac>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>The logit function transforms the continuous predictor variables
        in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_t_4chxl"/> to the range [0,1] as required
        when modelling a binomial response. In this equation, <emphasis
        role="bold">z</emphasis> is defined as:</para>

        <para>(5)</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_1ozwd">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>z</m:mi>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>v</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>...</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>v</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>5</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>5</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>with β representing the regression coefficients in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch6_t_4chxl"/> for the five predictor variables
        used.</para>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_4chxl">
            <caption>Logistic Regression Coefﬁcients for the Regionalised
            Method of Fragments sub-daily generation model<footnote>
                <para>All predictors were found to be statistically
                significant (usually with a p-value &lt;0.001 level), with the
                exception of several predictors labelled as NS (not
                significant). Seasons include December-January-February (DJF),
                March-April-May (MAM), June-July-August (JJA) and
                September-October- November (SON).</para>
              </footnote></caption>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <col width="12%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th colspan="2"/>

                <th colspan="6">Logistic regression Coefficients</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Season</td>

                <td>Subdaily Rainfall Attribute</td>

                <td>Intercept</td>

                <td>Latitude</td>

                <td>Longitude</td>

                <td>LatitudexLongitude</td>

                <td>DistanceCoast</td>

                <td>Elevation</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>DJF</td>

                <td>6min intensity</td>

                <td>0.426</td>

                <td>-0.345</td>

                <td>-0.0377</td>

                <td>0.0064</td>

                <td>-0.186</td>

                <td>-0.00089</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>DJF</td>

                <td>1h intensity</td>

                <td>0.823</td>

                <td>-0.333</td>

                <td>-0.0425</td>

                <td>0.0093</td>

                <td>-0.231</td>

                <td>-0.00075</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>DJF</td>

                <td>Fraction of zeros</td>

                <td>-0.375</td>

                <td>-0.253</td>

                <td>-0.0318</td>

                <td>0.0075</td>

                <td>-0.242</td>

                <td>-0.00065</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>DJF</td>

                <td>6min time</td>

                <td>0.0979</td>

                <td>-0.137</td>

                <td>-0.0099</td>

                <td>0.0022</td>

                <td>-0.453</td>

                <td>-0.00141</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>MAM</td>

                <td>6min intensity</td>

                <td>-0.067</td>

                <td>-0.192</td>

                <td>-0.0065</td>

                <td>NS</td>

                <td>-0.218</td>

                <td>-0.00130</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>MAM</td>

                <td>1h intensity</td>

                <td>0.308</td>

                <td>-0.178</td>

                <td>-0.0074</td>

                <td>NS</td>

                <td>-0.107</td>

                <td>-0.00098</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>MAM</td>

                <td>Fraction of zeros</td>

                <td>-0.806</td>

                <td>-0.157</td>

                <td>-0.0105</td>

                <td>0.0025</td>

                <td>-0.165</td>

                <td>-0.00060</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>MAM</td>

                <td>6min time</td>

                <td>1.256</td>

                <td>-0.140</td>

                <td>-0.0226</td>

                <td>-0.0034</td>

                <td>-0.227</td>

                <td>-0.00092</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>JJA</td>

                <td>6min intensity</td>

                <td>-0.197</td>

                <td>-0.097</td>

                <td>-0.0110</td>

                <td>0.0034</td>

                <td>-0.096</td>

                <td>-0.00198</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>JJA</td>

                <td>1h intensity</td>

                <td>0.471</td>

                <td>-0.0102</td>

                <td>-0.0204</td>

                <td>0.0033</td>

                <td>NS</td>

                <td>-0.00335</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>JJA</td>

                <td>Fraction of zeros</td>

                <td>-0.365</td>

                <td>-0.073</td>

                <td>-0.0171</td>

                <td>0.0031</td>

                <td>-0.101</td>

                <td>-0.00116</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>JJA</td>

                <td>6min time</td>

                <td>2.078</td>

                <td>-0.098</td>

                <td>-0.0321</td>

                <td>0.0037</td>

                <td>-0.156</td>

                <td>-0.00069</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>SON</td>

                <td>6min intensity</td>

                <td>0.474</td>

                <td>-0.387</td>

                <td>-0.0722</td>

                <td>0.0129</td>

                <td>NS</td>

                <td>-0.00146</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>SON</td>

                <td>1h intensity</td>

                <td>0.824</td>

                <td>-0.325</td>

                <td>-0.0835</td>

                <td>0.0135</td>

                <td>NS</td>

                <td>-0.00132</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>SON</td>

                <td>Fraction of zeros</td>

                <td>-0.382</td>

                <td>-0.239</td>

                <td>-0.0623</td>

                <td>0.0104</td>

                <td>-0.087</td>

                <td>-0.00095</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>SON</td>

                <td>6min time</td>

                <td>1.028</td>

                <td>-0.162</td>

                <td>-0.0287</td>

                <td>0.0042</td>

                <td>-0.317</td>

                <td>NS</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <para>This allows the identification of the most to least similar
        sub-daily locations for each attribute of interest, which forms the
        basis for identification of a subset of locations used to sample the
        fragments. As multiple sub-daily attributes are considered in this
        choice, this subset is selected based on a common rank averaged across
        all the attributes for each season. The number of locations the
        fragments are pooled from depend on their respective data lengths as a
        total of 500 years of data (including zeroes) is needed for the
        approach to work.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_vdwym">
      <title>Identifying ‘nearby’ stations - application to Sydney
      Airport</title>

      <para>We start by demonstrating a single application of the approach at
      one location: Sydney Airport (gauge number 066037). This location
      represents a relatively long-record pluviograph station, and therefore
      provides a useful record for verification of the method.</para>

      <para>The approach to identifying ‘nearby’ stations is as
      follows:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>For all the 1396 pluviograph stations in Australia (excluding
          the Sydney Airport gauge), calculate each of the regression
          predictors; namely, difference in latitude, longitude,
          latitude*longitude, elevation and normalised distance to coast,
          relative to the Sydney Airport station;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Having developed the 1396 x 5 predictor matrix, apply the
          regression model presented in <emphasis role="bold">Equation 4
          </emphasis> and</para>

          <para><emphasis role="bold"> 5 </emphasis> using the regression
          coefficients shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_t_1n4n0"/> for each
          season and attribute to calculate the probability Pr(<emphasis
          role="italic">u</emphasis> =1);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Separately for each season and attribute, rank the
          probabilities from highest to lowest;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>For each season calculate the average rank for each station
          across all attributes;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select the <emphasis role="italic">S</emphasis> lowest-ranked
          stations for inclusion in the disaggregation model.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>This algorithm yields different choices of stations for each
      season, as physiographic influences may vary depending on the dominant
      synoptic systems occurring and different times of the year. It is noted
      that the selection of the size of <emphasis role="italic">S</emphasis>
      represents a somewhat subjective decision, as larger values of <emphasis
      role="italic">S</emphasis> increase the probability of selecting
      stations which are statistically different to the target station,
      whereas smaller values of S will result in small sample sizes. For this
      case we a total of 500 years of data (including zero rainfalls)
      distributed over the 13 stations (S=13).</para>

      <para>These lowest-ranked 13 stations for the summer season are shown in
      <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_5z8tk"/>. As expected, the lowest ranked
      stations (i.e. those with the greatest chance of being ‘similar’ to
      Sydney Airport) are those which are most proximate to this station,
      generally within a small distance to coast, and all are at low coastal
      elevations. In this case, therefore, the stations appear to be selected
      over a wide range of latitudes, which is probably due to the strong
      increases in elevation and relative distance to coast with changing
      longitude.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_5z8tk">
        <title>Sydney Airport (large red dot) and nearby pluviograph stations
        (blue and brown dots). The highest ranked 13 pluviograph stations
        based on the full logistic regression model are shown as brown dots,
        with the associated ranking.</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2025.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>It should be noted that the RMOF approach can be expanded to use
      more sub-daily data than the 1306 stations used in the example for
      Sydney Airport presented above. New data can be included without the
      need to update the coefficients of the logistic regression model unless
      these inclusions are substantial enough to change the distributional
      characteristics of the data being used. This allows improvements in the
      representativeness of the continuous simulations as more data over
      time.</para>

      <para>It should also be noted that the RMOF can be used at completely
      locations having no sub-daily or daily rainfall observations, or to
      disaggregate daily rainfall records at locations where sub-daily data is
      not available. In the first case, we recommend use of a daily generation
      approach such as the RMMM to generate daily sequences that should then
      be disaggregated using RMOF. In the latter case, the observed daily
      sequence can be used directly as the basis for disaggregation.</para>

      <para>The software for the RMOF approach is available on request from
      the authors at this stage, and will be uploaded to the Hydrology@UNSW
      Software website after a formal review process (<link
      xlink:href="http://www.hydrology.unsw.edu.au/download/software/">http://www.hydrology.unsw.edu.au/download/software/</link>).
      This document will be updated to reflect the full location once the
      download of the software is completed.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_7lc37">
      <title>Modification of Generated Design Rainfall Attributes</title>

      <para>The stochastic nature of the algorithms described in previous
      sections mean that the stochastic sequences will also produce stochastic
      estimates of design rainfall. In many cases this is a desirable outcome
      of the approach, as it enables the representation of uncertainty
      associated with design rainfall. However, in some situations, it may be
      desirable to post-process the design rainfall characteristics obtained
      through stochastic generation in order to reflect published
      Intensity-Frequency-Duration curves. This is likely to be particularly
      useful when conducting comparisons between the outputs of continuous
      versus event-based models, or when seeking to understand the role of a
      catchment’s antecedent moisture content conditional to pre-specified
      design rainfall features.</para>

      <para>For cases where it is necessary to have consistency between the
      Australian Bureau of Meteorology IFDs and the IFDs derived from
      continuous simulation, a modification in the generation algorithms for
      RMMM and RMOF was proposed. The main steps involved as illustrated in
      <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_8xo6m"/>. First, annual extreme rainfall is
      corrected at multiple durations so that the IFD based on the generated
      rainfall matches up with the observed IFD (henceforth referred as
      ‘target IFD’). Second, the non-extreme rainfall (i.e., rainfall that is
      not part of the annual extreme series) is corrected in such a way that
      the cumulative rainfall before and after correction is maintained. The
      dry periods are kept the same before and after bias correction, hence no
      correction is required for dry periods. As the majority of the data is
      in the non-extreme category, the corrections are markedly smaller for
      the non-extreme case.</para>

      <para>Due to the inter-dependence of the extreme rainfall across various
      durations, it is necessary to apply the above corrections in a recursive
      manner, with each recursion repeating the above steps using a new set of
      durations exhibiting the maximum difference between the generated and
      target Intensities. This recursion is applied until the following
      objective function reaches a minimum:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b2_ch6_e_jheh1">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>RMAE</m:mi>

              <m:mi>AEP</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mfrac>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>|</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msubsup>
                    <m:mi>IFD</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>AEP</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                  </m:msubsup>

                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                  <m:msubsup>
                    <m:mi>IFD</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>AEP</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>G</m:mi>
                  </m:msubsup>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>|</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:msubsup>
                <m:mi>IFD</m:mi>

                <m:mi>AEP</m:mi>

                <m:mi>T</m:mi>
              </m:msubsup>
            </m:mfrac>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where the objective to be minimised is a dimensionless
      standardised error measure referred as relative mean absolute error
      (RMAE) for consistent comparison across various durations and exceedance
      probabilities. The RMAE at each of the annual exceedance probabilities
      (AEP) is estimated through the mean of the absolute difference between
      the target IFD (<inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msubsup>
              <m:mi>IFD</m:mi>

              <m:mi>AEP</m:mi>

              <m:mi>T</m:mi>
            </m:msubsup>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation>) and generated IFD (<inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msubsup>
              <m:mi>IFD</m:mi>

              <m:mi>AEP</m:mi>

              <m:mi>G</m:mi>
            </m:msubsup>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation>) scaled by the target IFD.</para>

      <para>Minimisation of the RMAE in [6] requires the specification of the
      set of target durations to be used in its adjustment. The choice of
      durations is governed by the dependence that the extremes for one
      duration have with the extremes for another. For instance, it is more
      likely for 6-minute extremes to be a subset of 30-minute extremes than
      6-hour extremes (say). In such a case, the durations should be selected
      keeping an interval that maximises the independence between the extremes
      being evaluated. In practice, the procedure uses two recursions with
      separate durations. For both recursions, three target durations, i.e.,
      <emphasis role="italic">D </emphasis>= 6 min, 1 hr and 3 hrs are
      considered, which keeps the distance between the durations far enough to
      reduce the dependence between them. Options exist to use a broader set
      of durations in the second iteration (6m, 30m, 1h, 3h, 6h, 12h) although
      assessment with data for selected city centres in Australia indicated
      the benefits from this were not significant.<figure
          xml:id="b2_ch6_f_8xo6m">
          <title>Overview of workflow illustrating the main steps involved in
          the adjustment of raw continuous rainfall sequences to preserve the
          intensity-frequency-duration (IFD) relationships.</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2026.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure></para>

      <para>The software for the post-processing approach described above is
      available on request from the authors at this stage, and will be
      uploaded to the Hydrology@UNSW Software website after a formal review
      process (<link
      xlink:href="http://www.hydrology.unsw.edu.au/download/software/">http://www.hydrology.unsw.edu.au/download/software/</link>).
      This document will be updated to reflect the full location once the
      download of the software is completed.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_is18d">
      <title>Example illustration of daily and sub-daily rainfall
      generation</title>

      <para>This example presents the generation of daily, sub-daily and
      corrected sub-daily rainfall for Alice Springs, including the case where
      we need to assume that data for the location is not available. Hence,
      the results here represent a typical example users may face when
      generating rainfall sequences for any ungauged location in
      Australia.</para>

      <para>Alice Springs is an arid region with average annual rainfall of
      280 mm. The observed record at Alice Springs Airport exists for 67 years
      (1942-2008) and the sub-daily record for 57 years (1951-2007, with
      missing periods). Each of the statistics presented are based on 100
      realisations of length 67 years.</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_g6wwf">
        <title>Daily rainfall generation</title>

        <para>For daily rainfall generation, two options are considered; a)
        observed rainfall record at the location is available (at-site
        generation) and b) no daily rainfall record is available i.e. location
        is ungauged (regionalised generation).</para>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_e2k73">
            <caption>Statistical assessment of daily rainfall from RMMM for
            Alice Springs using 100 replicates 67 years long.</caption>

            <col width="25%"/>

            <col width="25%"/>

            <col width="25%"/>

            <col width="25%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th rowspan="2">Attribute</th>

                <th rowspan="2">Observed</th>

                <th colspan="2">Simulated</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td><emphasis role="bold">At-site</emphasis></td>

                <td><emphasis role="bold">Regionalised</emphasis></td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Average annual wet days (Nos)</td>

                <td>41</td>

                <td>40</td>

                <td>31</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Average Annual rainfall (mm)</td>

                <td>279</td>

                <td>297</td>

                <td>306</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Average standard deviation of annual wet days (Nos)</td>

                <td>13</td>

                <td>12</td>

                <td>15</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Average standard deviation of annual rainfall (mm)</td>

                <td>152</td>

                <td>160</td>

                <td>189</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <para>Annual rainfall simulations for Alice Springs using 100
        replicates. The probability distribution of annual rainfall is well
        represented even in the case of the regionalized simulation where
        at-site data was not used. This indicates a reasonable representation
        of the inter-annual variability that characterizes Australian
        rainfall.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_w9zla">
          <title>Annual rainfall simulations for Alice Springs using 100
          replicates. The probability distribution of annual rainfall is well
          represented even in the case of the regionalized simulation where
          at-site data was not used. This indicates a reasonable
          representation of the inter-annual variability that characterizes
          Australian rainfall.</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2027.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_26l3v">
          <title>Intensity-frequency relationship for 24-hour duration. As
          with the annual rainfall in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_8xo6m"/>, the
          extremes are reasonably well simulated even for the regionalized
          case, except for the most extreme event on record, which the model
          undersimulates in the regionalized setting.</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2028.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>It should be noted that the results of the RMMM approach use
        2708 daily rainfall stations with long records, instead of the
        complete daily rainfall observation dataset for Australia. One can
        expect better representation of underlying rainfall attributes as
        better and longer datasets are used.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_3zjzy">
        <title>Sub-daily rainfall generation</title>

        <para>Sub-daily rainfall generation is based on Regionalised Method of
        Fragments approach (RMOF) described earlier. Keeping in mind data
        availability scenarios for sub-daily rainfall generation, the
        following generation options are possible:</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Daily and sub-daily rainfall record at the location of
            interest is available. Daily time series is disaggregated using
            available at-site sub-daily time series. To obtain multiple
            simulations, same daily rainfall time series is used (at-site
            daily and at-site sub-daily).</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Only daily rainfall record at the location of interest is
            available. Daily time series is disaggregated using sub-daily time
            series from nearby locations (regionalised sub-daily). To obtain
            multiple simulations, same daily rainfall time series is used
            (at-site daily and regionalised sub-daily).</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>No daily or sub-daily rainfall record at the location of
            interest is available. First multiple realisations of daily time
            series are obtained using regionalised daily model. In the second
            step, each daily time series is disaggregated using sub-daily time
            series from nearby locations (regionalised sub-daily)
            (regionalised daily and regionalised sub-daily).</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>Selected results from this assessment are presented in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch6_t_n5jse"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_26l3v"/>. Once
        can notice the deterioration in the representation of extremes in the
        shorter duration case when regionalised options are considered,
        especially for the smallest duration (6-minute).</para>

        <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch6_t_n5jse">
            <caption>Performance of extremes and representation of zeroes (for
            6-minute time-steps) from the sub-daily rainfall generation using
            RMOF for at-site generation using observed sub-daily data (option
            A), at-site disaggregation using observed daily data (option B),
            and the purely regionalized case (option C).</caption>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <col width="20%"/>

            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th colspan="5">Average annual maximum rainfall (mm) in spell
                of</th>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <th>Duration</th>

                <th>Observed</th>

                <th>Option A</th>

                <th>Option B</th>

                <th>Option C</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>6 min</td>

                <td>5.5</td>

                <td>6.75</td>

                <td>6.77</td>

                <td>8.02</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>30 min</td>

                <td>16.71</td>

                <td>18.07</td>

                <td>18.23</td>

                <td>20.97</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>1 hr</td>

                <td>22.14</td>

                <td>24.19</td>

                <td>24.17</td>

                <td>26.56</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>3 hr</td>

                <td>32.58</td>

                <td>34.77</td>

                <td>33.56</td>

                <td>34.94</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>6 hr</td>

                <td>39.61</td>

                <td>41.73</td>

                <td>39.79</td>

                <td>40.74</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>12 hr</td>

                <td>48.18</td>

                <td>47.65</td>

                <td>46.5</td>

                <td>46.78</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Percentage of zeros</td>

                <td>98.54</td>

                <td>98.62</td>

                <td>98.78</td>

                <td>98.68</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_oju3g">
          <title>6-minute (left column) and 6 hour (right column) annual
          maximum rainfall against exceedance probability for Alice Springs.
          Top panel presents results for option A, at-site daily rainfall and
          fragments, middle panel presents results for option B, regionalised
          daily rainfall at-site fragments, while the bottom panel presents
          results for option C, regionalised results using ‘nearby’ daily as
          well as sub-daily records. Black dots represent observed data, black
          solid line represents the median of 100 simulations, and black
          dotted lines represent the 5 and 95 percentile simulated
          values.</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2029.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_m28dn">
        <title>Post-processing of continuous rainfall to correct for IFD
        biases</title>

        <para>As illustrated in <xref linkend="b2_ch6_f_oju3g"/>, in cases
        where observed rainfall datasets used for continuous simulation are of
        poor quality or are pooled from locations that are dis-similar to the
        target, the RMMM and RMOF approaches will simulate sequences with
        different IFD attributes compared to those published by the Australian
        Bureau of Meteorology. This is addressed using a post-processing step
        that involves scaling of the continuous sequences to alter extremes
        while attempting to maintain the average annual rainfall for the
        location of interest.</para>

        <para>Results from this post-processing step for the continuous
        rainfall sequences from RMOF for Alice Springs are presented in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch6_f_fmx30"/>. The continuous series that was generated
        has not used rainfall data from Alice Springs for the purpose of
        generation. In addition to representing low-frequency variability
        characteristics through the proper simulation of daily rainfalls,
        these continuous sequences are able to mimic actual IFDs and annual
        rainfall totals, thus making them suitable for continuous flow
        simulation.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch6_f_fmx30">
          <title>Intensity-duration-frequency (IFD) relationships for target
          and simulated rainfall before and after bias correction at Alice
          Springs. The broken lines (red and blue) indicate the 5 and 95
          percentiles for raw and bias corrected data, respectively.</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2030.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_tblms">
    <title>Implications of climate change</title>

    <para>The implications of climate change on design rainfall have been
    discussed in <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Chapter
    X<?oxy_custom_end ?> and are not repeated here. The focus of this section
    is to discuss how the procedures for continuous simulation described here
    may be altered to account for climate change. This may be particularly
    important if there are changes in extreme rainfall, in antecedent
    rainfall, or in the dependence between the two, all of which will have
    significant impacts on the resulting design flood.</para>

    <para>Both the daily and the sub-daily continuous simulation alternatives
    discussed here will be affected by climate change. Users may need to use
    daily rainfall sequences that are representative of future warmer
    climates, and are referred to the statistical downscaling extensions of
    the RMMM daily generation approach discussed here [<emphasis
    role="italic">R. Mehrotra and Sharma</emphasis>, 2010] for an alternative
    for generating daily sequences for any location of interest. This
    generation requires selection of appropriate General Circulation Models
    (GCMs) and atmospheric predictors, followed by sensible correction of GCM
    simulations to remove known biases. Readers are referred to [<emphasis
    role="italic">Sharma et al.</emphasis>, 2013] for a review of the
    approaches used commonly for these purposes.</para>

    <para>Generation of sub-daily sequences will require modification of the
    RMOF to alternatives that take into account changes to extremes at
    sub-daily timescales [<emphasis role="italic">S. Westra et al.</emphasis>,
    2014] as well as changes to associated temporal patterns [<emphasis
    role="italic">Wasko and Sharma</emphasis>, 2015]. An alternative that can
    be used to accommodate these changes is presented in [<emphasis
    role="italic">S. Westra et al.</emphasis>, 2013]. In general, approaches
    for stochastically generating continuous (sub-daily) rainfall sequences
    under a future climate are a rapidly evolving area of research, and
    detailed advice on theory and approaches for continuous simulation under a
    future climate are outside of the scope of this document.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch6_s_qf4b4">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Arnold, J. G., and J. R. Williams (1989), Stochastic Generation of
    Internal Storm Structure at a Point, <emphasis role="italic">Transactions
    of the ASAE</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">32</emphasis>(1),
    0161.</para>

    <para>Bardossy, A., and E. J. Plate (1992), Space-time model for daily
    rainfall using atmospheric circulation patterns, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">28</emphasis>(5), 1247-1259.</para>

    <para>Bárdossy, A., and G. G. S. Pegram (2009), Copula based multisite
    model for daily precipitation simulation, <emphasis role="italic">Hydrol.
    Earth Syst. Sci.</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">13</emphasis>(12),
    2299-2314.</para>

    <para>Bárdossy, A., and G. Pegram (2014), Infilling missing precipitation
    records – A comparison of a new copula-based method with other techniques,
    <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">519, Part A</emphasis>, 1162-1170.</para>

    <para>Beesley, C. A., A. J. Frost, and J. Zajaczkowski (2009), A
    comparison of the BAWAP and SILO spatially interpolated daily rainfall
    datasets, paper presented at 18th World IMACS / MODSIM Congress, MSSANZ,
    Cairns, Australia</para>

    <para>Blazkova, S., and K. Beven (2002), Flood frequency estimation by
    continuous simulation for a catchment treated as ungauged (with
    uncertainty), <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">38</emphasis>(8).</para>

    <para>Boughton, W., and O. Droop (2003), Continuous simulation for design
    flood estimation - a review, <emphasis role="italic">Environmental
    Modelling &amp; Software</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">18</emphasis>(4), 309-318.</para>

    <para>Boughton, W. C. (1999), A daily rainfall generating model for water
    yield and flood studies<emphasis role="italic">Rep. Report
    99/9</emphasis>, 21pp pp, CRC for Catchment Hydrology, Monash University,
    Melbourne.</para>

    <para>Buishand, T. A. (1977), Stochastic modeling of daily rainfall
    sequences, <emphasis role="italic">Meded. Landbouwhogesch.
    Wageningen</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">77</emphasis>(3), 211
    pp.</para>

    <para>Cameron, D., K. Beven, J. Tawn, and P. Naden (2000), Flood frequency
    estimation by continuous simulation (with likelihood based uncertainty
    estimation), <emphasis role="italic">Hydrology and Earth System
    Sciences</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">4</emphasis>(1),
    23-34.</para>

    <para>Carey-Smith, T., J. Sansom, and P. Thomson (2014), A hidden seasonal
    switching model for multisite daily rainfall, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">50</emphasis>(1), 257-272.</para>

    <para>Caskey, J. E. (1963), A MARKOV CHAIN MODEL FOR THE PROBABILITY OF
    PRECIPITATION OCCURRENCE IN INTERVALS OF VARIOUS LENGTH, <emphasis
    role="italic">Mon. Wea. Rev.</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">91</emphasis>(6), 298-301.</para>

    <para>Chapman, T. G. (1997), Stochastic models for daily rainfall in the
    Western Pacific, <emphasis role="italic">Mathematics and Computers in
    Simulation</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">43</emphasis>,
    351-358.</para>

    <para>Chappell, A., L. J. Renzullo, T. H. Raupach, and M. Haylock (2013),
    Evaluating geostatistical methods of blending satellite and gauge data to
    estimate near real-time daily rainfall for Australia, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">493</emphasis>, 105-114.</para>

    <para>Charles, S. P., B. C. Bates, and J. P. Hughes (1999), A
    spatiotemporal model for downscaling precipitation occurrence and amounts,
    <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Geophysical
    Research-Atmospheres</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">104</emphasis>(D24), 31657-31669.</para>

    <para>Chin, E. H., and J. F. Miller (1980), On the Conditional
    Distribution of Daily Precipitation Amounts, <emphasis role="italic">Mon.
    Wea. Rev.</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">108</emphasis>(9),
    1462-1464.</para>

    <para>Chowdhury, S., and A. Sharma (2007), Mitigating Parameter Bias in
    Hydrological Modelling due to Uncertainty in Covariates, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">340</emphasis>(doi:10.1016/j.jhydrol.2007.04.010),
    197-204.</para>

    <para>Ciach, G. J. (2003), Local random errors in tipping-bucket rain
    gauge measurements, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Atmospheric and
    Oceanic Technology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">20</emphasis>(5),
    752-759.</para>

    <para>Coe, R., and R. D. Stern (1982), Fitting Models to Daily Rainfall
    Data, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Applied Meteorology</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">21</emphasis>(7), 1024-1031.</para>

    <para>Cole, J. A., and J. D. F. Sherriff (1972), Some single- and
    multi-site models of rainfall within discrete time increments, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">17</emphasis>(1-2), 97-113.</para>

    <para>Connolly, R. D., J. Schirmer, and P. K. Dunn (1998), A daily
    rainfall disaggregation model, <emphasis role="italic">Agricultural and
    Forest Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">92</emphasis>(2),
    105-117.</para>

    <para>Cowpertwait, P. S. P. (2010), A spatial-temporal point process model
    with a continuous distribution of storm types, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">46</emphasis>(12).</para>

    <para>Cowpertwait, P. S. P., C. G. Kilsby, and P. E. O'Connell (2002), A
    space-time Neyman-Scott model of rainfall: Empirical analysis of extremes
    - art. no. 1131, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">38</emphasis>(8),
    1131-1131.</para>

    <para>Cowpertwait, P. S. P., P. E. O'Connell, A. V. Metcalfe, and J. A.
    Mawdsley (1996), Stochastic point process modelling of rainfall. II.
    Regionalisation and disaggregation, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">175</emphasis>(1-4),
    47-65.</para>

    <para>Das, D., E. Kodra, Z. Obradovic, and A. R. Ganguly (2012), Mining
    extremes: Severe rainfall and climate change, in <emphasis
    role="italic">Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and
    Applications</emphasis>, edited, pp. 899-900.</para>

    <para>de Lima, M. I. P., and J. Grasman (1999), Multifractal analysis of
    15-min and daily rainfall from a semi-arid region in Portugal, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">220</emphasis>(1-2), 1-11.</para>

    <para>Deidda, R., R. Benzi, and F. Siccardi (1999), Multifractal modeling
    of anomalous scaling laws in rainfall, <emphasis role="italic">Water
    Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">35</emphasis>(6),
    1853-1867.</para>

    <para>Dennett, M. D., J. A. Rodgers, and R. D. Stern (1983), Independence
    of Rainfalls through the Rainy Season and the Implications for the
    Estimation of Rainfall Probabilities, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Climatology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">3</emphasis>(4),
    375-384.</para>

    <para>Eagleson, P. S. (1978), Climate, Soil, and Vegetation 2. The
    Distribution of Annual Precipitation Derived From Observed Storm
    Sequences, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">14</emphasis>(5), 713-721.</para>

    <para>Econopouly, T. W., D. R. Davis, and D. A. Woolhiser (1990),
    Parameter transferability for a daily rainfall disaggregation model,
    <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">118</emphasis>(1-4), 209-228.</para>

    <para>Evin, G., and A.-C. Favre (2012), Further developments of a
    transient Poisson-cluster model for rainfall, <emphasis
    role="italic">Stochastic Environmental Research and Risk
    Assessment</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">27</emphasis>(4),
    831-847.</para>

    <para>Fasano, G., and A. Franceschini (1987), A Multidimensional Version
    of the Kolmogorov-Smirnov Test, <emphasis role="italic">Mon Not R Astron
    Soc</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">225</emphasis>(1), 155-170.</para>

    <para>Feyerherm, A. M., and L. D. Bark (1965), Statistical Methods for
    Persistent Precipitation Patterns, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Applied Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">4</emphasis>(3),
    320-328.</para>

    <para>Feyerherm, A. M., and L. D. Bark (1967), Goodness of Fit of a Markov
    Chain Model for Sequences of Wet and Dry Days, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Applied Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">6</emphasis>(5), 770-773.</para>

    <para>Gabriel, K. R., and J. Neumann (1962), A Markov chain model for
    daily rainfall occurrence at Tel Aviv, <emphasis role="italic">Q.J Royal
    Met. Soc.</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">88</emphasis>(375),
    90-95.</para>

    <para>Garcia-Guzman, A., and E. Aranda-Oliver (1993), A stochastic model
    of dimensionless hyetograph, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">29</emphasis>(7),
    2363-2370.</para>

    <para>Gates, P., and H. Tong (1976), On Markov Chain Modeling to Some
    Weather Data, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Applied
    Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">15</emphasis>(11),
    1145-1151.</para>

    <para>Gregory, J. M., T. M. L. Wigley, and P. D. Jones (1993), Application
    of Markov models to area-average daily precipitation series and
    interannual variability in seasonal totals, <emphasis role="italic">Clim.
    Dyn.</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">8</emphasis>, 299–310.</para>

    <para>Gupta, V. K., and E. C. Waymire (1993), A Statistical Analysis of
    Mesoscale Rainfall as a Random Cascade, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Applied Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">32</emphasis>(2),
    251-267.</para>

    <para>Gyasi-Agyei, Y. (2013), Evaluation of the effects of temperature
    changes on fine timescale rainfall, <emphasis role="italic">Water
    Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">49</emphasis>(7),
    4379-4398.</para>

    <para>Haan, C. T., D. M. Allen, and J. D. Street (1976), A Markov chain
    model of daily rainfall, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resour.
    Res.</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">12</emphasis>, 443–449.</para>

    <para>Harrold, T. I., A. Sharma, and S. J. Sheather (2003a), A
    nonparametric model for stochastic generation of daily rainfall occurrence
    - art. no. 1300, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">39</emphasis>(10),
    1300-1300.</para>

    <para>Harrold, T. I., A. Sharma, and S. J. Sheather (2003b), A
    nonparametric model for stochastic generation of daily rainfall amounts -
    art. no. 1343, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">39</emphasis>(12),
    1343-1343.</para>

    <para>Heaps, S. E., R. J. Boys, and M. Farrow (2015), Bayesian modelling
    of rainfall data by using non-homogeneous hidden Markov models and latent
    Gaussian variables, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of the Royal
    Statistical Society: Series C (Applied Statistics)</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">64</emphasis>(3), 543-568.</para>

    <para>Heneker, T. M., M. F. Lambert, and G. Kuczera (2001), A point
    rainfall model for risk-based design, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">247</emphasis>(1-2),
    54-71.</para>

    <para>Hershenhorn, J., and D. A. Woolhiser (1987), Disaggregation of daily
    rainfall, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">95</emphasis>(3-4), 299-322.</para>

    <para>Hopkins, J. W., and P. Robillard (1964), Some Statistics of Daily
    Rainfall Occurrence for the Canadian Prairie Provinces, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Applied Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">3</emphasis>(5), 600-602.</para>

    <para>Hughes, J. P., and P. Guttorp (1994), Incorporating Spatial
    Dependence and Atmospheric Data in a Model of Precipitation, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Applied Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">33</emphasis>(12), 1503-1515.</para>

    <para>Jeffrey, S. J., J. O. Carter, K. B. Moodie, and A. R. Beswick
    (2001), Using spatial interpolation to construct a comprehensive archive
    of Australian climate data, <emphasis role="italic">Environmental
    Modelling &amp; Software</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">16</emphasis>(6), 309-330.</para>

    <para>Jha, S. K., G. Mariethoz, J. Evans, M. F. McCabe, and A. Sharma
    (2015), A space and time scale dependent non-linear geostatistical
    approach for downscaling daily precipitation and temperature, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">online 20 July 2015</emphasis>.</para>

    <para>Jones, D., W. Wang, and R. Fawcett (2009), High-quality spatial
    climate data-sets for Australia, <emphasis role="italic">Australian
    Meteorological and Oceanographic Journal</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">58</emphasis>, 233-248.</para>

    <para>Jones, P. G., and P. K. Thornton (1997), Spatial and temporal
    variability of rainfall related to a third-order Markov model, <emphasis
    role="italic">Agricultural and Forest Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">86</emphasis>(1-2), 127-138.</para>

    <para>Katz, R. W., and M. B. Parlange (1998), Overdispersion phenomenon in
    stochastic modeling of precipitation, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Climate</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">11</emphasis>(4),
    591-601.</para>

    <para>Katz, R. W., M. B. Parlange, and C. Tebaldi (2003), Stochastic
    modeling of the effects of large-scale circulation on daily weather in the
    southeastern US, <emphasis role="italic">Climatic Change</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">60</emphasis>(1-2), 189-216.</para>

    <para>Kavvas, M. L., and J. W. Delleur (1981), A stochastic cluster model
    of daily rainfall sequences, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">17</emphasis>(4),
    1151-1160.</para>

    <para>Kim, D., J. Kim, and Y.-S. Cho (2014), A Poisson Cluster Stochastic
    Rainfall Generator That Accounts for the Interannual Variability of
    Rainfall Statistics: Validation at Various Geographic Locations across the
    United States, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Applied
    Mathematics</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">2014</emphasis>,
    1-14.</para>

    <para>Kim, Y., R. W. Katz, B. Rajagopalan, G. P. Podestá, and E. M. Furrer
    (2012), Reducing overdispersion in stochastic weather generators using a
    generalized linear modeling approach, <emphasis role="italic">Climate
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">53</emphasis>(1),
    13-24.</para>

    <para>Kleiber, W., R. W. Katz, and B. Rajagopalan (2012), Daily
    spatiotemporal precipitation simulation using latent and transformed
    Gaussian processes, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">48</emphasis>(1).</para>

    <para>Koutsoyiannis, D. (2001), Coupling stochastic models of different
    timescales, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">37</emphasis>(2), 379-391.</para>

    <para>Koutsoyiannis, D., and D. Pachakis (1996), Deterministic chaos
    versus stochasticity in analysis and modeling of point rainfall series,
    <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Geophysical Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">101</emphasis>(D21), 26,444-426,451.</para>

    <para>Koutsoyiannis, D., and C. Onof (2000), A computer program for
    temporal rainfall disaggregation using adjusting procedures, paper
    presented at 25th General Assembly of the European Geophysical Society,
    EGS, Nice.</para>

    <para>Koutsoyiannis, D., C. Onof, and H. S. Wheater (2003), Multivariate
    rainfall disaggregation at a fine timescale - art. no. 1173, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">39</emphasis>(7), 1173-1173.</para>

    <para>La Barbera, P., L. G. Lanza, and L. Stagi (2002), Tipping bucket
    mechanical errors and their influence on rainfall statistics and extremes,
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Science and Technology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">45</emphasis>(2), 1-10.</para>

    <para>Lall, U., and A. Sharma (1996), A nearest neighbor bootstrap for
    time series resampling, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">32</emphasis>(3),
    679-693.</para>

    <para>Lall, U., B. Rajagopalan, and D. G. Tarboton (1996), A nonparametric
    wet/dry spell model for resampling daily precipitation, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">32</emphasis>(9), 2803-2823.</para>

    <para>Lamb, R., and A. L. Kay (2004), Confidence intervals for a spatially
    generalized, continuous simulation flood frequency model for Great
    Britain, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">40</emphasis>(7).</para>

    <para>Lambert, M., and G. Kuczera (1998), Seasonal generalized exponential
    probability models with application to interstorm and storm durations,
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">34</emphasis>(1), 143-148.</para>

    <para>Leblois, E., and J.-D. Creutin (2013), Space-time simulation of
    intermittent rainfall with prescribed advection field: Adaptation of the
    turning band method, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">49</emphasis>(6),
    3375-3387.</para>

    <para>Leonard, M., M. F. Lambert, A. V. Metcalfe, and P. S. P. Cowpertwait
    (2008), A space-time Neyman-Scott rainfall model with defined storm
    extent, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">44</emphasis>(9).</para>

    <para>Lovejoy, S., and D. Schertzer (1990), Multifractals, universality
    classes and satellite and radar measurements of cloud and rain fields,
    <emphasis role="italic">J. Geophys. Res.</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">95</emphasis>(D3), 2021.</para>

    <para>McMahon, T. A., and R. Srikanthan (1983), Statistical
    characteristics of Australian Rainfall and Evaporation<emphasis
    role="italic">Rep.</emphasis></para>

    <para>Mehrotra, R., and A. Sharma (2006), A nonparametric stochastic
    downscaling framework for daily rainfall at multiple locations, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">111</emphasis>(D15101),
    doi:10.1029/2005JD006637.</para>

    <para>Mehrotra, R., and A. Sharma (2007a), Preserving low-frequency
    variability in generated daily rainfall sequences, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">345</emphasis>(1-2), 102-120.</para>

    <para>Mehrotra, R., and A. Sharma (2007b), A semi-parametric model for
    stochastic generation of multi-site daily rainfall exhibiting
    low-frequency variability, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">335</emphasis>(1-2),
    180-193.</para>

    <para>Mehrotra, R., and A. Sharma (2010), Development and Application of a
    Multisite Rainfall Stochastic Downscaling Framework for Climate Change
    Impact Assessment, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">46</emphasis>.</para>

    <para>Mehrotra, R., S. Westra, A. Sharma, and R. Srikanthan (2012),
    Continuous rainfall simulation: 2 - A regionalised daily rainfall
    generation approach, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">48</emphasis>(1),
    W01536</para>

    <para>Mehrotra, R., J. Li, S. Westra, and A. Sharma (2015), A programming
    tool to generate multi-site daily rainfall using a two-stage semi
    parametric model <emphasis role="italic">Environmental Modelling &amp;
    Software</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">63</emphasis>,
    230–239.</para>

    <para>Menabde, M., and M. Sivapalan (2000), Modeling of rainfall time
    series and extremes using bounded random cascades and Levy-stable
    distribution, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">36</emphasis>(11), 3293-3300.</para>

    <para>Menabde, M., A. Seed, D. Harris, and G. Austin (1997), Self-similar
    random fields and rainfall simulation, <emphasis role="italic">J. Geophys.
    Res.</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">102</emphasis>(D12),
    13509.</para>

    <para>Micevski, T., and G. Kuczera (2009), Combining Site and Regional
    Flood Information Using a Bayesian Monte Carlo Approach, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>(doi:10.1029/2008WR007173), in press (online on <link
    xlink:href="http://www.agu.org/journals/wr/papersinpress.shtml)">http://www.agu.org/journals/wr/papersinpress.shtml)</link>.</para>

    <para>Molnar, P., and P. Burlando (2005), Preservation of rainfall
    properties in stochastic disaggregation by a simple random cascade model,
    <emphasis role="italic">Atmospheric Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">77</emphasis>(1-4), 137-151.</para>

    <para>Olsson, J., and R. Berndtsson (1998), Temporal rainfall
    disaggregration based on scaling properties, <emphasis role="italic">Water
    Science and Technology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">37</emphasis>(11), 73-79.</para>

    <para>Onof, C., and J. Townend (2004), Modelling 5-minute rainfall
    extremes, paper presented at British Hydrological Society International
    Conference, London.</para>

    <para>Onof, C., R. E. Chandler, A. Kakou, P. Northrop, H. S. Wheater, and
    V. Isham (2000), Rainfall modelling using Poisson-cluster processes: a
    review of developments, <emphasis role="italic">Stochastic Environmental
    Research and Risk Assessment</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">14</emphasis>(6), 384-411.</para>

    <para>Oriani, F., J. Straubhaar, P. Renard, and G. Mariethoz (2014),
    Simulation of rainfall time series from different climatic regions using
    the direct sampling technique, <emphasis role="italic">Hydrology and Earth
    System Sciences</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">18</emphasis>(8),
    3015-3031.</para>

    <para>Over, T. M., and V. K. Gupta (1996), A space-time theory of
    mesoscale rainfall using random cascades, <emphasis role="italic">J.
    Geophys. Res.</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">101</emphasis>(D21),
    26319.</para>

    <para>Pathiraja, S., S. Westra, and A. Sharma (2012), Why Continuous
    Simulation? The Role of Antecedent Moisture in Design Flood Estimation,
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">48</emphasis>(W06534).</para>

    <para>Pegram, G. G. S. (1980), An Autoregressive Model for Multilag Markov
    Chains, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Applied Probability</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">17</emphasis>(2), 350.</para>

    <para>Pui, A., A. Lal, and A. Sharma (2011), How does the Interdecadal
    Pacific Oscillation affect design floods in Australia?, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">47</emphasis>(5).</para>

    <para>Pui, A., A. Sharma, A. Santoso, and S. Westra (2012), Impact of the
    El Niño Southern Oscillation, Indian Ocean Dipole, and Southern Annular
    Mode on daily to sub-daily rainfall characteristics in East Australia,
    <emphasis role="italic">Monthly Weather Review</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">140</emphasis>, 1665-1681.</para>

    <para>Racsko, P., L. Szeidl, and M. Semenov (1991), A serial approach to
    local stochastic weather models, <emphasis role="italic">Ecological
    Modelling</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">57</emphasis>(1-2),
    27-41.</para>

    <para>Ramirez, J. A., and R. L. Bras (1985), Conditional Distributions of
    Neyman-Scott Models for Storm Arrivals and Their Use in Irrigation
    Scheduling, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">21</emphasis>(3), 317-330.</para>

    <para>Richardson, C. W. (1981), Stochastic Simulation of Daily
    Precipitation, Temperature, and Solar-Radiation, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">17</emphasis>(1), 182-190.</para>

    <para>Rodriguez-Iturbe, I., V. K. Gupta, and E. Waymire (1984), Scale
    considerations in the modeling of temporal rainfall, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">20</emphasis>(11), 1611-1619.</para>

    <para>Rodriguez-Iturbe, I., D. R. Cox, and V. Isham (1987), Some Models
    for Rainfall Based on Stochastic Point Processes, <emphasis
    role="italic">Proceedings of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical
    and Engineering Sciences</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">410</emphasis>(1839), 269-288.</para>

    <para>Rodriguez-Iturbe, I., D. R. Cox, and V. Isham (1988), A Point
    Process Model for Rainfall: Further Developments, <emphasis
    role="italic">Proceedings of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical
    and Engineering Sciences</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">417</emphasis>(1853), 283-298.</para>

    <para>Roldan, J., and D. A. Woolhiser (1982), Stochastic daily
    precipitation models 1. A comparison of occurrence models, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">18</emphasis>(5), 1451-1459.</para>

    <para>Schertzer, D., and S. Lovejoy (1987), Physical modeling and analysis
    of rain and clouds by anisotropic scaling multiplicative processes,
    <emphasis role="italic">J. Geophys. Res.</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">92</emphasis>(D8), 9693.</para>

    <para>Seed, A. W., R. Srikanthan, and M. Menabde (1999), A space and time
    model for design storm rainfall, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Geophysical Research-Atmospheres</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">104</emphasis>(D24), 31623-31630.</para>

    <para>Selvalingam, S., and M. Miura (1978), STOCHASTIC MODELING OF MONTHLY
    AND DAILY RAINFALL SEQUENCES, <emphasis role="italic">J Am Water Resour
    As</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">14</emphasis>(5), 1105-1120.</para>

    <para>Serinaldi, F. (2009), A multisite daily rainfall generator driven by
    bivariate copula-based mixed distributions, <emphasis role="italic">J.
    Geophys. Res.</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">114</emphasis>(D10).</para>

    <para>Serinaldi, F., and C. G. Kilsby (2014), Simulating daily rainfall
    fields over large areas for collective risk estimation, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">512</emphasis>, 285-302.</para>

    <para>Sharma, A., and U. Lall (1999), A nonparametric approach for daily
    rainfall simulation, <emphasis role="italic">Mathematics and Computers in
    Simulation</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">48</emphasis>(4-6),
    361-371.</para>

    <para>Sharma, A., and R. O'Neill (2002), A nonparametric approach for
    representing interannual dependence in monthly streamflow sequences - art.
    no. 1100, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">38</emphasis>(7), 1100-1100.</para>

    <para>Sharma, A., and R. Srikanthan (2006), Continuous Rainfall
    Simulation: A Nonparametric Alternative, paper presented at 30th Hydrology
    and Water Resources Symposium, Institution of Engineers (Australia),
    Launceston.</para>

    <para>Sharma, A., and R. Mehrotra (2010), Rainfall Generation, in
    <emphasis role="italic">Rainfall: State of the Science</emphasis>, edited
    by F. Y. Testik and M. Gebremichael, p. 287, American Geophysical Union,
    San Francisco.</para>

    <para>Sharma, A., R. Mehrotra, and F. Johnson (2013), A New Framework for
    Modeling Future Hydrologic Extremes: Nested Bias Correction as a Precursor
    to Stochastic Rainfall Downscaling (invited), in <emphasis
    role="italic">Climate Change Modeling, Mitigation, and
    Adaptation</emphasis>, edited by R. Y. Surampalli, T. C. Zhang, C. S. P.
    Ojha, B. R. Gurjar, R. D. Tyagi and C. M. Kao, p. 698, American Society of
    Civil Engineers, Reston, Virginia.</para>

    <para>Singh, S. V., and R. H. Kripalani (1986), Analysis of persistence in
    daily monsoon rainfall over India, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Climatology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">6</emphasis>(6),
    625-639.</para>

    <para>Sivakumar, B., R. Berndtsson, J. Olsson, and K. Jinno (2001),
    Evidence of chaos in the rainfall-runoff process, <emphasis
    role="italic">Hydrological Sciences Journal</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">46</emphasis>(1), 131-145.</para>

    <para>Srikanthan, R., and T. A. McMahon (1985), Stochastic generation of
    rainfall and evaporation data, Tech. Paper No. 84, Aust. Water Resour.
    Council, Canberra, 1985, <emphasis role="italic">Australian Water
    Resources Council</emphasis>, Technical Paper No. 84.</para>

    <para>Srikanthan, R., and G. Pegram (2009), A Nested Multisite Daily
    Rainfall Stochastic Generation Model, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">in
    press</emphasis>(available online at <link
    xlink:href="http://www.science-direct.com/">http://www.science-direct.com/</link>
    until publication).</para>

    <para>Srikanthan, R., T. McMahon, T. Harrold, and A. Sharma (2003),
    Stochastic Generation of Daily Rainfall Data<emphasis
    role="italic">Rep.</emphasis>, CRC for Catchment Hydrology Technical
    Report 03/?, Melbourne, Australia.</para>

    <para>Steinschneider, S., and U. Lall (2015), A hierarchical Bayesian
    regional model for nonstationary precipitation extremes in Northern
    California conditioned on tropical moisture exports, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">51</emphasis>(3), 1472-1492.</para>

    <para>Stern, R. D., and R. Coe (1984), A Model Fitting Analysis of Daily
    Rainfall Data, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of the Royal Statistical
    Society. Series A (General)</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">147</emphasis>(1), 1.</para>

    <para>Viney, N. R., and B. C. Bates (2004), It never rains on Sunday: The
    prevalence and implications of untagged multi-day rainfall accumulations
    in the Australian high quality data set, <emphasis
    role="italic">International Journal of Climatology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">24</emphasis>, 1171-1192.</para>

    <para>Wallis, T. W. R., and J. F. Griffiths (1997), Simulated
    meteorological input for agricultural models, <emphasis
    role="italic">Agricultural and Forest Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">88</emphasis>(1-4), 241-258.</para>

    <para>Wang, Q. J., and R. J. Nathan (2007), A method for coupling daily
    and monthly time scales in stochastic generation of rainfall series,
    <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">346</emphasis>(3-4), 122-130.</para>

    <para>Wasko, C., and A. Sharma (2015), Steeper temporal distribution of
    rain intensity at higher temperatures within Australian storms, <emphasis
    role="italic">Nat Geosci</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">8</emphasis>,
    527–529.</para>

    <para>Waymire, E., and V. K. Gupta (1981a), The mathematical structure of
    rainfall representations: 1. A review of the stochastic rainfall models,
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">17</emphasis>(5), 1261-1272.</para>

    <para>Waymire, E., and V. K. Gupta (1981b), The mathematical structure of
    rainfall representations: 2. A review of the theory of point processes,
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">17</emphasis>(5), 1273-1285.</para>

    <para>Westra, S., R. Mehrotra, A. Sharma, and R. Srikanthan (2012),
    Continuous rainfall simulation: 1 - A regionalised sub-daily
    disaggregation approach, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">48</emphasis>(1),
    W01535.</para>

    <para>Westra, S., J. P. Evans, R. Mehrotra, and A. Sharma (2013), A
    conditional disaggregation algorithm for generating fine time-scale
    rainfall data in a warmer climate, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">479</emphasis>,
    86-99.</para>

    <para>Westra, S., H. J. Fowler, J. P. Evans, L. V. Alexander, P. Berg, F.
    Johnson, E. J. Kendon, G. Lenderink, and N. M. Roberts (2014), Future
    changes to the intensity and frequency of short-duration extreme rainfall,
    <emphasis role="italic">Rev Geophys</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">52</emphasis>.</para>

    <para>Wheater, H. S., V. S. Isham, D. R. Cox, R. E. Chandler, A. Kakou, P.
    J. Northrop, L. Oh, C. Onof, and I. Rodriguez-Iturbe (2000),
    Spatial-temporal rainfall fields: modelling and statistical aspects,
    <emphasis role="italic">Hydrology and Earth System Sciences</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="italic">4</emphasis>(4), 581-601.</para>

    <para>Wilby, R. L., T. M. L. Wigley, D. Conway, P. D. Jones, B. C.
    Hewitson, J. Main, and D. S. Wilks (1998), Statistical Downscaling of
    General Circulation Model Output - a Comparison of Methods, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">34</emphasis>(11), 2995-3008.</para>

    <para>Wilks, D. S. (1998), Multisite generalization of a daily stochastic
    precipitation generation model, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">210</emphasis>,
    178-191.</para>

    <para>Wilks, D. S. (1999a), Simultaneous stochastic simulation of daily
    precipitation, temperature and solar radiation at multiple sites in
    complex terrain, <emphasis role="italic">Agricultural and Forest
    Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">96</emphasis>(1-3),
    85-101.</para>

    <para>Wilks, D. S. (1999b), Multisite downscaling of daily precipitation
    with a stochastic weather generator, <emphasis role="italic">Climate
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">11</emphasis>(2),
    125-136.</para>

    <para>WMO (1994), <emphasis role="italic">WMO Guide to Hydrological
    Practices</emphasis>, 770 pp., World Meteorological Organisation,
    Geneva.</para>

    <para>Woolhiser, D. A. (1992), Modeling daily precipitation - progress and
    problems, in <emphasis role="italic">Statistics in the environmental and
    earth sciences</emphasis>, edited by A. T. Walden and P. Guttorp, p. 306,
    Edward Arnold, London, U.K.</para>

    <para>Woolhiser, D. A., and G. G. S. Pegram (1979), Maximum Likelihood
    Estimation of Fourier Coefficients to Describe Seasonal Variations of
    Parameters in Stochastic Daily Precipitation Models, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Applied Meteorology</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">18</emphasis>(1), 34-42.</para>

    <para>Woolhiser, D. A., and J. Roldán (1982), Stochastic daily
    precipitation models: 2. A comparison of distributions of amounts,
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">18</emphasis>(5), 1461-1468.</para>

    <para>Woolhiser, D. A., and J. Roldán (1986), Seasonal and Regional
    Variability of Parameters for Stochastic Daily Precipitation Models: South
    Dakota, U.S.A, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, <emphasis role="italic">22</emphasis>(6),
    965-978.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
