<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<glossdiv version="5.0" xml:id="glossdiv_c" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
   xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
   xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
   xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
   xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
   <title>C</title>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Catchment Characteristics</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>The catchment characteristics are the physical attributes of a
            catchment which affect its response and behaviour to flood producing
            rainfall. These characteristics may provide independent variables for
            regional flood estimation (e.g. catchment area, stream slope, drainage
            density) and may vary significantly and discontinuously over a geographic
            region.</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Climate Characteristics</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>The climate characteristics are the climate-related attributes of a
            region which act as causative or modifying factors in the generation of
            floods and which may provide independent variables for regional flood
            estimation (e.g. rainfall, evaporation). In general, these characteristics
            can be assumed to vary smoothly over a region.</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Confidence Limits</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>Confidence limits are the lower and upper boundaries / values of a
            confidence interval, that is, the values which define the range of a
            confidence interval. A confidence interval gives an estimated range of
            values which is likely to include an unknown population parameter, the
            estimated range being calculated from a given set of sample data.
            Typically 90% confidence limits are determined (i.e. 5-95%).</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Correlation</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>A statistical measure of the strength of the relationship
            (specifically the linear relationship) between two random variables;
            correlation between flood data at different locations in a region
            (inter-station or spatial dependence) reduces the information available
            for regional analysis.</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>
</glossdiv>
