<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<glossdiv version="5.0" xml:id="glossdiv_i" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
   xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
   xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
   xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
   xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
   <title>I</title>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Independent Random Values</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>Two random variables are independent if they convey no information
            about each other and, as a consequence, receiving information about one of
            the two does not change our assessment of the probability distribution of
            the other.</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Independent Variables</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>The set of measurable characteristics (also referred to as
            explanatory variables) used in explanatory or predictive relationships for
            flood characteristics such as peak flow or flood volume; they include
            catchment and climate characteristics.</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>


   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Index Flood Method</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>A Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) method in which the
            frequency curves at different stations in a homogeneous region are assumed
            to be identical after standardisation by the index variable (usually taken
            as the mean annual event); the standardised regional frequency curve is
            referred to as the regional growth curve.</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Inter-station dependence</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
         <para>The effect of any correlation between the flood data at different
            locations in a region; this spatial dependence reduces the information
            content of the pooled data set from stations in the region compared to a
            set of independent stations (as assumed in the Station-Year Method)</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>

   <glossentry>
      <glossterm>Peak Over Threshold Series</glossterm>
      <abbrev>POT</abbrev>
      <glossdef>
         <para>One method of analyzing extreme values is called the Peak Over
            Threshold (POT) method. To use the POT method, the dataset must be
            sufficiently large so that it would be infeasible or inaccurate to
            directly analyse. The POT method involves choosing some threshold value,
            collecting the extreme values above that threshold into a sample, and then
            drawing conclusions based on that sample. It is that sample that is
            referred to as the POT series.</para>
      </glossdef>
   </glossentry>
</glossdiv>
