<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b7_ch10"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  
       <info>
       <title>Documentation, Interpretation and Presentation of Results</title>
      
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
              
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weeks_william.xml"/>
              

      
       </info>
       
       <informaltable border="1">
              <tr>
                     <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Date last updated</td>
                     <td>06/07/16 </td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Content</td>
                     <td>Working draft</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>General</td>
                     <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
              </tr>
       </informaltable>
       <section>
              <title>Introduction</title>
              <para>Catchment modelling systems for flood estimation are applied to provide
                     information to decision makers and designers on magnitudes and probabilities of
                     flood characteristics, as a basis for decisions on flood-related planning,
                     design and operations. The purpose, scope and required outputs of any flood
                     investigation should be clearly described in the brief or technical
                     specification for the design problem or flood study <citation>b7_c10_r1,b1_c5_r42</citation>. It is therefore important
                     that the client who commissions flood investigations should be comprehensive in
                     the preparation of the brief to ensure that all requirements and objectives are
                     covered in detail. The brief should be detailed but should not specify
                     unrealistic objectives for the model performance. Unrealistic objectives may
                     include over-optimistic calibration performance. </para>
              <para> The results of any modelling should be documented and presented in a way that
                     satisfies the requirements of the brief. However, even if such a brief or
                     specification is not readily available, it is the responsibility of the
                     modelling team to ensure that the modelling process is well documented and that
                     the results are presented and communicated in a way that will be clearly
                     understood by the target audience and will avoid any misinterpretation or
                     misuse of the information. The documentation may need to cover requirements for
                     several different audiences in particular circumstances, so it must be relevant
                     for these audiences. In some cases, different reports may need to be prepared
                     for these varied audiences.</para>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Audience Considerations</title>
              <para>Depending on the project and the specific requirements of the specification, the
                     documentation should cater for the required audiences. Different audiences
                     could include:</para>
              <itemizedlist>
                     <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="italic">Client </emphasis> - The client is the
                                   agency that has commissioned the flood report, and they will be
                                   seeking a report that outlines the whole scope of the report,
                                   especially covering the main issues required, as well as
                                   limitations and comments on accuracy and reliability. This report
                                   will be the basis for the client’s requirements, whether this is
                                   for planning, feasibility or design of infrastructure. The report
                                   should also clearly demonstrate the methodology and show that it
                                   was appropriate for the requirements, subject to the limitations
                                   of the specification. The client will also need to have a report
                                   that will be archived in their technical library and be available
                                   for reference in the future when the flood study may be reviewed
                                   or if later queries arise. All supporting data should also be
                                   archived
                                   <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190502T143620+1000" content="buy"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190502T143620+1000"?>by<?oxy_insert_end?>
                                   the client for future reference.</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="italic">Regulatory or Approval Agencies</emphasis>
                             - Where the client is not itself a regulatory agency, these
                                   agencies need to be considered. For example, these may include
                                   agencies such as local authorities who need to consider impacts
                                   of projects on flood levels outside the project boundary, or
                                   environmental agencies who may need to understand any impacts on
                                   water quality or fauna movement. The report needs to demonstrate
                                   to these agencies that the flood study has been carried out to an
                                   acceptable technical standard and that their interests are
                                   satisfied.</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="italic">Residents and the Public</emphasis> -
                                   Local residents will take an interest in the findings of flood
                                   studies, particularly as they affect their individual interests.
                                   To meet their interests, the report should be written in plain
                                   English, though still to a high level of technical credibility,
                                   and should clearly outline the impacts on the local community and
                                   demonstrate that any adverse impacts have been mitigated or, if
                                   this proves impossible, demonstrate that all efforts have been
                                   made to minimise impacts.</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="italic">Other Stakeholders</emphasis> - These may
                                   include local community or environmental groups, who have no
                                   direct regulatory interest but who have a community interest in
                                   the results of the flood study. In this case, the report must be
                                   written in plain English but it must also be of a high technical
                                   standard, since these stakeholders will often have a high level
                                   of technical expertise.</para>
                     </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Documentation</title>
              <section>
                     <title>General</title>
                     <para>Documentation should be progressive through the different steps of a
                            flood estimation study. The scope and level of detail of the
                            documentation will depend to some degree on the nature of the modelling
                            application but should be sufficient to provide the basis for an
                            independent review of the modelling process and the results produced
                            <citation>b1_c5_r11</citation>. </para>
                     <para>As discussed above the documentation needs to consider the requirements
                            of the audience for the report, noting that there may be more than one
                            audience. The documentation requirements outlined below apply to both
                            the hydrologic and hydraulic modelling phases of a flood study. More
                            detailed guidance on interpretation of the results of hydraulic
                            modelling is provided in the ARR Project 15 report <citation>b5_c2_r1</citation>. </para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Data Collation and Quality Checking</title>
                     <para>The data used in the model development and study is the basis for the
                            work, and a clear description and documentation of this data is
                            essential for review and understanding of the process as well as for
                            archiving and future reference. This documentation should cover all
                            forms of data used from systematically recorded or surveyed data to
                            informal sources of flood information, including historic records of
                            rainfall, streamflow, flood level, flood extent data, topographic and
                            survey data, as well as photographic and documentary information on
                            floods (see <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>). It is recommended that the
                            project report include a copy of the design input data downloaded from
                            the ARR Data Hub (data.arr.org.au) to aid in the reproducibility and
                            review of results.</para>
                     <para> It is important that the process of data quality checking and the
                            associated decisions are clearly recorded, as well as any assumptions or
                            limitations. The documentation should clearly describe the approach to
                            checking the data and indicate a descriptive understanding of the data
                            quality and the impacts of this quality on the final outcomes of the
                            project. To the extent that data ownership allows, a copy of the
                            original data sets and the finally adopted data sets should be
                            kept.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Model Development and Calibration</title>
                     <para>The documentation should cover all the stages of the model development,
                            including the selection of the catchment modelling system, the key
                            assumptions made in the model representation of the catchment or the
                            flooded area, the selection of model parameter and design inputs, and
                            the process used to ensure that the model is fit for the intended
                            purpose. Key decisions made in this process should be clearly recorded.
                            Comments on the parameter estimation process and the expected
                            reliability of the results should also be included.</para>
                     <para> It is now quite common in flood study briefs to include as part of the
                            study deliverables a requirement to provide a copy of the calibrated
                            model <citation>b7_c10_r1</citation>. This should include the relevant
                            information to allow a third party to run the model and review the
                            modelling results. More details are provided
                            in<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190502T170206+1000" content=" in"?>
                            the <citation>b4_c2_r2</citation>.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Modelling Results</title>
                     <para>Records of modelling results should include clear documentation of the
                            scenarios, parameters and design inputs for the model runs. Electronic
                            records of results should be in a format that allows ready processing
                            for summaries and reports.</para>
                     <para>The modelling results should be supported by maps and graphs which can
                            illustrate the procedures and methodology. Maps are an excellent means
                            of allowing a comprehensive but easily understood interpretation of the
                            results.</para>
              </section>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Interpretation of Modelling Results</title>
              <section>
                     <title>Model Representation vs Reality</title>
                     <para>Hydrologic and hydraulic models are simplified representations of reality
                            that are developed to allow assessment of flood problems, the final step
                            in any form of modelling is therefore the interpretation of the
                            modelling results in the light of the assumptions and simplifications
                            made in the model formulation and any other limitations that might
                            affect the modelling results. This can be seen as the reverse of the
                            process of representing the real catchment and floodplain by a
                            simplified, conceptualised model. The practitioner is in the best
                            position to assess the impacts of the simplifications of the real system
                            in terms of the uncertainties and potential bias introduced into the
                            modelling results and it is thus the practitioner’s responsibility to
                            communicate the results of this assessment.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Checking of Results</title>
                     <para>The documentation for studies should describe the checking of results
                            that has been carried out. This checking covers a number of formal and
                            informal processes and must ensure that the client and other readers
                            have confidence in the conclusions and are satisfied that the model and
                            results are as consistent as possible with reality. This checking can
                            also assist clients in model applications and any limitations.</para>
                     <para>As discussed elsewhere in Australian Rainfall and Runoff, inaccuracies
                            can result from a number of sources including:</para>
                     <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Data Quality</emphasis>
                                    - The quality of the hydrologic and hydraulic modelling
                                          depends on the quality of the local data used in the
                                          development and testing of the model.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="italic">Model Representation</emphasis>
                                   - The model is a theoretical representation of reality and
                                          the quality of this representation should be
                                          indicated.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Model Extrapolation</emphasis>
                                    - The model will be developed using certain available data
                                          for calibration or using regional parameter estimates. The
                                          application to design situations then requires
                                          extrapolation to larger floods or alternative catchment
                                          development scenarios. The quality of the model
                                          extrapolation into these alternative conditions should be
                                          reviewed.</para>
                            </listitem>
                     </itemizedlist>
                     <para>All of these issues should be described in the study
                            documentation.</para>
                     <para>The process for checking the performance of the model with these concerns
                            will need to focus firstly on the basis of the model development and
                            implementation. Secondary checks, which are equally important should
                            focus on the results, where there are several approaches to
                            checking.</para>
                     <para>Developing a process for checking that model results are sensible and
                            consistent is a vital quality control measure for the practitioner. The
                            practitioner needs to satisfy themselves that the model results are
                            reasonable prior to publishing them in a report. The following is a
                            checklist that the practitioner should consider when interpreting
                            results:</para>
                     <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Mass Balance</emphasis>
                                    – errors greater than 1% to 2% should generally be
                                          investigated, and the cause of the errors identified and
                                          rectified where possible;</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Runoff Volumes</emphasis>
                                    – the total runoff as a percentage of rainfall volume
                                          should be determined and checked against typical runoff
                                          coefficients for similar catchments;</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Runoff Rates</emphasis>
                                    – can be used to check that the runoff rates predicted by
                                          the hydrologic model do not significantly diverge from
                                          runoff rates predicted by the hydraulic model. If
                                          divergence is significant, reason(s) for such should be
                                          determined. </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Continuity</emphasis>
                                    – discharge hydrographs should be obtained at several
                                          locations along each flow path, and at locations upstream
                                          and downstream of major flow path intersections, to check
                                          that the continuity and attenuation of flows is
                                          reasonable;</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Stability</emphasis>
                                    – the results should be checked for signs of instability,
                                          such as unrealistic jumps or discontinuities in flow
                                          behaviour, oscillations (particularly around structures or
                                          boundaries), excessive reductions in time step or
                                          iterations required to achieve convergence. Many models
                                          will specify criteria based on the Courant number (refer
                                          to Book 6) that can be checked to assess model
                                          instability;</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Froude Numbers</emphasis>
                                    – Froude numbers should be checked to identify areas of
                                          trans-critical and super-critical flow, and the
                                          implications of this flow behaviour on the model results
                                          considered. In general, model results in areas of
                                          trans-critical flow should be used with extreme caution.
                                          Flow over embankments, levees and other hydraulic control
                                          structures should be roughly checked with suitable hand
                                          calculations, such as the broad-crested weir
                                          equation;</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Model Startup</emphasis>
                                    – many models do not perform well from a completely “dry”
                                          start during the initial wetting stage. The practitioner
                                          should consider using a suitable “hot-start” condition if
                                          such functionality exists, or should exclude results from
                                          the very start of the model run from their analysis. This
                                          can be particularly important near structures;</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Structure Head Losses</emphasis> –
                                          head losses through structures such as bridges, culverts,
                                          siphons etc should be checked against suitable hand
                                          calculations. More discussion on how to deal with
                                          structures is presented in <xref linkend="b6_ch3"/>. In
                                          particular, consideration should be made of the amount of
                                          expansion/contraction losses that are captured by the two
                                          dimensional schematisation, and whether the flow regime is
                                          adequately handled by the model; and</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                   <para><emphasis role="italic">Steep areas/shallow flow</emphasis>
                                    – it may be difficult to interpolate flow depths where
                                          steep shallow flow is occurring, particularly if the flow
                                          is not sub-critical. It may be necessary to check results
                                          against total energy calculations in such
                                          locations.</para>
                            </listitem>
                     </itemizedlist>
                     <para>Results for similar projects in the vicinity should be reviewed to ensure
                            that the results are consistent with these previous analyses. If there
                            are differences, reasons for these differences should be sought and
                            explained. If this is not the case, reconsideration of the model
                            selection or implementation should be considered.</para>
                     <para>Alternative flood estimation methods, generally a simple regional method
                            should also be considered again to check consistency. Again where there
                            are inconsistencies, these should be investigated and reasons found for
                            the differences.</para>
                     <para>These checks of results are important and increase confidence in the
                            analysis. The flood study documentation should clearly outline this
                            checking and demonstrate the level of confidence in the results.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Accuracy of Results</title>
                     <para><xref linkend="b1_ch2_s_4vjbf"/> gives information on the sources of
                            uncertainty and <xref linkend="b7_ch8"/> of this book provides guidance
                            on methods for determining uncertainty in modelling results. However,
                            the formal sensitivity or uncertainty analysis will generally only cover
                            the influence of the most important inputs and parameters on the
                            modelling results. The practitioner thus needs to consider the likely
                            magnitude of additional uncertainties introduced by secondary inputs and
                            parameters. </para>
                     <para>The degree of scatter in results shown up by uncertainty analyses
                            describes the <emphasis role="italic">precision</emphasis> of the flood
                            estimate. However, the accuracy of modelling results depends also the
                            degree of <emphasis role="italic">bias</emphasis> in the results
                            (systematic underestimation or overestimation). Inappropriate
                            representation of the real system by the adopted model is likely to
                            introduce model errors (additional uncertainty and bias) into the
                            modelling results, which are not captured by normal uncertainty
                            analysis. The results of uncertainty analyses should thus be regarded as
                            lower bound estimates of uncertainty. </para>
                     <para>An estimate of the likely model errors can be obtained by comparing
                            results produced by different models of the same system or by comparison
                            of flood estimates obtained by different flood estimation approaches. </para>
                     <para> The documentation must include sufficient discussion to allow the client
                            and others who read the report (including non-experts) to understand the
                            level of accuracy provided and to ensure that the report is not used to
                            indicate a higher accuracy than can be justified by the model and the
                            particular application of model calibration. To avoid misinterpretation,
                            modelling results should be presented to the number of significant
                            figures implied by accuracy considerations. Where there is uncertainty,
                            this must be described clearly and understandably so that the client and
                            others can make a reasonable decision on the results.</para>
              </section>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Presentation of Results</title>
              <section>
                     <title>General</title>
                     <para>Depending on the nature and scope of the flood investigation, the
                            modelling results may be presented in the form of a summary table of
                            flood estimates, graphs, detailed reports, maps, audio-visual
                            presentations or combinations of these elements. In all cases it is
                            important that the form and detail of the presentation is directed at
                            the target audience. Generally different forms and levels of
                            presentation of study findings will be required for different
                            stakeholder groups.</para>
                     <para> In addition to the summary of results, the documentation should include
                            comments on the accuracy and reliability of the results. It should cover
                            the basic discussion of calibration to historical flood events as well
                            as extrapolation of the model to the design scenarios and to assessments
                            beyond the scope of the calibration.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Qualifications and Caveats</title>
                     <para>The scenarios used in deriving the flood estimates need to be clearly
                            stated, including the assumptions made with regard to climate and land
                            use conditions, and possibly other system characteristics (eg.
                            operational conditions).</para>
                     <para>The modelling will have been developed for a specific application and
                            therefore the model performance for other applications may be limited.
                            This limitation could include the geographical extent as well as the
                            flood magnitudes considered. For example, if the model has been
                            developed for design of major infrastructure, it may be prepared for
                            analysis of large floods, so the calibration may be inappropriate for
                            small in-channel flows which may be required for another
                            application.</para>
                     <para> The documentation therefore should clearly describe the limitations and
                            the scope where the model results may be appropriate.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Use of Modelling Results in Decision Making</title>
                     <para>While the main interest of the stakeholders is mainly on ‘best estimates’
                            of the flood characteristics as the direct basis for flood maps and
                            other regulatory instruments, reporting on the uncertainties attached to
                            these ‘best estimates’ is important as a basis for decision making. This
                            additional information and comments on the interpretation of the
                            modelling results (<xref linkend="b7_ch8_s_wkr07"/>) are essential
                            inputs to risk assessment and risk management studies that will use the
                            modelling results (<xref linkend="b1_ch5"/>).</para>
              </section>
       </section>

       <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
              <xi:fallback>
                     <para>No included references yet...</para>
              </xi:fallback>
       </xi:include>

</chapter>

<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>