<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b4_ch3" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    status = "In Preparation">
    
    <title>Types of Simulation Approaches</title>
    
    <para>
        <informaltable border="1">
            <tr>
                <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Book</td>
                <td>4</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Chapter</td>
                <td>3</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Date</td>
                <td>27/11/2015</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Content</td>
                <td>In preparation</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Graphs and Figures</td>
                <td>In preparation</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Examples</td>
                <td>In preparation</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>General</td>
                <td/>
            </tr>
        </informaltable>
    </para>
    <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>Differentiate between event-based and continuous simulation approaches, and introduce
            the three different event-based methods relevant to ARR guidance. Broadly describe how
            event-based approaches use IFD relationships and storms of specific duration, and the
            different degrees of sophistication used to accommodate probability-neutrality in the
            transformation of design rainfalls into design floods. Differentiate these approaches
            with concepts used in continuous simulation.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Simple Event</title>

        <para>Describe the simple design event approach (as used in ARR87), its strengths and
            limitations, the implicit assumption of probability-neutrality involved in the selection
            of fixed design inputs. </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Ensemble Event</title>

        <para>Describe the use of ensemble approaches to accommodate variability in temporal
            patterns, and link to evidence where this has been shown to be valid. Describe its
            application to losses and the problems of including further inputs with non-linear
            behaviour; summarise the strengths and weaknesses of the approach.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Monte Carlo Event</title>

        <para>Describe the use of Monte Carlo approaches to accommodate variability in key factors,
            the use of unconstrained and stratified sampling schemes, and the need to consider
            dependencies between inputs. Differentiate between accommodating natural (aleatory)
            variability as distinct from parameter (epistemic) uncertainty. Outline the need to use
            frequency analysis or Total Probability Theorem to derive design estimates for
            unconstrained and stratified schemes, respectively. Summarise the strengths and
            weaknesses of the approach, focusing on its use to handle joint probability of factors
            involved in the rainfall-runoff process. </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Continuous Simulation</title>

        <para>Highlight the different concepts involved in the use of continuous simulation
            approaches compared to event-based approaches. Discuss the different model structures
            involved, the different style of climatic inputs required, its implicit treatment of
            joint probability factors, and the need for frequency analysis to then derive design
            flood estimates. Summarise the strengths and weaknesses of the approach, focusing on its
            applicability to the modelling of complex volume-dependent systems.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Hybrid Schemes</title>
        <para>Discuss the use of hybrid schemes in which continuous simulation models are used to
            accommodate the joint probabilities between soil moisture (or water levels in a cascade
            system) and rainfall sequences at a coarse time step, then their use of an event-based
            model to simulate flood generation at a finer time-step. Discuss the difference in model
            structure and climatic inputs, the implicit treatment of selected joint factors, and the
            need for frequency analysis to then derive design flood estimates. Summarise the
            strengths and weaknesses of the approach, highlighting the lack of extensive experience
            with these techniques.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Worked Examples</title>
        <para>Include a worked example that illustrates application of simple, ensemble, and MC
            approaches to generation of a rainfall-based flood frequency curve, and compare to
            results from flood frequency analysis to observed maxima.</para>
    </section>
    
</chapter>
