<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="b9_ch1" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
       xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
       xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
       xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
       status="In Preparation">
       <info>
              <title>Introduction</title>
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/coombes_peter.xml"/>
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/roso_steve.xml"/>
       </info>
       <informaltable border="1">
              <tr>
                     <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Date last updated</td>
                     <td>19/11/18 </td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Content</td>
                     <td>Advanced draft</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>General</td>
                     <td>Subject to industry feedback</td>
              </tr>
       </informaltable>
       <section>
              <title>Introduction</title>
              <para>There have been profound changes to the science and practice of urban hydrology
                     and stormwater management since the last edition of Australian Rainfall and
                     Runoff (ARR) published in 1987 <citation>arr_1987</citation>. During this
                     period analysis methods have evolved from use of the slide rule to the computer
                     age and beyond. The revision of ARR has aimed for an evidence based approach
                     that incorporates 30 years of additional data, science and knowledge. This
                     includes a move away from simple design rainfall burst event methods towards
                     Ensemble and Monte Carlo approaches to better capture variability. There is
                     less reliance on the rational method, more data available, new Intensity
                     Frequency Duration (IFD) data and better flow estimates for ungauged catchments
                     (refer to <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>).</para>
              <para>There are new challenges and gaps in knowledge about urban hydrology that is
                     part of an increasingly complex urban water cycle and town planning processes.
                     The designer now aims to retain stormwater within urban landscapes, manage
                     stormwater quality, maximize the potential of the stormwater resource and to
                     slow flows into receiving waterways. Australian Rainfall and Runoff now employs
                     Australian data which ensures that urban designers can better represent real
                     local systems and address these new challenges. </para>
              <para>Wherever possible this version of ARR provides information about the uncertainty
                     of methods and inputs. This will better equip urban designers to understand
                     risks in the urban environment. The Urban Book (Book 9 – Runoff in Urban Areas)
                     has been constructed to utilise and complement the broader set of tools in ARR
                     used to manage the water cycle. The over-arching objective of this book is to
                     provide revised and up-to-date guidance for analysis and management of urban
                     stormwater runoff.</para>
              <section>
                     <title>Urban Stormwater Runoff</title>
                     <para>Urban stormwater runoff and associated stormwater management responses
                            are part of a linked urban water cycle which includes stormwater
                            quantity and quality, water supply, sewerage, urban form and waterways.
                            Urban runoff has hydrologic characteristics such as flow rate and volume
                            which differ considerably from natural and rural systems. As a result
                            there is significant potential for impacts on natural processes and on
                            society. These include nuisance flooding, disruption of traffic and
                            business functions, flood disasters and damage, stream erosion, and
                            destruction of natural waterway form and function. These water balance
                            and linked systems issues are discussed in <xref linkend="b9_ch2"/> and
                                   <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/>.</para>
                     <para>Whilst urban runoff can be a problem to be managed, it is also a
                            potential opportunity to be exploited if viewed as an environmental
                            resource. There are urban runoff design and investigation techniques
                            that can be used to achieve better economic, social and environmental
                            outcomes. The discussion of managing urban stormwater runoff in this
                            Book also intersects with managing stormwater quality which is addressed
                            in a number of guidelines throughout Australia such as Australian Runoff
                            Quality. Many of these practices are introduced in this book.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Stormwater Management Infrastructure</title>
                     <para>Urban runoff was traditionally managed using networks of pipes and
                            channels to convey stormwater rapidly away from urban areas. The
                            definition of drainage has now broadened to incorporate both conveyance
                            and management of stormwater volumes via a wider range of measures,
                            including natural and man-made infrastructure to restore natural flood
                            behavior where possible. </para>
                     <para>Two classes of stormwater management infrastructure are described in this
                            book; volume management (<xref linkend="b9_ch4"/>) and conveyance
                            systems (<xref linkend="b9_ch5"/>).</para>
                     <para>Volume management includes measures that can store runoff for a period of
                            time, promote infiltration and store harvested stormwater for beneficial
                            uses. Modern best practice aims to achieve a range of hydrologic and
                            water quality objectives within these facilities. Volume management is a
                            key element of stormwater management and flood control which has
                            increased in importance and will continue to evolve into the future.
                            Stormwater volume controls have been subject to substantial and
                            increased research effort since 1987.</para>
                     <para>Conveyance systems allow runoff to pass through urban areas and provide
                            connections through the catchment. Conveyance systems can be classified
                            in different ways, for example underground versus surface and trunk
                            versus non-trunk. The traditional description of urban stormwater
                            management involves a minor and major event management philosophy where
                            the minor concept involves pipe drainage networks and the major concept
                            addresses flood events that are conveyed as surface flows. A minor
                            versus major design concept is also still relevant in order to
                            efficiently convey urban runoff while mitigating nuisance, damage and
                            disaster. Regardless, the focus for conveyance should be careful
                            management of surface flows and restoration of natural flow behaviour
                            wherever possible.</para>
                     <para>Volume management facilities and conveyance systems are interlinked to
                            form a network with volume management most often at discrete locations
                            connected by more linear conveyance systems. Both conveyance and volume
                            management can exist at multiple scales from lot scale (‘source
                            control’) to regional scale (‘end of pipe’). In the context of Book 9
                            natural and semi-natural urban waterways are considered part of the
                            network of conveyance and storage infrastructure.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Modelling</title>
                     <para>The unique characteristics of urban modelling include measurement and
                            assessment of the hydrologic and hydraulic effect of impervious
                            surfaces, conveyance systems and hydraulic structures including volume
                            management facilities. Analysis of urban areas involves data intensive
                            and complex processes. There is a need for complex computing tasks aided
                            by software to assist with modern investigation. A wide range of
                            computer software is available to the designer. Hand calculations are
                            generally unsuitable for most urban applications other than basic checks
                            and approximations.</para>
                     <para>Choice of computer software such as urban hydrology and hydraulic models
                            depends on a number of factors including spatial scale of the
                            investigation area and the magnitude of the floods of interest. <xref
                                   linkend="b9_ch6"/> provides guidance on how to pick a short list
                            of suitable models based on these factors. The aim should be to best
                            match the selected model with the type of investigation being
                            undertaken.</para>
                     <para>Once a suitable model has been selected, the challenge is to ensure the
                            model is applied correctly. <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/> does not provide
                            guidance on how to use specific modelling software and instead describes
                            the urban modelling process in a software independent manner. Some
                            models can be simplified and the physical resolution reduced, depending
                            on the spatial scale of the investigation and experience of the
                            modelling team. Urban modelling frameworks are described providing
                            guidance for key segments of urban catchments from the behaviour of land
                            uses within sub-catchments that flow to inlet structures, through urban
                            stormwater networks, and into the receiving waterway.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Structure and Purpose of this Book</title>
                     <para>This Urban Book is a guideline rather than a standard or recipe as
                            Australia is too diverse and the urban practice involves increasing
                            complex combinations of solutions. A primary audience of this book
                            includes readers from multiple disciplines and early career urban
                            designers. </para>
                     <para>This book focusses on the entire spectrum of runoff events and potential
                            flooding outcomes. <xref linkend="b9_ch2"/> provides an overview of the
                            characteristics of urban hydrology. <xref linkend="b9_ch3"/> introduces
                            some of the key concepts in urban stormwater management as part of an
                            urban water cycle and urban systems. It is built around <xref
                                   linkend="b9_ch4"/> and <xref linkend="b9_ch5"/> which describe
                            the key stormwater design elements of volume management and conveyance.
                                   <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/> provides guidance on urban modelling
                            including model selection and application. Two case studies are also
                            provided in <xref linkend="b9_ch6"/>.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>The Future</title>
                     <para>There is a need to allow changes in interpretation of the stormwater
                            components of this book to accommodate contemporary and integrated
                            approaches to water cycle management in urban areas, which starts with
                            the integration of land and water planning across time horizons and
                            spatial scales. This guidance encourages advances in urban water cycle
                            management, and expects advances in science and professional practice
                            over the next 30 years. There is an enabling framework of guidance in
                            all ARR Books, which encourages and permits advanced analysis techniques
                            and innovative designs. The guidance in ARR does not intend to hold back
                            advances in analysis of integrated solutions.</para>
                     <para>In some jurisdictions, there has been disproportionate focus on
                            mitigating nuisance in the minor system at the expense of a proper
                            analysis of the major system. Replacement of the minor or major drainage
                            approach with the relativity of mitigating nuisance or disaster may be a
                            future innovation of stormwater management. Allowing space for a major
                            system can help manage large events and provides flexibility for
                            adapting stormwater management to incorporate integrated systems and
                            better management of nuisance. </para>
                     <para>It is expected that policy frameworks will evolve to further integrate
                            land and water management with design processes at all spatial scales
                            from local to regional and which also applies to urban renewal and asset
                            renewal or replacement choices. Future design methods fomakr integrated
                            solutions are likely to include most of the variability of real rainfall
                            events by using continuous simulation, Monte Carlo frameworks and
                            techniques that consider complete storms, frequency of rainfall volumes
                            and the spatial variability of events.</para>
                     <para>Good urban runoff management will only be achieved when it is integrated
                            with the complete management of the urban water cycle and includes
                            proper consideration of runoff quality. The guidance in the Urban Book
                            must be linked with Australian Runoff Quality (ARQ)
                                   <citation>b9_c4_r14</citation> and other water quality guidelines
                            so that urban stormwater management is an integrated part of the urban
                            water cycle and avoids duplication of infrastructure. An integrated
                            approach to stormwater management should avoid installation of
                            infrastructure to meet separate objectives that, in combination, create
                            unexpected diminished performance. There is a need to consider
                            integrated approaches for future urban water management. Integrated
                            systems have the capacity to produce solutions that respond to multiple
                            objectives including economic, social and environmental criteria.</para>
                     <para>This Book on Runoff in Urban Areas is part of the evolving story of
                            stormwater management and aims to encourage innovation into the future.
                     </para>
              </section>
       </section>
    <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
           <xi:fallback>
                  <para>No included references yet...</para>
           </xi:fallback>
    </xi:include>
</chapter>
