<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="b9_ch1" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         status = "In Preparation">
      
       <info>
              <title>Introduction</title>
                            
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>
              
              <xi:include href="../../common/authors/testoni_isabelle.xml"/>
       </info>      
       
 
       <informaltable border="1">
              <tr>
                     <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Date last updated</td>
                     <td>06/07/16 </td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Content</td>
                     <td>Working draft</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>General</td>
                     <td>Subject to industry feedback and final editing </td>
              </tr>
       </informaltable>
       <section>
              <title>Objectives and Scope</title>
              <para>There is a need to provide guidance on issues related directly to urban
                     catchments. The approach and constraints for urban catchments is significantly
                     different to rural catchments in some aspects of flood hydrology. It is
                     therefore necessary to outline specific approaches and philosophies applied to
                     the urban environment in a separate book. </para>
              <para>The considerations in managing runoff in urban catchments is varied and complex.
                     Some considerations explored in this book are:</para>
              <itemizedlist>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>How urbanisation effects catchment characteristics</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Drainage systems </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Overland flooding versus riverine (or channel) flooding</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Storage of runoff in detention and retention systems</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para>Design of pipe systems</para>
                     </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <para> As part of the ARR revision projects a search was undertaken to uncover long
                     term streamflow gauges in urban areas. Insufficient data was uncovered to allow
                     the development of an urban flood method. The existing urban streamflow gauges
                     should be given special recognition for their importance to the development of
                     future techniques. This recognition could be used to help justify the ongoing
                     support and maintenance of these gauges. </para>
              <para> It is highly desirable to identify a set of high quality urban catchments to
                     allow new methods to be tested against observed data. Such catchments should
                     have long term gauged records, good quality rating curves, and a reasonably
                     stationary level of development.</para>
              <para>While theory hydraulic structures is covered in <xref linkend="book6"/>,
                     practical guidance on how it applies to an urban context is covered in this
                     book. Although ARR aims to cover best practice in flood estimation, new
                     methods, data and software is constantly being developed. Careful consideration
                     should be taken in using the most up the date and appropriate methods. </para>
       </section>

</chapter>
