<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b3_ch3"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Regional Flood Methods</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/rahman_ataur.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/haddad_khaled.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_0g2kk">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Estimation of peak flows on small to medium sized rural catchments
    is required for the design of culverts, small to medium sized bridges,
    causeways, soil conservation works and for various planning and regulatory
    purposes. Typically, many small to medium sized catchments are ungauged or
    have little recorded streamflow data. In these cases, peak flow estimates
    can be obtained using a regional flood frequency estimation (RFFE)
    approach, which transfers flood characteristics information from a group
    of gauged catchments to the catchment location of interest. Even in cases
    where there is recorded streamflow data it is beneficial to pool the
    information in the gauged record with the RFFE information. A RFFE
    technique is expected to be simple, requiring only readily accessible
    input data to obtain design flood estimates relatively quickly.</para>

    <para>The basis for the development of the RFFE technique recommended
    herein is a national database consisting of 853 gauged catchments. These
    data were used to develop and test the RFFE technique presented in this
    chapter. Further details of the database and the development of the RFFE
    technique are provided by the references noted in Appendix A.</para>

    <para>The following sections of this chapter contain a description of the
    conceptual and statistical framework of the adopted RFFE technique, a
    computer-based application tool, referred to as ‘RFFE Model 2015’ that
    implements the adopted RFFE technique and a number of worked examples to
    demonstrate the application of the model.</para>

    <para>Following the guidance provided in Book 1 and Chapter 1 of this
    book, users of the RFFE technique are reminded that there are alternatives
    to the RFFE technique. Furthermore, in accordance with this guidance,
    designers and analysts have a duty to use an alternative technique where
    that alternative is more appropriate for their design flood
    problem.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ynzmg">
    <title>Conceptual Framework</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_oubiy">
      <title>Definition of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation</title>

      <para>Regional flood frequency estimation (RFFE) is a data-driven
      approach, which attempts to transfer flood characteristics information
      from a group of gauged catchments to an ungauged catchment of interest
      (where design floods need to be estimated). A range of different methods
      are available to extract regional flood information from the pooled data
      and to transfer the relevant information to an individual ungauged
      catchment in the region (Sivapalan, Blöschl and Wagener, 2013). All of
      these RFFE techniques use the results of at-site flood frequency
      analysis as basic data. A RFFE technique essentially consists of two
      steps: (i) formation of regions, which involves identification of the
      regions for which flood data from the available streamflow gauging
      stations can be pooled for analysis; and (ii) development of regional
      estimation equations, which involves derivation of prediction equations
      to be used for design flood estimation within a region.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_mctc1">
      <title>Formation of Regions</title>

      <para>In RFFE, formation of regions can be based on geographic proximity
      or on similarity in catchment attributes. A region can be fixed, having
      a definite common boundary for all sites within it, or it can be formed
      around the ungauged catchment of interest (i.e. the location where the
      flood quantile estimation is desired), taking the nearest stations in
      geographic or catchment attributes space. A region must satisfy
      explicitly or implicitly the assumption of ‘regional homogeneity’. The
      decision on what constitutes a homogeneous region for the purposes of
      regional flood estimation depends on the methods used, more specifically
      on the extent to which differences in flood characteristics can be
      expressed through parameters in the regionalisation method. There have
      been many techniques developed which attempt to establish homogenous
      regions. For example the recommended RFFE model for eastern New South
      Wales and Victoria in Australian Rainfall and Runoff 1987 (ARR1987),
      namely the Probabilistic Rational Method, used geographical contiguity
      as an indication of homogeneity; in other words the catchments which are
      closer to each other should have similar runoff coefficients (I. E.
      Aust., 1987).</para>

      <para>There has been little success in the identification of ‘acceptably
      homogeneous regions’ in Australia using statistical measures such as
      those proposed by Hosking and Wallis (1993). A common approach to
      defining a fixed region has been to base the region on political
      boundaries. However, these fixed regions based on state borders and
      other geographical boundaries have often been found to be highly
      heterogeneous (Bates et al., 1998; Rahman, 1997; Haddad, 2008).</para>

      <para>As an alternative to fixed regions, Burn (1990a, 1990b) and Zrinji
      and Burn (1994) proposed the region-of-influence (ROI) approach where a
      site of interest (i.e. the catchment where flood quantiles are to be
      estimated) is allowed to form its own region by selecting a group of
      ‘nearby catchments’ in either a geographical or catchment attributes
      space. The ROI approach attempts to reduce the degree of heterogeneity
      in a proposed region by excluding sites located remotely in geographical
      or catchment attributes space. The ROI approach often uses a statistical
      criterion to select the optimum size of the region, such as ‘minimum
      model error variance’ in the regression.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_tjham">
      <title>Development of RFFE Technique</title>

      <para>According to Bates (1994), the most commonly adopted methods to
      develop regional flood estimation techniques include various forms of
      the Rational Method, the Index Flood Method and regression based
      techniques. In ARR1987, the Probabilistic Rational Method was
      recommended for general use in Victoria and eastern NSW (I. E. Aust.,
      1987). The foundations of the Probabilistic Rational Method are
      presented by Pilgrim (1982), Pilgrim and McDermott (1982), Mittelstadt,
      et al. (1987), and Adams (1984). The central component of the
      Probabilistic Rational Method, is the runoff coefficient and, in
      particular, the 10 year ARI runoff coefficient. It is worth noting that
      this runoff coefficient is not a physical parameter but rather a
      parameter to ensure that the rainfall frequency is transferred to the
      flow frequency. Furthermore, this parameter has been assumed to vary
      smoothly over geographical space for purposes of extrapolating from
      known locations to random locations for application. However, it has
      been found that the runoff coefficient may show sharp variation within a
      close proximity, reflecting discontinuities at many locations,
      particularly at catchment boundaries. Additionally, French (2002) noted
      that the isopleths of the runoff coefficient in ARR1987 ignored the
      existence of watercourses.</para>

      <para>Alternative methods to the Probabilistic Rational Method, such as
      the Index Flood Method heavily rely on the assumption of ‘regional
      homogeneity’, which as previously mentioned is satisfied poorly for
      Australian regional flood data. Studies on regression-based RFFE
      techniques for Australia (e.g. Hackelbusch et al., 2009; Haddad, et al.,
      2008; Haddad et al., 2009; Haddad, et al., 2011; Haddad, et al., 2012;
      Haddad and Rahman, 2012; Micevski et al., 2014; Palmen and Weeks, 2009,
      2011; Pirozzi et al., 2009; Rahman, 2005; Rahman, Rima and Weeks, 2008;
      Rahman et al., 2009, 2011a, 2011b, 2012, 2014a, 2014b, 2014c) have
      demonstrated that these techniques are capable of providing quite
      accurate design flood estimates using only a few predictor variables. In
      particular, it has been found that the generalised least squares (GLS)
      based regression technique offers a powerful statistical method which
      accounts for the inter-station correlation of annual maximum flood
      series and across-site variation in flood series record lengths in the
      estimation of the flood quantiles. Use of a GLS-based regression method
      also allows differentiation between sampling error and model error and
      thus provides a more realistic framework for error analysis. The
      GLS-based quantile regression technique has been adopted in the US (see,
      for example, Stedinger and Tasker, 1985; Tasker and Stedinger, 1989;
      Griffis and Stedinger, 2007) for development of an RFFE
      technique.</para>

      <para>As an alternative to the quantile regression technique, the
      parameters of a particular probability distribution can be regressed
      against the catchment characteristics to develop prediction equations
      for the parameters of interest. This method is referred to as Parameter
      Regression Technique (PRT). It is this approach that is the basis of the
      recommended technique for design flood estimation in Australia using
      RFFE model. For development of a PRT, the Bayesian GLS regression method
      is used to develop prediction equations for the model parameters for the
      three-parameter Log-Pearson Type 3 (LP3) distribution; these model
      parameters are the mean, standard deviation and skewness of the Annual
      Maximum Flood series (natural logs). The PRT offers three significant
      advantages over the quantile regression technique:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>It ensures flood quantiles increase smoothly with decreasing
          annual exceedance probability (AEP), an outcome that may not always
          be achieved with quantile regression;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>It is straightforward to combine any at-site flood information
          with regional estimates using the approach described by Micevski and
          Kuczera (2009) to produce more accurate quantile estimates;
          and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>It permits quantiles to be estimated for any AEP in the range
          of interest.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_0zix8">
      <title>Data to Develop RFFE Technique</title>

      <para>The success of a RFFE technique largely depends on the quantity
      and quality of the available data and the capability of the adopted
      statistical techniques to transfer information from gauged to ungauged
      sites within the region. There are two basic types of data required for
      the development and application of RFFE techniques:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>flood data at gauged sites; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>catchment characteristics data relevant to flood production,
          for both gauged and ungauged catchments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>The flood observations at gauged sites constitute the foundation
      of a RFFE technique, and the quality and representativeness of the flood
      data determine to a large degree the accuracy and reliability of
      regional flood estimates. The challenge in collating a database for RFFE
      lies in maximising the amount of useful flood information, while
      minimising the random and systematic error (or ‘noise’) that may be
      present in some flood data.</para>

      <para>In RFFE, various sources of errors in data and their effects on
      final flood estimates need to be recognised. The accuracy of flood
      quantile estimates at each individual gauged site depends largely on
      rating curve accuracy and record length at the individual site. Thus,
      the selection of a minimum record length at an individual site in the
      region is a very important step in any RFFE; the record length should be
      as long as possible while retaining enough sites in the region to make
      the results of RFFE statistically meaningful. Also, the flood data at
      each site should satisfy a number of basic assumptions e.g. homogeneity,
      independence and stationarity. In the case where these assumptions are
      violated, appropriate measures should be taken; suitable techniques
      include GLS regression to account for the inter-station correlation
      (e.g. Stedinger and Tasker, 1985; Griffis and Stedinger, 2007), and
      non-stationary flood frequency analysis to account for climate change
      impact. The data preparation issues for a RFFE technique are discussed
      in more detail by Haddad et al. (2010) and Rahman et al. (2014a,
      2014d).</para>

      <para>The transfer of flood information from gauged to ungauged
      catchments relies on the ability to identify a number of key catchment
      and climate characteristics which determine similarities and differences
      in the flood production of catchments. In the Probabilistic rational
      method similarity is assumed to exist on the basis of geographical
      proximity, but in other methods an appropriately small but informative
      set of predictor variables needs to be identified. The accuracy of a
      RFFE technique does not necessarily increase with the number of adopted
      predictor variables. For example, Rahman et al. (1999) used 12 predictor
      variables in an L moments-based index flood method for south-east
      Australia. A subsequent study by Rahman (2005) showed that use of only 2
      to 3 predictor variables can provide similar level of accuracy.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_voncz">
      <title>Accuracy Considerations</title>

      <para>All RFFE techniques are subjected to uncertainty, which,
      generally, is likely to be greater than for at-site flood frequency
      analysis when a good quality and long record of streamflow data set is
      available at the site of interest. A RFFE technique essentially
      represents a ‘transfer function’ that converts predictor variables to a
      flood quantile estimate. It is assumed that use of a limited number of
      predictor variables (e.g. catchment area and design rainfall intensity)
      combined with an optimised transfer function captures the general nature
      of the rainfall-runoff relationship for flood events and hence provides
      flood quantile estimates of ‘acceptable’ accuracy.</para>

      <para>Because a RFFE technique typically has limited predictive power,
      design flood estimates produced by it are likely to have a lower degree
      of accuracy than those from a well calibrated catchment modelling
      system. From the investigations made by Rahman et al. (2009, 2012,
      2014b), it may be stated that the relative accuracy of regional flood
      estimates using the RFFE model presented in this chapter is likely to be
      within ±50% of true value; however, in a limited number of cases the
      estimation error may exceed ±100% (see Section 7). It is unlikely that
      any RFFE technique would be able to provide flood quantile estimates
      which are of much greater accuracy than this, given the current
      availability of streamflow data (in terms of temporal and spatial
      coverage) in Australia.</para>

      <para>For catchments having limited recorded streamflow data, the
      combination of at-site data with a RFFE technique is likely to provide
      more accurate flood quantile estimates than either the at-site or
      regional method alone. Details of how limited streamflow data can be
      combined with a RFFE technique is presented in Book 4, Chapter 2 of
      ARR.</para>

      <para>An important assumption in all RFFE techniques is that the small
      set of predictor variables used in the regression equations is able to
      explain the differences in flood producing characteristics of the
      catchments in a region. Not all ungauged catchments located in the
      region satisfy this basic homogeneity assumption; some catchments may
      have characteristics that are substantially different from the gauged
      catchments in the region. Section 10 contains further discussion on the
      limits of applicability of the RFFE technique, on what constitutes an
      ‘atypical catchment’ and recommendations on how to derive flood
      estimates for such catchments.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_kbrnd">
    <title>Statistical Framework</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8o524">
      <title>Region-of-influence (ROI) Approach</title>

      <para>In the formation of regions, the region-of-influence (ROI)
      approach has been adopted for the parts of Australia where there are
      adequate numbers of gauged stations within close proximity to form ROI
      sub-regions. In the absence of a proven technique for the use of
      catchment characteristics as the basis for the ROI, the adopted ROI
      approach uses the geographical distance between stations as the distance
      metric and sets a maximum distance for inclusion of stations in the ROI
      sub-region. In applying the ROI approach, in the first iteration, a ROI
      sub-region consisting of the ten nearest stations to the site of
      interest is formed, the regional prediction equation is developed and
      its prediction error variance noted. At each of the subsequent
      iterations, the radius of the ROI sub-region is increased by 10 km and
      new stations are added to the previously selected stations. This
      procedure ends when all the eligible stations are included in the ROI
      sub-region. The final ROI sub-region for the site of interest is then
      selected as the one exhibiting the lowest prediction error
      variance.</para>

      <para>One of the apparent limitations of the ROI approach is that for
      each of the gauged sites in the region, the regional prediction equation
      has a different set of model parameters; hence a single regional
      prediction equation cannot be pre-specified. To overcome this problem,
      the parameters of the regional prediction equations for all the gauged
      catchment locations are pre-estimated and integrated with the RFFE Model
      2015 (see Section 11 for more details). To derive flood quantile
      estimate at an ungauged catchment of interest, RFFE Model 2015 takes the
      inverse distance weighted average value of flood quantile estimates
      based on up to 15 nearest gauged catchment locations within 300 km
      radius from the catchment of interest. This ensures a smooth variation
      of flood quantile estimates over the space.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_epemh">
      <title>Parameter Regression Technique (PRT)</title>

      <para>In the adopted RFFE technique for the data-rich areas of Australia
      (see Section 4.1 for further details), the first three moments of the
      LP3 distribution (i.e. the mean, standard deviation and skewness of the
      natural logarithms of the annual maximum flood series) are regionalised.
      This method is referred to as the parameter regression technique (PRT).
      The LP3 distribution is described by the following equation:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_swrce">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>lnQ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>M</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>K</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mi>S</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> = the discharge having an AEP of x% (design flood or
      flood quantile);</para>

      <para>M = mean of the natural logarithms of the annual maximum flood
      series;</para>

      <para>S = standard deviation of the natural logarithms of the annual
      maximum flood series; and</para>

      <para><inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>K</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> = frequency factor for the LP3 distribution for AEP
      of x%, which is a function of the AEP and the skewness (SK) of the
      natural logarithms of the annual maximum flood series.</para>

      <para>The prediction equations for M, S and SK have been developed for
      all the gauged catchment locations in the data-rich areas using Bayesian
      GLS regression and model parameters are noted. These model parameters
      are integrated with the RFFE Model 2015.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_9bcrr">
      <title>Generalised Least Squares Regression</title>

      <para>In developing the prediction equations, for the data-rich regions,
      the Bayesian generalised least squares (GLS) regression is adopted. The
      GLS regression assumes that the hydrological variable of interest (e.g.
      a moment of the LP3 distribution) denoted by y<subscript>i
      </subscript>for a given site i can be described by a function of
      catchment characteristics (explanatory variables) with an additive error
      (Griffis and Stedinger, 2007):</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_wezxq">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>y</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                <m:mi>0</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:munderover>
                  <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>j</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>k</m:mi>
                </m:munderover>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>ij</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>...</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>X</m:mi>

              <m:mi>ij</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> (j = 1,…, k) are explanatory variables,
      <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>β</m:mi>

              <m:mi>j</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> are the regression coefficients, <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is the model error which is assumed to be normally
      and independently distributed with model error variance <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msubsup>
              <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>2</m:mi>
            </m:msubsup>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> , and n is the number of sites in the region. In all
      cases, an at-site estimate of yi denoted as <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mover>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>y</m:mi>

                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
            </m:mover>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is available. To account for the error in the
      at-site estimate, a sampling error <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>η</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> must be introduced into the model so that:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_pogxg">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>ŷ</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>Xβ</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>η</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>Xβ</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mtext>where</m:mtext>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>ŷ</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>γ</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>

                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>η</m:mi>

                                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>: і</m:mi>

                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                                <m:mi>1,2 ...,n</m:mi>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>Thus the observed regression model error ε is the sum of the model
      error δ and the sampling error η. The total error vector has a mean of
      zero and a covariance matrix:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_ujp3a">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msup>
              <m:mi>E[εε</m:mi>

              <m:mi>T</m:mi>
            </m:msup>

            <m:mo>]=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msubsup>
                <m:mi>Λ(σ</m:mi>

                <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                <m:mi>2</m:mi>
              </m:msubsup>

              <m:mo>) =</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msubsup>
                  <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                </m:msubsup>

                <m:mo>I+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>Σ(ŷ)</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where<inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mi>Σ(ŷ</m:mi>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation>) is the covariance matrix of the sampling error in
      the estimate of the flood quantile or the parameter of the LP3
      distribution and I is a (n x n) identity matrix. The covariance matrix
      for ηi depends on the record length available at each site and the cross
      correlation among annual maximum floods at different sites. Therefore,
      the observed regression model error is a combination of time-sampling
      error η<subscript>i</subscript> and an underlying model error
      δ<subscript>i</subscript>.</para>

      <para>The GLS estimator of β and its covariance matrix for a known
      σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² is given by:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_1jjd4">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>΅β</m:mi>

              <m:mi>GLS</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msup>
                    <m:mi>[X</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                  </m:msup>

                  <m:mo>Λ</m:mo>

                  <m:msubsup>
                    <m:mi>(σ</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                  </m:msubsup>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mo>)⁻ₑX]⁻ₑ</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msup>
                  <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                </m:msup>

                <m:mo>Λ</m:mo>

                <m:msubsup>
                  <m:mi>(σ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                </m:msubsup>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mi>)⁻ₑŷ</m:mi>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_iqkha">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>Σ [</m:mo>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>΅β</m:mi>

                <m:mi>GLS</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>]=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msup>
                  <m:mi>[X</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                </m:msup>

                <m:mo>Λ</m:mo>

                <m:msubsup>
                  <m:mi>(σ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                </m:msubsup>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)⁻ₑX]⁻ₑ</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>The model error variance σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² can be
      estimated by either generalised method of moments (MOM) or maximum
      likelihood estimators. The MOM estimator is determined by iteratively
      solving equation 5 along with the generalised residual mean square error
      equation:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_w6z3z">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>(ŷ</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>X΅β</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msubsup>
                    <m:mi>[΅σ</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                  </m:msubsup>

                  <m:mo>I+</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>Σ(ŷ</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>)]⁻ₑ(ŷ</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>΅β</m:mi>

                <m:mi>GLS</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>)=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>n</m:mi>

              <m:mo>- (</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>k</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>1)</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>In some situations, the sampling covariance matrix explains all
      the variability observed in the data, which means the left-hand side of
      equation (7) will be less than n – (k + 1) even if
      σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² is zero. In these circumstances, the MOM
      estimator of the model error variance is generally taken to be
      zero.</para>

      <para>With the Bayesian approach, it is assumed that there is no prior
      information on any of the β parameters; thus a multivariate normal
      distribution with mean zero and a large variance (e.g. greater than 100)
      is used as a prior for the regression coefficient parameters. This prior
      is considered to be almost non-informative, which produces a probability
      distribution function that is generally flat in the region of interest.
      The prior information for the model error variance
      σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² is represented by a one-parameter exponential
      distribution. Further description of the adopted Bayesian GLS regression
      can be found in Haddad, et al. (2011) and Haddad and Rahman
      (2012).</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_7r0rn">
      <title>Development of Confidence Limits for the Estimated Flood
      Quantiles</title>

      <para>In developing the confidence limits for the estimated flood
      quantiles, a Monte Carlo simulation approach is adopted by assuming that
      the uncertainty in the first three parameters of the LP3 distribution
      (i.e. the mean, standard deviation and skewness of the logarithms of the
      annual maximum flood series) can be specified by a multivariate normal
      distribution. Here the correlations among the three parameters for a
      given region are estimated from the residuals of the GLS regression
      models of the LP3 parameters. The mean of the LP3 parameter is given by
      its regional predicted value and the standard deviation of the LP3
      parameter is the square root of the average variance of prediction of
      the parameter at the nearest gauged site. Based on 10,000 simulated
      values of the LP3 parameters from the multivariate normal distribution
      as defined above, 10,000 Q<subscript>x</subscript> values are estimated,
      which are then used to develop the 90% confidence intervals.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_wfiku">
    <title>RFFE TECHNIQUE FOR DATA-RICH AREAS</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_2fdu4">
      <title>Data Used to Develop RFFE Technique</title>

      <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_i6yzh">
        <title>Flood data</title>

        <para>Data-rich areas include most of the coastal belts of Australia
        where there are a good number of recorded streamflow stations as shown
        in Figure 1. An upper limit of catchment size of 1,000 km² is adopted.
        However, in some states (such as the Northern Territory), a few larger
        catchments are included as the total number of catchments with areas
        less than 1,000 km² is too small. The cut-off record length is
        selected as 19 years to maximise the number of eligible stations on
        the consideration that a higher cut-off would reduce that
        number.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_55d8a">
          <title>Geographical distributions of the adopted 798 catchments from
          data-rich areas of Australia</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure1.PNG"
                         scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The selected streams are essentially unregulated since major
        regulation affects the rainfall-runoff relationship significantly
        (e.g. storage effects). Streams with minor regulation, such as small
        farm dams and diversion weirs, are not excluded because this type of
        regulation is unlikely to have a significant effect on large annual
        floods. Gauging stations on streams subject to major upstream
        regulation (e.g. a large dam on the stream) are excluded from the data
        set. Catchments with more than 10% of the area affected by
        urbanisation are also excluded from the study data set. Catchments
        known to have undergone major land use changes, such as the clearing
        of forests or changing of agricultural practices over the period of
        streamflow records are excluded from the data set. Stations graded as
        „poor quality or with specific comments by the gauging authority
        regarding quality of the data are assessed in greater detail; if
        stations are deemed „low quality they are excluded.</para>

        <para>The annual maximum flood series data may be affected by
        multi-decadal climate variability and climate change, which are not
        easy to deal with. The effects of multi-decadal climate variability
        can be accounted for by increasing the cut-off record length at an
        individual station; however, the impacts of climate change present a
        serious problem in terms of the applicability of the past data in
        predicting future flood frequency, which needs further research (Ishak
        <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2013). This is further discussed in
        Section 9.</para>

        <para>The data sets for the initially selected potential catchments
        are further examined, as detailed in Haddad <emphasis>et
        al</emphasis>. (2010) and Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>. 2014 (a,
        b, c): gaps in the annual maximum flood series were filled as far as
        could be justified, outliers were detected using the multiple
        Grubbs-Beck test (Lamontagne <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2013; Cohn
        <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2013), error associated with rating curve
        extrapolation was investigated and presence of trend was checked. From
        an initial number of about 1200 catchments, a total of 798 catchments
        were finally adopted from all over Australia (excluding catchments in
        the arid regions, where some of the above criteria were relaxed, as
        discussed in Section 5).</para>

        <para>The record lengths of the annual maximum flood series of these
        798 stations range from 19 to 102 years (median: 37 years). The
        catchment areas of the selected 798 catchments range from 0.5 km² to
        4,325 km² (median: 178 km²). The geographical distribution of the
        selected 798 catchments is shown in Figure 1 and Table 1 presents a
        summary of the selected catchments</para>

        <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_opf7j">
          <title>Summary of adopted catchments from data-rich areas of
          Australia</title>

          <tgroup cols="4">
            <colspec/>

            <colspec/>

            <colspec align="center"/>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>State</entry>

                <entry>No. of stations</entry>

                <entry>Streamflow record length (years) (range and
                median)</entry>

                <entry>Catchment size (km2) (range and median)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>New South Wales &amp; Australian Capital
                Territory</entry>

                <entry>176</entry>

                <entry>20 – 82 (34)</entry>

                <entry>1 – 1036 (204)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Victoria</entry>

                <entry>186</entry>

                <entry>20 – 60 (38)</entry>

                <entry>3 – 997 (209)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>South Australia</entry>

                <entry>28</entry>

                <entry>20 – 63 (37)</entry>

                <entry>0.6 – 708 (62.6)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Tasmania</entry>

                <entry>51</entry>

                <entry>19 – 74 (28)</entry>

                <entry>1.3 – 1900 (158.1)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Queensland</entry>

                <entry>196</entry>

                <entry>20 – 102 (42)</entry>

                <entry>7– 963 (227)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Western Australia</entry>

                <entry>111</entry>

                <entry>20 – 60 (30)</entry>

                <entry>0.5 – 1049.8 (49.2)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Northern Territory</entry>

                <entry>50</entry>

                <entry>19 – 57 (42)</entry>

                <entry>1.4 – 4325 (352)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>TOTAL</entry>

                <entry>798</entry>

                <entry>19 – 102 (37)</entry>

                <entry>0.5 – 4325 (178)</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>

        <para>The at-site flood frequency analyses are conducted using the
        FLIKE software (Kuczera, 1999). The potentially influential low flows
        (PILFs) are identified using multiple Grubbs-Beck test
        (Lamontagne<emphasis> et al</emphasis>., 2013) and are censored in the
        flood frequency analysis. A Bayesian parameter estimation procedure
        with LP3 distribution is used to estimate flood quantiles for each of
        the gauged site for AEPs of 50%, 20%, 10%, 5%, 2% and 1%.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ujhrw">
        <title>Catchment characteristics data</title>

        <para>As discussed by Rahman<emphasis> et al</emphasis>. (2009; 2012),
        over ten predictor variables are selected initially; however, it was
        found that the accuracy of a RFFE technique does not necessarily
        increase with the number of adopted predictor variables. A total of
        five predictor variables were finally adopted in the RFFE technique as
        outlined below:</para>

        <para>(i) catchment area in km² (<emphasis>area</emphasis>);</para>

        <para>(ii) design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid (in mm/h)
        for 6-hour duration and AEP of 50%
        (I<subscript>6,50</subscript>);</para>

        <para>(iii) design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid (in mm/h)
        for 6-hour duration and AEP of 2%
        (I<subscript>6,2</subscript>);</para>

        <para>(iv) ratio of design rainfall intensities of AEPs of 2% and 50%
        for duration of 6-hour
        (I<subscript>6,2</subscript>/I<subscript>6,50</subscript>); and</para>

        <para>(v) <emphasis>shape factor</emphasis>, which is defined as the
        shortest distance between catchment outlet and centroid divided by the
        square root of catchment area.</para>

        <para>Design rainfall values were extracted from the new
        intensity-frequency-duration (IFD) data for Australia as discussed in
        Book 2, Chapter 3 of ARR.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_pfnbw">
      <title>Adopted RFFE Regions</title>

      <para>Australia is divided into seven regions. There are five data rich
      areas, as shown in Table 2 and Figure 2. The remaining two regions are
      data poor and are located in the semi-arid and arid areas (referred to
      as arid areas) of Australia. The boundaries between the arid and
      data-rich regions in Figure 2 are drawn approximately based on the 500
      mm mean annual rainfall contour line. There are six fringe zones, as
      discussed in Section 6.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_49qvf">
        <title>Adopted regions for RFFE technique in Australia</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure2.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>
        <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_k3lzr">
          <title>Details of RFFE technique for data rich regions</title>

          <tgroup cols="4">
            <colspec/>

            <colspec/>

            <colspec align="center"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry align="center">Region</entry>

                <entry align="center">ROI (based on geographical
                proximity)</entry>

                <entry align="center">Number of stations</entry>

                <entry align="center">Estimation model</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Region 1: VIC + NSW + ACT + QLD</entry>

                <entry>ROI (based on geographical proximity)</entry>

                <entry>558</entry>

                <entry>Bayesian GLS regression-PRT</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 2: Tasmania</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry>51</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 3: South Australia</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry>28</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 4: NT + Kimberley WA</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry>58</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 5: SW Western Australia</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry>103</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_o7h7w">
      <title>Adopted Estimation Equations</title>

      <para>For the five data-rich regions described in Table 2, the adopted
      estimation equations for <emphasis>M</emphasis>, <emphasis>S</emphasis>
      and <emphasis>SK</emphasis> for the regional LP3 model (equation 1) have
      the following general form:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_yitfd">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>M</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>b₀</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>b₁(ln(area))</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>b₂(ln(I₆,₅₀))</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>b₃(ln(shape factor))</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_n8zye">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>S</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>c₀</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mi>c₁(ln(I₆,₂/I₆,₅₀))</m:mi>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_3r3ol">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>SK</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>d₀</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>d₁(ln(area))</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>d₂(ln(I₆,₂/I₆,₅₀))</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>d₃(ln(I₆,₂))</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where, <emphasis>area</emphasis> = catchment area (km²);</para>

      <para>I<subscript>6,50</subscript> = design rainfall intensity (mm/h) at
      catchment centroid for 6-hour duration and AEP of 50%;</para>

      <para><emphasis>shape factor</emphasis> = shortest distance between
      catchment outlet and
      centroid/<emphasis>area</emphasis><superscript>0.5</superscript>;
      and</para>

      <para>I<subscript>62</subscript> = design rainfall intensity (mm/h) at
      catchment centroid for 6-hour duration and AEP of 2%.</para>

      <para>For Region 1 and Region 2, equations 9 and 10 have only the model
      intercepts, i.e. for these two regions, the weighted average values of S
      and SK are adopted, which are determined on the basis of record lengths
      at the stations within the ROI sub-region.</para>

      <para>The values of b<subscript>0</subscript>,
      b<subscript>1</subscript>, b<subscript>2</subscript>,
      b<subscript>3</subscript>, c<subscript>0</subscript>,
      c<subscript>1</subscript>, d<subscript>0</subscript>,
      d<subscript>1</subscript>, d<subscript>2</subscript> and
      d<subscript>3</subscript> at all the 798 individual gauged catchment
      locations (in the data rich regions) are estimated and embedded in the
      REEF Model 2015. To derive flood quantile estimate at an ungauged
      catchment of interest, RFFE Model 2015 takes the inverse distance
      weighted average value of flood quantile estimates based on up to 15
      nearest gauged catchment locations within 300 km radius from the
      catchment of interest. This ensures a smooth variation of flood quantile
      estimates over the space.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ksbct">
    <title>RFFE TECHNIQUE FOR DATA-POOR AREAS</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_4foca">
      <title>Data Used to Develop RFFE Technique</title>

      <para>Most of Australia.s interior falls into the arid and semi-arid
      areas (referred to as arid areas), which are characterised by low mean
      annual rainfall in relation to mean annual potential evaporation.
      Rainfall events tend to be infrequent and their occurrence and severity
      are highly variable. Typically dry antecedent conditions may result in
      many rainfall events not producing any significant runoff. However,
      severe rainfall events can still result in significant flooding with
      serious consequences for a range of activities. Large transmission
      losses may also result in discharge reducing in a downstream direction,
      particularly in the lower river reaches of larger catchments in arid
      areas. The special flooding characteristics of catchments in arid areas
      make it desirable to treat them separately from catchments in more humid
      areas. In arid areas, annual maximum flood series generally contain many
      zero values and hence it is more appropriate to use the partial duration
      series in flood frequency analysis, which is adopted here.</para>

      <para>In ARR1987 (I. E. Aust., 1987), only a few catchments were used
      from arid areas to develop RFFE methods. Since the publication of
      ARR1987, there has been little improvement in terms of streamflow data
      availability in most of the arid areas of Australia. In the preparation
      of the regional flood estimation database, only a handful of catchments
      from the arid areas satisfy the selection criteria. To increase the
      number of stations from the arid areas to develop a „reasonably
      meaningful. RFFE method, the selection criteria are relaxed i.e. the
      threshold streamflow record length is reduced to 10 years and the limit
      of catchment size is increased from 1,000 km² to 6,000 km². These
      criteria result in the selection of 55 catchments from the arid areas of
      Australia (Figure 3 and Table 3). The selected catchments have average
      annual rainfall smaller than 500 mm. The catchment areas range from 0.1
      to 5,975 km² (median: 259 km²) and streamflow record lengths range from
      10 to 46 years (median: 27 years).</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_r2u60">
        <title>Locations of the selected catchments from the arid areas of
        Australia (see Figure 2 for the boundary of the two arid
        regions)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure3.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_0x8hz">
        <title>Summary of adopted stations from arid areas of
        Australia</title>

        <tgroup cols="4">
          <colspec/>

          <colspec/>

          <colspec align="center"/>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Location</entry>

              <entry>No. of stations</entry>

              <entry>Streamflow record length (years) (range and
              median)</entry>

              <entry>Catchment size (km<superscript>2</superscript>) (range
              and median)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Pilbara arid area</entry>

              <entry>11</entry>

              <entry>22 – 34 (28)</entry>

              <entry>0.2 – 5975 (303)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>All other arid areas</entry>

              <entry>45</entry>

              <entry>10 – 46 (27)</entry>

              <entry>3 – 997 (209)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>TOTAL</entry>

              <entry>55</entry>

              <entry>10 – 46 (27)</entry>

              <entry>0.1 – 5975 (259)</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_bqt0e">
      <title>Adopted Regions</title>

      <para>The formation of regions in the arid areas in Australia is a
      difficult task, as there are only 55 catchments available from a vast
      area of Australia. There are two alternatives: (i) formation of one
      region with all the 55 stations; and (ii) formation of smaller
      sub-regions based on geographical proximity, noting that too small a
      region makes the developed RFFE technique of little statistical
      significance. Examination of a number of alternative sub-regions led to
      the formation of two regions from the 55 arid catchments: Region 6 (11
      catchments from the Pilbara area of WA) and Region 7 (44 catchments from
      all other arid areas except Pilbara) (see Figure 2 for the extent of
      these two arid regions).</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ri9vz">
      <title>Adopted Estimation Equations</title>

      <para>Application of the ROI and PRT methods for arid regions is deemed
      inappropriate as the ROI method requires a number of gauging stations to
      form sub-regions and the number of gauging stations in the arid areas of
      Australia is insufficient for this purpose. Hence a simpler RFFE method
      is considered more appropriate for the two arid regions. Here, an index
      type approach as suggested by Farquharson et al. (1992) is adopted. The
      10% AEP flood quantile (Q<subscript>10</subscript>) is used as the index
      variable and a dimensionless growth factor for AEP of x%
      (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) is used to estimate
      Q<subscript>x</subscript>:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_xhxx7">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mi>10</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>×</m:mo>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>GF</m:mi>

                <m:mi>x</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>A prediction equation is developed for Q<subscript>10</subscript>
      as a function of catchment characteristics, and regional growth factors
      are developed based on the observed partial duration series flood data.
      In the arid areas, significant storm events do not typically occur every
      year, and some of these events do not produce significant floods. A
      partial duration series analysis with an average occurrence of less than
      one flood event per year is thus considered appropriate. In the
      application, partial series–based Q<subscript>x</subscript> estimates
      can be converted to equivalent annual maximum flood series estimates
      using the Langbein transformation (Langbein, 1949).</para>

      <para>The flood quantiles are estimated for AEPs of 50%, 20%, 10%, 5%,
      2% and 1% at each of the 55 stations based on the abstracted partial
      duration series data (adopting the average number of events per year =
      0.5) by fitting a Generalised Pareto distribution using L moments. The
      Q<subscript>x</subscript>/Q<subscript>10</subscript> values are first
      estimated at individual stations; the weighted average of these values
      (weighting is done based on record length at individual sites) over all
      the stations in a region then defines the growth factors
      (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) for the region.</para>

      <para>The adopted prediction equation for the index variable
      Q<subscript>10</subscript> has the following form:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_6mwfc">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>log₁₀</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>b₀</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>b₁(log₁₀(area))</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>b₂(log₁₀(I₆,₅₀))</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where b<subscript>0</subscript>, b<subscript>1</subscript> and
      b<subscript>2</subscript> are regression coefficients, estimated using
      ordinary least squares regression; area represents catchment area in
      km², and I<subscript>6,50</subscript> is the design rainfall intensity
      (mm/h) at catchment centroid for 6-hour duration and 50% AEP. The values
      of b<subscript>0</subscript>, b<subscript>1</subscript> and
      b<subscript>2</subscript> and the regional growth factors
      (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) are embedded into the REEF Model
      2015.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_m01jo">
    <title>FRINGE ZONES</title>

    <para>The boundaries between the arid and data-rich regions in Figure 2
    are drawn approximately based on the 500 mm mean annual rainfall contour
    line. To reduce the effects of sharp variation in flood estimates for the
    ungauged catchments located close to these regional boundaries, six fringe
    zones are delineated, as shown Figure 2. For these fringe zones, the flood
    estimate at an ungauged catchment location is taken as the inverse
    distance weighted average value of the flood estimates based on the two
    nearest regions. The method is embedded into the ARR RFFE Model
    2015.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_yj49v">
    <title>RELATIVE ACCURACY OF THE RFFE TECHNIQUE</title>

    <para>The reliability and accuracy of the quantile estimates by the RFFE
    technique is assessed using leave-one-out (LOO) validation. In the LOO
    validation, one catchment is left out from the model data set and the RFFE
    technique is applied to the catchment that was left out. The flood
    quantiles estimated using the RFFE technique are then compared with the
    at-site flood frequency estimates obtained by FLIKE (Kuczera, 1999) as
    mentioned in Section 4.1. The procedure is repeated for each catchment in
    the regional data set to provide an overall assessment of the performance
    of the RFFE technique.</para>

    <para>The reliability of the RFFE flood quantile confidence limits
    described in Section 3.4 is assessed empirically using standardised
    quantile residuals. The quantile residual is the difference between the
    logarithm of flood quantile estimates obtained using at-site flood
    frequency analysis and the RFFE technique. The standardised quantile
    residual is the quantile residual divided by its standard deviation which
    is the square root of the sum of the RFFE predictive variance of the flood
    quantile and at-site quantile variance (Haddad and Rahman, 2012; Micevski
    <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2014). This accounts for both the model error
    (e.g. inadequacy of the RFFE model) and the sampling error (e.g. due to
    limited streamflow record length). If the uncertainty in the log quantile
    estimates has been adequately described, the standardized quantile
    residuals should be consistent with a standard normal distribution.</para>

    <para>Figure 4 shows the plots of standardised residuals vs. normal scores
    for Region 1 for AEPs of 10% and 5% (the plots for other AEPs for Region 1
    are provided in Appendix B). Plots for other regions can be seen also in
    Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>. (2014b). These plots include 558
    catchments from Region 1 used in the RFFE model and some 28 catchments
    which were excluded from the RFFE model based on the results of
    preliminary analysis and unusual characteristics such as significant
    natural floodplain storage. Figure 4 reveals that most of the 558
    catchments closely follow a 1:1 straight line indicating that the
    assumption of normality of the residuals is not inconsistent with the
    evidence; this is supported by the application of the Anderson-Darling and
    Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests which show that the assumption of the normality
    of the residuals cannot be rejected at the 10% level of significance.
    Under the assumptions of normality, approximately 90% of the standardised
    quantile residuals should lie between ± 2, which is largely satisfied.
    There are a few catchments with standardised residual values close to ± 3.
    These correspond to instances where the RFFE confidence limits may not be
    reliable; an example of such catchment is provided in Section 12.3. Same
    conclusion applies to the other data-rich regions.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_6ppin">
      <title>Standardised residuals vs. normal scores for Region 1 based on
      leave-one-out validation for AEPs of 10% and 5%</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure4.PNG"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_2kbsr">
      <title>Details of RFFE technique for arid regions</title>

      <tgroup cols="4">
        <colspec/>

        <colspec/>

        <colspec align="center"/>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Region</entry>

            <entry>Method to form region</entry>

            <entry>Number of stations</entry>

            <entry>Estimation model</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Region 6: Pilbara arid area</entry>

            <entry>Fixed region</entry>

            <entry>11</entry>

            <entry>Index flood method with Q10 as index (partial duration
            series model with average number of events per year = 0.5)</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Region 7: All other arid areas</entry>

            <entry/>

            <entry>44</entry>

            <entry/>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <para>The main conclusion from this analysis is that the quantification of
    uncertainty in the quantile estimates by the RFFE technique is reliable
    for the vast majority of the cases. Figure 4 and Section 12.3 serve as a
    reminder that some catchments may not be adequately represented by the
    catchments used in the RFFE analysis. Users of the RFFE Model 2015 should
    check that the catchment of interest is not atypical compared with the
    gauged catchments included in the ROI used to develop the RFFE estimate.
    To assist users in this regard the RFFE Model 2015 discussed in Sections
    11 and 12 lists the RFFE Model gauged catchments located nearest to the
    ungauged catchment of interest. The accuracy of the flood quantile
    estimates provided by the RFFE technique is evaluated by using the
    relative error (RE) defined as:</para>

    <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_tq1ze">
      <m:math display="block">
        <m:mrow>
          <m:mi>RE(%)</m:mi>

          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

          <m:mrow>
            <m:mfrac>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>RFFE</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>FFA</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mi>FFA</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mfrac>

            <m:mo>×</m:mo>

            <m:mi>100</m:mi>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:mrow>
      </m:math>
    </equation>

    <para>where Q<subscript>RFFE</subscript> is the flood quantile estimate
    for a given site for a given AEP by the RFFE technique; and
    Q<subscript>FFA</subscript> is the flood quantile estimate from the
    at-site flood frequency analysis.</para>

    <para>It should be noted that the relative error given by equation 13
    makes no allowance for the fact that the at-site flood frequency estimates
    are themselves subject to sampling error. Therefore, this error should be
    seen as an upper bound on the true relative error.</para>

    <para>It should be noted here that LOO is a more rigorous validation
    technique compared with the split-sample validation where the model is
    tested on a smaller number of catchments (e.g. 10% of the total
    catchments). Hence, the relative error that is generated by LOO is
    expected to be higher than if split-sample validation were used. The
    medians of the absolute relative error values from the LOO validation for
    different regions are reported in Table 5. It can be seen that for the
    data rich regions, Region 5 (SW Western Australia) has the highest
    relative error (59 to 69%) and Region 3 (SA) has the smallest relative
    error (33 to 41%).</para>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_i5krg">
      <title>Screen shot of RFFE Model 2015 (landing page)</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure5.PNG"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_zm9sj">
        <title>Upper bound on (absolute) median relative error (RE) from
        leave-one-out validation of the REEF technique</title>

        <tgroup cols="7">
          <colspec align="center"/>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Region</entry>

              <entry/>

              <entry/>

              <entry>Median RE (%)</entry>

              <entry/>

              <entry/>

              <entry/>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry/>

              <entry/>

              <entry/>

              <entry>AEP</entry>

              <entry/>

              <entry/>

              <entry/>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry/>

              <entry>50%</entry>

              <entry>20%</entry>

              <entry>10%</entry>

              <entry>5%</entry>

              <entry>2%</entry>

              <entry>1%</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 1: VIC + NSW + ACT + QLD</entry>

              <entry>51</entry>

              <entry>49</entry>

              <entry>52</entry>

              <entry>53</entry>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <entry>59</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 2: Tasmania</entry>

              <entry>53</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>45</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 3: South Australia</entry>

              <entry>38</entry>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <entry>33</entry>

              <entry>35</entry>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <entry>41</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 4: NT + Kimberley WA</entry>

              <entry>33</entry>

              <entry>36</entry>

              <entry>36</entry>

              <entry>38</entry>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <entry>47</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 5: SW Western Australia</entry>

              <entry>61</entry>

              <entry>59</entry>

              <entry>66</entry>

              <entry>68</entry>

              <entry>68</entry>

              <entry>69</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 6: Pilbara arid area</entry>

              <entry>35</entry>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <entry>35</entry>

              <entry>42</entry>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <entry>43</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 7: All other arid areas</entry>

              <entry>63</entry>

              <entry>67</entry>

              <entry>67</entry>

              <entry>61</entry>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <entry>49</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_5x575">
    <title>COMBINING REGIONAL AND AT-SITE QUANTILE ESTIMATES</title>

    <para>Unless a station has a very long annual maximum flood series data
    (e.g. greater than 100 years), it is desirable to combine at-site and
    regional flood frequency quantile estimates to achieve a more accurate
    estimate. The RFFE Model 2015 (see Section 11 for the description of the
    model) provides the necessary parameter set and data in its output to
    combine the regional flood quantile estimates with the at-site data. This
    is discussed in more detail in Book 3,Chapter 2 of ARR.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_31eib">
    <title>IMPACT OF CLIMATE CHANGE</title>

    <para>The adopted regional estimation equations include design rainfall
    intensity as a key input variable. As a result the impact of climate
    change as reflected in changes in design rainfall estimates (which are
    expected to be upgraded regularly) can be propagated through the RFFE
    Model 2015 to provide a first order estimate of the impact of climate
    change on regional design flood estimates. This approach assumes that that
    the contribution of the other catchment characteristics affecting flood
    production does not change with future climate states. Given that this
    assumption is unlikely to be valid (Ball, 2014), the use of potential
    future rainfall intensities in the RFFE Model 2015 illustrates the
    sensitivity of the current design flood estimates to the rainfall
    intensities.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8airu">
    <title>PRACTICAL CONSIDERATIONS FOR APPLICATION OF RFFE TECHNIQUE</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_xq59y">
      <title>Limits of Applicability</title>

      <para>The RFFE Model 2015 is applicable to any catchment that has
      similar attributes and flood producing characteristics as the catchments
      used in the derivation of the flood estimation equations. Catchments
      which do not satisfy this requirement can be divided into three groups:
      (i) catchments which have been substantially modified from their natural
      characteristics and for which the RFFE Model 2015 is not applicable and
      should thus not be used, (ii) catchments for which flood estimates must
      be expected to have lower accuracy than indicated in Section 7; and
      (iii) „atypical catchments where additional catchment attributes need to
      be considered and adjusted for.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_bq1hm">
      <title>Catchments for which the RFFE Model 2015 cannot be
      applied</title>

      <para>These are catchments where some of the catchment characteristics
      have been altered significantly from the natural conditions reflected in
      the set of gauged catchments used in the development of the RFFE
      technique. The following types of catchments fall into this
      group:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>urban catchments (more than 10% of the catchment affected by
          residential or urban development);</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>catchments where the construction of a dam or weir has
          significantly altered the natural rainfall-runoff behaviour;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>catchments where notable land clearing has taken place (e.g.
          some catchments in south-west of Western Australia); and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>catchments which have been significantly affected by
          agricultural activities, construction of drainage or irrigation
          infrastructure, soil conservation works or mining activities.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_qepsb">
      <title>Catchments where RFFE Model 2015 estimates have lower
      accuracy</title>

      <para>The following types of catchments do not strictly satisfy the
      requirements of the RFFE technique, and flood estimates for these
      catchments should thus be treated with caution and be expected to have
      lower accuracy than indicated in Section 7:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Catchments with an area less than 0.5 km² or greater than
          1,000 km², or catchments located further away than 300 km from the
          nearest gauged catchment location used to develop the RFFE
          technique. When the ungauged catchment of interest exceeds these
          limits, the RFFE Model 2015 gives a warning message that the results
          may not be directly applicable in practice.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Catchments in arid areas. The RFFE technique for the arid
          areas is based on a very small number of gauged catchments spanning
          a vast area of Australia. There is also a large variation in
          catchment conditions over the arid areas. It is therefore likely
          that the gauges are not fully representative of the wide range of
          conditions encountered in the arid areas. Gauges are generally
          installed in defined channels which may not be apparent in many arid
          areas. The flood estimates for the arid areas given by the RFFE
          Model 2015 should be used with caution. Users need to compare local
          catchment conditions with those at gauged locations and in many
          cases may need to adjust RFFE Model 2015 estimates to account for
          the local catchment conditions (see Section 10.4).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ft0us">
      <title>Catchments with A typical Characteristics</title>

      <para>The development of the RFFE technique is based on the assumption
      that the catchment characteristics represented in the regression
      equation (e.g. catchment area, design rainfall intensity and shape
      factor) account for the important differences in flood characteristics
      between sites in a region. It should be recognised that flood estimates
      generated by the RFFE Model 2015 for a catchment with flood
      characteristics that are distinctly different from typical gauged
      catchments in the region may not only be associated with larger error
      margins but also significant bias. In such situations hydrological
      judgment must be used to assess if any adjustment of the regional flood
      frequency estimate is required (based on comparison of other relevant
      catchment characteristics). To support such an assessment, the RFFE
      Model 2015 output describes the set of gauged catchments used in
      developing the RFFE Model, which are located closest to the ungauged
      catchment of interest.</para>

      <para>The following additional catchment attributes may need to be
      considered as a basis for adjustments to the flood estimates obtained
      directly from RFFE Model 2015:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Natural flood storage</emphasis> – large flood
          storage areas in catchments with extensive floodplains or swamps
          have the effect of attenuating flood peaks; flood estimates from
          RFFE Model 2015 would thus tend to <emphasis>overestimate</emphasis>
          peak flows and they could be regarded as <emphasis>upper bound flood
          estimates</emphasis> for these catchments. (See example in Section
          12.3.)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Drainage efficiency</emphasis> - steep catchments,
          streams with little vegetation along banks, catchments affected by
          large scale drainage or flood protection works can be expected to
          produce faster flood flows, less attenuation and thus higher peak
          flows; flood estimates from RFFE Model 2015 would thus tend to
          <emphasis>underestimate</emphasis> peak flows and they could be
          regarded as <emphasis>lower bound flood estimates</emphasis> for
          these catchments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>For flood estimation in catchments with atypical catchment
      characteristics it is desirable to examine the flood records of a gauged
      catchment with similar catchment attributes as a basis for adjustments
      to the flood estimates produced by the RFFE Model 2015.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_8n08s">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for data input for the Wollomombi
        River at Coinside, NSW</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure6.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs">
    <title>RFFE MODEL 2015</title>

    <para>The RFFE technique presented in this chapter has been incorporated
    into a software tool referred to as RFFE Model 2015. Figure 5 presents
    screen shot of the software landing page. The model requires the following
    basic inputs (to be entered by the user in the interface shown in Figure
    4) for the catchment of interest to generate design flood estimates for
    six AEPs (50%, 20%, 10%, 5%, 2% and 1%).</para>

    <para>(i) Latitude at catchment centroid in decimal degrees;</para>

    <para>(ii) Longitude at catchment centroid in decimal degrees;</para>

    <para>(iii) Latitude at catchment outlet in decimal degrees;</para>

    <para>(iv) Longitude at catchment outlet in decimal degrees;</para>

    <para>(v) Catchment area in km2; and</para>

    <para>(vi) Catchment name.</para>

    <para>In "Advanced" data input option, the user can also enter the
    following inputs:</para>

    <para>(i) Region name (can be selected from the dropdown list (see Table
    6));<table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_gpkr3">
        <title>Region names for application of the RFFE Model 2015 (see Figure
        2 for the extent of the regions)</title>

        <tgroup cols="2">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry align="center">Region name</entry>

              <entry align="center">Region code</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>VIC + NSW + ACT + QLD</entry>

              <entry>1</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Tasmania</entry>

              <entry>2</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>South Australia</entry>

              <entry>3</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>NT + Kimberley WA</entry>

              <entry>4</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>SW Western Australia</entry>

              <entry>5</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Pilbara arid area</entry>

              <entry>6</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>All other arid areas</entry>

              <entry>7</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table></para>

    <para>(ii) Design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid for AEP of 50%
    and duration of 6-hour in mm/h; and</para>

    <para>(iii) Design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid for AEP of 2%
    and duration of 6-hour in mm/h.</para>

    <para>RFFE Model 2015 output contains the following principal information
    (see Figure 7):</para>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_0hl0m">
      <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for model output for the Wollomombi
      River at Coinside, NSW</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure7.PNG"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>(i) A table that shows AEP in the first column, estimated flood
    quantiles labelled as “Flow (m3/s)” in the second column, lower confidence
    limit (5%) in the third column and upper confidence limit (95%) in the
    fourth column. The confidence limits represent the overall uncertainty
    with the estimated flood quantiles by the RFFE Model 2015.</para>

    <para>(ii) A second table that shows the statistics for the regional LP3
    model at the catchment of interest, which are particularly useful to
    combine at-site and regional information to enhance the accuracy of flood
    quantile estimates (for details see Kuczera and Franks, 2015).</para>

    <para>(iii) A graph that shows estimated flood quantiles and confidence
    limits against AEPs.</para>

    <para>(iv) A picture that shows the catchment of interest with outlet and
    centroid locations.</para>

    <para>(v) A list that shows various input data used by the model to
    produce flood estimates.</para>

    <para>(vi) A text output menu and a download menu that allow the user to
    save the results generated by the model.</para>

    <para>Three worked examples are provided in Section 12 to illustrate the
    use of RFFE Model 2015. First two examples relate to catchments having no
    major regulation, no major natural or artificial storage and no major land
    use change where the RFFE Model 2015 is directly applicable.</para>

    <para>The third example relates to a catchment which has significant
    natural floodplain storage where RFFE Model 2015 is not directly
    applicable. For this case, RFFE Model significantly overestimates the
    flood quantiles (as compared to at-site flood frequency analysis). Here,
    the RFFE Model estimates need to be adjusted to account for the storage
    effect of the catchment by applying an appropriate technique (see Section
    10.4 for further details).</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ue0ar">
    <title>WORKED EXAMPLES</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_05i4o">
      <title>Application of RFFE Model 2015 to the Wollomombi River at
      Coinside, NSW (Region 1) (a catchment having no major regulation, no
      major natural or artificial storage and no major land use
      change)</title>

      <para>The basic input data for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW are
      provided in Table 7. The model screen shot for the data input is
      provided in Figure 6. The flood quantiles generated by the RFFE Model
      2015 are provided in Figure 7. Figure 8 compares the RFFE Model and
      at-site FFA flood estimates, which shows that RFFE Model estimates match
      the at-site FFA estimates quite well except for 2% and 1% AEPs where the
      RFFE Model estimates are higher compared with the at-site FFA estimates.
      Figure 8 also shows that the confidence band by the RFFE Model 2015 is
      much wider compared with at-site FFA confidence band, which is as
      expected.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_mb7b8">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs. at-site FFA flood estimates for the
        Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure8.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_rdr78">
        <title>Application data for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW
        (Region 1) (Basic Input Data)</title>

        <tgroup cols="2">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry align="center">Menu</entry>

              <entry align="center">Input</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Latitude (Catchment Centroid) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-30.352</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Longitude (Catchment Centroid) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>151.936</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Latitude (Catchment Outlet) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-30.478</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Longitude (Catchment Outlet) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>152.026</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Area in sq km</entry>

              <entry>376</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Name</entry>

              <entry>Wollomombi River at Coinside</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>

      <para>Table 8 presents the list of 30 gauged catchments (used in
      developing the RFFE Model) that are located closest to the Wollomombi
      River at Coinside, NSW. The user should compare the characteristics of
      the ungauged catchment of interest with those of the nearest gauged
      catchments to ensure that the ungauged catchment is not atypical of the
      nearest gauged catchments used in developing the RFFE Model 2015.</para>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_3dowt">
        <title>30 gauged catchments (used in the development of RFFE Model
        2015) located closest to Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW</title>

        <tgroup cols="12">
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Distance (km)</entry>

              <entry>Site ID</entry>

              <entry>Latitude (outlet)</entry>

              <entry>Longitude (outlet)</entry>

              <entry>Catchment Area km<superscript>2</superscript></entry>

              <entry>Flow Record Length (years)</entry>

              <entry>6 hour 50% AEP Intensity (mm/h)</entry>

              <entry>6 hour 2% AEP Intensity (mm/h)</entry>

              <entry>Mean Annual Rainfall (mm)</entry>

              <entry>12 hour 50% AEP Intensity (mm/h)</entry>

              <entry>Shape Factor</entry>

              <entry>
                <inlineequation>
                  <m:math display="inline">
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mi>6 hour 50% AEP Intensity (mm/h)</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>6 hour 2% AEP Intensity (mm/h)</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>
                  </m:math>
                </inlineequation>
              </entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>0</entry>

              <entry>206014</entry>

              <entry>30.478</entry>

              <entry>152.027</entry>

              <entry>376</entry>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <entry>6.917</entry>

              <entry>15.917</entry>

              <entry>871</entry>

              <entry>4.24</entry>

              <entry>0.88</entry>

              <entry>2.3</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>18</entry>

              <entry>206001</entry>

              <entry>30.59</entry>

              <entry>152.162</entry>

              <entry>163</entry>

              <entry>33</entry>

              <entry>9.083</entry>

              <entry>22.55</entry>

              <entry>1167</entry>

              <entry>6.26</entry>

              <entry>1.08</entry>

              <entry>2.48</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>24.3</entry>

              <entry>204030</entry>

              <entry>30.26</entry>

              <entry>152.01</entry>

              <entry>200</entry>

              <entry>34</entry>

              <entry>7.133</entry>

              <entry>15.05</entry>

              <entry>939.64</entry>

              <entry>4.44</entry>

              <entry>1.39</entry>

              <entry>2.11</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>28</entry>

              <entry>206017</entry>

              <entry>30.478</entry>

              <entry>152.318</entry>

              <entry>22</entry>

              <entry>24</entry>

              <entry>10.217</entry>

              <entry>25.6</entry>

              <entry>1167</entry>

              <entry>7.21</entry>

              <entry>0.8</entry>

              <entry>2.51</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>31.6</entry>

              <entry>204008</entry>

              <entry>30.405</entry>

              <entry>152.345</entry>

              <entry>31</entry>

              <entry>29</entry>

              <entry>10.15</entry>

              <entry>25.5</entry>

              <entry>1249</entry>

              <entry>7</entry>

              <entry>0.68</entry>

              <entry>2.51</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>35.7</entry>

              <entry>206026</entry>

              <entry>30.42</entry>

              <entry>151.66</entry>

              <entry>8</entry>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <entry>6.917</entry>

              <entry>14.6</entry>

              <entry>789.35</entry>

              <entry>4.23</entry>

              <entry>0.73</entry>

              <entry>2.11</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>37.7</entry>

              <entry>206025</entry>

              <entry>30.68</entry>

              <entry>151.71</entry>

              <entry>594</entry>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <entry>6.667</entry>

              <entry>14.183</entry>

              <entry>944.63</entry>

              <entry>4.12</entry>

              <entry>0.62</entry>

              <entry>2.13</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>39.3</entry>

              <entry>206034</entry>

              <entry>30.7</entry>

              <entry>151.707</entry>

              <entry>117</entry>

              <entry>26</entry>

              <entry>6.617</entry>

              <entry>14.05</entry>

              <entry>758</entry>

              <entry>4.11</entry>

              <entry>0.89</entry>

              <entry>2.12</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>42</entry>

              <entry>418034</entry>

              <entry>30.3</entry>

              <entry>151.64</entry>

              <entry>14</entry>

              <entry>29</entry>

              <entry>6.933</entry>

              <entry>14.317</entry>

              <entry>818.48</entry>

              <entry>4.29</entry>

              <entry>0.79</entry>

              <entry>2.07</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>63.8</entry>

              <entry>418014</entry>

              <entry>30.47</entry>

              <entry>151.36</entry>

              <entry>855</entry>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <entry>6.6</entry>

              <entry>13.867</entry>

              <entry>725.43</entry>

              <entry>4.01</entry>

              <entry>0.42</entry>

              <entry>2.1</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>68.4</entry>

              <entry>206018</entry>

              <entry>31.052</entry>

              <entry>151.768</entry>

              <entry>894</entry>

              <entry>51</entry>

              <entry>6.683</entry>

              <entry>13.633</entry>

              <entry>711</entry>

              <entry>4.12</entry>

              <entry>0.48</entry>

              <entry>2.04</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>68.6</entry>

              <entry>204017</entry>

              <entry>30.307</entry>

              <entry>152.713</entry>

              <entry>82</entry>

              <entry>40</entry>

              <entry>13.633</entry>

              <entry>34.15</entry>

              <entry>1995</entry>

              <entry>10.07</entry>

              <entry>0.61</entry>

              <entry>2.51</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>72.3</entry>

              <entry>204037</entry>

              <entry>30.09</entry>

              <entry>152.63</entry>

              <entry>62</entry>

              <entry>40</entry>

              <entry>10</entry>

              <entry>24.75</entry>

              <entry>1586.24</entry>

              <entry>6.93</entry>

              <entry>0.73</entry>

              <entry>2.47</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>72.5</entry>

              <entry>205002</entry>

              <entry>30.427</entry>

              <entry>152.78</entry>

              <entry>433</entry>

              <entry>29</entry>

              <entry>11.333</entry>

              <entry>28.35</entry>

              <entry>1570</entry>

              <entry>8.16</entry>

              <entry>1.03</entry>

              <entry>2.5</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>81.4</entry>

              <entry>206009</entry>

              <entry>31.19</entry>

              <entry>151.83</entry>

              <entry>261</entry>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <entry>6.7</entry>

              <entry>13.433</entry>

              <entry>910.37</entry>

              <entry>4.26</entry>

              <entry>0.66</entry>

              <entry>2.01</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>81.4</entry>

              <entry>205006</entry>

              <entry>30.642</entry>

              <entry>152.855</entry>

              <entry>539</entry>

              <entry>35</entry>

              <entry>11.5</entry>

              <entry>28.733</entry>

              <entry>1353</entry>

              <entry>8.03</entry>

              <entry>0.56</entry>

              <entry>2.5</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>81.5</entry>

              <entry>204034</entry>

              <entry>29.763</entry>

              <entry>152.212</entry>

              <entry>389</entry>

              <entry>40</entry>

              <entry>7.383</entry>

              <entry>15.95</entry>

              <entry>914</entry>

              <entry>4.57</entry>

              <entry>1.03</entry>

              <entry>2.16</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>82.5</entry>

              <entry>205014</entry>

              <entry>30.388</entry>

              <entry>152.88</entry>

              <entry>51</entry>

              <entry>24</entry>

              <entry>13.55</entry>

              <entry>34.5</entry>

              <entry>2151</entry>

              <entry>10</entry>

              <entry>0.68</entry>

              <entry>2.55</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>83</entry>

              <entry>204026</entry>

              <entry>30.25</entry>

              <entry>152.85</entry>

              <entry>80</entry>

              <entry>29</entry>

              <entry>12.783</entry>

              <entry>31.633</entry>

              <entry>1894.35</entry>

              <entry>9.39</entry>

              <entry>0.45</entry>

              <entry>2.47</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>84.7</entry>

              <entry>419010</entry>

              <entry>30.97</entry>

              <entry>151.35</entry>

              <entry>829</entry>

              <entry>32</entry>

              <entry>6.95</entry>

              <entry>13.933</entry>

              <entry>773.13</entry>

              <entry>4.33</entry>

              <entry>0.98</entry>

              <entry>2.01</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>84.8</entry>

              <entry>418021</entry>

              <entry>30.23</entry>

              <entry>151.19</entry>

              <entry>311</entry>

              <entry>34</entry>

              <entry>6.75</entry>

              <entry>13.533</entry>

              <entry>785.73</entry>

              <entry>4.09</entry>

              <entry>1.63</entry>

              <entry>2.01</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>85.8</entry>

              <entry>204031</entry>

              <entry>29.722</entry>

              <entry>151.845</entry>

              <entry>348</entry>

              <entry>20</entry>

              <entry>7.25</entry>

              <entry>14.683</entry>

              <entry>990</entry>

              <entry>4.49</entry>

              <entry>1.27</entry>

              <entry>2.03</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>99.3</entry>

              <entry>204025</entry>

              <entry>30.26</entry>

              <entry>153.03</entry>

              <entry>135</entry>

              <entry>42</entry>

              <entry>14.35</entry>

              <entry>38.267</entry>

              <entry>1711.05</entry>

              <entry>10.41</entry>

              <entry>0.59</entry>

              <entry>2.67</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>101.6</entry>

              <entry>207015</entry>

              <entry>31.372</entry>

              <entry>152.245</entry>

              <entry>342</entry>

              <entry>27</entry>

              <entry>7.933</entry>

              <entry>16.533</entry>

              <entry>1678</entry>

              <entry>5.49</entry>

              <entry>0.76</entry>

              <entry>2.08</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>102.9</entry>

              <entry>419054</entry>

              <entry>31.04</entry>

              <entry>151.17</entry>

              <entry>391</entry>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <entry>6.833</entry>

              <entry>13.517</entry>

              <entry>780.1</entry>

              <entry>4.24</entry>

              <entry>0.96</entry>

              <entry>1.98</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>105.5</entry>

              <entry>207006</entry>

              <entry>31.39</entry>

              <entry>152.33</entry>

              <entry>363</entry>

              <entry>36</entry>

              <entry>10.367</entry>

              <entry>23.05</entry>

              <entry>1558.49</entry>

              <entry>7.09</entry>

              <entry>0.8</entry>

              <entry>2.22</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>107.3</entry>

              <entry>419016</entry>

              <entry>31.06</entry>

              <entry>151.13</entry>

              <entry>907</entry>

              <entry>34</entry>

              <entry>6.633</entry>

              <entry>13.15</entry>

              <entry>794.19</entry>

              <entry>4.08</entry>

              <entry>0.56</entry>

              <entry>1.98</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>107.7</entry>

              <entry>418005</entry>

              <entry>29.92</entry>

              <entry>151.11</entry>

              <entry>259</entry>

              <entry>40</entry>

              <entry>7.9</entry>

              <entry>15.983</entry>

              <entry>876.43</entry>

              <entry>4.87</entry>

              <entry>0.93</entry>

              <entry>2.02</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>115.2</entry>

              <entry>416016</entry>

              <entry>29.79</entry>

              <entry>151.13</entry>

              <entry>726</entry>

              <entry>40</entry>

              <entry>8.183</entry>

              <entry>16.6</entry>

              <entry>788.21</entry>

              <entry>4.93</entry>

              <entry>0.9</entry>

              <entry>2.03</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>116.3</entry>

              <entry>205007</entry>

              <entry>30.118</entry>

              <entry>153.163</entry>

              <entry>11</entry>

              <entry>22</entry>

              <entry>12.533</entry>

              <entry>33.967</entry>

              <entry>1577</entry>

              <entry>8.07</entry>

              <entry>0.79</entry>

              <entry>2.71</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ydu7q">
      <title>Application for the Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western
      Australia (Region 5) (a catchment having no major regulation, no major
      natural or artificial storage and no major land use change)</title>

      <para>The basic input data for the Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW
      Western Australia are provided in Table 9. The model screen shot for the
      data input is provided in Figure 9. The flood quantiles generated by the
      RFFE Model 2015 are provided in Figure 10. Figure 11 compares the RFFE
      Model and at-site FFA flood estimates which shows that RFFE Model
      estimates match the at-site FFA estimates quite well for all the six
      AEPs. Figure 11 also shows that the confidence band by the RFFE Model
      2015 is much wider compared with at-site FFA confidence band, which is
      as expected.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_yklir">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for data input for Four Mile Brook
        at Netic Rd, SW Western Australia</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure9.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>
        <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_5qduj">
          <title>Application data for Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western
          Australia (Region 5) (Basic Input Data)</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry align="center">Menu</entry>

                <entry align="center">Input</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Latitude (Catchment Centroid) in decimal
                degrees</entry>

                <entry>-34.318</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Longitude (Catchment Centroid) in decimal
                degrees</entry>

                <entry>116.021</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Latitude (Catchment Outlet) in decimal degrees</entry>

                <entry>-34.30</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Longitude (Catchment Outlet) in decimal degrees</entry>

                <entry>116.00</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Catchment Area in sq km</entry>

                <entry>13.1</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Catchment Name</entry>

                <entry>Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_9yh35">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for model output for Four Mile
        Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western Australia</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure10.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_afke3">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs. at-site FFA flood estimates for Four Mile
        Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western Australia</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure11.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_p4hvx">
      <title>Application for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region 1) (a
      catchment having significant natural floodplain storage where RFFE Model
      2015 output is not directly applicable)</title>

      <para>The basic input data for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC are
      provided in Table 10. The model screen shot for the data input is
      provided in Figure 12. The flood quantiles generated by the RFFE Model
      2015 are provided in Figure 13. Figure 14 compares the RFFE Model and
      at-site FFA flood estimates, which shows that RFFE Model estimates are
      much higher compared with at-site FFA estimates. This catchment has
      significant natural floodplain storage which is not typical for other
      catchments in the Region of Influence (ROI) on which the RFFE Model 2015
      estimates are based. The RFFE Model 2015 estimates are thus not directly
      applicable. Here, the RFFE Model estimates would need to be adjusted
      downwards to account for the floodplain storage effect by applying an
      appropriate technique.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_79qkw">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for data input for the Morass Creek
        at Uplands, VIC</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure12.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_w08tl">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for model output for the Morass
        Creek at Uplands, VIC</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure13.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_4v50p">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs. at-site FFA flood estimates (for the Morass
        Creek at Uplands, VIC)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="Figures/Figure14.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_z9vfi">
        <title>Application data for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region
        1) (Basic Input Data)</title>

        <tgroup cols="2">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry align="center">Menu</entry>

              <entry align="center">Input</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Latitude (Catchment Centroid) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-36.876</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Longitude (Catchment Centroid) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>147.840</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Latitude (Catchment Outlet) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-36.87</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Longitude (Catchment Outlet) in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>147.7</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Area in sq km</entry>

              <entry>471</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Name</entry>

              <entry>Morass Creek at Uplands</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8c69c">
    <title>REFERENCES</title>

    <para>Adams CA (1984), “Regional flood estimation for ungauged rural
    catchments in Victoria”, MEngSc Thesis, The University of
    Melbourne.</para>

    <para>Ball JE (2014), “Flood estimation under climate change”,
    <emphasis>19th IAHR-APD Congress</emphasis>, Hanoi, Vietnam.</para>

    <para>Bates BC (1994), <emphasis>“Regionalisation of hydrological data: A
    review”</emphasis>, Report 94/5, CRC for Catchment Hydrology, Monash
    University.</para>

    <para>Bates BC, Rahman A, Mein RG and Weinmann PE (1998), Climatic and
    physical factors that influence the homogeneity of regional floods in
    south-eastern Australia, <emphasis>Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
    34(12), 3369-3382.</para>

    <para>Burn DH (1990a), An appraisal of the region of influence approach to
    flood frequency analysis, <emphasis>Hydrological Sciences
    Journal</emphasis>, 35, 2, 149-165.</para>

    <para>Burn DH (1990b), Evaluation of regional flood frequency analysis
    with a region of influence approach, <emphasis>Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, 26, 10, 2257-2265.</para>

    <para>Cohn TA, England JF, Berenbrock CE, Mason RR, Stedinger JR and
    Lamontagne JR (2013), A generalized Grubbs-Beck test statistic for
    detecting multiple potentially influential low outliers in flood series,
    <emphasis>Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 49, 5047–5058.</para>

    <para>French R (2002), “Flaws in the rational method”,<emphasis> Proc.
    27th National Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>.,
    Melbourne.</para>

    <para>Farquharson FAK, Meigh JR and Sutcliffe JV (1992), Regional flood
    frequency analysis in arid and semi-arid areas, <emphasis>Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, 138, 487-501.</para>

    <para>Griffis VW and Stedinger JR (2007), The use of GLS regression in
    regional hydrologic analyses, <emphasis>Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>,
    344, 82-95.</para>

    <para>Hackelbusch A, Micevski T, Kuczera G, Rahman A and Haddad K (2009),
    “Regional flood frequency analysis for eastern New South Wales: a region
    of influence approach using generalised least squares based parameter
    regression”, <emphasis>Proc. 31st Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symp</emphasis>., Newcastle, 603-615.</para>

    <para>Haddad K (2008), <emphasis>“Design flood estimation in ungauged
    catchments using a quantile regression technique: ordinary and generalised
    least squares methods compared for Victoria”</emphasis>, Masters (Honours)
    thesis, School of Engineering, University of Western Sydney, New South
    Wales.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A and Weinmann PE (2008), “Development of a
    generalised least squares based quantile regression technique for design
    flood estimation in Victoria”, <emphasis>Proc. 31st Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symp</emphasis>., Adelaide, 2546-2557.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Pirozzi J, McPherson G, Rahman A and Kuczera G (2009),
    “Regional flood estimation technique for NSW: application of generalised
    least squares quantile regression technique”,<emphasis> Proc. 32nd
    Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., Newcastle, 829-840.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A, Weinmann PE, Kuczera G and Ball JE (2010),
    Streamflow data preparation for regional flood frequency analysis: Lessons
    from south-east Australia, <emphasis>Australian Journal of Water
    Resources</emphasis>, 14, 1, 17-32.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A and Kuczera G (2011), Comparison of ordinary and
    generalised least squares regression models in regional flood frequency
    analysis: A case study for New South Wales, <emphasis>Australian Journal
    of Water Resources</emphasis>, 15, 2, 59-70.</para>

    <para>Haddad K and Rahman A (2012), Regional flood frequency analysis in
    eastern Australia: Bayesian GLS regression-based methods within fixed
    region and ROI framework – quantile regression vs. parameter regression
    technique,<emphasis> Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, 430-431,
    142-161.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A and Stedinger JR (2012), Regional flood frequency
    analysis using Bayesian generalised least squares: A comparison between
    quantile and parameter regression techniques, <emphasis>Hydrological
    Processes</emphasis>, 26, 1008-1021.</para>

    <para>Hosking JRM and Wallis JR (1993), Some statistics useful in regional
    frequency analysis, <emphasis>Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 29(2),
    271-281.</para>

    <para>Institution of Engineers Australia (I. E. Aust.) (1987, 2001),
    <emphasis>“Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A Guide to Flood
    Estimation”</emphasis>. Editor: D.H. Pilgrim, Vol. 1, I. E. Aust.,
    Canberra.</para>

    <para>Ishak E, Rahman A, Westra S, Sharma A and Kuczera G (2013),
    Evaluating the non-stationarity of Australian annual maximum floods,
    <emphasis>Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, 494, 134-145.</para>

    <para>Kuczera G (1999), Comprehensive at-site flood frequency analysis
    using Monte Carlo Bayesian inference. <emphasis>Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, 35, 5, 1551-1557.</para>

    <para>Kuczera G and Franks S (2015). <emphasis>“At-site flood frequency
    analysis”</emphasis>. In Australian Rainfall and Runoff, 4th edition.
    Editor: J. Ball, I. E. Aust., Canberra.</para>

    <para>Langbein WB (1949), Annual floods and the partial duration flood
    series. <emphasis>Trans. American Geophysical Union</emphasis>, 30,
    879-881.</para>

    <para>Lamontagne JR, Stedinger JR, Cohn TA and Barth NA (2013), “Robust
    national flood frequency guidelines: What is an outlier?”,<emphasis> Proc.
    World Environmental and Water Resources Congress</emphasis>, ASCE,
    2454-2466.</para>

    <para>Madsen H, Pearson CP and Rosbjerg D (1997), Comparison of annual
    maximum series and partial duration series for modelling extreme
    hydrologic events, 2. Regional modelling, <emphasis>Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, 33, 4, 759-769.</para>

    <para>Micevski T and Kuczera G (2009), Combining site and regional flood
    information using a Bayesian Monte Carlo approach, <emphasis>Water
    Resources Research</emphasis>, 45, W04405,
    doi:10.1029/2008WR007173.</para>

    <para>Micevski T, Hackelbusch A, Haddad K. Kuczera G and Rahman A (2014),
    Regionalisation of the parameters of the log-Pearson 3 distribution: a
    case study for New South Wales, Australia, <emphasis>Hydrological
    Processes</emphasis>, DOI: 10.1002/hyp.10147.</para>

    <para>Mittelstadt GE, McDermott GE and Pilgrim DH (1987), Revised flood
    data and catchment characteristics for small to medium sized catchments in
    New South Wales. University of New South Wales, Department of Water
    Engineering, unpublished report.</para>

    <para>Palmen, LB and Weeks WD (2009), “Regional flood frequency for
    Queensland using the Quantile Regression Technique”,<emphasis> Proc. 32nd
    Hydrology and Water Resources Symp., Newcastle</emphasis>.</para>

    <para>Palmen LB and Weeks WD (2011), Regional flood frequency for
    Queensland using the quantile regression technique, <emphasis>Australian
    Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>, 15, 1, 47-57.</para>

    <para>Pegram G (2002), “Rainfall, rational formula and regional maximum
    flood – some scaling links”, <emphasis>Proc. 27th Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symp., Melbourne.</emphasis></para>

    <para>Pilgrim DH and McDermott G (1982), Design floods for small rural
    catchments in eastern New South Wales, <emphasis>Civil Engineering
    Transactions</emphasis>, I. E. Aust., CE24, 226-234.</para>

    <para>Pirozzi J, Ashraf M, Rahman A, and Haddad K (2009), “Design flood
    estimation for ungauged catchments in eastern NSW: evaluation of the
    Probabilistic Rational Method”, <emphasis>Proc. 32nd Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symp</emphasis>., Newcastle, 805-816.</para>

    <para>Rahman A (1997), <emphasis>“Flood estimation for ungauged
    catchments: a regional approach using flood and catchment
    characteristics”</emphasis>, PhD thesis, Department of Civil Engineering,
    Monash University.</para>

    <para>Rahman A (2005), A quantile regression technique to estimate design
    floods for ungauged catchments in south-east Australia,
    <emphasis>Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>, 9(1),
    81-89.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Bates BC, Mein RG and Weinmann PE (1999), Regional flood
    frequency analysis for ungauged basins in south – eastern Australia,
    <emphasis>Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>, 3(2),
    199-207.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Rima K and Weeks WD (2008), “Development of regional flood
    estimation methods using Quantile Regression Technique: a case study for
    north-eastern part of Queensland”, <emphasis>Proc. 31st Hydrology and
    Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., Adelaide, 329-340.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2009),
    <emphasis>“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5
    Regional Flood Methods, Stage 1 Report”</emphasis>, No. P5/S1/003, Nov
    2009, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering, 181pp.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Zaman M, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2011a),
    Design flood estimation in ungauged catchments: a comparison between the
    Probabilistic Rational Method and Quantile Regression Technique for NSW,
    <emphasis>Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>, 14, 2,
    127-139.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Zaman M, Fotos M, Haddad K, Rajaratnam L and Weeks WD
    (2011b), “Towards a new regional flood estimation method for the Northern
    Territory”, <emphasis>Proc. 34th IAHR World Congress</emphasis>, Brisbane,
    364-371.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Zaman M, Ishak E, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE
    (2012), <emphasis>“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects,
    Project 5 Regional flood methods, Stage 2 Report”</emphasis>, No.
    P5/S2/015, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering, 319pp.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Rahman AS, Haque MM (2014a),
    <emphasis>“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5
    Regional flood methods, Database used to develop ARR REEF Model
    2015”</emphasis>, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Haque M, Kuczera G, Weinmann PE (2014b),
    <emphasis>“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5
    Regional flood methods, Stage 3 Report”</emphasis>, Engineers Australia,
    Water Engineering.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Kuczera G, Weinmann PE, Weeks WD, Stensmyr P and
    Babister M (2014c), “An overview of the development of the new regional
    flood frequency estimation (RFFE) model for Australia”, <emphasis>35th
    Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., Engineers Australia,
    Perth.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Rahman AS, Haque MM, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE
    (2014d), “An overview of preparation of streamflow database for ARR
    Project 5 Regional Flood Method”, <emphasis>35th Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symp</emphasis>., Engineers Australia, Perth.</para>

    <para>Sivapalan M, Blöschl G and Wagener T (2013),<emphasis> “Runoff
    Prediction in Ungauged Basins: Synthesis across Processes, Places and
    Scales”</emphasis>, Cambridge University Press.</para>

    <para>Stedinger JR and Tasker GD (1985), Regional hydrologic analysis 1
    Ordinary, weighted, and generalised least squares compared,
    <emphasis>Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 21, 9, 1421-1432.</para>

    <para>Tasker GD and Stedinger JR (1989), An operational GLS model for
    hydrologic regression, <emphasis>Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, 111
    (1-4), 361-375.</para>

    <para>Zrinji Z and Burn DH (1994), Flood frequency analysis for ungauged
    sites using a region of influence approach. <emphasis>Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, 153, 1–21.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>

