<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" version="5.0" xml:id="b3_ch3"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Regional Flood Methods</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/rahman_ataur.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/haddad_khaled.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_0g2kk">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Estimation of peak flows on small to medium sized rural catchments
    is required for the design of culverts, small to medium sized bridges,
    causeways, soil conservation works and for various planning and regulatory
    purposes. Typically, <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T091614+1100" content="many"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T091615+1100"?>most
    design flood estimates for projects on<?oxy_insert_end ?> small to medium
    sized catchments<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T092033+1100"?>
    are on catchments that<?oxy_insert_end ?> are ungauged or have little
    recorded streamflow data. In these cases, peak flow estimates can be
    obtained using a Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) approach,
    which transfers flood frequency characteristics from a group of gauged
    catchments to the location of interest. Even in cases where there is
    recorded streamflow data it is beneficial to pool the information in the
    gauged record with the RFFE information. A RFFE technique is expected to
    be simple, requiring only readily accessible catchment data to obtain
    design flood estimates relatively quickly.</para>

    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T092048+1100"?>

    <para>The RFFE method described in this chapter ensures that design flood
    discharge estimates are consistent with the gauged records and with
    results for other ungauged catchments in a region. It is recognised that
    there will be considerable uncertainty in estimates for ungauged
    catchments because of the limited number of gauged catchments available to
    develop the method and the wide range of catchment types that exist
    throughout Australia.</para>

    <?oxy_insert_end ?>

    <para>In developing the RFFE technique, a number of criteria had to be
    satisfied. These criteria included:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>National consistency in approach;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Smooth interfacing at the boundaries between areas;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use readily accessible data; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Utilise as much of Australia's streamflow database as
        possible.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The basis for the development of the RFFE technique recommended
    herein, therefore, is a national database consisting of 853 gauged
    catchments. These data were used to develop and test the RFFE technique
    presented in this chapter. Further details of the development of the
    database and RFFE technique are provided by the references noted in
    Appendix A.</para>

    <para>The following sections <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101441+1100" content="of this chapter "?>contain
    a description of the conceptual and statistical framework of the adopted
    RFFE technique, a computer-based application tool, referred to as ‘RFFE
    Model 2015’, that implements the adopted RFFE technique and a number of
    worked examples to demonstrate the application of the model.</para>

    <para>Following the guidance provided in Book 1 and Chapter 1 of this
    book, users of the RFFE technique are reminded that there are alternatives
    to the RFFE technique. <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101450+1100" content="Furthermore, in accordance with this guidance, designers and analysts have a duty to use an alternative technique where that alternative is more appropriate for their design flood problem."?></para>

    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101458+1100"?>

    <para>While the RFFE technique described in this chapter is regarded as a
    state-of-the-art approach for estimation of design flood peak discharges
    at ungauged catchments, the limitations of the method must be recognised.
    The RFFE technique has been developed using the best available database of
    gauged catchments throughout Australia, but the fact remains that only a
    small number of gauged catchments were available to represent the wide
    range of conditions experienced over an area of about 7.5 million km2.
    Therefore, in accordance with the guidance in Book 1 Chapter 1 of ARR,
    designers and analysts have a duty to use an alternative technique if that
    technique can be shown to be superior to RFFE Model 2015 and to utilise
    any available local data, both formal and informal to assist in
    understanding local conditions and improve upon RFFE Model 2015 estimates.
    In comparing and selecting alternative methods, the uncertainty in the
    observed flood data due to factors such as limitations in record length
    and rating curve extrapolation should be recognised.</para>

    <?oxy_insert_end ?>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ynzmg">
    <title>Conceptual Framework</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_oubiy">
      <title>Definition of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation</title>

      <para>Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) is a data-driven
      approach, which attempts to transfer flood characteristics from a group
      of gauged catchments to ungauged locations of interest (where design
      floods need to be estimated). A range of different methods are available
      to extract regional flood information from the pooled data and to
      transfer the relevant information to an individual ungauged catchment in
      the region (Sivapalan et al. 2013). All of these RFFE techniques use the
      results of at-site Flood Frequency Analysis (FFA, refer to Book 3
      Chapter 2) as basic data. A RFFE technique essentially consists of two
      steps: (i) <emphasis>Formation of Regions</emphasis> - which involves
      identification of the regions for which flood data from the available
      streamflow gauging stations can be pooled for analysis; and
      (ii)<emphasis> Development of Regional Estimation Equations</emphasis> -
      which involves derivation of prediction equations to be used for design
      flood estimation within a region.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_mctc1">
      <title>Formation of Regions</title>

      <para>In RFFE techniques, the formation of regions can be based on
      geographic proximity or on similarity in catchment attributes. A region
      can be fixed, having a definite common boundary for all sites within it,
      or it can be formed around the ungauged catchment of interest (i.e. the
      location where <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101626+1100" content="the "?>flood
      quantile estimation is desired), <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101632+1100" content="taking"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101632+1100"?>using<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      the nearest stations in geographic or catchment attributes space.
      Regions must satisfy explicitly or implicitly the assumption of
      ‘regional homogeneity’. The decision on what constitutes a homogeneous
      region for the purposes of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation depends
      on the methods used, more specifically on the extent to which
      differences in flood characteristics can be expressed through parameters
      in the regionalisation method. There have been many techniques developed
      which attempt to establish homogenous regions. For example, the
      recommended RFFE model for eastern New South Wales (NSW) and Victoria in
      Australian Rainfall and Runoff 1987 (ARR1987), namely the Probabilistic
      Rational Method, used geographical contiguity as an indication of
      homogeneity; in other words the catchments which are closer to each
      other should have similar runoff coefficients (ARR1987).</para>

      <para>There has been little success in the identification of ‘acceptably
      homogeneous regions’ in Australia using statistical measures such as
      those proposed by Hosking and Wallis (1993). A common approach to
      defining a fixed region has been to base the region on political
      boundaries. However, these fixed regions based on state borders and
      other geographical boundaries have often been found to be highly
      heterogeneous (Bates et al., 1998; Rahman, 1997; Haddad, 2008).</para>

      <para>As an alternative to fixed regions, Burn (1990a, 1990b) and Zrinji
      and Burn (1994) proposed the Region Of Influence (ROI) approach where a
      location of interest (i.e. the catchment where flood quantiles are to be
      estimated) is allowed to form its own region by selecting a group of
      ‘nearby catchments’ in either a geographical or catchment attributes
      space (catchment attributes <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101653+1100" content="or"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101653+1100"?>refer
      to<?oxy_insert_end ?> the catchment characteristics that are influential
      in developing flood flows). The ROI approach attempts to reduce the
      degree of heterogeneity in a proposed region by excluding sites located
      remotely in geographical or catchment attributes space. The ROI approach
      often uses a statistical criterion to select the optimum size of the
      region, such as ‘minimum model error variance’ in the regression.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_tjham">
      <title>Development of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation
      Technique</title>

      <para>According to Bates (1994), the most commonly adopted methods to
      develop Regional Flood Frequency Estimation techniques include various
      forms of the Rational Method, the Index Flood Method and regression
      based techniques. In ARR1987, the Probabilistic Rational Method was
      recommended for general use in Victoria and eastern NSW (ARR1987). The
      foundations of the Probabilistic Rational Method are presented by
      Pilgrim and McDermott (1982), Mittelstadt, et al. (1987), and Adams
      (1984). The central component of the Probabilistic Rational Method, is
      the runoff coefficient and, in particular, the 10 year Average
      Recurrence Interval (ARI) runoff coefficient. It is worth noting that
      this runoff coefficient does not have a physical basis but rather is a
      parameter to ensure that the rainfall frequency is transferred to the
      flow frequency. Furthermore, this parameter has been assumed to vary
      smoothly over geographical space for purposes of extrapolating from
      known locations to <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101715+1100" content="random "?>locations
      for application. However, it has been found that the runoff coefficient
      may show sharp variation within a close proximity, reflecting
      discontinuities at many locations, particularly at catchment boundaries.
      Additionally, French (2002) noted that the isopleths of the runoff
      coefficient in ARR1987 ignored the existence of watercourses.</para>

      <para>Alternative methods to the Probabilistic Rational Method, such as
      the Index Flood Method heavily rely on the assumption of ‘regional
      homogeneity’, which as previously mentioned is satisfied poorly for
      Australian regional flood data. Studies on regression based RFFE
      techniques for Australia (e.g. Hackelbusch et al., 2009; Haddad, et al.,
      2008; Haddad et al., 2009; Haddad, et al., 2011; Haddad, et al., 2012;
      Haddad and Rahman, 2012; Micevski et al., 201<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101731+1100"?>5<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101729+1100" content="4"?>;
      Palmen and Weeks, 2009, 2011; Pirozzi et al., 2009; Rahman, 2005;
      Rahman, Rima and Weeks, 2008; Rahman et al., 2009, 2011a, 2011b, 2012,
      201<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101811+1100" content="4"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101811+1100"?>5<?oxy_insert_end ?>a,
      201<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101813+1100" content="4"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101813+1100"?>5<?oxy_insert_end ?>b,
      201<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101815+1100" content="4"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101815+1100"?>5<?oxy_insert_end ?>c<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101820+1100"?>,
      2015d<?oxy_insert_end ?>) have demonstrated that these techniques are
      capable of providing quite accurate design flood estimates using only a
      few predictor variables. In particular, it has been found that the
      Generalised Least Squares (GLS) based regression technique offers a
      powerful statistical method which accounts for the inter-station
      correlation of annual maximum flood series and across-site variation in
      flood series record lengths in the estimation of the flood quantiles.
      Use of a GLS-based regression method also allows differentiation between
      sampling error and model error and thus provides a more realistic
      framework for error analysis. The GLS based quantile regression
      technique has been adopted in the US (see, for example, Stedinger and
      Tasker, 1985; Tasker and Stedinger, 1989; Griffis and Stedinger,
      2007)<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101833+1100" content=" for development of an RFFE technique"?>.</para>

      <para>As an alternative to the quantile regression technique, the
      parameters of a particular probability distribution can be regressed
      against the catchment characteristics to develop prediction equations
      for the parameters of interest. This method is referred to as Parameter
      Regression Technique (PRT). It is this approach that is the basis of the
      recommended technique for design flood estimation in Australia using the
      RFFE model. For development of a PRT, the Bayesian GLS regression method
      is used to develop prediction equations for the model parameters for the
      three-parameter Log Pearson III (LPIII) distribution; these model
      parameters are the mean, standard deviation and skewness of the
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101917+1100"?>natural
      logarithm of the <?oxy_insert_end ?>annual maximum flood
      series<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T101929+1100" content=" (natural logs)"?>.
      The PRT offers three significant advantages over the quantile regression
      technique:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>It ensures flood quantiles increase smoothly with decreasing
          Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP), an outcome that may not always
          be achieved with quantile regression;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>It is straightforward to combine any at-site flood information
          with regional estimates (see Book 3 Chapter 2) using the approach
          described by Micevski and Kuczera (2009) to produce more accurate
          quantile estimates; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>It permits quantiles to be estimated for any AEP in the range
          of interest.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_0zix8">
      <title>Data Required to Develop Regional Flood Frequency Estimation
      Technique</title>

      <para>The success of a RFFE technique largely depends on the quantity
      and quality of the available data and the capability of the adopted
      statistical techniques to transfer information from gauged to ungauged
      sites within the region. There are two basic types of data required for
      the development and application of RFFE techniques:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flood data at gauged sites; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Catchment characteristics relevant to production of floods in
          both gauged and ungauged catchments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>The quality and representativeness of the flood data determine to
      a large degree the accuracy and reliability of regional flood estimates.
      The challenge in collating a database for RFFE lies in maximising the
      amount of useful flood information, while minimising the random and
      systematic error (or ‘noise’) that may be present in some flood
      data.</para>

      <para>In RFFE, various sources of errors in data and their effects on
      final flood estimates need to be recognised. The accuracy of flood
      quantile estimates at each individual gauged site depends largely on
      rating curve accuracy and record length at the individual site. Thus,
      the selection of a minimum record length at an individual site in the
      region is a very important step in any RFFE technique; the record length
      should be as long as possible while retaining enough sites in the region
      to make the results of RFFE useful. Also, the flood data at each site
      should satisfy a number of basic assumptions e.g. homogeneity,
      independence and stationarity. In the case where these assumptions are
      violated, appropriate measures should be taken; suitable techniques
      include GLS regression to account for the inter-station correlation
      (e.g. Stedinger and Tasker, 1985; Griffis and Stedinger, 2007), and
      non-stationary Flood Frequency Analysis to account for
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093120+1100"?>the
      impacts of <?oxy_insert_end ?>climate change <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093128+1100" content="impact"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093129+1100"?>and
      changes in catchment conditions during the period of
      record<?oxy_insert_end ?>. The data preparation issues for a RFFE
      technique are discussed in more detail by Haddad et al. (2010) and
      Rahman et al. <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102026+1100" content="(2014a, 2014d)."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102028+1100"?>(2015a,
      2015b, 2015c, 2015d). In addition to the consideration of the data
      available at individual gauging stations, it is important to also
      consider the representativeness of the gauged data. The available gauged
      catchments represent only a sample of the range of conditions that may
      occur throughout the regions where the RFFE method is developed and
      applied.<?oxy_insert_end ?></para>

      <para>The transfer of flood information from gauged to ungauged
      catchments relies on the ability to identify a number of key catchment
      and climate characteristics which determine similarities and differences
      in the flood production of catchments. In the Probabilistic Rational
      Method similarity is assumed to exist on the basis of geographical
      proximity, but in other methods an appropriately small but informative
      set of predictor variables needs to be identified. The accuracy of a
      RFFE technique does not necessarily increase with the number of adopted
      predictor variables. For example, Rahman et al. (1999) used 12 predictor
      variables in an L moments based Index Flood Method for south-east
      Australia. A subsequent study by Rahman (2005) showed that use of only 2
      to 3 predictor variables can provide a similar level of accuracy.</para>

      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102040+1100"?>

      <para>Because of the difficulty of obtaining a sufficiently large number
      of gauged catchments in developing and testing a RFFE method, there is a
      chance that the available gauged catchments do not fully represent the
      range of conditions encountered in the region, Therefore where a
      catchment is judged to be atypical in some critical characteristic, the
      regional method may not be directly applicable and further analysis may
      be needed to estimate design flood quantiles. This issue is discussed
      further below.</para>

      <?oxy_insert_end ?>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_voncz">
      <title>Accuracy Considerations</title>

      <para>All RFFE techniques are subject<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102050+1100" content="ed "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102051+1100"?>
      <?oxy_insert_end ?>to uncertainty, which, generally, is likely to be
      greater than for at-site Flood Frequency Analysis when a good quality
      and long record of streamflow data set is available at the location of
      interest. A RFFE technique essentially represents a ‘transfer function’
      that converts predictor variables to a flood quantile estimate. It is
      assumed that use of a limited number of predictor variables (e.g.
      catchment area and design rainfall intensity) combined with an optimised
      transfer function captures the general nature of the rainfall-runoff
      relationship for flood events and hence provides flood quantile
      estimates of ‘acceptable’ accuracy.</para>

      <para>Because a RFFE technique typically has limited predictive power,
      design flood estimates produced by it are likely to have a lower degree
      of accuracy than those from a well calibrated catchment modelling
      system. From the investigations made by Rahman et al. (2009, 2012,
      201<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102104+1100"?>5a,
      2015b<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102100+1100" content="4b"?>),
      it may be stated that the relative accuracy of regional flood estimates
      using the RFFE model presented in this chapter is likely to be within
      ±50% of the true value; however, in a limited number of cases the
      estimation error may exceed <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093415+1100" content="±100%"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093415+1100"?>the
      estimation by a factor of two or more<?oxy_insert_end ?> (see <xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_s_yj49v"/>). It is unlikely that any RFFE technique
      would be able to provide flood quantile estimates which are of much
      greater accuracy <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102533+1100" content="than this, given the current availability of streamflow data (in terms of temporal and spatial coverage) in Australia."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102428+1100"?>given
      the current availability of streamflow data (in terms of temporal and
      spatial coverage) and feasibility of the extraction of a greater number
      of catchment descriptors using simplified methods such as GIS based
      techniques. Because of the small sample of gauged catchments and limited
      availability of readily obtainable catchment descriptors, it is not
      possible to prepare an extremely detailed set of descriptor variables
      covering all possible conditions, so a sample must be selected that
      provides a suitable range to represent the critical parameters, but to
      limit the application of variables that do not contribute significantly
      to the overall performance of the RFFE technique.<?oxy_insert_end ?></para>

      <para>For catchments having limited recorded streamflow data, the
      combination of at-site data with a RFFE technique is likely to provide
      more accurate flood quantile estimates than either the at-site or
      regional method alone. Details of how limited streamflow data can be
      combined with a RFFE technique <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093510+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093511+1100"?>are<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      presented in Book 3 Chapter 2. Testing has shown this improves estimates
      in many cases.</para>

      <para>An important assumption in all RFFE techniques is that the small
      set of predictor variables used in the regression equations is able to
      explain the differences in flood producing characteristics of the
      catchments in a region. Not all ungauged catchments located in the
      region satisfy this basic homogeneity assumption; some catchments may
      have characteristics that are substantially different from the gauged
      catchments in the region. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8airu"/> contains
      further discussion on the limits of applicability of the RFFE technique,
      on what constitutes an atypical catchment and recommendations on how to
      derive flood estimates for such catchments.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_kbrnd">
    <title>Statistical Framework</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8o524">
      <title>Region Of Influence (ROI) Approach</title>

      <para>In the formation of regions, the Region Of Influence (ROI)
      approach has been adopted for the parts of Australia where there are
      adequate numbers of gauged stations within close proximity to form ROI
      sub-regions. In the absence of a proven technique for the use of
      catchment characteristics as the basis for the ROI, the adopted ROI
      approach uses the geographical distance between stations as the distance
      metric and sets a maximum distance for inclusion of stations in the ROI
      sub-region. More details regarding development of ROI sub-regions
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102714+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102714+1100"?>are<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      provided by <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102710+1100" content="("?>Rahman
      et al. <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102708+1100"?>(<?oxy_insert_end ?>2015<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102701+1100"?>b<?oxy_insert_end ?>).
      Nonetheless, a summary of the process is presented. In applying the ROI
      approach, in the first iteration, a ROI sub-region consisting of the ten
      nearest stations to the site of interest is formed, the regional
      prediction equation is developed and its prediction error variance
      noted. At each of the subsequent iterations, the radius of the ROI
      sub-region is increased by 10 km and new stations are added to the
      previously selected stations. The final ROI sub-region for the location
      of interest is then selected as the one exhibiting the lowest prediction
      error variance.</para>

      <para>One of the apparent limitations of the ROI approach is that for
      each of the gauged sites in the region, the regional prediction equation
      has a different set of model parameters; hence a single regional
      prediction equation cannot be pre-specified. To overcome this problem,
      the parameters of the regional prediction equations for all the gauged
      catchment locations are pre-estimated and integrated with the RFFE Model
      2015 (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs"/> for more details). To derive
      flood quantile estimate<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102723+1100"?>s<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      at an ungauged <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102728+1100" content="catchment"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102728+1100"?>location<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      of interest, the RFFE Model 2015 <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102753+1100"?>uses
      a natural neighbour interpolation method to derive<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102743+1100" content="takes the inverse distance weighted average value of flood"?>
      quantile estimates based on up to <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102801+1100"?>the
      <?oxy_insert_end ?>15 nearest gauged catchment locations within a 300 km
      radius from the <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102812+1100" content="catchment"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102812+1100"?>location<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      of interest. This ensures a smooth variation of flood quantile estimates
      over the space.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_epemh">
      <title>Parameter Regression Technique</title>

      <para>In the adopted RFFE technique for the Humid Coastal areas of
      Australia (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_2fdu4"/> for further details),
      the first three moments of the LPIII distribution (i.e. the mean,
      standard deviation and skewness of the natural logarithms of the annual
      maximum flood series) <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102849+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102849+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      regionalised. This method is referred to as the Parameter Regression
      Technique (PRT). The LPIII distribution is described by the following
      equation:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_swrce">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>lnQ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>M</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>K</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mi>S</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is the discharge having an AEP of X% (design flood
      or flood quantile),</para>

      <para>M is the mean of the natural logarithms of the <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102900+1100" content="A"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102900+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?>nnual
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102901+1100" content="M"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102902+1100"?>m<?oxy_insert_end ?>aximum
      flood series,</para>

      <para>S is the standard deviation of the natural logarithms of the
      annual maximum flood series, and</para>

      <para><inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>K</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is the frequency factor for the LPIII distribution
      of X% AEP, which is a function of the AEP and the skewness (SK) of the
      natural logarithms of the <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102905+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102905+1100" content="A"?>nnual
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102910+1100" content="M"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102911+1100"?>m<?oxy_insert_end ?>aximum
      flood series.</para>

      <para>The prediction equations for M, S and SK <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102916+1100" content="have been"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102916+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      developed for all the gauged catchment locations in the Humid Coastal
      areas using Bayesian GLS regression and model parameters <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102923+1100" content="as"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102923+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      noted. These model parameters are<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102931+1100"?>
      then<?oxy_insert_end ?> integrated with the RFFE Model 2015.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_9bcrr">
      <title>Generalised Least Squares Regression</title>

      <para>In developing the prediction equations, for the Humid Coastal
      areas, the Bayesian Generalised Least Squares (GLS) regression
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102937+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T102937+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      adopted. The GLS regression assumes that the variable of interest (e.g.
      a moment of the LPIII distribution) denoted by y<subscript>i
      </subscript>for a location i can be described by a function of catchment
      characteristics (explanatory variables) with an additive error (Griffis
      and Stedinger, 2007):</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_wezxq">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>y</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                <m:mi>0</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:munderover>
                  <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>j</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>k</m:mi>
                </m:munderover>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>⁢</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>ij</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>...</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>X</m:mi>

              <m:mi>ij</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> (j = 1,…, k) are explanatory variables,
      <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>β</m:mi>

              <m:mi>j</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> are the regression coefficients, <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is the model error which is assumed to be normally
      and independently distributed with model error variance <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msubsup>
              <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

              <m:mi>2</m:mi>
            </m:msubsup>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> , and n is the number of locations in the region. In
      all cases, an at-site estimate of y<subscript>i</subscript> denoted as
      <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mover>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>y</m:mi>

                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo form="postfix">^</m:mo>
            </m:mover>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is available. To account for the error in the
      at-site estimate, a sampling error <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>η</m:mi>

              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> must be introduced into the model so that:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_pogxg">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>ŷ</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>Xβ</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>η</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>Xβ</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mtext>where</m:mtext>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>ŷ</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                          </m:msub>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                              <m:mi>γ</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>

                            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>η</m:mi>

                                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>: і</m:mi>

                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                                <m:mi>1,2 ...,n</m:mi>
                              </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>Thus the observed regression model error <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mi>ε</m:mi>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is the sum of the model error <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mi>δ</m:mi>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> and the sampling error <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mi>η</m:mi>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation>. The total error vector has a mean of zero and a
      covariance matrix:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_ujp3a">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msup>
              <m:mi>E[εε</m:mi>

              <m:mi>T</m:mi>
            </m:msup>

            <m:mo>]=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msubsup>
                <m:mi>Λ(σ</m:mi>

                <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                <m:mi>2</m:mi>
              </m:msubsup>

              <m:mo>) =</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msubsup>
                  <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                </m:msubsup>

                <m:mo>I+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>Σ(ŷ)</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where<inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mi>Σ(ŷ</m:mi>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation>) is the covariance matrix of the sampling error in
      the estimate of the flood quantile or the parameter of the LPIII
      distribution and I is a (n x n) identity matrix. The covariance matrix
      for η<subscript>i</subscript> depends on the record length available at
      each location and the cross correlation among <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103030+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103029+1100" content="A"?>nnual
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103032+1100" content="M"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103032+1100"?>m<?oxy_insert_end ?>aximum
      floods at different locations. Therefore, the observed regression model
      error is a combination of time-sampling error η<subscript>i</subscript>
      and an underlying model error δ<subscript>i</subscript>.</para>

      <para>The GLS estimator of β and its covariance matrix for a known
      <inlineequation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msubsup>
                <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                <m:mn>2</m:mn>
              </m:msubsup>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </inlineequation> is given by:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_1jjd4">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>β</m:mi>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>G</m:mi>

                <m:mi>L</m:mi>

                <m:mi>S</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:msubsup>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msup>
                      <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                    </m:msup>

                    <m:mi>Λ</m:mi>

                    <m:msubsup>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msubsup>
                              <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                              <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                            </m:msubsup>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                    </m:msubsup>

                    <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

              <m:mo>−</m:mo>
            </m:msubsup>

            <m:msup>
              <m:mi>X</m:mi>

              <m:mi>T</m:mi>
            </m:msup>

            <m:mi>Λ</m:mi>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msubsup>
                  <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                </m:msubsup>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mover accent="true">
              <m:mi>y</m:mi>

              <m:mo>^</m:mo>
            </m:mover>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_iqkha">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>Σ</m:mi>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>[</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>G</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>L</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>]</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:msubsup>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msup>
                      <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                    </m:msup>

                    <m:mi>Λ</m:mi>

                    <m:msubsup>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:msubsup>
                              <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                              <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                            </m:msubsup>
                          </m:mrow>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                    </m:msubsup>

                    <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mi>e</m:mi>

              <m:mo>−</m:mo>
            </m:msubsup>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>The model error variance σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² can be
      estimated by either generalised Method of Moments (MOM) or maximum
      likelihood estimators. The MOM estimator is determined by iteratively
      solving <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_1jjd4"/> along with the generalised
      residual mean square error equation:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_w6z3z">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mover accent="true">
                  <m:mi>y</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>^</m:mo>
                </m:mover>

                <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:msubsup>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msubsup>
                          <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                          <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                        </m:msubsup>

                        <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>Σ</m:mi>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                          <m:mover accent="true">
                            <m:mi>y</m:mi>

                            <m:mo>^</m:mo>
                          </m:mover>

                          <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>−</m:mo>
                </m:msubsup>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mover accent="true">
                  <m:mi>y</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>^</m:mo>
                </m:mover>

                <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>G</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>L</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mi>n</m:mi>

            <m:mo>−</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>k</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mn>1</m:mn>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>In some situations, the sampling covariance matrix explains all
      the variability observed in the data, which means the left-hand side of
      <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_w6z3z"/> will be less than n – (k + 1) even if
      σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² is zero. In these circumstances, the MOM
      estimator of the model error variance is generally taken to be
      zero.</para>

      <para>With the <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103205+1100"?>adopted
      <?oxy_insert_end ?>Bayesian approach, it <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103210+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103210+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      assumed that there <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103215+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103215+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      no prior information on any of the β parameters; thus a multivariate
      normal distribution with mean zero and a large variance (e.g. greater
      than 100) <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103220+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103220+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      used as a prior for the regression coefficient parameters. This prior
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103224+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103224+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      considered to be almost non-informative, which produce<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103233+1100" content="s"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103233+1100"?>d<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      a probability distribution function that <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103227+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103227+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      generally flat in the region of interest. The prior information for the
      model error variance σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103238+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103238+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      represented by a one parameter exponential distribution. Further
      description of the adopted Bayesian GLS regression can be found in
      Haddad<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103250+1100" content=","?>
      et al. (2011) and Haddad and Rahman (2012).</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_7r0rn">
      <title>Development of Confidence Limits for the Estimated Flood
      Quantiles</title>

      <para>In developing the confidence limits for the estimated flood
      quantiles, a Monte Carlo simulation approach <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103348+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103348+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      adopted by assuming that the uncertainty in the first three parameters
      of the LPIII distribution (i.e. the mean, standard deviation and
      skewness of the logarithms of the annual maximum flood series) can be
      specified by a multivariate normal distribution. Here the correlations
      among the three parameters for a given region <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103400+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103400+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      estimated from the residuals of the GLS regression models of the LPIII
      parameters. The mean of the LPIII parameter is given by its regional
      predicted value and the standard deviation of the LPIII parameter is the
      square root of the average variance of prediction of the parameter at
      the nearest gauged location. Based on 10,000 simulated values of the
      LPIII parameters from the multivariate normal distribution as defined
      above, 10,000 Q<subscript>x</subscript> values are
      estimated<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103508+1100"?>
      in the RFFE Model 2015<?oxy_insert_end ?>, which are then used to
      develop the 90% confidence intervals.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_wfiku">
    <title>RFFE Techniques for Humid Coastal Areas</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_2fdu4">
      <title>Data Used to Develop RFFE Technique</title>

      <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_i6yzh">
        <title>Flood data</title>

        <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103525+1100" content="Data-rich areas include most of the coastal belts of Australia where there are a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103525+1100"?>Humid
        Coast areas had a relatively<?oxy_insert_end ?> large number of
        recorded streamflow stations<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093540+1100"?>,<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        as shown in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_55d8a"/>. An upper limit of
        catchment size of 1,000 km² <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103624+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103624+1100"?>was
        generally<?oxy_insert_end ?> adopted. However, in some states (such as
        the Northern Territory), a few larger catchments <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103635+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103636+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        included as the total number of catchments with areas less than 1,000
        km² <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103616+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T103616+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        too small. The cut-off record length of 19 years was selected to
        maximise the number of eligible stations on the consideration that a
        higher cut-off would reduce that number.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_55d8a">
          <title>Geographical distribution of the adopted 798 catchments from
          Humid Coastal areas of Australia<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T120308+1100"?>
          (blue circles) and 55 catchments from Arid/Semi-arid areas (black
          circles)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3038.PNG"
                         scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The selected streams were unregulated since major regulation
        (e.g. a large dam on the stream) affects the rainfall-runoff
        relationship significantly by increasing <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093556+1100" content="additional "?>storage
        effects. Streams with minor regulation, such as small farm dams and
        diversion weirs, were not excluded because this type of regulation is
        unlikely to have a significant effect on large annual floods. Gauging
        stations on streams subject to major upstream regulation were excluded
        from the data set. Catchments with more than 10% of the area affected
        by urbanisation were also excluded from the study data set. Catchments
        known to have undergone major land use changes, such as the clearing
        of forests or changing of agricultural practices over the period of
        streamflow records were excluded from the data set. Stations graded as
        'poor quality' or with specific comments by the gauging authority
        regarding quality of the data were assessed in greater detail; if
        stations were deemed 'low quality' they <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T133947+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T133947+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        excluded.</para>

        <para>The <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T133940+1100" content="A"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T133940+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?>nnual
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T133942+1100" content="M"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T133943+1100"?>m<?oxy_insert_end ?>aximum
        flood series data may be affected by multi-decadal climate variability
        and climate change, which are not easy to deal with. The effects of
        multi-decadal climate variability can be accounted for by increasing
        the cut-off record length at an individual station. However, the
        impacts of climate change present a serious problem in terms of the
        applicability of the past data in predicting future flood frequency;
        this requires further research (Ishak <emphasis>et al</emphasis>.,
        2013). This is further discussed in <xref
        linkend="b3_ch3_s_31eib"/>.</para>

        <para>The data sets for the initially selected potential catchments
        are further examined, as detailed in Haddad <emphasis>et
        al</emphasis>. (2010) and Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>. 2014 (a,
        b, c): gaps in the <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093627+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093626+1100" content="A"?>nnual
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093629+1100" content="M"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093629+1100"?>m<?oxy_insert_end ?>aximum
        flood series <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093619+1100" content="were"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093619+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        filled as far as could be justified, outliers were detected using the
        multiple Grubbs-Beck test (Lamontagne <emphasis>et al</emphasis>.,
        2013; Cohn <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2013), errors associated with
        extrapolation of rating curves were investigated and the presence of
        trends with the data were checked. From an initial number of
        approximately 1200 catchments, a total of 798 catchments were finally
        adopted from all over Australia (excluding catchments in the
        arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134002+1100"?>/semi-arid
        areas<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134001+1100" content=" regions"?>,
        where some of the above criteria were relaxed, as discussed in Section
        5).</para>

        <para>The record lengths of the <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134012+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134012+1100" content="A"?>nnual
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134015+1100" content="M"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134015+1100"?>m<?oxy_insert_end ?>aximum
        flood series of these 798 stations range from 19 to 102 years (median:
        37 years). The catchment areas of the selected 798 catchments range
        from 0.5 km² to 4,325 km² (median: 178 km²). <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134050+1100" content="The geographical distribution of the selected 798 catchments is shown in &lt;xref linkend=&quot;b3_ch3_f_55d8a&quot;/&gt; and &lt;xref linkend=&quot;b3_ch3_t_opf7j&quot;/&gt; presents a summary of the selected catchments"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134104+1100"?><xref
        linkend="b3_ch3_t_opf7j"/> provides summary of the selected catchments
        from Humid Coastal areas of Australia. .<?oxy_insert_end ?></para>

        <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_opf7j">
          <title>Summary of adopted catchments from Humid Coastal areas of
          Australia</title>

          <tgroup cols="4">
            <colspec/>

            <colspec/>

            <colspec align="center"/>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>State</entry>

                <entry>No. of stations</entry>

                <entry>Streamflow record length (years) (range and
                median)</entry>

                <entry>Catchment size (km<superscript>2</superscript>) (range
                and median)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>New South Wales &amp; Australian Capital
                Territory</entry>

                <entry>176</entry>

                <entry>20 – 82 (34)</entry>

                <entry>1 – 1036 (204)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Victoria</entry>

                <entry>186</entry>

                <entry>20 – 60 (38)</entry>

                <entry>3 – 997 (209)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>South Australia</entry>

                <entry>28</entry>

                <entry>20 – 63 (37)</entry>

                <entry>0.6 – 708 (62.6)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Tasmania</entry>

                <entry>51</entry>

                <entry>19 – 74 (28)</entry>

                <entry>1.3 – 1900 (158.1)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Queensland</entry>

                <entry>196</entry>

                <entry>20 – 102 (42)</entry>

                <entry>7– 963 (227)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Western Australia</entry>

                <entry>111</entry>

                <entry>20 – 60 (30)</entry>

                <entry>0.5 – 1049.8 (49.2)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Northern Territory</entry>

                <entry>50</entry>

                <entry>19 – 57 (42)</entry>

                <entry>1.4 – 4325 (352)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>TOTAL</entry>

                <entry>798</entry>

                <entry>19 – 102 (37)</entry>

                <entry>0.5 – 4325 (178)</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>

        <para>The at-site Flood Frequency Analyses <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134132+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134132+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        conducted using the FLIKE software (Kuczera, 1999). The Potential
        Influential Low Flows (PILFs) <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134135+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134135+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        identified using multiple Grubbs-Beck test (Lamontagne<emphasis> et
        al</emphasis>., 2013) and <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134138+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134138+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        censored in the Flood Frequency Analysis. A Bayesian parameter
        estimation procedure with LPIII distribution <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134151+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134151+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        used to estimate flood quantiles for each <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093701+1100" content="of the "?>gauged
        site for AEPs of 50%, 20%, 10%, 5%, 2% and 1%.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ujhrw">
        <title>Catchment characteristics data</title>

        <para>As discussed by Rahman<emphasis> et al</emphasis>. (2009; 2012),
        over ten predictor variables were selected initially; however, it was
        found that the accuracy of a RFFE technique does not necessarily
        increase with the number of adopted predictor variables. A total of
        five<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T093715+1100"?>
        candidate<?oxy_insert_end ?> predictor variables were adopted finally
        in the RFFE technique<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T094130+1100"?>,<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        as outlined below:</para>

        <para>(i) catchment area in km² (<emphasis>area</emphasis>);</para>

        <para>(ii) design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid (in mm/h)
        for the 6 hour duration and 50% AEP
        (<superscript>50%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>);</para>

        <para>(iii) design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid (in mm/h)
        for the 6 hour duration and 2% AEP
        (<superscript>2%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>);</para>

        <para>(iv) ratio of design rainfall intensities of AEPs of 2% and 50%
        for duration of 6 hour
        (<superscript>2%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>/<superscript>50%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>);
        and</para>

        <para>(v) <emphasis>shape factor</emphasis>, which is defined as the
        shortest distance between catchment outlet and centroid divided by the
        square root of catchment area.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134510+1100"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end ?></para>

        <para>Design rainfall values were extracted from the new Intensity
        Frequency Duration (IFD) data for Australia as discussed in Book 2
        Chapter 3 of ARR.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134314+1100"?><xref
        linkend="b3_ch3_t_osmfhe"/> provides the distribution of shape factors
        for the selected catchments.<table frame="void"
            xml:id="b3_ch3_t_osmfhe">
            <caption><emphasis role="bold">Distribution of shape factors for
            the selected catchments</emphasis></caption>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <col width="16%"/>

            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Percentile</td>

                <td>1%</td>

                <td>10%</td>

                <td>50%</td>

                <td>90%</td>

                <td>99%</td>
              </tr>

              <tr>
                <td>Shape Factor</td>

                <td>0.32</td>

                <td>0.51</td>

                <td>0.76</td>

                <td>1.06</td>

                <td>1.51</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table><?oxy_insert_end ?></para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_pfnbw">
      <title>Adopted RFFE Regions</title>

      <para>Australia is divided into seven regions. There are five Humid
      Coastal <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134708+1100" content="areas"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134708+1100"?>regions
      <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134715+1100" content=", as shown in "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134720+1100"?>(<?oxy_insert_end ?><xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_t_2kbsr"/><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134745+1100"?>)<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      and <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134758+1100"?>two
      arid/semi-arid regions (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_0x8hz"/>), as shown in
      <?oxy_insert_end ?><xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/>. <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T134941+1100" content="The remaining two regions are located in the semi-arid and arid areas of Australia. The boundaries between the arid and data-rich regions in &lt;xref linkend=&quot;b3_ch3_f_49qvf&quot;/&gt; are drawn approximately based on the 500 mm mean annual rainfall contour line. "?>There
      are seven fringe zones that are the interface between two regions, as
      discussed in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_m01jo"/>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_49qvf">
        <title>Adopted regions for RFFE technique in Australia</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3039.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para><table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_k3lzr">
          <title>Details of RFFE technique for Humid Coastal <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135021+1100" content="regions"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135021+1100"?>areas
          of Australia<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

          <tgroup cols="4">
            <colspec/>

            <colspec/>

            <colspec align="center"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry align="center">Region</entry>

                <entry align="center">Method to form region</entry>

                <entry align="center">Number of stations</entry>

                <entry align="center">Estimation model</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Region 1: East Coast</entry>

                <entry morerows="4">ROI (based on geographical
                proximity)</entry>

                <entry>558</entry>

                <entry morerows="4">Bayesian GLS regression-PRT</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 2: Tasmania</entry>

                <entry>51</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 3: Humid SA</entry>

                <entry>28</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 4: Top End NT and Kimberl<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135033+1100"?>e<?oxy_insert_end ?>y</entry>

                <entry>58</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Region 5: SW WA</entry>

                <entry>103</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_o7h7w">
      <title>Adopted Estimation Equations</title>

      <para>For the five Humid Coastal regions described in <xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_t_k3lzr"/>, the adopted estimation equations for
      M<emphasis>,</emphasis> S and <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135142+1100" type="surround"?><emphasis><?oxy_insert_end ?>SK</emphasis><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135138+1100" content="&lt;emphasis/&gt;"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135139+1100"?>
      <?oxy_insert_end ?>for the regional LPIII model (<xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_e_swrce"/>) have the following general form:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_yitfd">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>M</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>b</m:mi>

              <m:mn>0</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>b</m:mi>

              <m:mn>1</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>r</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>a</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>b</m:mi>

              <m:mn>2</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>6</m:mn>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mn>50</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>b</m:mi>

              <m:mn>3</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>shape factor</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_n8zye">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>S</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>c</m:mi>

              <m:mn>0</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>c</m:mi>

              <m:mn>1</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mfrac>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>6</m:mn>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>6</m:mn>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mn>50</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_3r3ol">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>S</m:mi>

            <m:mi>K</m:mi>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>d</m:mi>

              <m:mn>0</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>d</m:mi>

              <m:mn>1</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mtext>area</m:mtext>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>d</m:mi>

              <m:mn>2</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mfrac>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>6</m:mn>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mn>6</m:mn>

                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                        <m:mn>50</m:mn>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mfrac>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>d</m:mi>

              <m:mn>3</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mi>ln</m:mi>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mn>6</m:mn>

                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                    <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where, area is the catchment area (km²);</para>

      <para>I<subscript>6,50</subscript> is the design rainfall intensity
      (mm/h) at catchment centroid for 6 hour duration and 50% AEP;</para>

      <para>shape factor is the shortest distance between catchment outlet and
      centroid/<emphasis>area</emphasis><superscript>0.5</superscript>;
      and</para>

      <para>I<subscript>6,2</subscript> is the design rainfall intensity
      (mm/h) at catchment centroid for 6 hour duration and 2% AEP.</para>

      <para>For Region 1<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135424+1100" content="s"?>
      and 2, only the model intercept<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135445+1100"?>s<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135445+1100" content=" are available"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135450+1100"?>
      were used in<?oxy_insert_end ?> <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_n8zye"/> and
      <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_3r3ol"/><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135528+1100" content=". Hence, for these two regions, "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135528+1100"?>,
      which imply a regression equation without any predictor variable. Here,
      <?oxy_insert_end ?>the weighted average values of S and SK <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135547+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135547+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      adopted<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135608+1100"?>,
      <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135608+1100" content=". These values are determined using "?>record
      lengths at the stations within the ROI sub-region<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135620+1100"?>
      were used<?oxy_insert_end ?> as a basis for determining the
      weights.</para>

      <para>The values of b<subscript>0</subscript>,
      b<subscript>1</subscript>, b<subscript>2</subscript>,
      b<subscript>3</subscript>, c<subscript>0</subscript>,
      c<subscript>1</subscript>, d<subscript>0</subscript>,
      d<subscript>1</subscript>, d<subscript>2</subscript> and
      d<subscript>3</subscript> at all the 798 individual gauged catchment
      locations (in the Humid Coastal <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135631+1100" content="regions"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135631+1100"?>areas<?oxy_insert_end ?>)
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135633+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135633+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      estimated and embedded in the RFFE Model 2015. To derive flood quantile
      estimates at an ungauged location of interest, the RFFE Model 2015 uses
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135657+1100" content="an inverse distance weighted average value of flood "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135657+1100"?>a
      natural neighbour interpolation method to derive <?oxy_insert_end ?>quantile
      estimates based on up to the 15 nearest gauged catchment locations
      within 300 km radius from the location of interest. This ensures a
      smooth variation of flood quantile estimates over space.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ksbct">
    <title>RFFE Techniques for Arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135706+1100"?>/Semi-Arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    Areas</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_4foca">
      <title>Data Used to Develop RFFE Technique</title>

      <para>Most of Australia's interior falls into the
      arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135729+1100"?>/<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135727+1100" content=" and "?>semi-arid
      areas<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135725+1100" content=" (referred to as arid areas)"?>,
      which are characterised by low mean annual rainfall in relation to mean
      annual potential evaporation. Rainfall events tend to be infrequent and
      their occurrence and severity are highly variable. Typically dry
      antecedent conditions may result in many rainfall events not producing
      any significant runoff. However, severe rainfall events can still result
      in significant flooding with serious consequences. Large transmission
      losses (i.e. losses occurring from flow in rivers and other drainage
      channels) <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135735+1100" content="in "?>may
      also result in discharge reducing in a downstream direction,
      particularly in the lower river reaches of larger catchments in arid
      areas. The special flooding characteristics of catchments in
      arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135747+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas make it desirable to treat them separately from catchments in more
      humid areas. In arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135808+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas, annual maximum flood series generally contain many zero values;
      these values were censored in <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135814+1100"?>f<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135814+1100" content="F"?>lood
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135817+1100"?>f<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135817+1100" content="F"?>requency
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135819+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135819+1100" content="A"?>nalysis.</para>

      <para>In ARR1987 (Pilgrim, 1987), only a few catchments were used from
      arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135830+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas to develop RFFE methods. Since the publication of ARR1987, there
      has been little improvement in terms of streamflow data availability in
      most of the arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135835+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas of Australia.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135850+1100"?>
      There are a number of reasons for poor stream gauging coverage and
      quality in arid/semi-arid areas, as follows:<orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Poorly defined water course catchments, meaning that the
            water courses are hard to define and therefore gauge.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Large floods may be outside the water course, meaning that
            the cross section may be hard to measure and the flow may be
            difficult to gauge.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Infrequent flood events, meaning that the gauge may be
            operating for extended periods of time without any flow.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Remote location, making it difficult to take velocity
            measurements during the flood events.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Little incentive to gauge flows because of the perceived
            limited water resources and the limited demand for development of
            these resources.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist><?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140015+1100" content=" "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T135841+1100" type="split"?></para>

      <para><?oxy_insert_end ?>In the preparation of the Regional Flood
      Frequency Estimation database, only a handful of catchments from the
      arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140033+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas satisf<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140039+1100" content="y"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140039+1100"?>ied<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      the selection criteria. To increase the number of stations from the
      arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140045+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas to develop a RFFE method, the selection criteria were relaxed i.e.
      the threshold streamflow record length was reduced to 10 years and the
      limit of catchment size was increased from 1,000 km² to 6,000 km². These
      criteria result<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140102+1100"?>ed<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      in the selection of 55 catchments from the arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140108+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas of Australia (<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140400+1100" content="&lt;xref linkend=&quot;b3_ch3_f_r2u60&quot;/&gt; "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140400+1100"?><xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> <?oxy_insert_end ?>and <xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_t_0x8hz"/>). The selected catchments have average annual
      rainfall less than 500 mm. The catchment areas range from 0.1 to 5,975
      km² (median: 259 km²) and streamflow record lengths range from 10 to 46
      years (median: 27 years).</para>

      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T140442+1100" content="&lt;figure xml:id=&quot;b3_ch3_f_r2u60&quot;&gt;&lt;title&gt;Locations of the selected catchments from the arid areas of Australia (see &lt;xref linkend=&quot;b3_ch3_f_49qvf&quot;/&gt; for the boundary of the two arid regions)&lt;/title&gt;&lt;mediaobject&gt;&lt;imageobject&gt;&lt;imagedata contentdepth=&quot;100%&quot; fileref=&quot;../../figures/3040.PNG&quot; scalefit=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/imageobject&gt;&lt;/mediaobject&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;"?>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_0x8hz">
        <title>Summary of adopted stations from arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T143709+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        areas of Australia</title>

        <tgroup cols="4">
          <colspec/>

          <colspec/>

          <colspec align="center"/>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Location</entry>

              <entry>No. of stations</entry>

              <entry>Streamflow record length (years) (range and
              median)</entry>

              <entry>Catchment size (km<superscript>2</superscript>) (range
              and median)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Pilbara</entry>

              <entry>11</entry>

              <entry>22 – 34 (28)</entry>

              <entry>0.2 – 5975 (303)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Arid and Semi-arid</entry>

              <entry>44</entry>

              <entry>10 – 46 (27)</entry>

              <entry>3 – 997 (209)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>TOTAL</entry>

              <entry>55</entry>

              <entry>10 – 46 (27)</entry>

              <entry>0.1 – 5975 (259)</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_bqt0e">
      <title>Adopted Regions</title>

      <para>The <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T143718+1100" content="formation"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T143718+1100"?>definition<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      of regions in the arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T143722+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      areas in Australia is a difficult task, as there are only 55 catchments
      available over a vast area of Australia. There are two alternatives: (i)
      formation of one region with all the 55 stations; and (ii) formation of
      smaller sub-regions based on geographical proximity, noting that too
      small a region makes the developed RFFE technique of little statistical
      significance. Examination of a number of alternative sub-regions led to
      the formation of two regions from the 55 arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T143752+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      catchments: Region 6 (11 catchments from the Pilbara area of WA) and
      Region 7 (44 catchments from all other arid areas except Pilbara) (see
      <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> for the extent of these two
      arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T143805+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      regions<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144337+1100"?>
      and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_2kbsr"/> for other details<?oxy_insert_end ?>).</para>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_2kbsr">
        <title>Details of RFFE technique for arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144407+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        regions</title>

        <tgroup cols="4">
          <colspec/>

          <colspec/>

          <colspec align="center"/>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Region</entry>

              <entry>Method to form region</entry>

              <entry>Number of stations</entry>

              <entry>Estimation model</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 6: Pilbara</entry>

              <entry morerows="1">Fixed region</entry>

              <entry>11</entry>

              <entry align="center" morerows="1" vendor="">Index flood method
              with Q<subscript>10</subscript> as index <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144302+1100" content="(partial duration series model with average number of events per year = 0.5)"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144302+1100"?>variable<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 7: Arid and Semi-arid</entry>

              <entry>44</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ri9vz">
      <title>Adopted Estimation Equations</title>

      <para>Application of the ROI and PRT methods for arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144414+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      regions <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144422+1100" content="were"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144422+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      deemed inappropriate as the ROI due to <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144437+1100"?>an
      <?oxy_insert_end ?>insufficient number of gauges. Hence a simpler RFFE
      method <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144443+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144443+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      considered more appropriate for the two arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144428+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      regions. Here, an index type approach as suggested by Farquharson et al.
      (1992) is adopted. The 10% AEP flood quantile
      (Q<subscript>10</subscript>) <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144450+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144450+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      used as the index variable and a dimensionless Growth Factor for X% AEP
      (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144454+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144454+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      used to estimate Q<subscript>x</subscript>:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_xhxx7">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

              <m:mi>x</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mi>10</m:mi>
              </m:msub>

              <m:mo>×</m:mo>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>GF</m:mi>

                <m:mi>x</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>A prediction equation was developed for Q<subscript>10</subscript>
      as a function of catchment characteristics, and regional growth factors
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144511+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144511+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      developed based on the <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144529+1100" content="observed partial duration series"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144529+1100"?>estimated
      at-site<?oxy_insert_end ?> flood <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144531+1100" content="data"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144531+1100"?>quantile<?oxy_insert_end ?>.
      In the arid areas, significant storm events do not typically occur every
      year, and some of these events do not produce significant floods. The
      at-site Flood Frequency Analyses for the arid catchments <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144545+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144545+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      conducted using the FLIKE software (Kuczera, 1999). The Potential
      Influential Low Flows (PILFs) <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144559+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144559+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      identified using multiple Grubbs-Beck test (Lamontagne<emphasis
      role="italic"> et al</emphasis>., 2013) and <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144607+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144607+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      censored in the Flood Frequency Analysis. A Bayesian parameter
      estimation procedure with LPIII distribution <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144614+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144614+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      used to estimate flood quantiles for each <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095615+1100" content="of the "?>gauged
      site for AEPs of 50%, 20%, 10%, 5%, 2% and 1%. It should be noted that
      the Flood Frequency Analysis procedure adopted in the Humid Coastal and
      arid areas <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144623+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144623+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      the same.</para>

      <para>The Q<subscript>x</subscript>/Q<subscript>10</subscript> values
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144626+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144626+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      estimated at individual stations; the weighted average of these values
      (weighting <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144634+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144634+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      done based on record length at individual <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144637+1100" content="locations"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144637+1100"?>stations<?oxy_insert_end ?>)
      over all the stations in a region then define<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144645+1100" content="s"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144646+1100"?>d<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      the Growth Factors (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) for the region.</para>

      <para>The adopted prediction equation for the index variable
      Q<subscript>10</subscript> has the following form:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_6mwfc">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>log</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mn>10</m:mn>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>b</m:mi>

              <m:mn>0</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>b</m:mi>

              <m:mn>1</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>log</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mn>10</m:mn>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mtext>area</m:mtext>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>+</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>b</m:mi>

              <m:mn>2</m:mn>
            </m:msub>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>log</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mn>10</m:mn>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mn>6</m:mn>

                    <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                    <m:mn>50</m:mn>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where b<subscript>0</subscript>, b<subscript>1</subscript> and
      b<subscript>2</subscript> are regression coefficients, estimated using
      ordinary least squares regression; area represents catchment area in
      km², and I<subscript>6,50</subscript> is the design rainfall intensity
      (mm/h) at catchment centroid for 6 hour duration and 50% AEP. The values
      of b<subscript>0</subscript>, b<subscript>1</subscript> and
      b<subscript>2</subscript> and the regional Growth Factors
      (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) are embedded into the RFFE Model
      2015.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_m01jo">
    <title>Fringe Zones</title>

    <para>The boundaries between the arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144809+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    and Humid Coastal regions in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/>
    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144840+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144840+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    drawn<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144848+1100"?>
    (as a smoothed line)<?oxy_insert_end ?> approximately based on the 500 mm
    mean annual rainfall contour<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144902+1100" content=" line"?>.
    To reduce the effects of sharp variation in flood estimates for the
    ungauged catchments located close to these regional boundaries, seven
    fringe zones <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144908+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144908+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    delineated, as shown <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/>. <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144923+1100"?>The
    boundary of the fringe zone with the Humid Coastal region was
    approximately defined by the 500 mm mean annual rainfall isohyet, while
    the other side was defined by the 400 mm mean annual rainfall isohyet to
    establish a fringe zone. In drawing the boundary, some minor adjustment
    was made to make the boundary as smooth as possible. <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144918+1100" type="split"?></para>

    <para><?oxy_insert_end ?>For these fringe zones, the flood estimate at an
    ungauged catchment location is taken as the inverse distance weighted
    average value of the flood estimates based on the two nearest regions. The
    method is embedded into the RFFE Model 2015.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_yj49v">
    <title>Relative Accuracy of the RFFE Technique</title>

    <para>The reliability and accuracy of the<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144941+1100"?>
    RFFE<?oxy_insert_end ?> quantile estimates <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144954+1100" content="by the RFFE technique is "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T144954+1100"?>were
    <?oxy_insert_end ?>assessed using leave-one-out (LOO) validation. In the
    LOO validation, one catchment <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145000+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145000+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    left out from the model data set and the RFFE technique is applied to the
    catchment that was left out. The flood quantiles estimated using the RFFE
    technique <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145927+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145927+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    then compared with the at-site flood frequency estimates obtained by FLIKE
    (Kuczera, 1999) as mentioned in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_4foca"/>. The
    procedure <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145943+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145943+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    repeated for each catchment in the regional data set to provide an overall
    assessment of the performance of the RFFE technique.</para>

    <para>The reliability of the RFFE flood quantile confidence limits
    described in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_7r0rn"/> <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145957+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T145957+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    assessed empirically using standardised quantile residuals. The quantile
    residual is the difference between the logarithm of flood quantile
    estimates obtained using at-site Flood Frequency Analysis and the RFFE
    technique. The standardised quantile residual is the quantile residual
    divided by its standard deviation which is the square root of the sum of
    the RFFE predictive variance of the flood quantile and at-site quantile
    variance (Haddad and Rahman, 2012; Micevski <emphasis>et al</emphasis>.,
    201<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150004+1100" content="4"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150005+1100"?>5<?oxy_insert_end ?>).
    This accounts for both the model error (e.g. inadequacy of the RFFE model)
    and the sampling error (e.g. due to limite<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150018+1100"?>ations
    in<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150017+1100" content="d"?>
    streamflow record length). If the uncertainty in the log quantile
    estimates has been adequately described, the standardi<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095745+1100"?>s<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095745+1100" content="z"?>ed
    quantile residuals should be consistent with a standard normal
    distribution.</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_6ppin"/> shows the plots of standardised
    residuals vs. normal scores for Region 1 for AEPs of 10% and 5% (the plots
    for other AEPs for Region 1 are provided in Appendix B). Plots for other
    regions can be seen also in Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>.
    (201<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150118+1100"?>5<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150117+1100" content="4"?>b).<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150132+1100"?>
    These residuals were estimated without bias correction (details of bias
    correction are provided in ). <?oxy_insert_end ?> These plots include 558
    catchments from Region 1 used in the RFFE model and some 28 catchments
    which were excluded from the<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150254+1100"?>
    final<?oxy_insert_end ?> RFFE model<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150259+1100"?>
    data set<?oxy_insert_end ?> based on the results of preliminary analysis
    and unusual characteristics such as significant natural floodplain
    storage. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_6ppin"/> reveals that most of the 558
    catchments closely follow a 1:1 straight line indicating that the
    assumption of normality of the residuals <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150319+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150319+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    not inconsistent with the evidence; this is supported by the application
    of the Anderson-Darling and Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests which
    show<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150326+1100"?>ed<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    that the assumption of the normality of the residuals cannot be rejected
    at the 10% level of significance. Under the assumptions of normality,
    approximately 90% of the standardised quantile residuals should lie
    between ± 2, which is largely satisfied. There <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150347+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T150347+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    a few catchments with standardised residual values close to ± 3. These
    correspond to instances where the RFFE confidence limits may not be
    reliable; an example of such<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095809+1100"?>
    a<?oxy_insert_end ?> catchment is provided in <xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_s_p4hvx"/>. <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095813+1100"?>The
    <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095814+1100" content="S"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095814+1100"?>s<?oxy_insert_end ?>ame
    conclusion applies to the other Humid Coastal regions.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_6ppin">
      <title>Standardised residuals vs. normal scores for Region 1 based on
      Leave One Out validation for AEPs of 10% and 5%</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="75%" fileref="../../figures/3041.PNG"
                     scalefit="1" width="75%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>The main conclusion from this analysis is that the quantification of
    uncertainty in the quantile estimates by the RFFE technique is reliable
    for the vast majority of the cases. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_6ppin"/> and
    <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_p4hvx"/> serve as a reminder that some catchments
    may not be adequately represented by the catchments used in the RFFE
    analysis. Users of the RFFE Model 2015 should check that the catchment of
    interest is not atypical compared with the gauged catchments included in
    the ROI used to develop the RFFE estimate. To assist users in this regard
    the RFFE Model 2015 discussed in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs"/> and
    <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8airu"/> lists the RFFE Model gauged catchments
    located nearest to the ungauged catchment of interest. <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151118T163906+1100" type="split"?></para>

    <para><?oxy_insert_end ?>The accuracy of the flood quantile estimates
    provided by the RFFE technique is evaluated by using the Relative Error
    (RE) defined as:</para>

    <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_tq1ze">
      <m:math display="block">
        <m:mrow>
          <m:mi>RE(%)</m:mi>

          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

          <m:mrow>
            <m:mfrac>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>RFFE</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>-</m:mo>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>FFA</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mi>FFA</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
            </m:mfrac>

            <m:mo>×</m:mo>

            <m:mi>100</m:mi>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:mrow>
      </m:math>
    </equation>

    <para>where Q<subscript>RFFE</subscript> is the flood quantile estimate
    for a given site for a given AEP by the RFFE technique; and
    Q<subscript>FFA</subscript> is the flood quantile estimate from the
    at-site Flood Frequency Analysis<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164218+1100"?>
    (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_i6yzh"/> for details).<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164217+1100" content="."?></para>

    <para>It should be noted that the Relative Error given by <xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_e_tq1ze"/> makes no allowance for the fact that the
    at-site flood frequency estimates are themselves subject to sampling
    error. Therefore, this error should be seen as an upper bound on the true
    relative error.</para>

    <para>It should be noted here that LOO is a more rigorous validation
    technique compared with the split-sample validation where the model is
    tested on a smaller number of catchments (e.g. 10% of the total
    catchments). Hence, the relative error that is generated by LOO is
    expected to be higher than if split-sample validation were used. The
    medians of the absolute relative error values from the LOO validation for
    different regions are reported in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_0hp5h"/>. It can
    be seen that for the Humid Coastal regions, Region 5 (SW W<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164147+1100" content="estern Australia"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164147+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end ?>)
    has the highest relative error (59 to 69%) and Region 3 (<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164108+1100" content="South Australia"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164108+1100"?>Humid
    SA<?oxy_insert_end ?>) has the smallest relative error (33 to 41%).</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_jsne6">
    <title>Bias Correction</title>

    <para>In the spatial plots of the standardised residuals,
    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162607+1100"?>a
    <?oxy_insert_end ?>few <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162611+1100" content="pockets"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162612+1100"?>cluster<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    of notable under-estimation and over-estimation <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162619+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162619+1100"?>were<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    detected. To overcome this problem, a bias correction <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162625+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162625+1100"?>was<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    implemented, which attemp<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162631+1100"?>ed<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162631+1100" content="t"?>s
    to provide estimates of <emphasis role="italic">M</emphasis> (for Humid
    Coastal areas) (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162751+1100"?><xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_e_yitfd"/><?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162640+1100" content="Equation 1"?>)
    and Q<subscript>10</subscript> (for arid<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162922+1100"?>/semi-arid<?oxy_insert_end ?>
    areas) (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162903+1100"?><xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_e_6mwfc"/><?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162845+1100" content="Equation 12"?>)
    closer to the observed <emphasis role="italic">M</emphasis> or
    Q<subscript>10</subscript> at the location of each of the 853 model gauged
    catchments. This <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162935+1100" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162935+1100"?>correction
    was<?oxy_insert_end ?> based on <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162946+1100" content="a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162946+1100"?>an
    additive<?oxy_insert_end ?> bias correction factor <inlineequation>
        <m:math display="inline">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>M</m:mi>

              <m:mi>FFA</m:mi>
            </m:msub>

            <m:mo>-</m:mo>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>M</m:mi>

              <m:mi>RFFE</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </inlineequation><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162959+1100" content="(Q&lt;subscript&gt;obs_FFA/QRFFE_predicted&lt;/subscript&gt;"?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T163110+1100" content=")"?>,
    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T163113+1100"?>(<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T163124+1100" content="obtained at each of the 853 model gauged catchments"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T163124+1100"?>obtained
    at each of the model 798 gauged catchments in the Humid Coastal
    areas)<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T163143+1100" content="."?>
    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T163141+1100" content="A regional smooth bias correction factor is then derived applying a Natural Neighbor approach, which is embedded in the RFFE Model. In practice, for an ungauged location of interest, an interpolated bias correction factor is calculated by the software based on nearby 15 gauged catchments. It is found that this approach reduces the pockets of bias in the spatial plots of the standardised residuals and hence adopted in the RFFE Model 2015."?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T163141+1100"?>and
    <inlineequation>
        <m:math display="inline">
          <m:mfrac bevelled="true">
            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>10</m:mi>

                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                <m:mi>FFA</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:msub>

            <m:msub>
              <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>10</m:mi>

                <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                <m:mi>RFFE</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:msub>
          </m:mfrac>
        </m:math>
      </inlineequation> (obtained at each of the model 55 catchments in
    arid/semi-arid areas). In practice, for an ungauged location of interest,
    an interpolated bias correction factor is calculated by the software using
    Natural Neighbour approach based on nearby 15 gauged catchments. It was
    found that this approach reduced the clusters of bias in the spatial plots
    of the standardised residuals and hence was adopted in the RFFE Model
    2015. <?oxy_insert_end ?></para>

    <para><table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_0hp5h">
        <title>Upper bound on (absolute) median relative error (RE) from
        leave-one-out validation of the R<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162542+1100" content="EE"?>F<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162545+1100"?>FE<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        technique<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162551+1100"?>
        (without considering bias correction)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <tgroup cols="7">
          <colspec align="center"/>

          <colspec colname="_2"/>

          <colspec colname="_3"/>

          <colspec colname="_4"/>

          <colspec colname="_5"/>

          <colspec colname="_6"/>

          <colspec colname="_7"/>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry morerows="2">Region</entry>

              <entry nameend="_7" namest="_2">Median RE (%)</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry nameend="_7" namest="_2">AEP</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>50%</entry>

              <entry>20%</entry>

              <entry>10%</entry>

              <entry>5%</entry>

              <entry>2%</entry>

              <entry>1%</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 1: East Co<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162538+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?>st</entry>

              <entry>51</entry>

              <entry>49</entry>

              <entry>52</entry>

              <entry>53</entry>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <entry>59</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 2: Tasmania</entry>

              <entry>53</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>46</entry>

              <entry>45</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 3: Humid SA</entry>

              <entry>38</entry>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <entry>33</entry>

              <entry>35</entry>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <entry>41</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 4: Top End NT and Kimberl<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162529+1100"?>e<?oxy_insert_end ?>y</entry>

              <entry>33</entry>

              <entry>36</entry>

              <entry>36</entry>

              <entry>38</entry>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <entry>47</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 5: SW WA</entry>

              <entry>61</entry>

              <entry>59</entry>

              <entry>66</entry>

              <entry>68</entry>

              <entry>68</entry>

              <entry>69</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 6: Pilbara</entry>

              <entry>35</entry>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <entry>35</entry>

              <entry>42</entry>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <entry>43</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Region 7: Arid and Semi-arid</entry>

              <entry>63</entry>

              <entry>67</entry>

              <entry>67</entry>

              <entry>61</entry>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <entry>49</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table></para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_5x575">
    <title>Combining Regional and At-Site Quantile Estimates</title>

    <para>Unless a station has a very long <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162500+1100"?>a<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162500+1100" content="A"?>nnual
    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162502+1100"?>m<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162502+1100" content="M"?>aximum
    flood series data (e.g. greater than 100 years), it is desirable to
    combine at-site and regional flood frequency quantile estimates to achieve
    a more accurate estimate. The RFFE Model 2015 (see <xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs"/> for the description of the model) provides the
    necessary parameter set and data in its output to combine the regional
    flood quantile estimates with the at-site data. This is discussed in more
    detail in Book 3 Chapter 2.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_31eib">
    <title>Impact of Climate Change</title>

    <para>The adopted regional estimation equations include design rainfall
    intensity as a key input variable. As a result the impact of climate
    change as reflected in changes in design rainfall estimates (which are
    expected to be upgraded regularly) can be propagated through the RFFE
    Model 2015 to provide a first order estimate of the impact of climate
    change on regional design flood estimates. This approach assumes that that
    the contribution of the other catchment characteristics affecting flood
    production does not change with future climate state<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162352+1100" content="s"?>.
    Given that this assumption is unlikely to be valid (Ball,
    2014)<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162408+1100" content=","?>
    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162421+1100" content="the use of potential future rainfall intensities in the RFFE Model 2015 illustrates the sensitivity of the current design flood estimates to the rainfall intensities"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162421+1100"?>the
    use of potential future rainfall intensities in the RFFE Model 2015 will
    indicate the sensitivity of the design flood estimates with respect to
    climate change state. Further research on the impact of climate change on
    rainfall and flood in Australia will allow updating of the RFFE Model 2015
    by incorporating the impact of climate change<?oxy_insert_end ?>.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Progressive Improvement of RFFE Model 2015 v1</title>

    <para>It is expected that the RFFE Model 2015 v1 will be updated in
    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162320+1100" content="near "?>future
    when the streamflow record lengths at the selected 853 gauged catchments
    increase significantly and/or when additional catchments are available
    that satisfy the criteria of catchment selection (<xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_s_wfiku"/>). Furthermore, additional predictor variables
    can potentially be included in the RFFE Model to enhance model accuracy,
    in particular if GIS based techniques can be adopted to
    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151124T095936+1100"?>more
    readily <?oxy_insert_end ?>extract the additional predictor variables such
    as stream density and main stream slope.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8airu">
    <title>Practical Considerations for Application of the RFFE
    Technique</title>

    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T162123+1100"?>

    <para>The basis of the RFFE Model 2015 has been the analysis of all
    available stream gauging stations that meet the selection criteria
    described in this chapter, primarily that the stream gauge has an adequate
    length of record and the streamflow data are of “reasonable” quality and
    relate to relatively natural catchments. Most selected stream gauges have
    a catchment area less than 1,000 km2. The RFFE Model parameters were then
    developed based on regionalisation of the at-site flood quantiles for all
    of these gauges from a given region. All available and suitable streamflow
    data for all of Australia were adopted to develop the RFFE Model. While
    the RFFE Model is appropriate for catchment types represented by the
    gauged catchments used to develop this model, there are catchments where
    the method either cannot be applied or where there may be gross error in
    the flood quantile estimates if the RFFE Model were applied without
    adjustments. These catchment types are described below.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Urban
    catchments</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>One of the criteria for catchment selection in the development of
    the RFFE Model was that there should be essentially no urbanisation in the
    catchment, or at least such a small proportion that it does not affect
    flood generation. It is well known that flooding is affected, sometimes
    significantly by urbanisation. There are insufficient gauged urban
    catchments to allow development of a RFFE model for urban
    catchments.</para>

    <para>Therefore, the RFFE Model 2015 cannot be applied for any catchment
    where urbanisation accounts for more than 10% of the catchment area, or
    where it is considered that there may be an impact of urbanisation on
    rainfall runoff relationship. In these cases an alternative approach for
    estimating design floods is needed, as no equivalent regional method to
    the rural RFFE Model is available.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Catchments containing
    dams and other artificial storage</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>Dams or other artificial water storages attenuate flood hydrographs
    and therefore reduce the flood peak discharges at the catchment outlet.
    The catchments with dams that were regarded as sufficiently significant to
    have an impact on flood discharges were not included in the database used
    in the development of the RFFE Model. Hence, for a catchment having a dam
    of significant size, the RFFE Model cannot be applied directly. In this
    case, the RFFE Model can be used to calculate design flood discharges for
    the “natural” catchment condition and then the effects of the dam should
    be included by an appropriate technique such as the application of a
    runoff-routing model where the storage effects can be modelled
    directly.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Catchments affected by
    mining</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>Catchments where mining activity has affected a significant
    proportion of the catchment were not included in the database used in the
    development of the RFFE Model. Catchments where mining activities are
    significant may produce lower flood peak discharges than the natural
    condition. The smaller peak discharges result from the water management
    processes implemented in the mining operation where runoff is controlled
    and managed in water quality ponds, tailings dams and other water
    management infrastructure and the mine pit itself. In addition, runoff
    from mining areas including waste dumps and rehabilitated areas is quite
    distinct from catchments in their natural state.</para>

    <para>In cases where mining is judged to impact a significant proportion
    of a catchment, the RFFE Model can only be applied on the natural portions
    of the catchment. The area affected by mining activities should be
    modelled by an alternative method. Assessment of the water balance
    affecting the volume of runoff is needed to ensure that the effects of
    water control in ponds and mine pits and infiltration in highly modified
    catchments is represented correctly. The catchment response is also
    affected by drainage works and diversions. Calculation of runoff from
    mining areas is a complex and specialised exercise and detailed
    understanding of individual conditions is necessary. In general, a
    detailed runoff-routing model is needed as well as a good understanding of
    the water balance in these situations. However, direct calibration of
    runoff routing models on ungauged catchments is not possible, which may
    result in grossly inaccurate design flood estimates.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Catchments with
    intensive agricultural activity</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>While most of the catchments used in development of the RFFE Model
    have been located in agricultural regions, few are in areas of intensive
    agriculture, where the flood response may have been affected by farm dams,
    soil conservation works and irrigation infrastructure. Many intensive
    agricultural catchments have a topography that is artificial and quite
    different from the natural catchment condition. The objective of works on
    agricultural land is often to slow the rate of runoff and increase
    infiltration to the soil profile, thus the flood peak discharges is often
    reduced on these catchment types as compared to the natural catchments.
    Catchments affected by intense agricultural activities are similar to
    those affected by mining. In this case, the RFFE Model cannot be applied
    directly, and hence additional analysis is needed to assess the catchment
    characteristics and then develop a runoff-routing model to adjust the
    generic RFFE Model results using the catchment storage and channel
    characteristics. However, direct calibration of runoff routing models on
    ungauged catchments is not possible, which may result in grossly
    inaccurate design flood estimates.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Catchment
    size</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>The RFFE Model has been developed using all suitable gauged
    catchments throughout Australia with catchment areas generally less than
    1,000 km2. The RFFE Model can be applied to small catchments with no lower
    limit though it is recognised that there are only a few gauged catchments
    smaller than 10 km2 included in the database to develop the RFFE Model.
    Because of the limited available data, it is likely that there will be a
    greater degree of error in the quantile estimates for these smaller
    catchments. The RFFE Model should not be applied for catchments larger
    than 1,000 km2 because these larger catchments were not generally used in
    the development of the method.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Catchment
    shape</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>The distribution of the shape factors of the selected catchments in
    developing the RFFE Model is shown in Table 2. An ungauged catchment with
    shape factor beyond 10%-90% limit as shown in Table 2 will have lower
    accuracy in the estimated flood quantiles.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Atypical catchment
    types</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>The catchment characteristics adopted in the RFFE Model were limited
    to readily available/easily obtainable catchment variables. It is known
    that there are many other catchment characteristics that influence
    catchment response and flood discharges. These include factors such
    as:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment land use including vegetation coverage: The extent of
        clearing or forest cover can have a significant impact, especially in
        the south-west of Western Australia, for example.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Soils and geology: These factors influence the rainfall losses
        and catchment flood response.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Slopes: Steeper catchments respond more rapidly and therefore
        produce larger flood peaks.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Channel types and floodplain storage: Well defined channels and
        smaller floodplain storage extents produce faster response and
        therefore larger flood peaks.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>In cases where the catchment requiring the design flood estimate is
    judged to have characteristics significantly different from those used in
    the development of the RFFE Model, further hydrology and hydraulic
    analyses may be needed to refine the results from the generic RFFE Model
    results.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Catchment
    location</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>Considering the large size of Australia and the relatively small
    number of gauged catchments used for the development of the RFFE Model,
    the density of the gauged catchments used in developing the model is quite
    low. In addition, it must be recognised that there are errors in the
    streamflow data (e.g. rating curve extrapolation error) used to develop
    the RFFE Model. This means that catchments where design flood discharges
    are needed may be remote from the gauged catchments used to develop the
    RFFE Model and may have distinct differences from the adopted gauged
    catchments. In these cases, the application of the RFFE Model may produce
    grossly inaccurate results and hence additional review and checking are
    necessary to confirm that the catchment being analysed has similar
    characteristics to those used to develop the RFFE Model. Where there are
    significant differences, a similar assessment to that needed for atypical
    catchments should be considered, and an adjustment to the generic RFFE
    Model result may be needed.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Arid/semi-arid
    areas</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>The arid/semi-arid areas of Australia pose a particular problem. The
    RFFE Model divides these areas into two regions (1) Pilbara and (2) Arid
    and semi-arid. There are few gauged catchments in these regions. Only 55
    gauged catchments in total from an area of about 5 million km2 were
    included in the database to develop the RFFE Model for these two
    regions.</para>

    <para>The stream gauges located in these areas are often located in sites
    that may not be ideal, since the gauge sites are selected because of
    access, confined channel and stable control, which may not be typical of
    the types of sites where design flood discharges are needed in these
    areas.</para>

    <para>The Pilbara region, however, is not as diverse a region as the other
    arid and semi-arid region, which covers a very wide range of
    conditions.</para>

    <para>The RFFE Model estimates are likely to be associated with a higher
    level of error for arid/semi-arid areas. Because of this, the
    arid/semi-arid areas may require some additional analysis to refine the
    generic RFFE Model results. The RFFE Model data base report (Rahman et
    al., 2015a) has a listing of all of the catchments that were used in the
    development of the RFFE Model and the application of the RFFE software
    provides a map of the neighbouring catchments that were used in the
    development of the RFFE Model.</para>

    <para>The application of the RFFE Model in arid/semi-arid areas therefore
    may involve the following steps.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Calculate the design flood discharges using the RFFE Model and
        produce the table of design flood discharges for the target
        catchment.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Review the catchment characteristics of the target catchment.
        This should include the location, slopes, geology, land use and
        vegetation.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Review the neighbouring gauged catchments (identified on the map
        produced by the RFFE Model and in the RFFE model output of the list of
        nearby gauged catchments) taking into account similarity or
        dissimilarity of catchment characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Compare the catchment characteristics of the target catchment as
        well as the gauged catchments, in conjunction with results from
        alternative methods (if available), and determine an appropriate
        adjustment to the generic RFFE Model results.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis
    role="italic">Baseflow</emphasis></emphasis></para>

    <para>The RFFE Model has been developed using at-site flood frequency
    analysis results, so the peak discharges calculated using the RFFE Model
    include baseflow. This means that the flood quantiles from the RFFE Model
    are not directly comparable with those from runoff-routing models where
    only surface runoff is estimated. While baseflow is only a minor part of
    the total flood hydrograph in most Australian catchments, there are some
    areas where baseflow is more significant and, in particular, it becomes
    more important when considering smaller floods. When working with the two
    methods, the issue of baseflow should be addressed in the consideration of
    the total flood peak discharge and estimated hydrograph.</para>

    <?oxy_insert_end ?>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs">
    <title>RFFE Model 2015</title>

    <para>The RFFE technique presented in this chapter has been incorporated
    into a software tool referred to as RFFE Model 2015.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161637+1100"?>
    The current version of the RFFE Model 2015 can be accessed from the ARR
    website<footnote>
        <para>www.arr.org.au</para>
      </footnote>.<?oxy_insert_end ?> <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_i5krg"/>
    presents a screen shot of the RFFE Model 2015 software landing page. The
    model requires the following basic inputs (to be entered by the user in
    the interface shown in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_8n08s"/>) for the catchment
    of interest to generate design flood estimates for six AEPs (50%, 20%,
    10%, 5%, 2% and 1%).</para>

    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161456+1100" content="&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Latitude of catchment centroid in decimal degrees;&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Longitude of catchment centroid in decimal degrees;&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Latitude of catchment outlet in decimal degrees;&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Longitude of catchment outlet in decimal degrees;&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Catchment area in km&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt;; and&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Catchment name.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;"?>

    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161456+1100"?>

    <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment name;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment outlet latitude in decimal degrees;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment outlet longitude in decimal degrees;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment centroid latitude in decimal degrees;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment centroid longitude in decimal degrees; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment area in km<superscript>2</superscript>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <?oxy_insert_end ?>

    <para>In the "Advanced" data input option, the user can also enter the
    following inputs:</para>

    <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
      <listitem>
        <para>Region name (can be selected from the dropdown
        list<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161416+1100"?>,
        <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161415+1100" content=" ("?>see
        <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_gpkr3"/><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161349+1100" content=")"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161420+1100"?>
        for region name and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> for the extent of
        the regions<?oxy_insert_end ?>);<table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_gpkr3">
            <title>Region names for application of the RFFE Model 2015 (see
            <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> for the extent of the
            regions)</title>

            <tgroup cols="2">
              <thead>
                <row>
                  <entry align="center">Region name</entry>

                  <entry align="center">Region code</entry>
                </row>
              </thead>

              <tbody>
                <row>
                  <entry>Region 1: East Coast</entry>

                  <entry>1</entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>Region 2: Tasmania</entry>

                  <entry>2</entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>Region 3: Humid SA</entry>

                  <entry>3</entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>Region 4: Top End NT and Kimberl<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161235+1100"?>e<?oxy_insert_end ?>y</entry>

                  <entry>4</entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>Region 5: SW WA</entry>

                  <entry>5</entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>Region 6: Pilbara</entry>

                  <entry>6</entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry>Region 7: Arid and Semi-arid</entry>

                  <entry>7</entry>
                </row>
              </tbody>
            </tgroup>
          </table></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid for 50% AEP and
        duration of 6-hour in mm/h; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid for
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161230+1100"?>2<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161230+1100" content="50"?>%
        AEP and duration of 6-hour in mm/h.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>The RFFE Model 2015 output contains the following principal
    information (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_0hl0m"/><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161220+1100"?>
    as an example<?oxy_insert_end ?>)<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161213+1100" content=":"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161217+1100"?>.<?oxy_insert_end ?></para>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_i5krg">
      <title>Screen shot of RFFE Model 2015 (landing page)</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3042.PNG"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_8n08s">
      <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for data input for the Wollomombi
      River at Coinside, NSW</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3043.PNG"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_0hl0m">
      <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for model output for the Wollomombi
      River at Coinside, NSW<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T161145+1100"?>
      (Region 1)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3044.PNG"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
      <listitem>
        <para>A table of AEP (in the first column), estimated flood quantiles
        labelled as discharge (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s) in the second
        column, lower confidence limit (5%) (third column) and upper
        confidence limit (95%) (fourth column). The confidence limits
        represent the overall uncertainty with the estimated flood quantiles
        by the RFFE Model 2015.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>A second table labelled <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160727+1100"?>"S<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160728+1100" content="s"?>tatistics<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160730+1100"?>",
        <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160735+1100" content=" tha"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160737+1100"?>w<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160740+1100" content="t"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160740+1100"?>hich<?oxy_insert_end ?>
        shows the statistics for the regional LPIII model at the catchment of
        interest, which are particularly useful to combine at-site and
        regional information to enhance the accuracy of flood quantile
        estimates (for details see Book 3 Chapter 2).</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>A graph that shows estimated flood quantiles and confidence
        limits against AEPs.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>A graph that shows the catchment of interest with outlet and
        centroid locations<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160706+1100"?>
        and nearby gauged catchments that were included in the database to
        develop RFFE technique<?oxy_insert_end ?>.</para>
      </listitem>

      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160658+1100" content="&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;A list that shows various input data used by the model to produce flood estimates.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;"?>

      <listitem>
        <para>A download menu that allows the user to save the
        results<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160646+1100"?>
        and additional outputs<?oxy_insert_end ?> generated by the
        model.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>Three worked examples are provided in <xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_s_ue0ar"/> to illustrate the use of RFFE Model 2015. The
    first two examples relate to catchments with no major regulation, no major
    natural or artificial storage and no major land use changes over time
    where the RFFE Model 2015 is directly applicable.</para>

    <para>The third example relates to a catchment which has significant
    natural floodplain storage where RFFE Model 2015 is not directly
    applicable. For this case, the RFFE Model significantly overestimates the
    flood quantiles (as compared to at-site Flood Frequency Analysis). Here,
    the RFFE Model estimates need to be adjusted to account for the storage
    effect of the catchment by applying an appropriate technique (see
    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164603+1100"?><xref
    linkend="b3_ch3_s_8airu"/><?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T164542+1100" content="&lt;xref linkend=&quot;b3_ch3_s_ft0us&quot;/&gt;"?>
    for further details).</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ue0ar">
    <title>Worked Examples</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_05i4o">
      <title>Application of RFFE Model 2015 to the Wollomombi River at
      Coinside, NSW (Region 1) (a catchment having no major regulation, no
      major natural or artificial storage and no major land use
      change)</title>

      <para>The basic input data for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW are
      provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_rdr78"/>. The model screen shot for
      the data input is provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_8n08s"/>. The
      flood quantiles generated by the RFFE Model 2015 are provided in <xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_f_0hl0m"/>. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_mb7b8"/> compares
      the RFFE Model and at-site FFA estimates, which shows that the RFFE
      Model estimates match the at-site FFA estimates well except for
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160551+1100" content="2% and 1%"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160552+1100"?>rarer<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      AEPs where the RFFE Model estimates are higher compared with the at-site
      FFA estimates. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_mb7b8"/> also shows that the
      confidence <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160533+1100" content="limits"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T160533+1100"?>band<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      of the RFFE Model 2015 is much wider compared with at-site FFA
      confidence band, which is expected.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_mb7b8">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs. at-site FFA flood estimates for the
        Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155355+1100"?>
        (Region 1)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3045.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_rdr78">
        <title>Application data for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW
        (Region 1) (Basic Input Data)</title>

        <tgroup cols="2">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry align="center">Menu</entry>

              <entry align="center">Input</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Name</entry>

              <entry>Wollomombi River at Coinside</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155231+1100"?>Catchment
              Outlet <?oxy_insert_end ?>Latitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155234+1100" content=" (Catchment Centroid) "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155236+1100"?>
              <?oxy_insert_end ?>in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-30.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155321+1100"?>478<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155316+1100" content="352"?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155230+1100"?>Catchment
              Outlet <?oxy_insert_end ?>Longitude<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155246+1100"?>
              in<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155240+1100" content=" (Catchment Centroid) i"?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155243+1100" content="n"?>
              decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155338+1100" content="151.936"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155335+1100"?>152.026<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155221+1100"?>Catchment
              Centroid <?oxy_insert_end ?>Latitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155254+1100" content=" (Catchment Outlet) "?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155255+1100" content="i"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155300+1100"?>
              i<?oxy_insert_end ?>n decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-30.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155327+1100"?>352<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155324+1100" content="478"?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155225+1100"?>Catchment
              Centroid <?oxy_insert_end ?>Longitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155303+1100" content=" (Catchment Outlet) "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155306+1100"?>
              <?oxy_insert_end ?>in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155341+1100" content="152.026"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155341+1100"?>151.936<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Area in km<superscript>2</superscript></entry>

              <entry>376</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>

      <para><xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_3dowt"/> <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154915+1100" content="presents the list of 30"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154915+1100"?>shows
      a list of 15<?oxy_insert_end ?> gauged catchment<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154944+1100"?>s,
      which is generated as part of<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154940+1100" content="s (used in developing"?>
      the RFFE Model<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155000+1100"?>
      output. <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154957+1100" content=") that are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155024+1100"?>In
      this example, these gauged catchments are<?oxy_insert_end ?> located
      closest to the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155048+1100"?>
      and were used in the development of the RFFE model<?oxy_insert_end ?>.
      The user should compare the characteristics of the ungauged catchment of
      interest with those of the nearest gauged catchments <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T155116+1100"?>(as
      in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_3dowt"/>) <?oxy_insert_end ?>to ensure that
      the ungauged catchment is not atypical.</para>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_3dowt">
        <title><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153509+1100"?>Fifteen
        <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153506+1100" content="30 "?>gauged
        catchments (used in the development of RFFE Model 2015) located
        closest to Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW</title>

        <?oxy_attributes cols="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;12&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20151121T153310+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>

        <tgroup cols="10">
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <?oxy_insert_end ?>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <?oxy_insert_end ?>

          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;colspec colwidth=&quot;8*&quot;/&gt;"?>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

          <colspec colwidth="1*"/>

          <colspec colwidth="1*"/>

          <?oxy_insert_end ?>

          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153258+1100" content="&lt;colspec colwidth=&quot;8*&quot;/&gt;&lt;colspec colwidth=&quot;8*&quot;/&gt;"?>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;colspec colwidth=&quot;8*&quot;/&gt;"?>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;colspec colwidth=&quot;8*&quot;/&gt;"?>

          <colspec colwidth="8*"/>

          <colspec colwidth="12*"/>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>Site ID</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>Dist. (km)</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>Area km<superscript>2</superscript></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;Site ID&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>Lat. (outlet)</entry>

              <entry>Long. (outlet)</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153325+1100"?>

              <entry>Lat. (centroid)</entry>

              <entry>Long. (centroid)</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;Area km&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt;&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>Record Length (years)</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;&lt;superscript&gt;50%&lt;/superscript&gt;I&lt;subscript&gt;6h&lt;/subscript&gt;&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;&lt;superscript&gt;2%&lt;/superscript&gt;I&lt;subscript&gt;6h&lt;/subscript&gt;&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>Mean Annual Rainfall (mm)</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;&lt;superscript&gt;50%&lt;/superscript&gt;I&lt;subscript&gt;12h&lt;/subscript&gt;&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>Shape Factor</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;&lt;inlineequation&gt;&lt;m:math display=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;&lt;m:mfrac&gt; &lt;m:mmultiscripts&gt; &lt;m:mi&gt;I&lt;/m:mi&gt; &lt;m:mi&gt;6h&lt;/m:mi&gt; &lt;m:mi/&gt; &lt;m:mprescripts/&gt; &lt;m:mi/&gt; &lt;m:mi&gt;50%&lt;/m:mi&gt; &lt;/m:mmultiscripts&gt; &lt;m:mmultiscripts&gt; &lt;m:mi&gt;I&lt;/m:mi&gt; &lt;m:mi&gt;6h&lt;/m:mi&gt; &lt;m:mi/&gt; &lt;m:mprescripts/&gt; &lt;m:mi/&gt; &lt;m:mi&gt;2%&lt;/m:mi&gt; &lt;/m:mmultiscripts&gt; &lt;/m:mfrac&gt;&lt;/m:math&gt;&lt;/inlineequation&gt;&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206014</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>0<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153356+1100"?>.07<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>376</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206014&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153741+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.478</entry>

              <entry>152.0<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154130+1100" content="3"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154131+1100"?>267<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.352</entry>

              <entry>151.936</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;376&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.92&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;15.92&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>871</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.24&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.8<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154614+1100"?>786<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154613+1100" content="8"?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.3&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206001</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>18</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>163</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206001&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153743+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.59</entry>

              <entry>152.16<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154137+1100"?>17<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.5244</entry>

              <entry>152.279</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;163&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>33</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;9.08&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;22.6&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1167</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.26&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1.08<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154618+1100"?>2<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.48&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>204030</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>24.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153723+1100"?>29<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153721+1100" content="3"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>200</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;204030&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153745+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.26</entry>

              <entry>152.01</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.1904</entry>

              <entry>151.828</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;200&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>34</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;7.13&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;15.1&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>940</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.44&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1.39<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154632+1100"?>46<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.11&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206017</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>28<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153717+1100"?>.01<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>22</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206017&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153747+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.478</entry>

              <entry>152.3<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154140+1100"?>183<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154140+1100" content="2"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.4632</entry>

              <entry>152.352</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;22&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>24</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;10.2&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;25.6&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1167</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;7.21&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.8<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154634+1100"?>005<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.51&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>204008</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>31.6<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153713+1100"?>4<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>31</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;204008&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153749+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.405</entry>

              <entry>152.3<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154145+1100"?>45<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154144+1100" content="5"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.4139</entry>

              <entry>152.382</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;31&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>29</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;10.2&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;25.5&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1249</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;7&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.68<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154639+1100"?>24<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.51&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206026</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>35.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153710+1100"?>67<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153710+1100" content="7"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>8</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206026&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153751+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.42</entry>

              <entry>151.66</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.4201</entry>

              <entry>151.639</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;8&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.92&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;14.6&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>789</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.23&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.73<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154641+1100"?>4<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.11&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206025</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>37.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153707+1100"?>68<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153706+1100" content="7"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>594</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206025&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153753+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.68</entry>

              <entry>151.71</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.6802</entry>

              <entry>151.557</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;594&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>39</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.67&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;14.2&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>945</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.12&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.6<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154644+1100"?>194<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154644+1100" content="2"?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.13&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206034</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>39.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153656+1100"?>29<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153654+1100" content="3"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>117</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206034&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153754+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.7</entry>

              <entry>151.7<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154154+1100"?>067<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154154+1100" content="1"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.7666</entry>

              <entry>151.648</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;117&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>26</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.62&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;14.1&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>758</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.11&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.8<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154649+1100"?>859<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154647+1100" content="9"?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.12&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>418034</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>4<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153648+1100"?>1.98<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153647+1100" content="2"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>14</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;418034&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153755+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.3</entry>

              <entry>151.64</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.2758</entry>

              <entry>151.65</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;14&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>29</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.93&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;14.3&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>818</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.29&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.7<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154655+1100"?>876<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154653+1100" content="9"?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.07&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>418014</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>63.8<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153641+1100"?>3<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>855</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;418014&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153756+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.47</entry>

              <entry>151.36</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.5063</entry>

              <entry>151.476</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;855&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>37</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.60&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.9&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>725</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.01&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.4<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154700+1100"?>171<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154659+1100" content="2"?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.1&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206018</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>68.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153637+1100"?>38<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153636+1100" content="4"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>894</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206018&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153759+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>31.05<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153803+1100" content="2"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153803+1100"?>1<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <entry>151.7<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154159+1100"?>683<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154158+1100" content="7"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.9996</entry>

              <entry>151.634</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;894&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>51</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.68&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.6&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>711</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.12&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.48<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154704+1100"?>46<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.04&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>204017</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>68.6<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153633+1100"?>2<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>82</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;204017&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153819+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.30<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153815+1100" content="7"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153815+1100"?>6<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <entry>152.71<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154204+1100"?>33<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.3529</entry>

              <entry>152.698</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;82&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>40</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;13.6&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;34.2&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1995</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;10.07&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.6<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154709+1100"?>086<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154708+1100" content="1"?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.51&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>204037</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>72.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153630+1100"?>28<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153629+1100" content="3"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>62</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;204037&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153822+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.09</entry>

              <entry>152.63</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-30.1082</entry>

              <entry>152.576</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;62&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>40</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;10.0&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;24.8&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1586</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.93&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.73<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154714+1100"?>02<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.47&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>205002</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>72.5<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153643+1100"?>0<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>433</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;205002&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153823+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>30.42<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153825+1100" content="7"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153825+1100"?>6<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <entry>152.78</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>30.4537</entry>

              <entry>152.566</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;433&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>29</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;11.3&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;28.4&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1570</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;8.16&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>1.0<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154717+1100"?>277<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154717+1100" content="3"?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.5&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <row>
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100"?>

              <entry>206009</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <entry>81.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153625+1100"?>35<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153624+1100" content="4"?></entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100"?>

              <entry>261</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153142+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;206009&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153830+1100"?>-<?oxy_insert_end ?>31.19</entry>

              <entry>151.83</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153309+1100"?>

              <entry>-31.2597</entry>

              <entry>151.757</entry>

              <?oxy_insert_end ?>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153220+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;261&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>57</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153257+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;6.70&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.4&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>910</entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153255+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;4.26&lt;/entry&gt;"?>

              <entry>0.66<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T154721+1100"?>42<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153252+1100" content="&lt;entry&gt;2.01&lt;/entry&gt;"?>
            </row>

            <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T153526+1100" content="&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;81.4&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;205006&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;30.642&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;152.86&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;539&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;35&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;11.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;28.7&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1353&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;8.03&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.56&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;81.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;204034&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;29.763&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;152.21&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;389&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;40&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;7.38&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;15.9&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;914&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.57&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1.03&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.16&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;82.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;205014&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;30.388&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;152.88&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;51&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;24&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.6&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;34.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2151&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;10&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.68&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.55&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;83&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;204026&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;30.25&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;152.85&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;80&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;29&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;12.8&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;31.6&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1894&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;9.39&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.45&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.47&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;84.7&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;419010&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;30.97&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;151.35&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;829&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;32&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;6.95&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.9&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;773&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.33&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.98&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.01&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;84.8&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;418021&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;30.23&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;151.19&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;311&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;34&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;6.75&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;786&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.09&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1.63&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.01&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;85.8&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;204031&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;29.722&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;151.85&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;348&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;20&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;7.25&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;14.7&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;990&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.49&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1.27&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.03&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;99.3&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;204025&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;30.26&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;153.03&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;135&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;42&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;14.4&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;38.3&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1711&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;10.41&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.59&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.67&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;101.6&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;207015&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;31.372&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;152.25&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;342&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;27&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;7.93&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;16.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1678&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;5.49&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.76&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.08&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;102.9&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;419054&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;31.04&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;151.17&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;391&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;37&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;6.83&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;780.1&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.24&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.96&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1.98&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;105.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;207006&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;31.39&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;152.33&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;363&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;36&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;10.4&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;23.1&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1558&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;7.09&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.8&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.22&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;107.3&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;419016&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;31.06&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;151.13&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;907&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;34&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;6.63&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;13.1&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;794&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.08&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.56&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1.98&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;107.7&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;418005&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;29.92&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;151.11&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;259&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;40&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;7.90&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;16.0&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;876&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.87&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.93&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.02&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;115.2&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;416016&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;29.79&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;151.13&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;726&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;40&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;8.18&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;16.6&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;788&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;4.93&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.9&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.03&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;&lt;row&gt;&lt;entry&gt;116.3&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;205007&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;30.118&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;153.16&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;11&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;22&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;12.5&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;34.0&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;1577&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;8.07&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;0.79&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;entry&gt;2.71&lt;/entry&gt;&lt;/row&gt;"?>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ydu7q">
      <title>Application for the Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western
      Australia (Region 5) (a catchment having no major regulation, no major
      natural or artificial storage and no major land use change)</title>

      <para>The basic input data for the Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152210+1100" content="Western Australia"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152210+1100"?>WA<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152216+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152216+1100"?>is<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_5qduj"/>. The model screen shot for
      the data input is provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_yklir"/>. The
      flood quantiles generated by the RFFE Model 2015 are provided in <xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_f_9yh35"/>. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_afke3"/> compares
      the RFFE Model and at-site FFA flood estimates which shows that RFFE
      Model estimates match the at-site FFA estimates quite well for all the
      six AEPs. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_afke3"/> also shows that the
      confidence <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152303+1100" content="limits"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152303+1100"?>band<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      by the RFFE Model 2015 is much wider compared with at-site FFA
      confidence <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152258+1100" content="limits"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152258+1100"?>band<?oxy_insert_end ?>,
      which is as expected.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_yklir">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for data input for Four Mile Brook
        at Netic Rd, SW W<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152127+1100" content="estern Australia"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152127+1100"?>A
        (Region 5)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3046.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para><table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_5qduj">
          <title>Application data for Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western
          Australia (Region 5) (Basic Input Data)</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry align="center">Menu</entry>

                <entry align="center">Input</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Catchment Name</entry>

                <entry>Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151955+1100"?>Catchment
                Outlet <?oxy_insert_end ?>Latitude <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152014+1100"?>i<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152006+1100" content="(Catchment Centroid) "?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152010+1100" content="i"?>n
                decimal degrees</entry>

                <entry>-34.3<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152041+1100"?>0<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152041+1100" content="18"?></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151958+1100"?>Catchment
                Outlet <?oxy_insert_end ?>Longitude <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152017+1100" content="(Catchment Centroid) "?>in
                decimal degrees</entry>

                <entry>116.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152047+1100"?>00<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152044+1100" content="021"?></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151944+1100"?>Catchment
                Centroid <?oxy_insert_end ?>Latitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152022+1100" content=" ("?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152024+1100"?>
                <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151952+1100" content="Catchment Outlet)"?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152021+1100" content=" "?>in
                decimal degrees</entry>

                <entry>-34.3<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152051+1100"?>18<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152050+1100" content="0"?></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151947+1100"?>Catchment
                Centroid <?oxy_insert_end ?>Longitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152033+1100" content=" ("?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152034+1100"?>
                <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152028+1100" content="Catchment Outlet) "?>in
                decimal degrees</entry>

                <entry>116.0<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152055+1100"?>21<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152055+1100" content="0"?></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Catchment Area in<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152105+1100"?>
                (km<superscript>2</superscript>)<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T152104+1100" content=" sq km"?></entry>

                <entry>13.1</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_9yh35">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for model output for Four Mile
        Brook at Netic Rd, SW <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151911+1100" content="Western Australia"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151911+1100"?>WA
        (Region 5)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3047.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_afke3">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs. at-site FFA flood estimates for Four Mile
        Brook at Netic Rd, SW <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151846+1100" content="Western Australia"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151847+1100"?>WA
        (Region 5)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3048.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_p4hvx">
      <title>Application for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region 1) (a
      catchment having significant natural floodplain storage where RFFE Model
      2015 output is not directly applicable)</title>

      <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151659+1100" content="The basic input data for the"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151659+1100"?>This
      example<?oxy_insert_end ?> <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151703+1100"?>(<?oxy_insert_end ?>Morass
      Creek at Uplands, VIC<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151709+1100"?>)<?oxy_insert_end ?>
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151735+1100" content="are"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151735+1100"?>illustrates
      a catchment type where the RFFE Model is not applicable. The basic input
      data for this catchment is <?oxy_insert_end ?> provided in <xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_t_z9vfi"/>. The model screen shot for the data input is
      provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_79qkw"/>. The flood quantiles
      generated by the RFFE Model 2015 are provided in <xref
      linkend="b3_ch3_f_w08tl"/>. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_4v50p"/> compares
      the RFFE Model and at-site FFA flood estimates, which shows that RFFE
      Model estimates are much higher compared with at-site FFA estimates.
      This catchment has significant natural floodplain storage which is not
      typical for other catchments in the Region of Influence (ROI) on which
      the RFFE Model 2015 estimates are based. The RFFE Model 2015 estimates
      are thus not directly applicable. Here, the RFFE Model estimates would
      need to be adjusted downwards to account for the floodplain storage
      effect by applying an appropriate technique.</para>

      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_z9vfi">
        <title>Application data for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region
        1) (Basic Input Data)</title>

        <tgroup cols="2">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry align="center">Menu</entry>

              <entry align="center">Input</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Name</entry>

              <entry>Morass Creek at Uplands</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151123+1100"?>Catchment
              Outlet <?oxy_insert_end ?>Latitud<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151205+1100"?>e<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151206+1100" content="e "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151207+1100"?>
              <?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151137+1100" content="(Catchment Centroid) i"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151251+1100"?>i<?oxy_insert_end ?>n
              decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-36.8<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151300+1100"?>7<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151300+1100" content="8"?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151158+1100"?>Catchment
              Outlet <?oxy_insert_end ?>Longitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151212+1100" content=" ("?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151151+1100" content="Catchment Centroid)"?>
              in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>147.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151303+1100"?>70<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151303+1100" content="84"?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151137+1100"?>Catchment
              Centroid <?oxy_insert_end ?>Latitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151220+1100" content=" "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151242+1100"?>
              i<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151240+1100" content="(Catchment Outlet) i"?>n
              decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>-36.8<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151307+1100"?>8<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151306+1100" content="7"?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151151+1100"?>Catchment
              Centroid <?oxy_insert_end ?>Longitude<?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151158+1100" content=" (Catchment Outlet)"?>
              in decimal degrees</entry>

              <entry>147.<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151310+1100"?>84<?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151309+1100" content="7"?></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Catchment Area in <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151327+1100"?>(<?oxy_insert_end ?>km<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151318+1100"?><superscript>2</superscript><?oxy_insert_end ?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151315+1100" content="2"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151324+1100"?>)<?oxy_insert_end ?></entry>

              <entry>471</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_79qkw">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for data input for the Morass Creek
        at Uplands, VIC<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151028+1100"?>
        (Region 1)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3049.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_w08tl">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 screen shot for model output for the Morass
        Creek at Uplands, VIC<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151021+1100"?>
        (Region 1)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3050.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_4v50p">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs. at-site FFA flood estimates (for the Morass
        Creek at Uplands, VIC)<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T151010+1100"?>
        (Region 1)<?oxy_insert_end ?></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3051.PNG"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8c69c">
    <title>References</title>

    <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T150929+1100"?>

    <para>Adams CA (1984), “Regional flood estimation for ungauged rural
    catchments in Victoria”, MEngSc Thesis, The University of
    Melbourne.</para>

    <para>Ball JE (2014), “Flood estimation under climate change”, <emphasis
    role="italic">19th IAHR-APD Congress</emphasis>, Hanoi, Vietnam.</para>

    <para>Bates BC (1994), <emphasis role="italic">“Regionalisation of
    hydrological data: A review”</emphasis>, Report 94/5, CRC for Catchment
    Hydrology, Monash University.</para>

    <para>Bates BC, Rahman A, Mein RG and Weinmann PE (1998), Climatic and
    physical factors that influence the homogeneity of regional floods in
    south-eastern Australia, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, 34(12), 3369-3382.</para>

    <para>Burn DH (1990a), An appraisal of the region of influence approach to
    Flood Frequency Analysis, <emphasis role="italic">Hydrological Sciences
    Journal</emphasis>, 35, 2, 149-165.</para>

    <para>Burn DH (1990b), Evaluation of regional Flood Frequency Analysis
    with a region of influence approach, <emphasis role="italic">Water
    Resources Research</emphasis>, 26, 10, 2257-2265.</para>

    <para>Cohn TA, England JF, Berenbrock CE, Mason RR, Stedinger JR and
    Lamontagne JR (2013), A generalized Grubbs-Beck test statistic for
    detecting multiple potentially influential low outliers in flood series,
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 49,
    5047–5058.</para>

    <para>French R (2002), “Flaws in the rational method”,<emphasis
    role="italic"> Proc. 27th National Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symp</emphasis>., Melbourne.</para>

    <para>Farquharson FAK, Meigh JR and Sutcliffe JV (1992), Regional Flood
    Frequency Analysis in arid and semi-arid areas, <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, 138, 487-501.</para>

    <para>Griffis VW and Stedinger JR (2007), The use of GLS regression in
    regional hydrologic analyses, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, 344, 82-95.</para>

    <para>Hackelbusch A, Micevski T, Kuczera G, Rahman A and Haddad K (2009),
    “Regional Flood Frequency Analysis for eastern New South Wales: a region
    of influence approach using generalised least squares based parameter
    regression”, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 31st Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symp</emphasis>., Newcastle, 603-615.</para>

    <para>Haddad K (2008), <emphasis role="italic">“Design flood estimation in
    ungauged catchments using a quantile regression technique: ordinary and
    generalised least squares methods compared for Victoria”</emphasis>,
    Masters (Honours) thesis, School of Engineering, University of Western
    Sydney, New South Wales.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A and Weinmann PE (2008), “Development of a
    generalised least squares based quantile regression technique for design
    flood estimation in Victoria”, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 31st
    Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., Adelaide,
    2546-2557.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Pirozzi J, McPherson G, Rahman A and Kuczera G (2009),
    “Regional flood estimation technique for NSW: application of generalised
    least squares quantile regression technique”,<emphasis role="italic">
    Proc. 32nd Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., Newcastle,
    829-840.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A, Weinmann PE, Kuczera G and Ball JE (2010),
    Streamflow data preparation for regional Flood Frequency Analysis: Lessons
    from south-east Australia, <emphasis role="italic">Australian Journal of
    Water Resources</emphasis>, 14, 1, 17-32.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A and Kuczera G (2011), Comparison of ordinary and
    generalised least squares regression models in regional Flood Frequency
    Analysis: A case study for New South Wales, <emphasis
    role="italic">Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>, 15, 2,
    59-70.</para>

    <para>Haddad K and Rahman A (2012), Regional Flood Frequency Analysis in
    eastern Australia: Bayesian GLS regression-based methods within fixed
    region and ROI framework – quantile regression vs. parameter regression
    technique,<emphasis role="italic"> Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>,
    430-431, 142-161.</para>

    <para>Haddad K, Rahman A and Stedinger JR (2012), Regional Flood Frequency
    Analysis using Bayesian generalised least squares: A comparison between
    quantile and parameter regression techniques, <emphasis
    role="italic">Hydrological Processes</emphasis>, 26, 1008-1021.</para>

    <para>Hosking JRM and Wallis JR (1993), Some statistics useful in regional
    frequency analysis, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
    Research</emphasis>, 29(2), 271-281.</para>

    <para>Institution of Engineers Australia (I. E. Aust.) (1987, 2001),
    <emphasis role="italic">“Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A Guide to Flood
    Estimation”</emphasis>. Editor: D.H. Pilgrim, Vol. 1, I. E. Aust.,
    Canberra.</para>

    <para>Ishak E, Rahman A, Westra S, Sharma A and Kuczera G (2013),
    Evaluating the non-stationarity of Australian annual maximum floods,
    <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, 494,
    134-145.</para>

    <para>Kuczera G (1999), Comprehensive at-site Flood Frequency Analysis
    using Monte Carlo Bayesian inference. <emphasis role="italic">Water
    Resources Research</emphasis>, 35, 5, 1551-1557.</para>

    <para>Lamontagne JR, Stedinger JR, Cohn TA and Barth NA (2013), “Robust
    national flood frequency guidelines: What is an outlier?”,<emphasis
    role="italic"> Proc. World Environmental and Water Resources
    Congress</emphasis>, ASCE, 2454-2466.</para>

    <para>Micevski T and Kuczera G (2009), Combining site and regional flood
    information using a Bayesian Monte Carlo approach, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 45, W04405,
    doi:10.1029/2008WR007173.</para>

    <para>Micevski T, Hackelbusch A, Haddad K. Kuczera G and Rahman A (2015),
    Regionalisation of the parameters of the log-Pearson 3 distribution: a
    case study for New South Wales, Australia, <emphasis
    role="italic">Hydrological Processes</emphasis>, 29, 2, 250-260.</para>

    <para>Mittelstadt GE, McDermott GE and Pilgrim DH (1987), Revised flood
    data and catchment characteristics for small to medium sized catchments in
    New South Wales. University of New South Wales, Department of Water
    Engineering, unpublished report.</para>

    <para>Palmen, LB and Weeks WD (2009), “Regional flood frequency for
    Queensland using the Quantile Regression Technique”,<emphasis
    role="italic"> Proc. 32nd Hydrology and Water Resources Symp.,
    Newcastle</emphasis>.</para>

    <para>Palmen LB and Weeks WD (2011), Regional flood frequency for
    Queensland using the quantile regression technique, <emphasis
    role="italic">Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>, 15, 1,
    47-57.</para>

    <para>Pilgrim DH and McDermott G (1982), Design floods for small rural
    catchments in eastern New South Wales, <emphasis role="italic">Civil
    Engineering Transactions</emphasis>, I. E. Aust., CE24, 226-234.</para>

    <para>Pirozzi J, Ashraf M, Rahman A, and Haddad K (2009), “Design flood
    estimation for ungauged catchments in eastern NSW: evaluation of the
    Probabilistic Rational Method”, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 32nd
    Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., Newcastle, 805-816.</para>

    <para>Rahman A (1997), <emphasis role="italic">“Flood estimation for
    ungauged catchments: a regional approach using flood and catchment
    characteristics”</emphasis>, PhD thesis, Department of Civil Engineering,
    Monash University.</para>

    <para>Rahman A (2005), A quantile regression technique to estimate design
    floods for ungauged catchments in south-east Australia, <emphasis
    role="italic">Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>, 9(1),
    81-89.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Bates BC, Mein RG and Weinmann PE (1999), Regional Flood
    Frequency Analysis for ungauged basins in south – eastern Australia,
    <emphasis role="italic">Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>,
    3(2), 199-207.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Rima K and Weeks WD (2008), “Development of Regional Flood
    Frequency Estimation methods using Quantile Regression Technique: a case
    study for north-eastern part of Queensland”, <emphasis role="italic">Proc.
    31st Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., Adelaide,
    329-340.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2009), <emphasis
    role="italic">“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5
    Regional Flood Methods, Stage 1 Report”</emphasis>, No. P5/S1/003, Nov
    2009, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering, 181pp.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Zaman M, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2011a),
    Design flood estimation in ungauged catchments: a comparison between the
    Probabilistic Rational Method and Quantile Regression Technique for NSW,
    <emphasis role="italic">Australian Journal of Water Resources</emphasis>,
    14, 2, 127-139.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Zaman M, Fotos M, Haddad K, Rajaratnam L and Weeks WD
    (2011b), “Towards a new Regional Flood Frequency Estimation method for the
    Northern Territory”, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 34th IAHR World
    Congress</emphasis>, Brisbane, 364-371.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Zaman M, Ishak E, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE
    (2012), <emphasis role="italic">“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision
    Projects, Project 5 Regional flood methods, Stage 2 Report”</emphasis>,
    No. P5/S2/015, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering, 319pp.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Rahman AS, Haque MM, 2015a, <emphasis
    role="italic">“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5
    Regional flood methods, Database used to develop ARR REEF Model
    2015”</emphasis>, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Rahman AS, Haque MM, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE,
    2015b, Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 5: Regional Flood
    Methods: Stage 3, ARR Report Number P5/S3/025, ISBN
    978-0-85825-869-3.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haddad K, Haque MM, Kuczera G, Weinmann PE, Stensmyr P,
    Babister M, Weeks WD (2015c), (2015c), “The New Regional Flood Frequency
    Estimation Model for Australia: RFFE Model 2015”, <emphasis
    role="italic">36th Hydrology and Water Resources Symp</emphasis>., 7-10
    Dec, 2015, Hobart.</para>

    <para>Rahman A, Haque, M, Haddad, K, Rahman, AS, Caballero, WL (2015d),
    “Database Underpinning the RFFE 2015 Model in the new Australian Rainfall
    and Runoff”, 36th Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, 7-10 Dec, 2015,
    Hobart</para>

    <para>Sivapalan M, Blöschl G and Wagener T (2013),<emphasis role="italic">
    “Runoff Prediction in Ungauged Basins: Synthesis across Processes, Places
    and Scales”</emphasis>, Cambridge University Press.</para>

    <para>Stedinger JR and Tasker GD (1985), Regional hydrologic analysis 1
    Ordinary, weighted, and generalised least squares compared, <emphasis
    role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 21, 9,
    1421-1432.</para>

    <para>Tasker GD and Stedinger JR (1989), An operational GLS model for
    hydrologic regression, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
    Hydrology</emphasis>, 111 (1-4), 361-375.</para>

    <para>Zrinji Z and Burn DH (1994), Flood frequency analysis for ungauged
    sites using a region of influence approach. <emphasis
    role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>, 153, 1–21.</para>

    <?oxy_insert_end ?>

    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20151121T150917+1100" content="&lt;para&gt;Adams CA (1984), “Regional flood estimation for ungauged rural catchments in Victoria”, MEngSc Thesis, The University of Melbourne.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Ball JE (2014), “Flood estimation under climate change”, &lt;emphasis&gt;19th IAHR-APD Congress&lt;/emphasis&gt;, Hanoi, Vietnam.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Bates BC (1994), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Regionalisation of hydrological data: A review”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, Report 94/5, CRC for Catchment Hydrology, Monash University.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Bates BC, Rahman A, Mein RG and Weinmann PE (1998), Climatic and physical factors that influence the homogeneity of regional floods in south-eastern Australia, &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 34(12), 3369-3382.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Burn DH (1990a), An appraisal of the region of influence approach to Flood Frequency Analysis, &lt;emphasis&gt;Hydrological Sciences Journal&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 35, 2, 149-165.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Burn DH (1990b), Evaluation of regional Flood Frequency Analysis with a region of influence approach, &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 26, 10, 2257-2265.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Cohn TA, England JF, Berenbrock CE, Mason RR, Stedinger JR and Lamontagne JR (2013), A generalized Grubbs-Beck test statistic for detecting multiple potentially influential low outliers in flood series, &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 49, 5047–5058.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;French R (2002), “Flaws in the rational method”,&lt;emphasis&gt; Proc. 27th National Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Melbourne.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Farquharson FAK, Meigh JR and Sutcliffe JV (1992), Regional Flood Frequency Analysis in arid and semi-arid areas, &lt;emphasis&gt;Journal of Hydrology&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 138, 487-501.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Griffis VW and Stedinger JR (2007), The use of GLS regression in regional hydrologic analyses, &lt;emphasis&gt;Journal of Hydrology&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 344, 82-95.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Hackelbusch A, Micevski T, Kuczera G, Rahman A and Haddad K (2009), “Regional Flood Frequency Analysis for eastern New South Wales: a region of influence approach using generalised least squares based parameter regression”, &lt;emphasis&gt;Proc. 31st Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Newcastle, 603-615.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Haddad K (2008), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Design flood estimation in ungauged catchments using a quantile regression technique: ordinary and generalised least squares methods compared for Victoria”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, Masters (Honours) thesis, School of Engineering, University of Western Sydney, New South Wales.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Haddad K, Rahman A and Weinmann PE (2008), “Development of a generalised least squares based quantile regression technique for design flood estimation in Victoria”, &lt;emphasis&gt;Proc. 31st Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Adelaide, 2546-2557.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Haddad K, Pirozzi J, McPherson G, Rahman A and Kuczera G (2009), “Regional flood estimation technique for NSW: application of generalised least squares quantile regression technique”,&lt;emphasis&gt; Proc. 32nd Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Newcastle, 829-840.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Haddad K, Rahman A, Weinmann PE, Kuczera G and Ball JE (2010), Streamflow data preparation for regional Flood Frequency Analysis: Lessons from south-east Australia, &lt;emphasis&gt;Australian Journal of Water Resources&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 14, 1, 17-32.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Haddad K, Rahman A and Kuczera G (2011), Comparison of ordinary and generalised least squares regression models in regional Flood Frequency Analysis: A case study for New South Wales, &lt;emphasis&gt;Australian Journal of Water Resources&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 15, 2, 59-70.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Haddad K and Rahman A (2012), Regional Flood Frequency Analysis in eastern Australia: Bayesian GLS regression-based methods within fixed region and ROI framework – quantile regression vs. parameter regression technique,&lt;emphasis&gt; Journal of Hydrology&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 430-431, 142-161.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Haddad K, Rahman A and Stedinger JR (2012), Regional Flood Frequency Analysis using Bayesian generalised least squares: A comparison between quantile and parameter regression techniques, &lt;emphasis&gt;Hydrological Processes&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 26, 1008-1021.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Hosking JRM and Wallis JR (1993), Some statistics useful in regional frequency analysis, &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 29(2), 271-281.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Institution of Engineers Australia (I. E. Aust.) (1987, 2001), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A Guide to Flood Estimation”&lt;/emphasis&gt;. Editor: D.H. Pilgrim, Vol. 1, I. E. Aust., Canberra.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Ishak E, Rahman A, Westra S, Sharma A and Kuczera G (2013), Evaluating the non-stationarity of Australian annual maximum floods, &lt;emphasis&gt;Journal of Hydrology&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 494, 134-145.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Kuczera G (1999), Comprehensive at-site Flood Frequency Analysis using Monte Carlo Bayesian inference. &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 35, 5, 1551-1557.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Langbein WB (1949), Annual floods and the partial duration flood series. &lt;emphasis&gt;Trans. American Geophysical Union&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 30, 879-881.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Lamontagne JR, Stedinger JR, Cohn TA and Barth NA (2013), “Robust national flood frequency guidelines: What is an outlier?”,&lt;emphasis&gt; Proc. World Environmental and Water Resources Congress&lt;/emphasis&gt;, ASCE, 2454-2466.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Madsen H, Pearson CP and Rosbjerg D (1997), Comparison of annual maximum series and partial duration series for modelling extreme hydrologic events, 2. Regional modelling, &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 33, 4, 759-769.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Micevski T and Kuczera G (2009), Combining site and regional flood information using a Bayesian Monte Carlo approach, &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 45, W04405, doi:10.1029/2008WR007173.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Micevski T, Hackelbusch A, Haddad K. Kuczera G and Rahman A (2014), Regionalisation of the parameters of the log-Pearson 3 distribution: a case study for New South Wales, Australia, &lt;emphasis&gt;Hydrological Processes&lt;/emphasis&gt;, DOI: 10.1002/hyp.10147.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Mittelstadt GE, McDermott GE and Pilgrim DH (1987), Revised flood data and catchment characteristics for small to medium sized catchments in New South Wales. University of New South Wales, Department of Water Engineering, unpublished report.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Palmen, LB and Weeks WD (2009), “Regional flood frequency for Queensland using the Quantile Regression Technique”,&lt;emphasis&gt; Proc. 32nd Hydrology and Water Resources Symp., Newcastle&lt;/emphasis&gt;.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Palmen LB and Weeks WD (2011), Regional flood frequency for Queensland using the quantile regression technique, &lt;emphasis&gt;Australian Journal of Water Resources&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 15, 1, 47-57.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Pegram G (2002), “Rainfall, rational formula and regional maximum flood – some scaling links”, &lt;emphasis&gt;Proc. 27th Hydrology and Water Resources Symp., Melbourne.&lt;/emphasis&gt;&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Pilgrim DH and McDermott G (1982), Design floods for small rural catchments in eastern New South Wales, &lt;emphasis&gt;Civil Engineering Transactions&lt;/emphasis&gt;, I. E. Aust., CE24, 226-234.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Pirozzi J, Ashraf M, Rahman A, and Haddad K (2009), “Design flood estimation for ungauged catchments in eastern NSW: evaluation of the Probabilistic Rational Method”, &lt;emphasis&gt;Proc. 32nd Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Newcastle, 805-816.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A (1997), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Flood estimation for ungauged catchments: a regional approach using flood and catchment characteristics”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, PhD thesis, Department of Civil Engineering, Monash University.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A (2005), A quantile regression technique to estimate design floods for ungauged catchments in south-east Australia, &lt;emphasis&gt;Australian Journal of Water Resources&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 9(1), 81-89.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Bates BC, Mein RG and Weinmann PE (1999), Regional Flood Frequency Analysis for ungauged basins in south – eastern Australia, &lt;emphasis&gt;Australian Journal of Water Resources&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 3(2), 199-207.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Rima K and Weeks WD (2008), “Development of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation methods using Quantile Regression Technique: a case study for north-eastern part of Queensland”, &lt;emphasis&gt;Proc. 31st Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Adelaide, 329-340.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2009), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5 Regional Flood Methods, Stage 1 Report”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, No. P5/S1/003, Nov 2009, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering, 181pp.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Zaman M, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2011a), Design flood estimation in ungauged catchments: a comparison between the Probabilistic Rational Method and Quantile Regression Technique for NSW, &lt;emphasis&gt;Australian Journal of Water Resources&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 14, 2, 127-139.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Zaman M, Fotos M, Haddad K, Rajaratnam L and Weeks WD (2011b), “Towards a new Regional Flood Frequency Estimation method for the Northern Territory”, &lt;emphasis&gt;Proc. 34th IAHR World Congress&lt;/emphasis&gt;, Brisbane, 364-371.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Zaman M, Ishak E, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2012), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5 Regional flood methods, Stage 2 Report”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, No. P5/S2/015, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering, 319pp.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Rahman AS, Haque MM (2014a), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5 Regional flood methods, Database used to develop ARR REEF Model 2015”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Haque M, Kuczera G, Weinmann PE (2014b), &lt;emphasis&gt;“Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Projects, Project 5 Regional flood methods, Stage 3 Report”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, Engineers Australia, Water Engineering.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Kuczera G, Weinmann PE, Weeks WD, Stensmyr P and Babister M (2014c), “An overview of the development of the new Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) model for Australia”, &lt;emphasis&gt;35th Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Engineers Australia, Perth.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Rahman AS, Haque MM, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE (2014d), “An overview of preparation of streamflow database for ARR Project 5 Regional Flood Method”, &lt;emphasis&gt;35th Hydrology and Water Resources Symp&lt;/emphasis&gt;., Engineers Australia, Perth.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Rahman A, Haddad K, Rahman AS, Haque MM, Kuczera G and Weinmann PE, 4 March 2015, Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 5: Regional Flood Methods: Stage 3, ARR Report Number P5/S3/025, ISBN 978-0-85825-869-3&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Sivapalan M, Blöschl G and Wagener T (2013),&lt;emphasis&gt; “Runoff Prediction in Ungauged Basins: Synthesis across Processes, Places and Scales”&lt;/emphasis&gt;, Cambridge University Press.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Stedinger JR and Tasker GD (1985), Regional hydrologic analysis 1 Ordinary, weighted, and generalised least squares compared, &lt;emphasis&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 21, 9, 1421-1432.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Tasker GD and Stedinger JR (1989), An operational GLS model for hydrologic regression, &lt;emphasis&gt;Journal of Hydrology&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 111 (1-4), 361-375.&lt;/para&gt;&lt;para&gt;Zrinji Z and Burn DH (1994), Flood frequency analysis for ungauged sites using a region of influence approach. &lt;emphasis&gt;Journal of Hydrology&lt;/emphasis&gt;, 153, 1–21.&lt;/para&gt;"?>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Further Information on the Development and Testing of RFFE
    Technique 2015</title>

    <para><table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_w5xgv">
        <title>Further Information on the Development and Testing of RFFE
        Technique 2015</title>

        <tgroup cols="2">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry align="center">Information</entry>

              <entry align="center">Source</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Database consisting of 853 gauged catchments used to
              develop RFFE Technique 2015</entry>

              <entry>Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2015a</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Aspects of streamflow data preparation</entry>

              <entry>Haddad <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2010</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Comparison of Probabilistic Rational Method and quantile
              regression technique</entry>

              <entry>Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2011a</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Comparison of ordinary and generalised least squares
              regression techniques</entry>

              <entry>Haddad, Rahman and Kuczera, 2011</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Comparison of fixed region and region-of-influence
              approaches for quantile and parameter regression
              techniques</entry>

              <entry>Haddad and Rahman, 2012</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Regionalisation of the parameters of the LP3
              distribution</entry>

              <entry>Haddad, Rahman and Stedinger, 2012 and Micevski
              <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2014</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Development and testing of the RFFE technique</entry>

              <entry>Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2009; 2012 and
              2015b</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table></para>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_weovt">
      <title>Standardised residuals vs. normal scores for Region 1 based on
      Leave One Out validation for AEPs of 50%, 20%, 2% and 1%</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3052.png"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_2a59v">
      <title>Standardised residuals vs. normal scores for Region 1 based on
      leave-one-out validation for AEPs of 2% and 1%</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3053.png"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
</chapter>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>
