<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" version="5.0" xml:id="b3_ch3" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Regional Flood Methods</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/rahman_ataur.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/haddad_khaled.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190503T160300+1000" content="06/07/16"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190503T160300+1000"?>6/5/2019<?oxy_insert_end?>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190503T160236+1000" content="&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Content&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Advanced draft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;General&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Subject to industry feedback &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;"?>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_0g2kk">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Estimation of peak flows on small to medium sized rural catchments is required for the
      design of culverts, small to medium sized bridges, causeways, soil conservation works and for
      various planning and regulatory purposes. Typically, most design flood estimates for projects
      on small to medium sized catchments are on catchments that are ungauged or have little
      recorded streamflow data. In these cases, peak flow estimates can be obtained using a Regional
      Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) approach, which transfers flood frequency characteristics
      from a group of gauged catchments to the location of interest. Even in cases where there is
      recorded streamflow data it is beneficial to pool the information in the gauged record with
      the RFFE information. A RFFE technique is expected to be simple, requiring only readily
      accessible catchment data to obtain design flood estimates relatively quickly.</para>
    <para>The RFFE method described in this chapter ensures that design flood discharge estimates
      are consistent with the gauged records and with results for other ungauged catchments in a
      region. It is recognised that there will be considerable uncertainty in estimates for ungauged
      catchments because of the limited number of gauged catchments available to develop the method
      and the wide range of catchment types that exist throughout Australia.</para>
    <para>In developing the RFFE technique, a number of criteria had to be satisfied. These criteria
      included:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>National consistency in approach;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Smooth interfacing at the boundaries between areas;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use readily accessible data; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Utilise as much of Australia's streamflow database as possible.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The basis for the development of the RFFE technique recommended herein, therefore, is a
      national database consisting of 853 gauged catchments. These data were used to develop and
      test the RFFE technique presented in this chapter. Further details of the development of the
      database and RFFE technique are provided by the references noted in Appendix A.</para>
    <para>The following sections contain a description of the conceptual and statistical framework
      of the adopted RFFE technique, a computer-based application tool, referred to as ‘RFFE Model
      2015’, that implements the adopted RFFE technique and a number of worked examples to
      demonstrate the application of the model.</para>
    <para>Following the guidance provided in <xref linkend="book1"/> and <xref linkend="b3_ch1"/>,
      users of the RFFE technique are reminded that there are alternatives to the RFFE technique. </para>
    <para>While the RFFE technique described in this chapter is regarded as a state-of-the-art
      approach for estimation of design flood peak discharges at ungauged catchments, the
      limitations of the method must be recognised. The RFFE technique has been developed using the
      best available database of gauged catchments throughout Australia, but the fact remains that
      only a small number of gauged catchments were available to represent the wide range of
      conditions experienced over an area of about 7.5 million km<superscript>2</superscript>.
      Therefore, in accordance with the guidance in <xref linkend="b1_ch1"/> of ARR, designers and
      analysts have a duty to use an alternative technique if that technique can be shown to be
      superior to RFFE Model 2015 and to utilise any available local data, both formal and informal
      to assist in understanding local conditions and improve upon RFFE Model 2015 estimates. In
      comparing and selecting alternative methods, the uncertainty in the observed flood data due to
      factors such as limitations in record length and rating curve extrapolation should be
      recognised.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ynzmg">
    <title>Conceptual Framework</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_oubiy">
      <title>Definition of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation</title>

      <para>Regional Flood Frequency Estimation (RFFE) is a data-driven approach, which attempts to
        transfer flood characteristics from a group of gauged catchments to ungauged locations of
        interest (where design floods need to be estimated). A range of different methods are
        available to extract regional flood information from the pooled data and to transfer the
        relevant information to an individual ungauged catchment in the region
          <citation>b3_c3_r44</citation>. All of these RFFE techniques use the results of at-site
        Flood Frequency Analysis (FFA, refer to <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>) as basic data. A RFFE
        technique essentially consists of two steps: (i) <emphasis>Formation of Regions</emphasis> -
        which involves identification of the regions for which flood data from the available
        streamflow gauging stations can be pooled for analysis; and (ii)<emphasis> Development of
          Regional Estimation Equations</emphasis> - which involves derivation of prediction
        equations to be used for design flood estimation within a region.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_mctc1">
      <title>Formation of Regions</title>

      <para>In RFFE techniques, the formation of regions can be based on geographic proximity or on
        similarity in catchment attributes. A region can be fixed, having a definite common boundary
        for all sites within it, or it can be formed around the ungauged catchment of interest (i.e.
        the location where flood quantile estimation is desired), using the nearest stations in
        geographic or catchment attributes space. Regions must satisfy explicitly or implicitly the
        assumption of ‘regional homogeneity’. The decision on what constitutes a homogeneous region
        for the purposes of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation depends on the methods used, more
        specifically on the extent to which differences in flood characteristics can be expressed
        through parameters in the regionalisation method. There have been many techniques developed
        which attempt to establish homogenous regions. For example, the recommended RFFE model for
        eastern New South Wales (NSW) and Victoria in Australian Rainfall and Runoff 1987
          <citation>arr_1987</citation>, namely the Probabilistic Rational Method, used geographical
        contiguity as an indication of homogeneity; in other words the catchments which are closer
        to each other should have similar runoff coefficients <citation>arr_1987</citation>.</para>

      <para>There has been little success in the identification of ‘acceptably homogeneous regions’
        in Australia using statistical measures such as those proposed by Hosking and Wallis
          (1993)<citation>b3_c3_r19+1</citation>. A common approach to defining a fixed region has
        been to base the region on political boundaries. However, these fixed regions based on state
        borders and other geographical boundaries have often been found to be highly heterogeneous
          <citation>b3_c3_r4,b3_c3_r32,b3_c3_r12</citation>.</para>

      <para>As an alternative to fixed regions, <citation>b3_c3_r5,b3_c3_r6</citation> and
          <citation>b3_c3_r47+1</citation> proposed the Region Of Influence (ROI) approach where a
        location of interest (i.e. the catchment where flood quantiles are to be estimated) is
        allowed to form its own region by selecting a group of ‘nearby catchments’ in either a
        geographical or catchment attributes space (catchment attributes refer to the catchment
        characteristics that are influential in developing flood flows). The ROI approach attempts
        to reduce the degree of heterogeneity in a proposed region by excluding sites located
        remotely in geographical or catchment attributes space. The ROI approach often uses a
        statistical criterion to select the optimum size of the region, such as ‘minimum model error
        variance’ in the regression.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_tjham">
      <title>Development of Regional Flood Frequency Estimation
      Technique</title>

      <para>According to <citation>b3_c3_r3+1</citation>, the most commonly adopted methods to
        develop Regional Flood Frequency Estimation techniques include various forms of the Rational
        Method, the Index Flood Method and regression based techniques. In ARR 1987, the
        Probabilistic Rational Method was recommended for general use in Victoria and eastern NSW
          <citation>arr_1987</citation>. The foundations of the Probabilistic Rational Method are
        presented by <citation>b3_c3_r30+1</citation>, <citation>b3_c3_r27+1</citation>, and
          <citation>b3_c3_r1+1</citation>. The central component of the Probabilistic Rational
        Method, is the runoff coefficient and, in particular, the 10 year Average Recurrence
        Interval (ARI) runoff coefficient. It is worth noting that this runoff coefficient does not
        have a physical basis but rather is a parameter to ensure that the rainfall frequency is
        transferred to the flow frequency. Furthermore, this parameter has been assumed to vary
        smoothly over geographical space for purposes of extrapolating from known locations to
        locations for application. However, it has been found that the runoff coefficient may show
        sharp variation within a close proximity, reflecting discontinuities at many locations,
        particularly at catchment boundaries. Additionally, <citation>b3_c3_r8+1</citation> noted
        that the isopleths of the runoff coefficient in ARR 1987 ignored the existence of
        watercourses.</para>

      <para>Alternative methods to the Probabilistic Rational Method, such as the Index Flood Method
        heavily rely on the assumption of ‘regional homogeneity’, which as previously mentioned is
        satisfied poorly for Australian regional flood data. Studies on regression based RFFE
        techniques for Australia (e.g.
          <citation>b3_c3_r11,b3_c3_r13,b3_c3_r14,b3_c3_r16,b3_c3_r18,b3_c3_r17,b3_c3_r26,b3_c3_r28,b3_c3_r29,b3_c3_r31,b3_c3_r33,b3_c3_r35,b3_c3_r36,b3_c3_r37,b3_c3_r38,b3_c3_r39,b3_c3_r40,b3_c3_r41,b3_c3_r42,b3_c3_r43</citation>)
        have demonstrated that these techniques are capable of providing quite accurate design flood
        estimates using only a few predictor variables. In particular, it has been found that the
        Generalised Least Squares (GLS) based regression technique offers a powerful statistical
        method which accounts for the inter-station correlation of annual maximum flood series and
        across-site variation in flood series record lengths in the estimation of the flood
        quantiles. Use of a GLS-based regression method also allows differentiation between sampling
        error and model error and thus provides a more realistic framework for error analysis. The
        GLS based quantile regression technique has been adopted in the US (see, for example,
          <citation>b3_c3_r45,b3_c3_r46,b3_c3_r10</citation>).</para>

      <para>As an alternative to the quantile regression technique, the parameters of a particular
        probability distribution can be regressed against the catchment characteristics to develop
        prediction equations for the parameters of interest. This method is referred to as Parameter
        Regression Technique (PRT). It is this approach that is the basis of the recommended
        technique for design flood estimation in Australia using the RFFE model. For development of
        a PRT, the Bayesian GLS regression method is used to develop prediction equations for the
        model parameters for the three-parameter Log Pearson III (LP III) distribution; these model
        parameters are the mean, standard deviation and skewness of the natural logarithm of the
        annual maximum flood series. The PRT offers three significant advantages over the quantile
        regression technique:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>It ensures flood quantiles increase smoothly with decreasing
          Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP), an outcome that may not always
          be achieved with quantile regression;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>It is straightforward to combine any at-site flood information with regional
            estimates (see <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>) using the approach described by
              <citation>b3_c3_r25+1</citation> to produce more accurate quantile estimates;
            and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>It permits quantiles to be estimated for any AEP in the range
          of interest.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_0zix8">
      <title>Data Required to Develop Regional Flood Frequency Estimation Technique</title>
      <para>The success of a RFFE technique largely depends on the quantity and quality of the
        available data and the capability of the adopted statistical techniques to transfer
        information from gauged to ungauged sites within the region. There are two basic types of
        data required for the development and application of RFFE techniques:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flood data at gauged sites; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Catchment characteristics relevant to production of floods in both gauged and
            ungauged catchments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>The quality and representativeness of the flood data determine to a large degree the
        accuracy and reliability of regional flood estimates. The challenge in collating a database
        for RFFE lies in maximising the amount of useful flood information, while minimising the
        random and systematic error (or ‘noise’) that may be present in some flood data.</para>
      <para>In RFFE, various sources of errors in data and their effects on final flood estimates
        need to be recognised. The accuracy of flood quantile estimates at each individual gauged
        site depends largely on rating curve accuracy and record length at the individual site.
        Thus, the selection of a minimum record length at an individual site in the region is a very
        important step in any RFFE technique; the record length should be as long as possible while
        retaining enough sites in the region to make the results of RFFE useful. Also, the flood
        data at each site should satisfy a number of basic assumptions e.g. homogeneity,
        independence and stationarity. In the case where these assumptions are violated, appropriate
        measures should be taken; suitable techniques include GLS regression to account for the
        inter-station correlation (e.g. <citation>b3_c3_r45,b3_c3_r10</citation>), and
        non-stationary Flood Frequency Analysis to account for the impacts of climate change and
        changes in catchment conditions during the period of record. The data preparation issues for
        a RFFE technique are discussed in more detail by <citation>b3_c3_r15+1</citation> and
          <citation>b3_c3_r40,b3_c3_r41,b3_c3_r42,b3_c3_r43</citation>. In addition to the
        consideration of the data available at individual gauging stations, it is important to also
        consider the representativeness of the gauged data. The available gauged catchments
        represent only a sample of the range of conditions that may occur throughout the regions
        where the RFFE method is developed and applied.</para>
      <para>The transfer of flood information from gauged to ungauged catchments relies on the
        ability to identify a number of key catchment and climate characteristics which determine
        similarities and differences in the flood production of catchments. In the Probabilistic
        Rational Method similarity is assumed to exist on the basis of geographical proximity, but
        in other methods an appropriately small but informative set of predictor variables needs to
        be identified. The accuracy of a RFFE technique does not necessarily increase with the
        number of adopted predictor variables. For example, <citation>b3_c3_r34+1</citation> used 12
        predictor variables in an L-moments based Index Flood Method for south-east Australia. A
        subsequent study by <citation>b3_c3_r33+1</citation> showed that use of only 2 to 3
        predictor variables can provide a similar level of accuracy.</para>
      <para>Because of the difficulty of obtaining a sufficiently large number of gauged catchments
        in developing and testing a RFFE method, there is a chance that the available gauged
        catchments do not fully represent the range of conditions encountered in the region,
        Therefore where a catchment is judged to be atypical in some critical characteristic, the
        regional method may not be directly applicable and further analysis may be needed to
        estimate design flood quantiles. This issue is discussed further below.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_voncz">
      <title>Accuracy Considerations</title>

      <para>All RFFE techniques are subject to uncertainty, which, generally, is likely to be
        greater than for at-site Flood Frequency Analysis when a good quality and long record of
        streamflow data set is available at the location of interest. A RFFE technique essentially
        represents a ‘transfer function’ that converts predictor variables to a flood quantile
        estimate. It is assumed that use of a limited number of predictor variables (e.g. catchment
        area and design rainfall intensity) combined with an optimised transfer function captures
        the general nature of the rainfall-runoff relationship for flood events and hence provides
        flood quantile estimates of ‘acceptable’ accuracy.</para>

      <para>Because a RFFE technique typically has limited predictive power, design flood estimates
        produced by it are likely to have a lower degree of accuracy than those from a well
        calibrated catchment modelling system. From the investigations made by
          <citation>b3_c3_r36,b3_c3_r39,b3_c3_r40,b3_c3_r41</citation>, it may be stated that the
        relative accuracy of regional flood estimates using the RFFE model presented in this chapter
        is likely to be within ±50% of the true value; however, in a limited number of cases the
        estimation error may exceed the estimation by a factor of two or more (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_yj49v"/>). It is unlikely that any RFFE technique would be able to
        provide flood quantile estimates which are of much greater accuracy given the current
        availability of streamflow data (in terms of temporal and spatial coverage) and feasibility
        of the extraction of a greater number of catchment descriptors using simplified methods such
        as GIS based techniques. Because of the small sample of gauged catchments and limited
        availability of readily obtainable catchment descriptors, it is not possible to prepare an
        extremely detailed set of descriptor variables covering all possible conditions, so a sample
        must be selected that provides a suitable range to represent the critical parameters, but to
        limit the application of variables that do not contribute significantly to the overall
        performance of the RFFE technique.</para>

      <para>For catchments having limited recorded streamflow data, the combination of at-site data
        with a RFFE technique is likely to provide more accurate flood quantile estimates than
        either the at-site or regional method alone. Details of how limited streamflow data can be
        combined with a RFFE technique are presented in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>. Testing has shown
        this improves estimates in many cases.</para>

      <para>An important assumption in all RFFE techniques is that the small
      set of predictor variables used in the regression equations is able to
      explain the differences in flood producing characteristics of the
      catchments in a region. Not all ungauged catchments located in the
      region satisfy this basic homogeneity assumption; some catchments may
      have characteristics that are substantially different from the gauged
      catchments in the region. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8airu"/> contains
      further discussion on the limits of applicability of the RFFE technique,
      on what constitutes an atypical catchment and recommendations on how to
      derive flood estimates for such catchments.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_kbrnd">
    <title>Statistical Framework</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8o524">
      <title>Region Of Influence (ROI) Approach</title>

      <para>In the formation of regions, the Region Of Influence (ROI) approach has been adopted for
        the parts of Australia where there are adequate numbers of gauged stations within close
        proximity to form ROI sub-regions. In the absence of a proven technique for the use of
        catchment characteristics as the basis for the ROI, the adopted ROI approach uses the
        geographical distance between stations as the distance metric and sets a maximum distance
        for inclusion of stations in the ROI sub-region. More details regarding development of ROI
        sub-regions are provided by <citation>b3_c3_r41</citation>. Nonetheless, a summary of the
        process is presented. In applying the ROI approach, in the first iteration, a ROI sub-region
        consisting of the ten nearest stations to the site of interest is formed, the regional
        prediction equation is developed and its prediction error variance noted. At each of the
        subsequent iterations, the radius of the ROI sub-region is increased by 10 km and new
        stations are added to the previously selected stations. The final ROI sub-region for the
        location of interest is then selected as the one exhibiting the lowest prediction error
        variance.</para>

      <para>One of the apparent limitations of the ROI approach is that for each of the gauged sites
        in the region, the regional prediction equation has a different set of model parameters;
        hence a single regional prediction equation cannot be pre-specified. To overcome this
        problem, the parameters of the regional prediction equations for all the gauged catchment
        locations are pre-estimated and integrated with the RFFE Model 2015 (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs"/> for more details). To derive flood quantile estimates at an
        ungauged location of interest, the RFFE Model 2015 uses a natural neighbour interpolation
        method to derive quantile estimates based on up to the 15 nearest gauged catchment locations
        within a 300 km radius from the location of interest. This ensures a smooth variation of
        flood quantile estimates over the space.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_epemh">
      <title>Parameter Regression Technique</title>

      <para>In the adopted RFFE technique for the Humid Coastal areas of Australia (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_2fdu4"/> for further details), the first three moments of the LP III
        distribution (i.e. the mean, standard deviation and skewness of the natural logarithms of
        the annual maximum flood series) were regionalised. This method is referred to as the
        Parameter Regression Technique (PRT). The LP III distribution is described by the following
        equation:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_swrce">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>lnQ</mi>

              <mi>x</mi>
            </msub>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <mrow>
              <mi>M</mi>

              <mo>+</mo>

              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>K</mi>

                  <mi>x</mi>
                </msub>

                <mi>S</mi>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>where <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <msub>
              <mi>Q</mi>

              <mi>x</mi>
            </msub>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> is the discharge having an AEP of X% (design flood
      or flood quantile),</para>

      <para>M is the mean of the natural logarithms of the annual maximum flood series,</para>

      <para>S is the standard deviation of the natural logarithms of the
      annual maximum flood series, and</para>

      <para><inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>x</mi>
            </msub>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> is the frequency factor for the LP III distribution of X% AEP, which is a
        function of the AEP and the skewness (SK) of the natural logarithms of the annual maximum
        flood series.</para>

      <para>The prediction equations for M, S and SK were developed for all the gauged catchment
        locations in the Humid Coastal areas using Bayesian GLS regression and model parameters were
        noted. These model parameters are then integrated with the RFFE Model 2015.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_9bcrr">
      <title>Generalised Least Squares Regression</title>

      <para>In developing the prediction equations, for the Humid Coastal areas, the Bayesian
        Generalised Least Squares (GLS) regression was adopted. The GLS regression assumes that the
        variable of interest (e.g. a moment of the LP III distribution) denoted by y<subscript>i
        </subscript>for a location i can be described by a function of catchment characteristics
        (explanatory variables) with an additive error <citation>b3_c3_r10</citation>:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_wezxq">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>y</mi>

              <mi>i</mi>
            </msub>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>β</mi>

                <mi>0</mi>
              </msub>

              <mo>+</mo>

              <mrow>
                <munderover>
                  <mo>∑</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <mi>j</mi>

                    <mo>=</mo>

                    <mi>1</mi>
                  </mrow>

                  <mi>k</mi>
                </munderover>

                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>β</mi>

                    <mi>j</mi>
                  </msub>

                  <mo>⁢</mo>

                  <msub>
                    <mi>X</mi>

                    <mi>ij</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>

              <mo>+</mo>

              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>δ</mi>

                  <mi>i</mi>
                </msub>

                <mo>,</mo>

                <mrow>
                  <mi>i</mi>

                  <mo>=</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <mi>1</mi>

                    <mo>,</mo>

                    <mrow>
                      <mi>2</mi>

                      <mo>,</mo>

                      <mrow>
                        <mi>...</mi>

                        <mo>,</mo>

                        <mi>n</mi>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>where <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <msub>
              <mi>X</mi>

              <mi>ij</mi>
            </msub>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> (j = 1,…, k) are explanatory variables,
      <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <msub>
              <mi>β</mi>

              <mi>j</mi>
            </msub>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> are the regression coefficients, <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <msub>
              <mi>δ</mi>

              <mi>i</mi>
            </msub>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> is the model error which is assumed to be normally
      and independently distributed with model error variance <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <msubsup>
              <mi>σ</mi>

              <mi>δ</mi>

              <mi>2</mi>
            </msubsup>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> , and n is the number of locations in the region. In
      all cases, an at-site estimate of y<subscript>i</subscript> denoted as
      <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mover>
              <msub>
                <mi>y</mi>

                <mi>i</mi>
              </msub>

              <mo form="postfix">^</mo>
            </mover>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> is available. To account for the error in the
      at-site estimate, a sampling error <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <msub>
              <mi>η</mi>

              <mi>i</mi>
            </msub>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> must be introduced into the model so that:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_pogxg">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mi>ŷ</mi>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <mrow>
              <mi>Xβ</mi>

              <mo>+</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mi>η</mi>

                <mo>+</mo>

                <mrow>
                  <mi>δ</mi>

                  <mo>=</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <mi>Xβ</mi>

                    <mo>+</mo>

                    <mrow>
                      <mi>ε</mi>

                      <mrow>
                        <mtext>where</mtext>

                        <mrow>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>ŷ</mi>

                            <mi>i</mi>
                          </msub>

                          <mo>=</mo>

                          <mrow>
                            <msub>
                              <mi>γ</mi>

                              <mi>i</mi>
                            </msub>

                            <mo>+</mo>

                            <mrow>
                              <msub>
                                <mi>η</mi>

                                <mi>i</mi>
                              </msub>

                              <mrow>
                                <mi>: і</mi>

                                <mo>=</mo>

                                <mi>1,2 ...,n</mi>
                              </mrow>
                            </mrow>
                          </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>Thus the observed regression model error <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mi>ε</mi>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> is the sum of the model error <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mi>δ</mi>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> and the sampling error <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mi>η</mi>
          </math>
        </inlineequation>. The total error vector has a mean of zero and a
      covariance matrix:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_ujp3a">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msup>
              <mi>E[εε</mi>

              <mi>T</mi>
            </msup>

            <mo>]=</mo>

            <mrow>
              <msubsup>
                <mi>Λ(σ</mi>

                <mi>δ</mi>

                <mi>2</mi>
              </msubsup>

              <mo>) =</mo>

              <mrow>
                <msubsup>
                  <mi>σ</mi>

                  <mi>δ</mi>

                  <mi>2</mi>
                </msubsup>

                <mo>I+</mo>

                <mi>Σ(ŷ)</mi>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>where<inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mi>Σ(ŷ</mi>
          </math>
        </inlineequation>) is the covariance matrix of the sampling error in the estimate of the
        flood quantile or the parameter of the LP III distribution and I is a (n x n) identity
        matrix. The covariance matrix for η<subscript>i</subscript> depends on the record length
        available at each location and the cross correlation among annual maximum floods at
        different locations. Therefore, the observed regression model error is a combination of
        time-sampling error η<subscript>i</subscript> and an underlying model error
          δ<subscript>i</subscript>.</para>

      <para>The GLS estimator of β and its covariance matrix for a known
      <inlineequation>
          <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mrow>
              <msubsup>
                <mi>σ</mi>

                <mi>δ</mi>

                <mn>2</mn>
              </msubsup>
            </mrow>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> is given by:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_1jjd4">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>β</mi>

              <mrow>
                <mi>G</mi>

                <mi>L</mi>

                <mi>S</mi>
              </mrow>
            </msub>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <msubsup>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>[</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mi>X</mi>

                      <mi>T</mi>
                    </msup>

                    <mi>Λ</mi>

                    <msubsup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>

                          <mrow>
                            <msubsup>
                              <mi>σ</mi>

                              <mi>δ</mi>

                              <mn>2</mn>
                            </msubsup>
                          </mrow>

                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>

                      <mi>e</mi>

                      <mo>−</mo>
                    </msubsup>

                    <mi>X</mi>
                  </mrow>

                  <mo>]</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>

              <mi>e</mi>

              <mo>−</mo>
            </msubsup>

            <msup>
              <mi>X</mi>

              <mi>T</mi>
            </msup>

            <mi>Λ</mi>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <msubsup>
                  <mi>σ</mi>

                  <mi>δ</mi>

                  <mo>−</mo>
                </msubsup>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mover accent="true">
              <mi>y</mi>

              <mo>^</mo>
            </mover>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_iqkha">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mi>Σ</mi>

            <mrow>
              <mo>[</mo>

              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>β</mi>

                  <mrow>
                    <mi>G</mi>

                    <mi>L</mi>

                    <mi>S</mi>
                  </mrow>
                </msub>
              </mrow>

              <mo>]</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <msubsup>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>[</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mi>X</mi>

                      <mi>T</mi>
                    </msup>

                    <mi>Λ</mi>

                    <msubsup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>

                          <mrow>
                            <msubsup>
                              <mi>σ</mi>

                              <mi>δ</mi>

                              <mn>2</mn>
                            </msubsup>
                          </mrow>

                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>

                      <mi>e</mi>

                      <mo>−</mo>
                    </msubsup>

                    <mi>X</mi>
                  </mrow>

                  <mo>]</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>

              <mi>e</mi>

              <mo>−</mo>
            </msubsup>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>The model error variance σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² can be
      estimated by either generalised Method of Moments (MOM) or maximum
      likelihood estimators. The MOM estimator is determined by iteratively
      solving <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_1jjd4"/> along with the generalised
      residual mean square error equation:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_w6z3z">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mover accent="true">
                  <mi>y</mi>

                  <mo>^</mo>
                </mover>

                <mo>−</mo>

                <mi>X</mi>

                <msub>
                  <mi>β</mi>

                  <mi>i</mi>
                </msub>

                <msubsup>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>[</mo>

                      <mrow>
                        <msubsup>
                          <mi>σ</mi>

                          <mi>δ</mi>

                          <mn>2</mn>
                        </msubsup>

                        <mi>I</mi>

                        <mo>+</mo>

                        <mi>Σ</mi>

                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>

                          <mover accent="true">
                            <mi>y</mi>

                            <mo>^</mo>
                          </mover>

                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>

                      <mo>]</mo>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>

                  <mi>e</mi>

                  <mo>−</mo>
                </msubsup>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mover accent="true">
                  <mi>y</mi>

                  <mo>^</mo>
                </mover>

                <mo>−</mo>

                <mi>X</mi>

                <msub>
                  <mi>β</mi>

                  <mrow>
                    <mi>G</mi>

                    <mi>L</mi>

                    <mi>S</mi>
                  </mrow>
                </msub>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <mi>n</mi>

            <mo>−</mo>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mi>k</mi>

                <mo>+</mo>

                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>In some situations, the sampling covariance matrix explains all
      the variability observed in the data, which means the left-hand side of
      <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_w6z3z"/> will be less than n – (k + 1) even if
      σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² is zero. In these circumstances, the MOM
      estimator of the model error variance is generally taken to be
      zero.</para>

      <para>With the adopted Bayesian approach, it was assumed that there was no prior information
        on any of the β parameters; thus a multivariate normal distribution with mean zero and a
        large variance (e.g. greater than 100) was used as a prior for the regression coefficient
        parameters. This prior was considered to be almost non-informative, which produced a
        probability distribution function that was generally flat in the region of interest. The
        prior information for the model error variance σ<subscript>δ</subscript>² was represented by
        a one parameter exponential distribution. Further description of the adopted Bayesian GLS
        regression can be found in <citation>b3_c3_r16+1</citation> and
          <citation>b3_c3_r17+1</citation>.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_7r0rn">
      <title>Development of Confidence Limits for the Estimated Flood
      Quantiles</title>

      <para>In developing the confidence limits for the estimated flood quantiles, a Monte Carlo
        simulation approach was adopted by assuming that the uncertainty in the first three
        parameters of the LP III distribution (i.e. the mean, standard deviation and skewness of the
        logarithms of the annual maximum flood series) can be specified by a multivariate normal
        distribution. Here the correlations among the three parameters for a given region were
        estimated from the residuals of the GLS regression models of the LP III parameters. The mean
        of the LP III parameter is given by its regional predicted value and the standard deviation
        of the LP III parameter is the square root of the average variance of prediction of the
        parameter at the nearest gauged location. Based on 10 000 simulated values of the LP III
        parameters from the multivariate normal distribution as defined above, 10 000
          Q<subscript>x</subscript> values are estimated in the RFFE Model 2015, which are then used
        to develop the 90% confidence intervals.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_wfiku">
    <title>RFFE Techniques for Humid Coastal Areas</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_2fdu4">
      <title>Data Used to Develop RFFE Technique</title>

      <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_i6yzh">
        <title>Flood data</title>

        <para>Humid Coast areas had a relatively large number of recorded streamflow stations, as
          shown in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_55d8a"/>. An upper limit of catchment size of 1000 km²
          was generally adopted. However, in some states (such as the Northern Territory), a few
          larger catchments were included as the total number of catchments with areas less than
          1000 km² was too small. The cut-off record length of 19 years was selected to maximise the
          number of eligible stations on the consideration that a higher cut-off would reduce that
          number.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_55d8a">
          <title>Geographical Distribution of the Adopted 798 Catchments from Humid Coastal Areas of
            Australia (blue circles) and 55 Catchments from Arid/Semi-arid Areas (black
            circles)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3038.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The selected streams were unregulated since major regulation (e.g. a large dam on the
          stream) affects the rainfall-runoff relationship significantly by increasing storage
          effects. Streams with minor regulation, such as small farm dams and diversion weirs, were
          not excluded because this type of regulation is unlikely to have a significant effect on
          large annual floods. Gauging stations on streams subject to major upstream regulation were
          excluded from the data set. Catchments with more than 10% of the area affected by
          urbanisation were also excluded from the study data set. Catchments known to have
          undergone major land use changes, such as the clearing of forests or changing of
          agricultural practices over the period of streamflow records were excluded from the data
          set. Stations graded as 'poor quality' or with specific comments by the gauging authority
          regarding quality of the data were assessed in greater detail; if stations were deemed
          'low quality' they were excluded.</para>

        <para>The annual maximum flood series data may be affected by multi-decadal climate
          variability and climate change, which are not easy to deal with. The effects of
          multi-decadal climate variability can be accounted for by increasing the cut-off record
          length at an individual station. However, the impacts of climate change present a serious
          problem in terms of the applicability of the past data in predicting future flood
          frequency; this requires further research <citation>b3_c3_r22</citation>. This is further
          discussed in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_31eib"/>.</para>

        <para>The data sets for the initially selected potential catchments are further examined, as
          detailed in <citation>b3_c3_r15+1</citation> and
            <citation>b3_c3_r40,b3_c3_r41,b3_c3_r42</citation>: gaps in the annual maximum flood
          series was filled as far as could be justified, outliers were detected using the multiple
          Grubbs-Beck test <citation>b3_c3_r24,b3_c3_r7</citation>, errors associated with
          extrapolation of rating curves were investigated and the presence of trends with the data
          were checked. From an initial number of approximately 1200 catchments, a total of 798
          catchments were finally adopted from all over Australia (excluding catchments in the
          arid/semi-arid areas, where some of the above criteria were relaxed, as discussed in
          Section 5).</para>

        <para>The record lengths of the annual maximum flood series of these 798 stations range from
          19 to 102 years (median: 37 years). The catchment areas of the selected 798 catchments
          range from 0.5 km² to 4325 km² (median: 178 km²). <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_opf7j"/>
          provides summary of the selected catchments from Humid Coastal areas of Australia.
          .</para>
        <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_opf7j" frame="void">
          <caption>Summary of Adopted Catchments from Humid Coastal Areas of Australia</caption>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <col width="25%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>State</th>
              <th>No. of Stations</th>
              <th>Streamflow Record Length (years) (range and median)</th>
              <th>Catchment Size (km<superscript>2</superscript>) (range and median)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>New South Wales &amp; Australian Capital Territory</td>
              <td>176</td>
              <td>20 – 82 (34)</td>
              <td>1 – 1036 (204)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Victoria</td>
              <td>186</td>
              <td>20 – 60 (38)</td>
              <td>3 – 997 (209)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>South Australia</td>
              <td>28</td>
              <td>20 – 63 (37)</td>
              <td>0.6 – 708 (62.6)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Tasmania</td>
              <td>51</td>
              <td>19 – 74 (28)</td>
              <td>1.3 – 1900 (158.1)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Queensland</td>
              <td>196</td>
              <td>20 – 102 (42)</td>
              <td>7– 963 (227)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Western Australia</td>
              <td>111</td>
              <td>20 – 60 (30)</td>
              <td>0.5 – 1049.8 (49.2)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Northern Territory</td>
              <td>50</td>
              <td>19 – 57 (42)</td>
              <td>1.4 – 4325 (352)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>TOTAL</td>
              <td>798</td>
              <td>19 – 102 (37)</td>
              <td>0.5 – 4325 (178)</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>

        <para>The at-site Flood Frequency Analyses were conducted using the FLIKE software
            <citation>b3_c3_r23</citation>. The Potential Influential Low Flows (PILFs) were
          identified using multiple Grubbs-Beck test <citation>b3_c3_r24</citation> and were
          censored in the Flood Frequency Analysis. A Bayesian parameter estimation procedure with
          LP III distribution was used to estimate flood quantiles for each gauged site for AEPs of
          50%, 20%, 10%, 5%, 2% and 1%.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ujhrw">
        <title>Catchment Characteristics Data</title>

        <para>As discussed by <citation>b3_c3_r36,b3_c3_r39</citation>, over ten predictor variables
          were selected initially; however, it was found that the accuracy of a RFFE technique does
          not necessarily increase with the number of adopted predictor variables. A total of five
          candidate predictor variables were adopted finally in the RFFE technique, as outlined
          below:</para>

        <para>(i) catchment area in km² (<emphasis>area</emphasis>);</para>

        <para>(ii) design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid (in mm/h)
        for the 6 hour duration and 50% AEP
        (<superscript>50%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>);</para>

        <para>(iii) design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid (in mm/h)
        for the 6 hour duration and 2% AEP
        (<superscript>2%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>);</para>

        <para>(iv) ratio of design rainfall intensities of AEPs of 2% and 50%
        for duration of 6 hour
        (<superscript>2%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>/<superscript>50%</superscript>I<subscript>6h</subscript>);
        and</para>

        <para>(v) <emphasis>shape factor</emphasis>, which is defined as the shortest distance
          between catchment outlet and centroid divided by the square root of catchment area. </para>

        <para>Design rainfall values were extracted from the new Intensity Frequency Duration (IFD)
          data for Australia as discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch3"/> of ARR. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_osmfhe"/> provides the distribution of shape factors for the selected
            catchments.<table frame="void" xml:id="b3_ch3_t_osmfhe">
            <caption>Distribution of Shape Factors for the Selected Catchments</caption>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Percentile</td>
                <td>1%</td>
                <td>10%</td>
                <td>50%</td>
                <td>90%</td>
                <td>99%</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Shape Factor</td>
                <td>0.32</td>
                <td>0.51</td>
                <td>0.76</td>
                <td>1.06</td>
                <td>1.51</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_pfnbw">
      <title>Adopted RFFE Regions</title>

      <para>Australia is divided into seven regions. There are five Humid Coastal regions (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_2kbsr"/>) and two arid/semi-arid regions (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_0x8hz"/>), as shown in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/>. There are seven fringe zones that are the
        interface between two regions, as discussed in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_m01jo"/>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_49qvf">
        <title>Adopted Regions for RFFE Technique in Australia</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3039.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_k3lzr" frame="void">
        <caption>Details of RFFE
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100639+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100639+1100" content="t"?>echnique
          for Humid Coastal
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100643+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100642+1100" content="a"?>reas
          of Australia</caption>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%" align="center"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Region</th>
            <th>Method to form region</th>
            <th>Number of stations</th>
            <th>Estimation model</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Region 1: East Coast</td>
            <td rowspan="5">ROI (based on geographical proximity)</td>
            <td>558</td>
            <td rowspan="5">Bayesian GLS regression-PRT</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Region 2: Tasmania</td>
            <td>51</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Region 3: Humid SA</td>
            <td>28</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Region 4: Top End NT and Kimberley</td>
            <td>58</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Region 5: SW WA</td>
            <td>103</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_o7h7w">
      <title>Adopted Estimation Equations</title>

      <para>For the five Humid Coastal regions described in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_k3lzr"/>, the
        adopted estimation equations for M<emphasis>,</emphasis> S and <emphasis>SK</emphasis> for
        the regional LP III model (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_swrce"/>) have the following general
        form:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_yitfd">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mi>M</mi>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>b</mi>

              <mn>0</mn>
            </msub>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>b</mi>

              <mn>1</mn>
            </msub>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mi>ln</mi>

                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <mi>a</mi>

                    <mi>r</mi>

                    <mi>e</mi>

                    <mi>a</mi>
                  </mrow>

                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>b</mi>

              <mn>2</mn>
            </msub>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mi>ln</mi>

                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>I</mi>

                      <mrow>
                        <mn>6</mn>

                        <mo>,</mo>

                        <mn>50</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>

                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>b</mi>

              <mn>3</mn>
            </msub>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mi>ln</mi>

                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>

                  <mrow>
                    <mtext>shape factor</mtext>
                  </mrow>

                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_n8zye">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mi>S</mi>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>c</mi>

              <mn>0</mn>
            </msub>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>c</mi>

              <mn>1</mn>
            </msub>

            <mi>ln</mi>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>I</mi>

                      <mrow>
                        <mn>6</mn>

                        <mo>,</mo>

                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>

                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>I</mi>

                      <mrow>
                        <mn>6</mn>

                        <mo>,</mo>

                        <mn>50</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_3r3ol">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <mi>S</mi>

            <mi>K</mi>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>d</mi>

              <mn>0</mn>
            </msub>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>d</mi>

              <mn>1</mn>
            </msub>

            <mi>ln</mi>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mtext>area</mtext>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>d</mi>

              <mn>2</mn>
            </msub>

            <mi>ln</mi>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>I</mi>

                      <mrow>
                        <mn>6</mn>

                        <mo>,</mo>

                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>

                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>I</mi>

                      <mrow>
                        <mn>6</mn>

                        <mo>,</mo>

                        <mn>50</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>d</mi>

              <mn>3</mn>
            </msub>

            <mi>ln</mi>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>I</mi>

                  <mrow>
                    <mn>6</mn>

                    <mo>,</mo>

                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </msub>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>where, area is the catchment area (km²);</para>

      <para>I<subscript>6,50</subscript> is the design rainfall intensity
      (mm/h) at catchment centroid for 6 hour duration and 50% AEP;</para>

      <para>shape factor is the shortest distance between catchment outlet and
      centroid/<emphasis>area</emphasis><superscript>0.5</superscript>;
      and</para>

      <para>I<subscript>6,2</subscript> is the design rainfall intensity
      (mm/h) at catchment centroid for 6 hour duration and 2% AEP.</para>

      <para>For Region 1 and 2, only the model intercepts were used in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_n8zye"/> and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_3r3ol"/>, which imply a regression
        equation without any predictor variable. Here, the weighted average values of S and SK were
        adopted, record lengths at the stations within the ROI sub-region were used as a basis for
        determining the weights.</para>

      <para>The values of b<subscript>0</subscript>, b<subscript>1</subscript>,
          b<subscript>2</subscript>, b<subscript>3</subscript>, c<subscript>0</subscript>,
          c<subscript>1</subscript>, d<subscript>0</subscript>, d<subscript>1</subscript>,
          d<subscript>2</subscript> and d<subscript>3</subscript> at all the 798 individual gauged
        catchment locations (in the Humid Coastal areas) were estimated and embedded in the RFFE
        Model 2015. To derive flood quantile estimates at an ungauged location of interest, the RFFE
        Model 2015 uses a natural neighbour interpolation method to derive quantile estimates based
        on up to the 15 nearest gauged catchment locations within 300 km radius from the location of
        interest. This ensures a smooth variation of flood quantile estimates over space.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ksbct">
    <title>RFFE Techniques for Arid/Semi-Arid Areas</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_4foca">
      <title>Data Used to Develop RFFE Technique</title>
      <para>Most of Australia's interior falls into the arid/semi-arid areas, which are
        characterised by low mean annual rainfall in relation to mean annual potential evaporation.
        Rainfall events tend to be infrequent and their occurrence and severity are highly variable.
        Typically dry antecedent conditions may result in many rainfall events not producing any
        significant runoff. However, severe rainfall events can still result in significant flooding
        with serious consequences. Large transmission losses (i.e. losses occurring from flow in
        rivers and other drainage channels) may also result in discharge reducing in a downstream
        direction, particularly in the lower river reaches of larger catchments in arid areas. The
        special flooding characteristics of catchments in arid/semi-arid areas make it desirable to
        treat them separately from catchments in more humid areas. In arid/semi-arid areas, annual
        maximum flood series generally contain many zero values; these values were censored in flood
        frequency analysis.</para>
      <para>In ARR 1987 <citation>arr_1987</citation>, only a few catchments were used from
        arid/semi-arid areas to develop RFFE methods. Since the publication of ARR 1987, there has
        been little improvement in terms of streamflow data availability in most of the
        arid/semi-arid areas of Australia. There are a number of reasons for poor stream gauging
        coverage and quality in arid/semi-arid areas, as follows:<orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Poorly defined water course catchments, meaning that the water courses are hard to
              define and therefore gauge.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Large floods may be outside the water course, meaning that the cross-section may
              be hard to measure and the flow may be difficult to gauge.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Infrequent flood events, meaning that the gauge may be operating for extended
              periods of time without any flow.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Remote location, making it difficult to take velocity measurements during the
              flood events.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Little incentive to gauge flows because of the perceived limited water resources
              and the limited demand for development of these resources.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>
      <para>In the preparation of the Regional Flood Frequency Estimation database, only a handful
        of catchments from the arid/semi-arid areas satisfied the selection criteria. To increase
        the number of stations from the arid/semi-arid areas to develop a RFFE method, the selection
        criteria were relaxed i.e. the threshold streamflow record length was reduced to 10 years
        and the limit of catchment size was increased from 1000 km² to 6000 km². These criteria
        resulted in the selection of 55 catchments from the arid/semi-arid areas of Australia (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_0x8hz"/>). The selected catchments
        have average annual rainfall less than 500 mm. The catchment areas range from 0.1 to 5975
        km² (median: 259 km²) and streamflow record lengths range from 10 to 46 years (median: 27
        years).</para>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_0x8hz" frame="void">
        <caption>Summary of adopted stations from arid/semi-arid areas of Australia</caption>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Location</th>
            <th>No. of stations</th>
            <th>Streamflow record length (years) (range and median)</th>
            <th>Catchment size (km<superscript>2</superscript>) (range and median)</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Pilbara</td>
            <td>11</td>
            <td>22 – 34 (28)</td>
            <td>0.2 – 5975 (303)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Arid and Semi-arid</td>
            <td>44</td>
            <td>10 – 46 (27)</td>
            <td>3 – 997 (209)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>TOTAL</td>
            <td>55</td>
            <td>10 – 46 (27)</td>
            <td>0.1 – 5975 (259)</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
     
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_bqt0e">
      <title>Adopted Regions</title>

      <para>The definition of regions in the arid/semi-arid areas in Australia is a difficult task,
        as there are only 55 catchments available over a vast area of Australia. There are two
        alternatives: (i) formation of one region with all the 55 stations; and (ii) formation of
        smaller sub-regions based on geographical proximity, noting that too small a region makes
        the developed RFFE technique of little statistical significance. Examination of a number of
        alternative sub-regions led to the formation of two regions from the 55 arid/semi-arid
        catchments: Region 6 (11 catchments from the Pilbara area of WA) and Region 7 (44 catchments
        from all other arid areas except Pilbara) (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> for the
        extent of these two arid/semi-arid regions and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_2kbsr"/> for other
        details).</para>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_2kbsr" frame="void">
        <caption>Details of RFFE technique for arid/semi-arid regions</caption>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Region</th>
            <th>Method to form region</th>
            <th>Number of stations</th>
            <th>Estimation model</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Region 6: Pilbara</td>
            <td rowspan="2">Fixed region</td>
            <td>11</td>
            <td rowspan="2">Index flood method with Q<subscript>10</subscript> as index
              variable</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Region 7: Arid and Semi-arid</td>
            <td>44</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

    
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ri9vz">
      <title>Adopted Estimation Equations</title>

      <para>Application of the ROI and PRT methods for arid/semi-arid regions was deemed
        inappropriate as the ROI due to an insufficient number of gauges. Hence a simpler RFFE
        method was considered more appropriate for the two arid/semi-arid regions. Here, an index
        type approach as suggested by <citation>b3_c3_r9+1</citation> is adopted. The 10% AEP flood
        quantile (Q<subscript>10</subscript>) was used as the index variable and a dimensionless
        Growth Factor for X% AEP (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) was used to estimate
          Q<subscript>x</subscript>:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_xhxx7">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>Q</mi>

              <mi>x</mi>
            </msub>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>Q</mi>

                <mi>10</mi>
              </msub>

              <mo>×</mo>

              <msub>
                <mi>GF</mi>

                <mi>x</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>A prediction equation was developed for Q<subscript>10</subscript> as a function of
        catchment characteristics, and regional growth factors were developed based on the estimated
        at-site flood quantile. In the arid areas, significant storm events do not typically occur
        every year, and some of these events do not produce significant floods. The at-site Flood
        Frequency Analyses for the arid catchments was conducted using the FLIKE software
          <citation>b3_c3_r23</citation>. The Potential Influential Low Flows (PILFs) were
        identified using multiple Grubbs-Beck test <citation>b3_c3_r24</citation> and were censored
        in the Flood Frequency Analysis. A Bayesian parameter estimation procedure with LP III
        distribution was used to estimate flood quantiles for each gauged site for AEPs of 50%, 20%,
        10%, 5%, 2% and 1%. It should be noted that the Flood Frequency Analysis procedure adopted
        in the Humid Coastal and arid areas was the same.</para>

      <para>The Q<subscript>x</subscript>/Q<subscript>10</subscript> values were estimated at
        individual stations; the weighted average of these values (weighting was done based on
        record length at individual stations) over all the stations in a region then defined the
        Growth Factors (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) for the region.</para>

      <para>The adopted prediction equation for the index variable
      Q<subscript>10</subscript> has the following form:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_6mwfc">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mrow>
                <mi>log</mi>
              </mrow>

              <mrow>
                <mn>10</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msub>

            <mo>=</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>b</mi>

              <mn>0</mn>
            </msub>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>b</mi>

              <mn>1</mn>
            </msub>

            <msub>
              <mrow>
                <mi>log</mi>
              </mrow>

              <mrow>
                <mn>10</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msub>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <mtext>area</mtext>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>

            <mo>+</mo>

            <msub>
              <mi>b</mi>

              <mn>2</mn>
            </msub>

            <msub>
              <mrow>
                <mi>log</mi>
              </mrow>

              <mrow>
                <mn>10</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msub>

            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>

              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>I</mi>

                  <mrow>
                    <mn>6</mn>

                    <mo>,</mo>

                    <mn>50</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </msub>
              </mrow>

              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>

      <para>where b<subscript>0</subscript>, b<subscript>1</subscript> and
      b<subscript>2</subscript> are regression coefficients, estimated using
      ordinary least squares regression; area represents catchment area in
      km², and I<subscript>6,50</subscript> is the design rainfall intensity
      (mm/h) at catchment centroid for 6 hour duration and 50% AEP. The values
      of b<subscript>0</subscript>, b<subscript>1</subscript> and
      b<subscript>2</subscript> and the regional Growth Factors
      (GF<subscript>x</subscript>) are embedded into the RFFE Model
      2015.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_m01jo">
    <title>Fringe Zones</title>
    <para>The boundaries between the arid/semi-arid and Humid Coastal regions in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> were drawn (as a smoothed line) approximately based on the 500 mm
      mean annual rainfall contour. To reduce the effects of sharp variation in flood estimates for
      the ungauged catchments located close to these regional boundaries, seven fringe zones were
      delineated, as shown <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/>. The boundary of the fringe zone with
      the Humid Coastal region was approximately defined by the 500 mm mean annual rainfall isohyet,
      while the other side was defined by the 400 mm mean annual rainfall isohyet to establish a
      fringe zone. In drawing the boundary, some minor adjustment was made to make the boundary as
      smooth as possible. </para>
    <para>For these fringe zones, the flood estimate at an ungauged catchment location is taken as
      the inverse distance weighted average value of the flood estimates based on the two nearest
      regions. The method is embedded into the RFFE Model 2015.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_yj49v">
    <title>Relative Accuracy of the RFFE Technique</title>
    <para>The reliability and accuracy of the RFFE quantile estimates were assessed using
      leave-one-out (LOO) validation. In the LOO validation, one catchment was left out from the
      model data set and the RFFE technique is applied to the catchment that was left out. The flood
      quantiles estimated using the RFFE technique were then compared with the at-site flood
      frequency estimates obtained by FLIKE <citation>b3_c3_r23</citation> as mentioned in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_4foca"/>. The procedure was repeated for each catchment in the regional
      data set to provide an overall assessment of the performance of the RFFE technique.</para>
    <para>The reliability of the RFFE flood quantile confidence limits described in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_7r0rn"/> was assessed empirically using standardised quantile residuals.
      The quantile residual is the difference between the logarithm of flood quantile estimates
      obtained using at-site Flood Frequency Analysis and the RFFE technique. The standardised
      quantile residual is the quantile residual divided by its standard deviation which is the
      square root of the sum of the RFFE predictive variance of the flood quantile and at-site
      quantile variance <citation>b3_c3_r17,b3_c3_r26</citation>. This accounts for both the model
      error (e.g. inadequacy of the RFFE model) and the sampling error (e.g. due to limiteations in
      streamflow record length). If the uncertainty in the log quantile estimates has been
      adequately described, the standardised quantile residuals should be consistent with a standard
      normal distribution.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_6ppin"/> shows the plots of standardised residuals vs. normal
      scores for Region 1 for AEPs of 10% and 5% (the plots for other AEPs for Region 1 are provided
      in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_wt69y"/>). Plots for other regions can be seen also in
        <citation>b3_c3_r41+1</citation>. These residuals were estimated without bias correction
      (details of bias correction are provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_jsne6"/> ). These plots
      include 558 catchments from Region 1 used in the RFFE model and some 28 catchments which were
      excluded from the final RFFE model data set based on the results of preliminary analysis and
      unusual characteristics such as significant natural floodplain storage. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_6ppin"/> reveals that most of the 558 catchments closely follow a 1:1
      straight line indicating that the assumption of normality of the residuals was not
      inconsistent with the evidence; this is supported by the application of the Anderson-Darling
      and Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests which showed that the assumption of the normality of the
      residuals cannot be rejected at the 10% level of significance. Under the assumptions of
      normality, approximately 90% of the standardised quantile residuals should lie between ± 2,
      which is largely satisfied. There were a few catchments with standardised residual values
      close to ± 3. These correspond to instances where the RFFE confidence limits may not be
      reliable; an example of such a catchment is provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_p4hvx"/>. The
      same conclusion applies to the other Humid Coastal regions.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_6ppin">
      <title>Standardised
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100712+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100711+1100" content="r"?>esiduals
        vs.
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100715+1100"?>N<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100715+1100" content="n"?>ormal
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100718+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100718+1100" content="s"?>cores
        for Region 1
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100721+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100721+1100" content="b"?>ased
        on Leave One Out
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100726+1100"?>V<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100724+1100" content="v"?>alidation
        for AEPs of 10% and 5%</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="75%" fileref="../../figures/3041.png" scalefit="1" width="75%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>The main conclusion from this analysis is that the quantification of uncertainty in the
      quantile estimates by the RFFE technique is reliable for the vast majority of the cases. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_6ppin"/> and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_p4hvx"/> serve as a reminder that
      some catchments may not be adequately represented by the catchments used in the RFFE analysis.
      Users of the RFFE Model 2015 should check that the catchment of interest is not atypical
      compared with the gauged catchments included in the ROI used to develop the RFFE estimate. To
      assist users in this regard the RFFE Model 2015 discussed in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs"/>
      and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8airu"/> lists the RFFE Model gauged catchments located nearest to
      the ungauged catchment of interest. </para>
    <para>The accuracy of the flood quantile estimates provided by the RFFE technique is evaluated
      by using the Relative Error (RE) defined as:</para>
    <equation xml:id="b3_ch3_e_tq1ze">
      <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
        <mrow>
          <mi>RE(%)</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>Q</mi>
                  <mi>RFFE</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>Q</mi>
                  <mi>FFA</mi>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>Q</mi>
                <mi>FFA</mi>
              </msub>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>×</mo>
            <mi>100</mi>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </math>
    </equation>
    <para>where Q<subscript>RFFE</subscript> is the flood quantile estimate for a given site for a
      given AEP by the RFFE technique; and Q<subscript>FFA</subscript> is the flood quantile
      estimate from the at-site Flood Frequency Analysis (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_i6yzh"/> for
      details).</para>
    <para>It should be noted that the Relative Error given by <xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_tq1ze"/> makes
      no allowance for the fact that the at-site flood frequency estimates are themselves subject to
      sampling error. Therefore, this error should be seen as an upper bound on the true relative
      error.</para>
    <para>It should be noted here that LOO is a more rigorous validation technique compared with the
      split-sample validation where the model is tested on a smaller number of catchments (e.g. 10%
      of the total catchments). Hence, the relative error that is generated by LOO is expected to be
      higher than if split-sample validation were used. The medians of the absolute relative error
      values from the LOO validation for different regions are reported in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_0hp5h"/>. It can be seen that for the Humid Coastal regions, Region 5 (SW
      WA) has the highest relative error (59 to 69%) and Region 3 (Humid SA) has the smallest
      relative error (33 to 41%).</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_jsne6">
    <title>Bias Correction</title>

    <para>In the spatial plots of the standardised residuals, a few cluster of notable
      underestimation and overestimation were detected. To overcome this problem, a bias correction
      was implemented, which attempeds to provide estimates of <emphasis role="italic">M</emphasis>
      (for Humid Coastal areas) (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_yitfd"/>) and Q<subscript>10</subscript>
      (for arid/semi-arid areas) (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_e_6mwfc"/>) closer to the observed <emphasis role="italic">M</emphasis> or Q<subscript>10</subscript> at the location of each of the 853
      model gauged catchments. This correction was based on an additive bias correction factor <inlineequation>
        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>M</mi>
              <mi>FFA</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <msub>
              <mi>M</mi>
              <mi>RFFE</mi>
            </msub>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </inlineequation>, (obtained at each of the model 798 gauged catchments in the Humid Coastal
      areas) and <inlineequation>
        <math display="inline" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mfrac bevelled="true">
            <msub>
              <mi>Q</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mi>10</mi>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mi>FFA</mi>
              </mrow>
            </msub>
            <msub>
              <mi>Q</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mi>10</mi>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <mi>RFFE</mi>
              </mrow>
            </msub>
          </mfrac>
        </math>
      </inlineequation> (obtained at each of the model 55 catchments in arid/semi-arid areas). In
      practice, for an ungauged location of interest, an interpolated bias correction factor is
      calculated by the software using Natural Neighbour approach based on nearby 15 gauged
      catchments. It was found that this approach reduced the clusters of bias in the spatial plots
      of the standardised residuals and hence was adopted in the RFFE Model 2015. </para>
    <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_0hp5h" frame="void">
      <caption>Upper bound on (absolute) median relative error (RE) from leave-one-out validation of
        the RFFE technique (without considering bias correction)</caption>
      <col width="14%"/>
      <col width="14%"/>
      <col width="14%"/>
      <col width="14%"/>
      <col width="14%"/>
      <col width="14%"/>
      <col width="14%"/>
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th rowspan="3">Region</th>
          <th colspan="6">Median RE (%)</th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <th colspan="6">AEP</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>50%</th>
          <th>20%</th>
          <th>10%</th>
          <th>5%</th>
          <th>2%</th>
          <th>1%</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Region 1: East Coast</td>
          <td>51</td>
          <td>49</td>
          <td>52</td>
          <td>53</td>
          <td>57</td>
          <td>59</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Region 2: Tasmania</td>
          <td>53</td>
          <td>46</td>
          <td>46</td>
          <td>46</td>
          <td>46</td>
          <td>45</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Region 3: Humid SA</td>
          <td>38</td>
          <td>39</td>
          <td>33</td>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>39</td>
          <td>41</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Region 4: Top End NT and Kimberley</td>
          <td>33</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>38</td>
          <td>39</td>
          <td>47</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Region 5: SW WA</td>
          <td>61</td>
          <td>59</td>
          <td>66</td>
          <td>68</td>
          <td>68</td>
          <td>69</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Region 6: Pilbara</td>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>37</td>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>42</td>
          <td>37</td>
          <td>43</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Region 7: Arid and Semi-arid</td>
          <td>63</td>
          <td>67</td>
          <td>67</td>
          <td>61</td>
          <td>57</td>
          <td>49</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>

  
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_5x575">
    <title>Combining Regional and At-Site Quantile Estimates</title>

    <para>Unless a station has a very long annual maximum flood series data (e.g. greater than 100
      years), it is desirable to combine at-site and regional flood frequency quantile estimates to
      achieve a more accurate estimate. The RFFE Model 2015 (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs"/>
      for the description of the model) provides the necessary parameter set and data in its output
      to combine the regional flood quantile estimates with the at-site data. This is discussed in
      more detail in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_31eib">
    <title>Impact of Climate Change</title>

    <para>The adopted regional estimation equations include design rainfall intensity as a key input
      variable. As a result the impact of climate change as reflected in changes in design rainfall
      estimates (which are expected to be upgraded regularly) can be propagated through the RFFE
      Model 2015 to provide a first order estimate of the impact of climate change on regional
      design flood estimates. This approach assumes that that the contribution of the other
      catchment characteristics affecting flood production does not change with future climate
      state. Given that this assumption is unlikely to be valid <citation>b3_c3_r2</citation> the
      use of potential future rainfall intensities in the RFFE Model 2015 will indicate the
      sensitivity of the design flood estimates with respect to climate change state. Further
      research on the impact of climate change on rainfall and flood in Australia will allow
      updating of the RFFE Model 2015 by incorporating the impact of climate change.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Progressive Improvement of RFFE Model 2015 v1</title>

    <para>It is expected that the RFFE Model 2015 v1 will be updated in future when the streamflow
      record lengths at the selected 853 gauged catchments increase significantly and/or when
      additional catchments are available that satisfy the criteria of catchment selection (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_wfiku"/>). Furthermore, additional predictor variables can potentially be
      included in the RFFE Model to enhance model accuracy, in particular if GIS based techniques
      can be adopted to more readily extract the additional predictor variables such as stream
      density and main stream slope.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>RFFE Implementation and Limitations</title>
    <section>
      <title>Overview of RFFE
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100925+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100925+1100" content="a"?>ccuracy</title>
      <section>
        <title>Data
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100930+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100930+1100" content="c"?>overage</title>
        <para>The RFFE Model has been developed from a detailed analysis of all appropriate
          streamflow gauging stations throughout Australia. The selected 853 gauges met the criteria
          for application to the development of the procedure.</para>
        <para>It must be recognised however that this is a small number of gauges in the 7.7 million
            km<superscript>2</superscript> area of Australia. In addition to the sparse gauge
          coverage, there is a significant variation in catchment types across Australia. The RFFE
          Model must use the available data to develop a regional procedure that can estimate flood
          quantiles with the best possible accuracy. Relevant catchment characteristics therefore
          may not be represented sufficiently to allow inclusion in the regional
          relationship.</para>
        <para>There are insufficient gauges to provide a representative coverage of all catchment
          types throughout Australia. This is a particular concern in the arid and semi-arid
          interior.</para>
        <para>The regional relationship implemented in ARR has therefore used only characteristics
          that are sampled sufficiently. These characteristics are catchment area, rainfall
          intensity parameters and shape factor. Other factors, such as land use, slope, soils,
          geology or vegetation, are not sampled sufficiently to allow inclusion in the parameters
          used for the procedure, even though they are known to be important in the estimation of
          flood quantiles.</para>
        <para>The RFFE Model therefore may be regarded as providing a “generic” estimate of flood
          quantiles for a range of typical catchment types. It may be expected that different flood
          estimates would be derived for other catchment types that have catchment characteristics
          that are dissimilar to those used in development of the method. If there were a larger
          sample of gauged catchments in Australia and they sampled a wider variety of catchment
          types, it is expected that the RFFE Model would incorporate a wider range of catchment
          characteristics and would therefore be capable of more reliable estimates for a wider
          range of catchments.</para>
        <para>The procedure is based on the analysis of the selected catchment characteristics, but
          improvements in the procedure are possible with additional analysis.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Data
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100934+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100934+1100" content="a"?>ccuracy</title>
        <para>While there is a relatively small and possibly unrepresentative distribution of gauged
          catchments used in the development of the procedure, it is also noted that there are
          inaccuracies in the base data used to develop the procedure. The gauges were selected to
          ensure at least a minimum quality standard. However all gauges have some level of
          inaccuracy, which could be caused by extrapolation of rating curves, variability with
          rating curves over time, effects of backwater at the gauge, changing catchment conditions,
          or flow diversions and overflows that affect flows. These factors particularly impact on
          the quality of flow records for the larger flows, which are the important records for
          Flood Frequency Analysis.</para>
        <para>Imposing a higher data quality standard will reduce the number of gauges for analysis
          while lowering the standard will result in greater errors in the data used to develop the
          procedure.</para>
        <para>For the development of the RFFE Model, the decision has been to impose a minimum data
          quality standard, to ensure a maximum number of gauges were included.</para>
        <para>It must be noted though that such data inaccuracies were not be identified during the
          development of the RFFE Model as the analysis involved a large number of stations and
          detailed assessment of each of these was not feasible. The meta-data and other
          documentation provided by the water agencies was not sufficiently detailed to allow a
          routine assessment of data quality, and it was necessary to rely on local advice as to the
          suitability of the data used.</para>
        <para>The inclusion of this data may impact on the quality of the regional results, but does
          improve the representativeness of the data. While it is impossible to quantify this
          impact, the possible impact needs to be borne in mind.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Representative
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100938+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100937+1100" content="p"?>eriods
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100941+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100940+1100" content="r"?>ecord</title>
        <para>The selection of the gauged catchments for analysis was based on the period of record
          with a minimum record length of 20 years. This record length could have been for the most
          recent period for stations that are still operating or it could have been for an earlier
          period for closed stations.</para>
        <para>Longer periods of record are more likely to represent the variability in flood
          magnitude and also more likely to sample large floods that occur infrequently. However,
          even with a record length of more than 20 years, it is possible that the record may not
          sample a wide range of flood sizes and there is still a potential source of inaccuracy
          when extrapolating to larger floods. The samples from different time periods may also
          affect the flood quantiles since it is well known that there are longer term variations in
          the distribution of flood maxima due to inter-decadel variability in climate. This may
          result in differences in the design flood quantiles that are purely a result of the sample
          period rather than a real difference in flood probability.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>RFFE Implementation</title>
      <para>The estimates of flood quantiles from the RFFE Model must be regarded as a first
        approximation of the required quantiles. In many cases, the estimates from the RFFE Model
        may provide an acceptable result for application.</para>
      <para>However, given the accuracy considerations discussed above, some additional testing and
        review is recommended.</para>
      <para>The additional testing and review can include the following processes:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Review the catchment characteristics for the catchment being analysed and assess
            whether this catchment is typical for catchments that have been used in the development
            of the method: This review needs to consider the catchments in the local area, or
            elsewhere in Australia. The most relevant characteristics to review include the
            catchment shape, slope, soils and vegetation. The extent of floodplain storage, either
            natural or artificial needs to be reviewed. If the target catchment has features that
            are distinctly different from the range found in “typical” gauged catchments, the
            results from the RFFE Model can be either discarded or adjusted to allow for the local
            conditions.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Review the nearby catchments listed in the RFFE Model: These are the nearest gauged
            catchments that have been used in the development of the procedure and are some gauges
            that will influence the results for the Region of Influence calculations. </para>
          <para>This review will need to consider whether these nearby catchments are similar to the
            target catchment or if there are any apparent outliers in this group. As with the review
            of catchment characteristics, the review of the nearby catchments in the RFFE Model
            could lead to an adjustment in the results, or the decision for the flood quantiles for
            the target catchment to be transposed directly (allowing for differences in catchment
            area) from a nearby catchment that is most similar to the target catchment.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Consider an independent flood estimation procedure: such as the application of a
            runoff-routing model using regional parameter estimates that are appropriate for
            ungauged catchments in the local region. It must be remembered that these alternative
            procedures are still uncertain, but reconciliation of estimates from different sources
            provides valuable information with which to derive a “best estimate”. Consideration of
            catchment characteristics and similarities or differences need to be a part of this
            assessment. The RFFE Model results may be adjusted or neglected depending on the
            conclusions of this independent analysis.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Review any local available data: This data may be as uncertain as a limited amount
            of anecdotal data, such as an observation of the frequency of overtopping of a bridge
            for example. Depending on the findings of the check of local observations, the RFFE
            Model results may need adjustment. The results of the RFFE Model calculation can be
            compared with the local observation to at least ensure that the calculated design flood
            quantiles are consistent with the local observations.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The conclusion of this additional analysis is that the calculated RFFE Model flood
        quantiles are not perfect, though they do provide the means to develop estimates that are
        consistent with a large body of gauged records. Further consideration of the results and
        possible adjustment will help to ensure a better estimate of the design flood quantiles
        needed for inclusion in the analysis.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8airu">
    <title>Practical Considerations for Application of the RFFE Technique</title>
    <para>The basis of the RFFE Model 2015 has been the analysis of all available streamflow gauging
      stations that meet the selection criteria described in this chapter, primarily that the stream
      gauge has an adequate length of record and the streamflow data are of “reasonable” quality and
      relate to relatively natural catchments. Most selected streamflow gauges have a catchment area
      less than 1000 km<superscript>2</superscript>. The RFFE Model parameters were then developed
      based on regionalisation of the at-site flood quantiles for all of these gauges from a given
      region. All available and suitable streamflow data for all of Australia were adopted to
      develop the RFFE Model. </para>
    <para>While the RFFE Model is appropriate for catchment types represented by the gauged
      catchments used to develop this model, there are catchments where the method either cannot be
      applied or where there may be gross error in the flood quantile estimates if the RFFE Model
      were applied without adjustments. These catchment types are described below.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Urban
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100948+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100947+1100" content="c"?>atchments</title>
      <para>One of the criteria for catchment selection in the development of the RFFE Model was
        that there should be essentially no urbanisation in the catchment, or at least such a small
        proportion that the Flood Frequency Analysis was not affected. It is well known that
        flooding is affected, sometimes significantly by urbanisation. There are insufficient gauged
        urban catchments to allow development of a RFFE Model for urban catchments.</para>
      <para>Therefore, the RFFE Model 2015 cannot be applied for any catchment where urbanisation
        accounts for more than 10% of the catchment area, or where it is considered that there may
        be an impact of urbanisation on rainfall runoff relationship. In these cases an alternative
        approach for estimating design floods is needed, as no equivalent regional method to the
        rural RFFE Model is available.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Catchments
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100951+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100950+1100" content="c"?>ontaining
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100954+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100953+1100" content="d"?>ams
        and
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100956+1100"?>O<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T100955+1100" content="o"?>ther
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101000+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101000+1100" content="a"?>rtificial
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101002+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101002+1100" content="s"?>torage</title>
      <para>Dams or other artificial water storages will attenuate flood hydrographs and will
        therefore reduce the flood peak discharges at the catchment outlet. The selection of
        catchments used in the development of the RFFE Model excluded those with dams that were
        regarded as sufficiently significant to have an impact on flood discharges.</para>
      <para>If a catchment has a dam where there will be an impact on flood discharges, the RFFE
        Model cannot be applied directly. In this case, the RFFE Model can be used to calculate
        design flood discharges for the “natural” catchment and then the effects of the dam can be
        included by the application of a runoff-routing model where the storage effects can be
        modelled directly.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Catchments
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101006+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101005+1100" content="a"?>ffected
        by
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101009+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101008+1100" content="m"?>ining</title>
      <para>Catchments where mining activity has affected a significant portion of the catchment
        area have also been excluded from those used to develop the RFFE Model. Catchments where
        mining activities are significant may produce lower flood peak discharges than natural
        catchments due to the presence of water quality ponds, tailings dams and other water
        management infrastructure and the mine pit itself. In addition, the runoff response from
        mining areas that include waste dumps and rehabilitated areas will be quite distinct from
        natural catchments.</para>
      <para>In cases where mining is judged to impact a significant proportion of a catchment, the
        RFFE Model can only be applied on the natural portions of the catchment. The area affected
        by mining activities should be modelled by an alternative method. Assessment of the water
        balance affecting the volume of runoff is needed to ensure that the effects of water control
        in ponds and mine pits and infiltration in highly modified catchments is represented
        correctly. The catchment response is also affected by drainage works and diversions.
        Calculation of runoff from mining areas is a complex and specialised exercise and detailed
        understanding of individual conditions is necessary. In general, a detailed runoff-routing
        model is needed as well as a good understanding of the water balance in these situations.
        However, direct calibration of runoff routing models on ungauged catchments is not possible,
        which may result in grossly inaccurate design flood estimates.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Catchments with
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101015+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101014+1100" content="i"?>ntensive
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101017+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101016+1100" content="a"?>gricultural
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101019+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101019+1100" content="a"?>ctivity</title>
      <para>While many of the catchments used in development of the RFFE Model have been located in
        agricultural regions, few are in areas of intensive agriculture, where the flood response
        may be affected by farm dams, soil conservation works or irrigation infrastructure. Many
        agricultural regions may be laser levelled to produce topography that is artificial and
        quite different from the natural catchments that are the primary catchment types used to
        develop the RFFE Model. The objectives of works on agricultural land is often to slow the
        rate of runoff and increase infiltration to the soil profile, thus the flood peak discharges
        will often be reduced on these catchment types as compared to the general catchment type as
        used to develop the RFFE Model.</para>
      <para>Catchments affected by intense agricultural activities are similar to these affected by
        mining and similar analysis methods are needed to calculate flood discharges.</para>
      <para>In this case the RFFE Model cannot be applied directly but additional analysis is needed
        to assess the catchment characteristics and then prepare a runoff-routing model to adjust
        the generic RFFE Model results using the catchment storage and channel
        characteristics.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Catchment
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101025+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101024+1100" content="s"?>ize</title>
      <para>The RFFE Model has been developed using all suitable gauged catchments throughout
        Australia with catchment areas generally less than 1000 km<superscript>2</superscript>. </para>
      <para>The RFFE Model can be applied to small catchments with no lower limit though it is
        recognised that there are only a few gauged catchments smaller than 10
          km<superscript>2</superscript> included in the database to develop the RFFE Model. Because
        of the limited available data, it is likely that there will be a greater degree of error in
        the quantile estimates for these smaller catchments. </para>
      <para>The RFFE Model should not be applied for catchments larger than 1000
          km<superscript>2</superscript> because these larger catchments were not generally used in
        the development of the method.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Catchment
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101030+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101029+1100" content="s"?>hape</title>
      <para>The distribution of the shape factors of the selected catchments in developing the RFFE
        Model is shown in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_osmfhe"/>. An ungauged catchment with shape factor
        beyond 10%-90% limit as shown in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_osmfhe"/> will have lower accuracy
        in the estimated flood quantiles.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Atypical
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101034+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101034+1100" content="c"?>atchment
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101036+1100"?>T<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101036+1100" content="t"?>ypes</title>
      <para>The catchment characteristics adopted in the RFFE Model were limited to readily
        available/easily obtainable catchment variables. The catchment characteristics used to
        calculate model parameters are limited and testing did not determine that more complex
        characteristics provide significant benefit in the regional relationship.</para>
      <para>It is known that there are many other catchment characteristics that influence catchment
        response and flood discharges. These include factors such as:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Catchment land use including vegetation coverage: The extent of clearing or forest
            cover can have a significant impact, especially in the south-west of Western Australia,
            for example.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Soils and geology: These factors influence the rainfall losses and catchment flood
            response.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Slopes: Steeper catchments respond more rapidly and therefore produce larger flood
            peaks.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Channel types and floodplain storage: Well defined channels and smaller floodplain
            storage extents produce faster response and therefore larger flood peaks.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>In cases where the catchment requiring the design flood estimate is judged to have
        characteristics significantly different from those used in the development of the RFFE
        Model, further hydrology and hydraulic analyses may be needed to refine the results from the
        generic RFFE Model results.</para>
      <para>The RFFE Model has been developed from the analysis of gauged catchments, but in reality
        all catchments exhibit some differences. Gauges need to be installed at locations where
        there is a sensitive and stable control and where the flow is well constrained within a
        defined stream channel. This means that larger catchments with extensive floodplain storage
        of widely distributed flow for example may not be well represented in the gauged dataset.
        These catchments may also have lower data quality but may well be required for design
        purposes.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Catchment
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101122+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101122+1100" content="l"?>ocation</title>
      <para>Considering the large size of Australia and the relatively small number of gauged
        catchments used for the development of the RFFE Model, the average density of gauged
        catchments used in developing the model is quite low. In addition, it must be recognised
        that there are errors in the streamflow data (e.g. rating curve extrapolation error) used to
        develop the RFFE Model. </para>
      <para>This means that catchments where design flood discharges are needed may be remote from
        the gauged catchments used to develop the RFFE Model and may have distinct differences from
        the adopted gauged catchments. </para>
      <para>In these cases, the application of the RFFE Model may produce inaccurate results and
        hence additional review and checking are necessary to confirm that the catchment being
        analysed has similar characteristics to those used to develop the RFFE Model. Where there
        are significant differences, a similar assessment to that needed for atypical catchments
        should be considered, and an adjustment to the generic RFFE Model result may be
        needed.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Arid and
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101159+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101158+1100" content="s"?>emi-arid
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101202+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101201+1100" content="a"?>reas</title>
      <para>The arid and semi-arid areas of Australia pose a particular problem. The RFFE Model
        divides these areas into two regions, the Pilbara and Arid and semi-arid. There are few
        gauged catchments in these regions with only 55 gauged catchments to represent a total area
        of about 5 million km<superscript>2</superscript>. </para>
      <para>The stream gauges in this region are often located at sites that may not be
        representative of the general area, since the gauge sites are selected because of access,
        confined channel and stable control, which may not be typical of the types of sites where
        design flood discharges are needed. </para>
      <para>The Pilbara region is not as diverse as the remainder of arid and semi-arid areas and
        the RFFE Model estimates for catchments in the Pilbara can be adopted subject to the other
        limitations discussed here.</para>
      <para>The general arid and semi-arid region though is more complex. The RFFE Model results for
        this region are based on the best available data from the gauges, but because of the
        diversity of conditions and the very low desnity of gauging, the RFFE Model results are very
        uncertain.</para>
      <para>Because of this the recommended approach for the arid and semi-arid zone requires some
        additional analysis to refine the standard results. The RFFE Model data-base report
          <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181210T095849+1100" content="(Rahman et al, 2015a)"?><citation>b3_c3_r40</citation>
        has a listing of all of the catchments that were used in the development of the method and
        the application of the RFFE Model software provides a map of the neighbouring catchments
        that were used in the development of the method.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Baseflow</title>
      <para>The RFFE Model has been developed using at-site flood frequency analysis, so the
        estimated peak discharges include baseflow. This means that the results from the RFFE Model
        will not be consistent with those from runoff-routing models where only surface runoff is
        calculated. While baseflow is only a minor part of the total flood hydrograph in many areas
        of Australia, there are some areas where it is more significant and it becomes more
        important when considering smaller floods. When working with the two methods it is thus
        necessary to make appropriate allowance for baseflow contribution to the peak and volume of
        the design flood.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_8u3cs">
    <title>RFFE Model 2015</title>
    <para>The RFFE technique presented in this chapter has been incorporated into a software tool
      referred to as RFFE Model 2015. The current version of the RFFE Model 2015 can be accessed
      from the ARR website<footnote>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190506T115724+1000" content="www.arr.org.au"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190506T115724+1000"?><link
          xlink:href="http://rffe.arr-software.org/"
          >http://rffe.arr-software.org/</link><?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </footnote>. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_i5krg"/> presents a screen shot of the RFFE Model 2015
      software landing page. The model requires the following basic inputs (to be entered by the
      user in the interface shown in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_8n08s"/>) for the catchment of interest
      to generate design flood estimates for six AEPs (50%, 20%, 10%, 5%, 2% and 1%).</para>
    <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment name;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment outlet latitude in decimal degrees;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment outlet longitude in decimal degrees;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment centroid latitude in decimal degrees;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment centroid longitude in decimal degrees; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment area in km<superscript>2</superscript>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>In the "Advanced" data input option, the user can also enter the following inputs:</para>
    <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
      <listitem>
        <para>Region name (can be selected from the dropdown list, see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_gpkr3"/> for region name and <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> for the
          extent of the regions);
          <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_gpkr3" frame="void">
            <caption>Region
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101251+1100"?>N<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101250+1100" content="n"?>ames
              for
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101253+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101253+1100" content="a"?>pplication
              of the RFFE Model 2015 (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_49qvf"/> for the
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101305+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101305+1100" content="e"?>xtent
              of the
              <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101309+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101309+1100" content="r"?>egions)</caption>
            <col width="50%"/>
            <col width="50%"/>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Region name</th>
                <th>Region code</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>Region 1: East Coast</td>
                <td>1</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Region 2: Tasmania</td>
                <td>2</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Region 3: Humid SA</td>
                <td>3</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Region 4: Top End NT and Kimberley</td>
                <td>4</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Region 5: SW WA</td>
                <td>5</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Region 6: Pilbara</td>
                <td>6</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Region 7: Arid and Semi-arid</td>
                <td>7</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid for 50% AEP and duration of 6 hour in
          mm/h; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Design rainfall intensity at catchment centroid for 2% AEP and duration of 6 hour in
          mm/h.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>The RFFE Model 2015 output contains the following principal information (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_0hl0m"/> as an example).</para>
    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_i5krg">
      <title>Screen
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101329+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101328+1100" content="s"?>hot
        of RFFE Model 2015
        (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101400+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101400+1100" content="l"?>anding
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101402+1100"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101402+1100" content="p"?>age)</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3042.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_8n08s">
      <title>RFFE Model 2015
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101341+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101337+1100" content="s"?>creen
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101343+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101343+1100" content="s"?>hot
        for
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101346+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101346+1100" content="d"?>ata
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101348+1100" content="i"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101352+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?>nput
        for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3043.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_0hl0m">
      <title>RFFE Model 2015
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101408+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101407+1100" content="s"?>creen
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101409+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101409+1100" content="s"?>hot
        for
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101412+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101411+1100" content="m"?>odel
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101414+1100"?>O<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101413+1100" content="o"?>utput
        for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW (Region 1)</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3044.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
      <listitem>
        <para>A table of AEP (in the first column), estimated flood quantiles labelled as discharge
            (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s) in the second column, lower confidence limit (5%)
          (third column) and upper confidence limit (95%) (fourth column). The confidence limits
          represent the overall uncertainty with the estimated flood quantiles by the RFFE Model
          2015.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A second table labelled "Statistics", which shows the statistics for the regional LP
          III model at the catchment of interest, which are particularly useful to combine at-site
          and regional information to enhance the accuracy of flood quantile estimates (for details
          see <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A graph that shows estimated flood quantiles and confidence limits against
          AEPs.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A graph that shows the catchment of interest with outlet and centroid locations and
          nearby gauged catchments that were included in the database to develop RFFE
          technique.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A download menu that allows the user to save the results and additional outputs
          generated by the model.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>Three worked examples are provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_ue0ar"/> to illustrate the
      use of RFFE Model 2015. The first two examples relate to catchments with no major regulation,
      no major natural or artificial storage and no major land use changes over time where the RFFE
      Model 2015 is directly applicable.</para>
    <para>The third example relates to a catchment which has significant natural floodplain storage
      where RFFE Model 2015 is not directly applicable. For this case, the RFFE Model significantly
      overestimates the flood quantiles (as compared to at-site Flood Frequency Analysis). Here, the
      RFFE Model estimates need to be adjusted to account for the storage effect of the catchment by
      applying an appropriate technique (see <xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_8airu"/> for further
      details).</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ue0ar">
    <title>Worked Examples</title>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_05i4o">
      <title>Application of RFFE Model 2015 to the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW (Region 1) (A
        Catchment Having No Major Regulation, No Major Natural or Artificial Storage and No Major
        Land Use Change)</title>
      <para>The basic input data for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW are provided in <xref
          linkend="b3_ch3_t_rdr78"/>. The model screen shot for the data input is provided in <xref
          linkend="b3_ch3_f_8n08s"/>. The flood quantiles generated by the RFFE Model 2015 are
        provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_0hl0m"/>. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_mb7b8"/> compares the
        RFFE Model and at-site FFA estimates, which shows that the RFFE Model estimates match the
        at-site FFA estimates well except for rarer AEPs where the RFFE Model estimates are higher
        compared with the at-site FFA estimates. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_mb7b8"/> also shows that
        the confidence band of the RFFE Model 2015 is much wider compared with at-site FFA
        confidence band, which is expected.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_mb7b8">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs.
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101624+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101623+1100" content="a"?>t-site
          FFA
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101626+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101626+1100" content="f"?>lood
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101628+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101628+1100" content="e"?>stimates
          for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW (Region 1)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3045.png" scalefit="1"
              width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_rdr78">
        <caption>Application
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101637+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101636+1100" content="d"?>ata
          for the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW (Region 1) (Basic Input Data)</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Menu</th>
            <th>Input</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Name</td>
            <td>Wollomombi River at Coinside</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Outlet Latitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>-30.478</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Outlet Longitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>152.026</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Centroid Latitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>-30.352</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Centroid Longitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>151.936</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Area in km<superscript>2</superscript></td>
            <td>376</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <para><xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_3dowt"/> shows a list of 15 gauged catchments, which is
        generated as part of the RFFE Model output. In this example, these gauged catchments are
        located closest to the Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW and were used in the development of
        the RFFE model. The user should compare the characteristics of the ungauged catchment of
        interest with those of the nearest gauged catchments (as in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_3dowt"
        />) to ensure that the ungauged catchment is not atypical.</para>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_3dowt" frame="void">
        <caption>Fifteen
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101644+1100"?>G<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101643+1100" content="g"?>auged
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101645+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101645+1100" content="c"?>atchments
          (<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101648+1100"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101647+1100" content="u"?>sed
          in the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101651+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101650+1100" content="d"?>evelopment
          of RFFE Model 2015)<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101702+1100"?>
          L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101654+1100" content=" l"?>ocated
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101705+1100"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101705+1100" content="c"?>losest
          to Wollomombi River at Coinside, NSW</caption>
        <col width="10%"/>
        <col width="10%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T104735+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="7%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T120707+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="10%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T104806+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="12%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T104809+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="12%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T104812+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="12%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T120738+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="10%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T120715+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="10%"/>
        <?oxy_attributes width="&lt;change type=&quot;modified&quot; oldValue=&quot;10%&quot; author=&quot;testoni&quot; timestamp=&quot;20181127T120748+1100&quot; /&gt;"?>
        <col width="10%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101824+1100"?>Site
              ID<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101830+1100"?>Dist.
              (km)<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101852+1100"?>Area
                km<superscript>2</superscript><?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T101958+1100"?>Lat.
              (outlet)<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102003+1100"?>Long.
              (outlet)<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102007+1100"?>Lat.
              (centroid)<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102018+1100"?>Long.
              (centroid)<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102024+1100"?>Record Length
              (years)<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102029+1100"?>Mean Annual
              Rainfall (mm)<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
            <th><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102034+1100"?>Shape
              Factor<?oxy_insert_end?></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102043+1100"?>206014<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102108+1100"?>0.07<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102111+1100"?>376<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102118+1100"?>-30.478<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102124+1100"?>152.0267<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102128+1100"?>-30.352<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102134+1100"?>151.936<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102139+1100"?>57<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102150+1100"?>871<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102204+1100"?>0.8786<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102049+1100"?>206001<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102209+1100"?>18<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102213+1100"?>163<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102218+1100"?>-30.59<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102222+1100"?>152.1617<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102226+1100"?>-30.5244<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102231+1100"?>152.279<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102234+1100"?>33<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102238+1100"?>1167<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102242+1100"?>1.082<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102055+1100"?>204030<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102541+1100"?>24.29<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102545+1100"?>200<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102551+1100"?>-30.26<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102559+1100"?>152.01<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102619+1100"?>-30.1904<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102624+1100"?>151.828<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102627+1100"?>34<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102632+1100"?>940<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
            <td><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102636+1100"?>1.3946<?oxy_insert_end?></td>
          </tr>
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T102710+1100"?>
          <tr>
            <td>206017</td>
            <td>28.01</td>
            <td>22</td>
            <td>-30.478</td>
            <td>152.3183</td>
            <td>-30.4632</td>
            <td>152.352</td>
            <td>24</td>
            <td>1167</td>
            <td>0.8005</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>204008</td>
            <td>31.64</td>
            <td>31</td>
            <td>-30.405</td>
            <td>152.345</td>
            <td>-30.4139</td>
            <td>152.382</td>
            <td>29</td>
            <td>1249</td>
            <td>0.6824</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>206026</td>
            <td>35.67</td>
            <td>8</td>
            <td>-30.42</td>
            <td>151.66</td>
            <td>-30.4201</td>
            <td>151.639</td>
            <td>37</td>
            <td>789</td>
            <td>0.734</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>206025</td>
            <td>37.68</td>
            <td>594</td>
            <td>-30.68</td>
            <td>151.71</td>
            <td>-30.6802</td>
            <td>151.557</td>
            <td>39</td>
            <td>945</td>
            <td>0.6194</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>206034</td>
            <td>39.29</td>
            <td>117</td>
            <td>-30.7</td>
            <td>151.7067</td>
            <td>-30.7666</td>
            <td>151.648</td>
            <td>26</td>
            <td>758</td>
            <td>0.8859</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>418034</td>
            <td>41.98</td>
            <td>14</td>
            <td>-30.3</td>
            <td>151.64</td>
            <td>-30.2758</td>
            <td>151.65</td>
            <td>29</td>
            <td>818</td>
            <td>0.7876</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>418014</td>
            <td>63.83</td>
            <td>855</td>
            <td>-30.47</td>
            <td>151.36</td>
            <td>-30.5063</td>
            <td>151.476</td>
            <td>37</td>
            <td>725</td>
            <td>0.4171</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>206018</td>
            <td>68.38</td>
            <td>894</td>
            <td>-31.051</td>
            <td>151.7683</td>
            <td>-30.9996</td>
            <td>151.634</td>
            <td>51</td>
            <td>711</td>
            <td>0.4846</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>204017</td>
            <td>68.62</td>
            <td>82</td>
            <td>-30.306</td>
            <td>152.7133</td>
            <td>-30.3529</td>
            <td>152.698</td>
            <td>40</td>
            <td>1995</td>
            <td>0.6086</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>204037</td>
            <td>72.28</td>
            <td>62</td>
            <td>-30.09</td>
            <td>152.63</td>
            <td>-30.1082</td>
            <td>152.576</td>
            <td>40</td>
            <td>1586</td>
            <td>0.7302</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>205002</td>
            <td>72.50</td>
            <td>433</td>
            <td>-30.426</td>
            <td>152.78</td>
            <td>30.4537</td>
            <td>152.566</td>
            <td>29</td>
            <td>1570</td>
            <td>1.0277</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>206009</td>
            <td>81.35</td>
            <td>261</td>
            <td>-31.19</td>
            <td>151.83</td>
            <td>-31.2597</td>
            <td>151.757</td>
            <td>57</td>
            <td>910</td>
            <td>0.6642</td>
          </tr>
          <?oxy_insert_end?>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_ydu7q">
      <title>Application for the Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western Australia (Region 5) (a
        Catchment Having No Major Regulation, No Major Natural or Artificial Storage and no Major
        Land Use Change)</title>

      <para>The basic input data for the Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW WA is provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_t_5qduj"/>. The model screen shot for the data input is provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_yklir"/>. The flood quantiles generated by the RFFE Model 2015 are
        provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_9yh35"/>. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_afke3"/> compares the
        RFFE Model and at-site FFA flood estimates which shows that RFFE Model estimates match the
        at-site FFA estimates quite well for all the six AEPs. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_afke3"/> also
        shows that the confidence band by the RFFE Model 2015 is much wider compared with at-site
        FFA confidence band, which is as expected.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_yklir">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105456+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105453+1100" content="s"?>creen
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105459+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105459+1100" content="s"?>hot
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105502+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105501+1100" content="d"?>ata
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105503+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T105503+1100" content="i"?>nput
          for Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW WA (Region 5)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3046.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111518+1100"?>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_5qduj" frame="void">
          <caption>Application Data for Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW Western Australia (Region 5)
            (Basic Input Data)</caption>
          <col width="50%"/>
          <col width="50%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Menu</th>
              <th>Input</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Catchment Name</td>
              <td>Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Catchment Outlet Latitude in decimal degrees</td>
              <td>-34.30</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Catchment Outlet Longitude in decimal degrees</td>
              <td>116.00</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Catchment Centroid Latitude in decimal degrees</td>
              <td>-34.318</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Catchment Centroid Longitude in decimal degrees</td>
              <td>116.021</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Catchment Area in (km<superscript>2</superscript>)</td>
              <td>13.1</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_9yh35">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111834+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111834+1100" content="s"?>creen
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111836+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111836+1100" content="s"?>hot
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111840+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111839+1100" content="m"?>odel
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111842+1100"?>O<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111841+1100" content="o"?>utput
          for Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW WA (Region 5)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3047.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_afke3">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs.
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111917+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111917+1100" content="a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111916+1100"?>t<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111914+1100" content="t"?>-site
          FFA
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111921+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111920+1100" content="f"?>lood
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111922+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111922+1100" content="e"?>stimates
          for Four Mile Brook at Netic Rd, SW WA (Region 5)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3048.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_p4hvx">
      <title>Application for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region 1) (a Catchment Having
        Significant Natural Floodplain Storage Where RFFE Model 2015 Output is Not Directly
        Applicable)</title>
      <para>This example (Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC) illustrates a catchment type where the RFFE
        Model is not applicable. The basic input data for this catchment is provided in <xref
          linkend="b3_ch3_t_z9vfi"/>. The model screen shot for the data input is provided in <xref
          linkend="b3_ch3_f_79qkw"/>. The flood quantiles generated by the RFFE Model 2015 are
        provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_w08tl"/>. <xref linkend="b3_ch3_f_4v50p"/> compares the
        RFFE Model and at-site FFA flood estimates, which shows that RFFE Model estimates are much
        higher compared with at-site FFA estimates. This catchment has significant natural
        floodplain storage which is not typical for other catchments in the Region of Influence
        (ROI) on which the RFFE Model 2015 estimates are based. The RFFE Model 2015 estimates are
        thus not directly applicable. Here, the RFFE Model estimates would need to be adjusted
        downwards to account for the floodplain storage effect by applying an appropriate
        technique.</para>
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112146+1100"?>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_z9vfi" frame="void">
        <caption>Application Data for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region 1) (Basic Input
          Data)</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Menu</th>
            <th>Input</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Name</td>
            <td>Morass Creek at Uplands</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Outlet Latitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>-36.87</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Outlet Longitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>147.70</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Centroid Latitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>-36.88</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Centroid Longitude in decimal degrees</td>
            <td>147.84</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Catchment Area in (km<superscript>2</superscript>)</td>
            <td>471</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <?oxy_insert_end?>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_79qkw">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111943+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111941+1100" content="s"?>creen
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111946+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111945+1100" content="s"?>hot
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111949+1100"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111948+1100" content="d"?>ata
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111951+1100"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T111951+1100" content="i"?>nput
          for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region 1)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3049.png" scalefit="1"
              width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_w08tl">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112525+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112524+1100" content="s"?>creen
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112526+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112526+1100" content="s"?>hot
          for
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112528+1100"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112528+1100" content="m"?>odel
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112530+1100"?>O<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112530+1100" content="o"?>utput
          for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC (Region 1)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3050.png" scalefit="1"
              width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_4v50p">
        <title>RFFE Model 2015 vs.
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112538+1100"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112537+1100" content="a"?>t-site
          FFA
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112540+1100"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112540+1100" content="f"?>lood
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112543+1100"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112542+1100" content="e"?>stimates
          (for the Morass Creek at Uplands, VIC) (Region 1)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3051.png" scalefit="1"
              width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch3_s_wt69y">
    <title>Further Information on the Development and Testing of RFFE Technique 2015</title>
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T120859+1100"?>
      <table xml:id="b3_ch3_t_w5xgv" frame="void">
        <caption>Further Information on the Development and Testing of RFFE Technique 2015</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Information</th>
            <th>Source</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Database consisting of 853 gauged catchments used to develop RFFE Technique
              2015</td>
            <td>Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2015a<citation>b3_c3_r40+1</citation></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Aspects of streamflow data preparation</td>
            <td>Haddad <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2010<citation>b3_c3_r15+1</citation></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Comparison of Probabilistic Rational Method and quantile regression technique</td>
            <td>Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2011a<citation>b3_c3_r38+1</citation></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Comparison of ordinary and generalised least squares regression techniques</td>
            <td>Haddad, Rahman and Kuczera, 2011<citation>b3_c3_r16+1</citation></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Comparison of fixed region and region-of-influence approaches for quantile and
              parameter regression techniques</td>
            <td>Haddad and Rahman, 2012<citation>b3_c3_r17+1</citation></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Regionalisation of the parameters of the LP3 distribution</td>
            <td>Haddad, Rahman and Stedinger, 2012 and Micevski <emphasis>et al</emphasis>.,
                2014<citation>b3_c3_r18,b3_c3_r26</citation></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Development and testing of the RFFE technique</td>
            <td>Rahman <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2009; 2012 and
                2015b<citation>b3_c3_r36,b3_c3_r39,b3_c3_r41</citation></td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <?oxy_insert_end?>
     
    
    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_weovt">
      <title>Standardised
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112552+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112552+1100" content="r"?>esiduals
        vs.
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112555+1100"?>N<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112554+1100" content="n"?>ormal
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112557+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112557+1100" content="s"?>cores
        for Region 1
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112559+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112559+1100" content="b"?>ased
        on
        Leave<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T121253+1100"?>-o<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T121252+1100" content=" O"?>ne<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T121306+1100"?>-o<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T121304+1100" content=" O"?>ut
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112603+1100"?>V<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T112602+1100" content="v"?>alidation
        for AEPs of 50%, 20%, 2% and 1%</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3052.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <figure xml:id="b3_ch3_f_2a59v">
      <title>Standardised
        <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115839+1100" content="r"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115845+1100"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?>esiduals
        vs.
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115849+1100"?>N<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115848+1100" content="n"?>ormal
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115851+1100"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115850+1100" content="s"?>cores
        for Region 1
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115854+1100"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115854+1100" content="b"?>ased
        on
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115857+1100"?>L<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115857+1100" content="l"?>eave-one-out
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115901+1100"?>V<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20181127T115901+1100" content="v"?>alidation
        for AEPs of 2% and 1%</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/3053.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
</chapter>


<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>