<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5" xml:id="b1_ch1-3" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Terminology</title>

  <section>
    <title>Background</title>

    <para>Probability concepts are fundamental to design flood estimation.
    Furthermore, the terminology used is important if the aim is for effective
    communication of design flood estimates. Terms commonly used in the past
    have included "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence interval</emphasis>",
    "<emphasis role="italic">return period</emphasis>", and various terms
    involving "<emphasis role="italic">probability</emphasis>". It is common
    for these terms to be used in a loose manner, and sometimes quite
    incorrectly. This has resulted in misinterpretation by the profession, the
    general community impacted by floods, and other stakeholders.</para>

    <para>In considering the terminology that should be used in this edition
    of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, the National Committee on Water
    Engineering had three major concerns; namely</para>

    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
        <para>Clarity of meaning;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Technical correctness; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Practicality and acceptability.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Clarity of Meaning</title>

    <para>Use of the terms "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence
    interval</emphasis>" and "<emphasis role="italic">return
    period</emphasis>" has been criticised as leading to confusion in the
    minds of some decision-makers and members of the public. Although the
    terms are simple superficially, they are misinterpreted regularly as
    implying that the associated event magnitude is only exceeded at regular
    intervals, and that they are referring to the elapsed time till the next
    exceedance. This misinterpretation of the terms used for expressing
    probabilities of flood magnitudes can be misleading and result in poor
    decisions.</para>

    <para>It is believed that irrespective of the terms used, that it is
    critical that all stakeholders have a common interpretation of the terms.
    Furthermore, it is believed that it is important that stakeholders
    understand that the terms refer to long term averages. This means, for a
    given climatic environment, that the probability of an event of a given
    magnitude being equalled or exceeded in a given period of time (for
    example, one year) is unchanged throughout the life of the structure or
    the drainage network. Furthermore, it is not uncommon for more than one
    occurrence of an event to occur in a single year. </para>

    <para>Additionally, given the wet and dry phases that occur in many
    regions of Australia, these events are likely to be clustered in time. The
    occurrence of these wet and dry climatic phases highlight the misleading
    and inappropriate interpretation that flood events occur at regular
    intervals as implied by "<emphasis role="italic">recurrence
    interval</emphasis>" and "<emphasis role="italic">return
    period</emphasis>”.</para>

    <para>Flood events generally are random occurrences, and the period
    between exceedances of a given value usually is a random variate, the
    properties of which are assumed to be constant in time for a given
    location and climatic environment. The adopted terminology reflects this
    fundamental concept and is intended to convey a clear and precise
    interpretation.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Technical Correctness</title>

    <para>In view of the loose and frequently incorrect manner in which
    probability terms are often used, it was considered that Australian
    Rainfall and Runoff should adopt terminology that is technically correct,
    as far as this is possible and in harmony with other objectives.
    Additionally, even if this is not entirely popular with all users,
    Engineers Australia has a responsibility to encourage and educate
    engineers regarding correct terminology.</para>

    <para>The two approaches used when describing probabilities of flood
    events in previous editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff were:</para>

    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
        <para>Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP) - the probability of an
        event being equalled or exceeded within a year. Typically the AEP is
        estimated by extracting the annual maximum in each year to produce an
        Annual Maxima Series (AMS); and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Average Recurrence Interval (ARI) - the average time period
        between occurrences equalling or exceeding a given value. Usually the
        ARI is derived from a Peak over Threshold series (PoTs) where every
        value over a chosen threshold is extracted from the period of
        record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Details of AMS and PoTs and the background to these alternative
    techniques for extracting flood series from recorded data are presented in
    Chapter 2 of Book 1 of Australian Rainfall and Runoff. Included in this
    discussion are the assumptions necessary for conversion of one probability
    terminology to the other using the Langbein formula (Langbein,
    1949).</para>

    <para>Using the Langbein formula, in probability terms, there is little
    practical difference for events rarer than 10% AEP. Historically, however,
    there has been a reluctance to convert from the approach used for
    derivation of the design flood estimate. Furthermore, terminology was
    attached to particular design flood estimation techniques; for example,
    when AMS were used to derive design flood estimates, the resultant
    probability was expressed as an AEP while when a PoTS was used for the
    same purpose, the resultant probability was expressed as an ARI.</para>

    <para>In many situations, this distinction between an ARI and an AEP was
    imprecise as the design flood prediction methodology adopted did not
    explicitly note use of either an AMS or a PoTS in the methodology. As a
    result, use of ARI and AEP was considered to be interchangeable. This
    interchangeable use often resulted in confusion.</para>

    <para>The National Committee on Water Engineering believes that within
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff a terminology should be used which, while
    being technically correct, is consistent with other uses. Furthermore, the
    terminology adopted should be easily understood both by the profession and
    by other stakeholders within the community. </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Practicality and Acceptability</title>

    <para>The National Committee on Water Engineering is aware that while the
    terminology adopted must be technically correct it must also be relatively
    simple and suitable for use in practice. Terminology that meets this
    criterion will be accepted by the profession and by other
    stakeholders.</para>

    <para>A change from the terminology adopted in the 1987 Edition of
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff has been deemed necessary as some confusion
    still exists with regard to the interpretation of certain terminology.
    This confusion exists both within the profession and within the community
    and other stakeholders.</para>

    <para>The interaction of the profession with the community and the
    increased public participation in decision making means that terminology
    needs to be clear not only to the profession but also to the community and
    other stakeholders, other professions involved in flood management, and to
    the managers of flood-prone land. This need has resulted in a strong move
    for a clear and unambiguous terminology by the National Committee on Water
    Engineering of Engineers Australia and the National Flood Risk Advisory
    Group (NFRAG): NFRAG is a reference group under the Australian and New
    Zealand Emergency Management Committee. All parties believe that
    terminology involving annual percentage probability best conveys the
    likelihood of flooding and is less open to misinterpretation by the
    public.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Adopted Terminology</title>

    <para>The term x year ARI and 1 in x AEP has caused confusion both within
    the industry and with the community and other stakeholders. It has been
    interpreted by many to imply that the periods between exceedances of a
    given event magnitude.</para>

    <para>To mitigate this confusion, the National Committee on Water
    Engineering has decided to adopt the terms shown in <xref
    linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/> and the suggested usage as indicated in
    that table.</para>

    <table xml:id="arr_pref_term_table">
      <caption> Australian Rainfall and Runoff Preferred Terminology
      </caption>

      <tr>
        <th scope="col">EY</th>

        <th scope="col">AEP (%)</th>

        <th scope="col">AEP (1 in x)</th>

        <th scope="col">ARI</th>

        <th scope="col">Use</th>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>6</td>

        <td>99.75</td>

        <td>1.002</td>

        <td>0.17</td>

        <td rowspan="5"><?dbhtml bgcolor="#c4dce7" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#c4dce7" ?>WSUD</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>4</td>

        <td>98.17</td>

        <td>1.02</td>

        <td>0.25</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>3</td>

        <td>95.02</td>

        <td>1.05</td>

        <td>0.33</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>2</td>

        <td>86.47</td>

        <td>1.16</td>

        <td>0.50</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>1</td>

        <td>63.21</td>

        <td>1.58</td>

        <td>1.00</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.69</td>

        <td>50.00</td>

        <td>2</td>

        <td>1.44</td>

        <td rowspan="4"><?dbhtml bgcolor="#d0b3b2" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#d0b3b2" ?>Stormwater/pit
        and pipe design</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>0.5</td>

        <td>39.35</td>

        <td>2.54</td>

        <td>2.00</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.22</td>

        <td>20.00</td>

        <td>5</td>

        <td>4.48</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>0.2</td>

        <td>18.13</td>

        <td>5.52</td>

        <td>5.00</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.11</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>10.00</td>

        <td>10</td>

        <td>9.49</td>

        <td rowspan="7"><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ada1c6" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ada1c6" ?>Flooding</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.05</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>5.00</td>

        <td>20</td>

        <td>19.5</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.02</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>2.00</td>

        <td>50</td>

        <td>49.5</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.01</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>1.00</td>

        <td>100</td>

        <td>99.5</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.01</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>0.50</td>

        <td>200</td>

        <td>199.5</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.002</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>0.20</td>

        <td>500</td>

        <td>499.5</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.001</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>0.10</td>

        <td>1000</td>

        <td>999.5</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.0005</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>0.05</td>

        <td>2000</td>

        <td>1999.5</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#ada1c6" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#ada1c6" ?>Limit CRC
        FORGE</td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td>0.0002</td>

        <td>0.02</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#bfcbe3" ?>5000</td>

        <td>4999.5</td>

        <td><?dbhtml bgcolor="#c9d69e" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#c9d69e" ?>Extreme
        risk/Dams</td>
      </tr>
    </table>

    <para>As shown in <xref linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/>, the term Annual
    Exceedance Probability (AEP) where AEP expresses the probability of an
    event being equalled or exceeded in any year. Additionally, AEP are to be
    expressed using percentage probability; for example, the 1% AEP design
    flood discharge. However, their will be situations where the use of
    percentage probability is not practicable; expression of extreme flood
    probabilities associated with dam spillways are one example of a situation
    where percentage probability is not appropriate. In these cases, it is
    recommended that the probability be expressed as 1 in X AEP where 100/X
    would be the equivalent percentage probability.</para>

    <para>For more frequent events an annualised exceedance probability is
    misleading and confusing. Furthermore, a recurrence interval approach also
    is misleading where strong seasonality is experienced. An example of
    strong seasonality is where the rainfall occurs predominately during the
    Summer or Winter period and as a consequence flood flows are more likely
    to occur during that period. As a result, when strong seasonality exists,
    calculating a design flood flow with a 3 month recurrence interval is of
    limited value as the expectation of the time period between occurrences
    will not be consistent throughout the year. For example, a flow with the
    magnitude of a 3 month recurrence interval would be expected to occur or
    be exceeded 4 times a year; however, in situations where there is strong
    seasonality in the rainfall, all of the occurrences are likely to occur in
    the dominate season.</para>

    <para>Consequently, events more frequent than 50% AEP should be expressed
    as X Exceedances per Year (EY). For example, 2 EY is equivalent to a
    design event with a 6 month recurrence interval when there is no
    seasonality in flood occurrence.</para>

    <para>An additional consideration in reducing the confusion is that
    different users of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, in general, will use
    different segments of the relationship between flood magnitude and
    exceedance probability. As the desire is to reduce confusion, switching
    between different terminologies within an industry segment will not reduce
    confusion but rather increase the confusion. Hence, while the recommended
    terminology for alternative frequencies is presented in <xref
    linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/>, it is recognised that usage may differ
    from the suggestions shown in <xref
    linkend="arr_pref_term_table"/>.</para>

    <para>Finally, it should be noted that no consideration has been given to
    the long term effects of climatic change in developing this terminology.
    Nonetheless, the adopted terminology is considered to be equally
    applicable to both stationary and non-stationary climatic environments as
    there is no requirement for the annual exceedance probabilities to be
    constant over time. In other words, there is no requirement for a given
    flood characteristic magnitude to maintain a given AEP over different
    years or, conversely, for a given AEP to maintain a constant flood
    characteristic magnitude over different years.</para>
  </section>
</section>
