<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5" xml:id="b1_ch1-4" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Australian Rainfall &amp; Runoff Contents</title>
<para>While the presentation of Australian Rainfall and Runoff has varied between the editions, the focal issue
has remained one of providing information relevant for design flood estimation.  These differing
presentation formats are illustrated with the two formats used for presentation of the 3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition.  As
noted earlier, the first publication of 3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition in 1987 comprised 14 chapters organised into 1 volume
while the second publication of the 3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition comprised these 14 chapters organised into 8 books.  The
organisation of the chapters into the 8 books was based on the information contained within the chapters
with the intention being that similar information was presented in the one book.  For example, Book 2
in the republished 3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition consisted of the chapters dealing with rainfall related issues; the chapters
included were Chapter 2 - Design Intensity-Frequency-Duration Rainfall, Chapter 3 - Temporal patterns
of Rainfall, and Chapter 6 - Storm Losses and design Rainfall Excess.</para>

<para>A similar concept has been maintained in the preparation of this revision of Australian Rainfall and
Runoff.  The organisation of information in this edition, however, differs from the republished 3<superscript>rd</superscript>
Edition.  A total of 9 Books has been prepared for this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff with
these books being:</para>

<para>Book 1 - SCOPE AND PHILOSOPHY</para>

<para>This book comprises six chapters.  The first of these chapters will be a general introduction to
Australian Rainfall and Runoff with an emphasis on the need for the revision, the history of
Australian Rainfall and Runoff and the development of past editions and a brief introduction to
terminology used within the document and its terminology.  The second and third chapters deal with
fundamental issues and the basic theory associated with the application of Australian Rainfall and
Runoff.   Introduced in the next chapter are data related aspects inclusive of its management and
the data uncertainty.  Discussed in the next chapter are concepts related to &#8220;risk based design&#8221;.</para>

<para>Book 2 - RAINFALL ESTIMATION</para>

<para>This book consists of six chapters.  The first chapter is a general introduction to the importance of
design rainfall for flood estimation and includes discussion of differences between historical and
design rainfalls, climate change influences on design rainfall and terminology relevant to rainfall. 
The second of these chapters is an introduction to issues associated with development of rainfall
models for design flood estimation  in Australian Rainfall and Runoff; the remaining chapters deal
with particular aspects of rainfall models for flood estimation.  Dealt with in the next three chapters
are IFD relationships, design spatial patterns of rainfall and design temporal patterns of rainfall. 
Considered in the final chapter of this book are continuous sequences rainfall inclusive of the
stochastic generation of alternative design storm sequences.</para>

<para>Book 3 - PEAK FLOW ESTIMATION</para>

<para>This book will comprise three chapters.  The first of these chapters is a general introduction to peak
flow estimation while the remaining chapters  deal with specific technical aspects of this topic area. 
The first of the technical chapters will deal with Flood Frequency Analysis and the second will deal
with regional flood frequency estimation techniques.</para>

<para><emphasis role="italic">Book 4 </emphasis>- CATCHMENT MODELLING FOR DESIGN FLOOD ESTIMATION</para>

<para>Similar to the previous books, the first chapter of this book will be a general introduction to the
concepts associated with catchment simulation for design flood estimation.  Included in this
discussion is the differences between simulation of a historical event and simulation of a design
event and the terminology relevant to catchment simulation.  This initial chapter is followed by a
discussion of the types of catchment modelling systems (event and continuous) and the associated
concepts of these systems in the following chapter.  A important component of this discussion
would be the need for integrated hydrologic, and hydraulic components of the system and
recognition of the different focal points of these components.  Presented in the next chapter is a
discussion of how catchment processes are integrated in the modelling system and how information
obtained from the catchment modelling system is dependent on the processes incorporated in the
system.  Furthermore, it is intended to highlight how the values of the same parameter (for example,
the loss rate parameter) depend upon how the modelling system is conceptualised and the various
processes combined in the system.</para>

<para><emphasis role="italic">Book 5 </emphasis>- FLOOD HYDROGRAPH ESTIMATION</para>

<para>This book comprises five chapters.  The focus of this book is the hydrologic models necessary for
prediction of design flood hydrographs.  As with previous books, the first chapter is a general
introduction to concepts presented in this book while the remaining chapters will deal with
particular theories, techniques and their application.  The first of the technical chapters deals with
the different types of hydrologic model, namely burst and event runoff models and continuous
runoff estimation; the focus of this discussion will be the flow components and their estimation in
either event modelling or continuous modelling.  Following that discussion is a chapter on
alternative approaches for direct runoff estimation  inclusive of time-area, unitgraph, kinematic,
diffusion, and 2-dimensional dynamic.  The final two chapters deal with baseflow and losses for
design flood estimation.</para>

<para><emphasis role="italic">Book 6 </emphasis>- FLOOD HYDRAULICS</para>

<para>This book will five (5) chapters.  Consistent with the approach adopted for the other books, the first
chapter in this book outlines the scope of the book and the material presented within the book.  The
second chapter in this book is concerned with the basic aspects of hydraulics and is intended to
provide a foundation for the subsequent chapters; it is worth noting that the material presented in
this chapter is not a replacement for the many textbooks in this area or that it will cover all the
information necessary for the application of hydraulic principles in design flood estimation.  The
remaining chapters in this book present, respectively, information relevant to the hydraulic
modelling of structures for design flood estimation, the application of software for numerical
modelling of flood hydrographs, and issues in the application of numerical models.</para>

<para><emphasis role="italic">Book 7 &#8211; APPLICATION OF CATCHMENT MODELLING SYSTEMS</emphasis></para>

<para>This book will comprise 6ix (6) chapters.  Similar to previous books, outlined in the introductory
chapter is the scope of the book and how material will be presented within the book.  Following this
introductory chapter is a discussion of major issues in the application of catchment modelling
systems.  The topics discussed in the following chapters are</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para> Usage of catchment modelling systems - Chapter 2.  This discussion includes all aspects of
usage from design of the study to presentation of results and the development of a suggested
flow chart for use by modellers.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Techniques and concepts for parameter estimation in both gauged and ungauged catchments -
Chapter 3.  This discussion inherently impinges on the philosophy of not recommending
software but it is appropriate, where a parameter is software specific, that mention is made of
the software when appropriate.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Techniques for determination of the uncertainty in design flood prediction - Chapter 4. 
Presented in this chapter are techniques for estimation of the uncertainty limits (confidence
limits).  This is a new but important aspect of catchment modelling for design flood estimation.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Application of Catchment Modelling Systems for Future Climates - Chapter 5.  The guidance 
presented in this chapter is likely to change when the outcomes of additional research into
modelling of potential future climate states becomes available.  Users of Australian Rainfall
and Runoff are reminded, therefore, of earlier advice that they should use the best information
available for the problem they are investigating.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Specific issues related to modelling of rural catchments - Chapter 6.</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<para><emphasis role="italic">Book 8 &#8211; LARGE TO EXTREME FLOOD ESTIMATION</emphasis></para>

<para>awaiting advice from authors.</para>

<para><emphasis role="italic">Book 9 &#8211; RUNOFF IN URBAN AREAS</emphasis></para>

<para>This book consists of eight chapters.  The first of these chapters is a general introduction to urban
drainage systems and the philosophy associated with Australian Rainfall and Runoff discussing
urban drainage approaches.  There is a link to Australian Runoff Quality (<emphasis role="bold">reference needed</emphasis>) in this
chapter.  Technical issues are discussed in the remaining chapters.  These technical issues include:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Aspects of Urban Hydrology - Chapter 2.  Introduced in this chapter are changes to the natural
hydrologic cycle resulting from urbanisation and how these changes impact on design flood
estimation in urban environments.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Estimation of Storm Flows - Chapter 3.  Presented in this chapter are techniques for estimation
of flows and the use of these flows in system design.  Included in discussion is a limitation on
the appropriateness of the Rational method, in particular, and other methods, in general. 
Limitations on usage of alternative models are presented.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Drainage System Hydraulics - Chapter 4.  This issue will include the impacts of blockage on
the flow hydraulics and recommendations on how blockage can be incorporated into the design
or analysis of urban drainage systems.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Runoff Detention and Retention - Chapter 5.  This issue includes discussion of storage
facilities from on-site storage to detention (retention) basins to large flood dams.  An important
aspect of this discussion is the introduction of volume based problems and the changes in
approach necessary for consideration of a volume problem rather than a flow problem.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Safety Design Criteria - Chapter 6.  Presented in this chapter is guidance on estimating the
safety of people and vehicles.  The people safety information presented includes a discussion
of the importance of the demographics in assessing safety. </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Urban drainage modelling - Chapter 7.  Presented in this chapter are modelling aspects
particular to urban drainage systems that have not been discussed previously in Book 7.</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>


    
</section>
