<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="b1_ch1-1" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
<title>General</title>
    <para>The first edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff was produced in
        1958 (<emphasis role="bold">ref</emphasis>). This publication arose from
        representations by the Local Government and Highways Engineering Branch of
        the Sydney Division of the Institution of Engineers, Australia which
        ultimately led to the formation of Technical Committee No. 2 - Stormwater
        Standards. The terms of reference of this committee are outlined in full
        by <emphasis role="bold">ref</emphasis> but can be summarised as to
        investigate rainfall intensities as well as the standard of practice in
        assessing discharge from catchment areas, frequency of flooding to be
        adopted in design and allied drainage problems.</para>
    
    <para>The Technical Committee ultimately evolved into the Institution of
        Engineers, Australia’s National Committee on Hydrology who in 1972
        recognised that there was a need to revise Australian Rainfall and Runoff.
        This revision was published in 1977 as the second edition of Australian
        Rainfall and Runoff (<emphasis role="bold">ref</emphasis>). In the
        preparation of this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff it was
        recognised that the purpose of the previous edition was to provide an
        unofficial code of recommended practice in the selection and application
        of approaches to hydrologic problems. In the preparation of the second
        edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, therefore, an attempt was made
        to remove the code of practice concept from the contents and to include in
        the document information about Australian rainfall characteristics and a
        description of some methods of hydrologic analysis and constraints which
        apply to their use. As such, the second edition of Australian Rainfall and
        Runoff was intended to be a handbook of information and hydrologic method.
        It was stated in the preface to this edition that the National Committee
        saw the need for the engineering hydrologists to be perceptive about
        problems and to develop solutions for these problems in a way that was
        most appropriate to the location, situation, information and skills that
        were available.</para>
    
    <para>In 1982, the National Committee on Hydrology and Water Resources of
        the Institution of Engineers, Australia recognised the need to revise the
        second edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff. This revised edition was
        published in 1987 (Pilgrim, 1987). In commissioning the 1987 edition, the
        National Committee on Hydrology and Water Resources of the Institution of
        Engineers, Australia adopted the view that much firmer guidance should be
        given to designers. It was considered that the profession required a guide
        to practice that can be regarded as authoritative by all stakeholders. It
        was recognised also that irrespective of the attitude taken by an
        editorial committee or the National Committee on Hydrology and Water
        Resources, a document published by the Institution of Engineers, Australia
        will inevitably be regarded as a statement of sound and desirable
        practice. For these reasons, the third edition of Australian Rainfall and
        Runoff provided firmer guidance on appropriate methodologies for analysis
        of hydrologic problems and the design of hydrologic structures.
        Furthermore, in previous editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff,
        information pertaining to the rainfall characteristics had been limited to
        points where data were available. In this edition of Australian Rainfall
        and Runoff, information about rainfall characteristics across the complete
        country was attempted and, as a result, the third edition of Australian
        Rainfall and Runoff was published in two volumes for the first time. The
        intention of splitting Australian Rainfall and Runoff into two volumes was
        that the first edition would contain the guidance while the second volume
        would contain information that was necessary for implementation of the
        recommended approaches but which was not necessary for presentation of the
        approach.</para>
    
    <para>In 1997, the 3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition of Australian
        Rainfall and Runoff was republished with the Chapters in Volume 1
        rearranged into eight books. No changes were made to Volume 2 of the
        document. Following this republication, Book 6 - Extreme and Large Floods
        was completely revised and a new version published in 1999. No other books
        or chapters were revised and therefore the 3<superscript>rd</superscript>
        Edition, published in 1987, remained current.</para>
    
    <para>This edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff is the fourth
        edition. Following the re-publication of the
        3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff,
        it was recognised by Engineers Australia’s National Committee on Water
        Engineering that the increased computational capacity available to
        engineering and related professions was resulting in significant changes
        in the approaches being used for flood estimation within Australia.
        Additionally, theoretical advances in flood estimation techniques and
        their understanding had resulted in the approaches to design flood
        estimation presented in the 3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition of
        Australian Rainfall and Runoff no longer representing best practice.
        Furthermore, there has been a recognition that the information needs from
        design flood estimates had expanded. An example of this expansion of
        information needs is the common requirement now for pluvial design flood
        estimates in urban areas; pluvial floods are those arising from surface
        runoff that is flowing towards a drainage channel (surface or
        underground). The techniques presented in the
        3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff
        were focussed on fluvial design flood estimates (i.e. focussed on
        estimating floods that arise as a result of overflows from drainage
        channels) and many are not suitable for development of a pluvial design
        flood estimate (see, for example, <emphasis role="bold">ref
            needed</emphasis>).</para>
    
    <para>As a result of this recognition for the revision of Australian
        Rainfall and Runoff, the National Committee on Water Engineering commenced
        work in 2003 on the preparation of a revision to Australian Rainfall and
        Runoff. Preparation of this 4<superscript>th</superscript> Edition has
        been supported significantly by the Commonwealth of Australia through
        grants from the Department of Climate Change and Energy Efficiency, and
        Geosciences Australia, and by the profession through the in-kind support
        provided by many private companies, state and local government agencies,
        and universities.</para>
    
    <para>Similar to the previous editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff,
        it was recognised that, irrespective of the attitude taken by the
        editorial committee or the National Committee on Water Engineering, a
        document published by the Engineers Australia will inevitably be regarded
        as a statement of sound and desirable practice. For this reason, the
        editorial committee decided that all methodologies presented in the
        document needed to meet the following:</para>
    
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
            <para>Methods to be included had to be published and subjected to peer
                review by the profession;</para>
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
            <para>Methods to be included had to be based on real data; and</para>
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
            <para>Methods to be included needed to be capable of design flood
                estimation for potential future climate regimes where suitable
                information is available or is expected to become available in the
                foreseeable future.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para>In addition, the editorial committee recognised that</para>
    
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
            <para>Generation of new information and new technologies was likely to
                increase and, therefore, the information in the new edition of
                Australian Rainfall and Runoff needed to be capable of easy change
                when necessary;</para>
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
            <para>Design flood predictions are not exact and hence the uncertainty
                in prediction needed to be conveyed to users;</para>
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
            <para>Information and methodologies are becoming increasingly digital
                in nature and that it was incumbent on Australian Rainfall and Runoff
                to provide software for situations where market economics has resulted
                in a failure to provide suitable software; and</para>
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
            <para>It was not the role of Australian Rainfall and Runoff to endorse
                particular software packages but rather to endorse design flood
                estimation methodologies which can be, or have been, incorporated into
                software for use by the industry.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para><emphasis role="bold">need words here to describe developments from
        Australian Rainfall and Runoff research projects.</emphasis></para>
    
</section>