<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b1_ch1"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>

  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>24/04/2018</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch1_s_juh46">
    <title>General</title>

    <para>While previous editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff have
    served the engineering profession and the general community well, in the
    period since the release of the previous edition, a number of developments
    have arisen that necessitate the production of a new edition. These
    developments include the many recent advances in knowledge regarding flood
    processes, the increased computational capacity available to engineering
    hydrologists, expanding knowledge and application of hydroinformatics,
    improved information about climate change and the use of stochastic inputs
    and Monte Carlo methods.</para>

    <para>The intention during the development of this new edition has been to
    provide appropriate guidance addressing these issues. In many situations,
    the guidance provided in this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff
    requires an enhanced knowledge of flood generation and the design process.
    The guidance developed has maintained the aim of Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff which is to provide the best available information on design flood
    estimation in a manner suitable for use by Australian practitioners with
    varying levels of knowledge about the design flood problem, flood
    processes, and engineering hydrology.</para>

    <para>Development of guidance for inclusion in Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff consistent with the aims previously stated poses the question of a
    definition for the design flood problem. Design flood estimation remains a
    problem for many engineering projects. Advice is required regarding design
    flood characteristics for the:</para>

    <para><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>design of culverts and bridges for cross drainage of transport
          routes;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>floodplain management and planning;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>design of urban drainage systems;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>design of flood mitigation levees and other flood mitigation
          structures;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>setting of flood planning levels; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>design of dam spillways.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist> The flood characteristic of most importance depends on
    the nature of the problem under consideration, but typically it is one of
    the following:</para>

    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Flow rate</emphasis> - commonly the peak but other
        flood flows may be needed for particular projects;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Level </emphasis>- commonly the peak but other flood
        levels may be needed for particular projects;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Volume</emphasis> - the volume of flood hydrographs is
        required for the design of many hydraulic structures designed to
        retain part of the flood hydrograph for flood mitigation
        purposes;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Rate of rise </emphasis>- needed for the planning
        associated with operation flood management such as preparation of
        evacuation routes; or</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>System failure</emphasis> - this may be failure of a
        dendritic network within a catchment, the failure of a transport route
        crossing multiple catchments, or the failure of some other system due
        to the occurrence of one or more flood events.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>While all of these flood characteristics have been noted as being of interest to flood
      practitioners, the dominant characteristic of concern, historically, has been the peak flood
      flow. The peak flood flow was also the main focus of the previous edition of Australian
      Rainfall and Runoff <citation>arr_1987</citation>.</para>

    <para>In this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, many of the
    recommended practices focus on the prediction of peak design flows and
    prediction of full hydrographs. Since publication of the last edition of
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff, it has been recognised that this focus on
    flows provided insufficient guidance on other flood characteristics. For
    the holistic planning, design and operation of flood management systems,
    flood characteristics other than peak flow will also be relevant. For
    example, the design flood storage for the many retarding basins located in
    urban areas is usually a flood volume issue rather than a peak flow issue.
    As a result, other recommendations in this edition of Australian Rainfall
    and Runoff focus on all flood characteristics that may be of interest in
    design flood estimation.</para>

    <para>This approach is consistent with the aims of Engineers Australia's
    National Committee on Water Engineering when they resolved that a revision
    of Australian Rainfall and Runoff was needed by the profession and the
    wider community. These aims can be stated broadly as being:</para>

    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
        <para>to collect, review and evaluate available design procedures, and
        to update the document to include the best available methods and
        design data Australia wide;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>to provide guidance to designers on procedures and design values
        to be used in design flood estimation;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>to provide guidance on the concepts involved in the recommended
        procedures and their application;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>to provide separate design information for individual regions
        where necessary;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>to provide guidance on design flood estimation under changing
        climatic conditions;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>to provide guidance on the likely accuracies, or uncertainty, in
        the application of the recommended techniques; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>to carry out those research activities necessary to meet the
        above objectives.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>In development of this guidance, it was recognised that knowledge
    and information availability is not fixed and that future research and
    applications will develop new techniques and information. This is
    particularly relevant in applications where techniques have been
    extrapolated from the region of their development to other regions and
    where efforts should be made to reduce large uncertainties in current
    estimates of design flood characteristics.</para>

    <para>Therefore, where circumstances warrant, designers have a duty to use
    other procedures and design information more appropriate for their design
    flood problem. The authorship team of this edition of Australian Rainfall
    and Runoff believe that the use of new or improved procedures should be
    encouraged, especially where these are more appropriate than the methods
    described in this publication. Assessment of the relative merits of new
    procedures and design information should be based on the following
    desirable attributes:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>based on observed data relevant to the specific
          application;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>consistent with current knowledge of flood processes;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>able to reproduce observed flood behaviour in the area of
          interest; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>where possible, endorsed by a peer review process</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>

    <para>While most of the procedures presented in the guidelines require software for their
      implementation, the role of Australian Rainfall and Runoff is not to endorse particular
      software packages but rather to provide details of the procedures to be incorporated in flood
      estimation software packages. However, enabling software is provided to allow site-specific
      design data to be extracted from databases (e.g. for the design rainfall database and the
      regional flood frequency estimation). These databases will be updated when warranted by the
      availability of significant amounts of new or revised information.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch1-5">
    <title>Contents</title>
    <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T133642+1100" comment="?
"?>
    <para>While the presentation and formats of Australian Rainfall and Runoff have varied between
      the editions, the focal aim has remained one of providing information relevant to design flood
      estimation<?oxy_comment_end?> in a form readily accessible to practitioners.</para>
    <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20151126T133653+1100" comment="?
"?>
    <para>This edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff has followed the same philosophy and has
      grouped information on different aspects of design flood estimation into separate books. The
      aim of this is to allow easy updating of components in the future. <?oxy_comment_end?>A total
      of 9 Books has been prepared for this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff with the
      following contents:</para>
    <para><xref linkend="book1"/> - SCOPE AND PHILOSOPHY</para>
    <para>This book provides a general introduction to Australian Rainfall and Runoff with an
      emphasis on the need for the revision and the basic philosophy for the application of the
      guidelines. It gives a brief introduction to terminology used within the document, discusses
      fundamental issues and basic approaches to flood estimation, data related aspects inclusive of
      its management and data uncertainty, risk based design and dealing with climate change.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="book2"/> - RAINFALL ESTIMATION</para>
    <para>This book discusses the importance of design rainfall for flood estimation, and includes
      discussion of differences between historical and design rainfalls, issues associated with
      development of rainfall models for design flood estimation in Australian Rainfall and Runoff.
      It provides the basis for the recommended Intensity Frequency Duration relationships, design
      spatial patterns of rainfall and design temporal patterns of rainfall. Also considered in this
      book are continuous sequences rainfall inclusive of the stochastic generation of alternative
      design storm sequences.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="book3"/> - PEAK FLOW ESTIMATION</para>
    <para>This book provides a general introduction to peak flow estimation based on flood frequency
      analysis, as well as covering specific technical aspects of this topic area. The first of the
      technical chapters provides guidelines for Flood Frequency Analysis at a specific site,
      illustrated by a range of examples. The second deals with Regional Flood Frequency Estimation
      techniques and describes the application of a tool developed to readily provide peak flow
      frequency estimates for any location in Australia.</para>
    <para> </para>
    <para><xref linkend="book4"/> - CATCHMENT SIMULATION FOR DESIGN FLOOD ESTIMATION</para>
    <para>This book deals with general concepts and issues in catchment modelling for design flood
      estimation. The first chapter discusses the need for catchment simulation and introduces
      general catchment simulation concepts. The next chapter discusses key hydrologic processes
      contributing to floods and how they are represented in modelling systems. This chapter is
      followed by a discussion of the types of catchment modelling systems (event and continuous)
      and the need for integrating hydrologic, and hydraulic components of the system. The final
      chapters deal with the treatment of joint probability issues and uncertainty in the outputs of
      simulation models.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="book5"/> - FLOOD HYDROGRAPH ESTIMATION</para>
    <para>The focus of this book is the hydrologic models necessary for prediction of design flood
      hydrographs. The first chapter gives a general introduction to concepts presented in this book
      while the remaining chapters deal with the modelling of particular components of the flood
      formation process. The first of the technical chapters deals with the different types of
      hydrologic models used to represent the runoff generation and runoff routing phases of the
      flood formation process. The final two chapters deal with baseflow and losses for design flood
      estimation and provide design data for these important inputs to flood hydrograph
      estimation.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="book6"/> - FLOOD HYDRAULICS</para>
    <para>This book is concerned with the basic aspects of hydraulics. It is worth noting that the
      material presented in this chapter is not a replacement for the many textbooks in this area or
      that it will cover all the information necessary for the application of hydraulic principles
      in design flood estimation. The chapters in this book present information relevant to the
      hydraulic modelling of river reaches, floodplains and structures for design flood estimation,
      the application of software for numerical modelling of flood hydrographs, blockage of
      hydraulic structures and interaction of coastal and catchment flooding. A tool has been
      developed to assist practitioners in assessing the interation of coastal and catchment
      flooding. Also included in this book is guidance on designing for the safety of people and
      vehicles. The people safety information presented includes a discussion of the importance of
      the demographics in assessing safety.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="book7"/> - APPLICATION OF CATCHMENT MODELLING SYSTEMS</para>
    <para>This book provides discussion of major issues in the practical application of catchment
      modelling systems to different flood estimation problems, including establishment of catchment
      modelling systems, calibration and validation of model parameters and dealing with uncertainty
      in model outputs. </para>
    <para><xref linkend="book8"/> - VERY RARE TO EXTREME FLOOD ESTIMATION</para>
    <para>This book provides information and guidelines for the special design applications where
      floods of low Annual Exceedance Probabilities need to be estimated. Examples of these design
      applications include the sizing of spillways for large dams, design of major structures
      located in the floodplain and flood risk management in situations where very large flood
      damages or significant risk to life from flooding could be expected. Floods in the range of
      very rare to extreme events are generally estimated by the methods described in <xref
        linkend="b8_ch2"/> to <xref linkend="b8_ch7"/> but a number of special considerations and
      additional design data are required, as described in <xref linkend="book8"/>. This book
      includes an overview of the procedures available for estimating very rare to extreme floods,
      estimation of design rainfall and rainfall excess for rarer events, and special requirements
      for the models used to generate flood hydrographs for very rare to extreme flood events. The
      application of these special procedures is illustrated by a number of examples.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="book9"/> - RUNOFF IN URBAN AREAS</para>
    <para>This book first provides a general introduction to urban drainage systems and the
      philosophy adopted in Australian Rainfall and Runoff. It then discusses urban drainage
      approaches, changes to the natural hydrologic cycle resulting from urbanisation and how these
      changes impact on design flood estimation in urban environments, and use of storage facilities
      from on-site storage to detention (retention) basins to large flood mitigation dams. An
      important aspect of this discussion relates to limitations of the Rational method and the
      changes in approach necessary for consideration of volume-based problems rather than peak flow
      based problems.</para>
  </section>
  
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  

</chapter>
