<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="b1_ch1-1" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    
    <title>General</title>
    
    <para>While previous editions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff have served the engineering
        profession and the general community well, in the period since the release of the previous
        edition, a number of developments have arisen that necessitate the production of a new
        edition.  These developments include the many recent advances in knowledge regarding flood
        processes, the increased computational capacity available to engineering hydrologists, the
        rapidly expanding knowledge and application of hydroinformatics, and the rapidly expanding
        body of information about climate change.</para>
    
    <para>In the development of this new edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, the intention has
        been to provide appropriate guidance addressing these issues.  In many situations, the
        guidance provided in this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff requires an enhanced
        knowledge of flood generation and the design process.  At the same time, the guidance
        developed has maintained the aim of Australian Rainfall and Runoff which can be enunciated
        as providing Australian designers with the best available information on design flood
        estimation in a manner suitable for use by practioners with varying levels of knowledge about
        the design flood problem, about flood processes, and about engineering hydrology.</para>
    
    <para>Development of guidance for inclusion in Australian Rainfall and Runoff consistent with the
        aims previously stated poses the question of a definition for the design flood problem.  It is
        reasonable to state that design flood estimation remains a problem for many engineering
        projects.  Advice is required regarding design flood characteristics for the design of culverts
        and bridges necessary for cross drainage of transport routes, the design of urban drainage
        systems, the design of flood mitigation levees and other flood mitigation structures, design of
        dam spillways, and many other situations. The flood characteristic of most importance
        depends on the nature of the problem under consideration, but typically it is one of the
        following:</para>
    
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
            <para>Flood flow rate, commonly the peak but other flood flows may be needed for particular
                projects;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Flood level, similar to flood flow rate, this is commonly the peak but other flood levels
                may be needed for particular projects;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Flood volume, the volume of flood hydrographs is required for the design of many
                hydraulic structures designed to retain part of the flood hydrograph for flood mitigation
                purposes;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Flood rate of rise, needed for the planning associated with operation flood management
                such as preparation of evacuation routes; or</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>System failure, this may be failure of a dendritic network within a catchment, the failure
                of a transport route crossing multiple catchments, or the failure some other system due to
                the occurrence of one or more flood events.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para>While all of these flood characteristics have been noted as being of interest to flood designers,
        the dominant characteristic of concern, historically, has been the flood flow rate.  The flood
        flow rate also  was the focus of the previous edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff
        (Pilgrim, 1987).</para>
    
    <para>In this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, many of the recommended practices retain a
        focus on the prediction of design flows and, predominately, on the prediction of the peak of
        the design flow hydrograph.  Since publication of the last edition of Australian Rainfall and
        Runoff, it has been recognised that this focus on flows provided insufficient guidance on
        other flood characteristics.  For example, the design flood storage for the many retarding
        basins located in urban areas usually is a flood volume issue rather than a peak flow issue; in
        this example, it is the peak volume stored that is the design consideration given constraints
        arising from upstream and downstream flows.  As a result, other recommendations in this
        edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff focus on all flood characteristics that may be of
        interest in design flood prediction.</para>
    
    <para>This approach is consistent with the aims of Engineers Australia's National Committee on
        Water Engineering when they resolved that a revision of Australian Rainfall and Runoff was
        needed by the profession and the wider community.  The aims of Engineers Australia's
        National Committee on Water Engineering can be stated broadly as being:</para>
    
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
        <listitem>
            <para>to collect, review and evaluate available design procedures, and to update the document
                to include the best available methods and design data;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>to provide separate design information for individual regions where necessary;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>to provide guidance on design flood estimation under changing climatic conditions;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>to provide guidance to designers on procedures and design values to be used in design
                flood estimation;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>to provide guidance on the concepts involved in the recommended procedures and their
                application;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>to provide guidance on the likely accuracies, or uncertainty, in the application of the
                recommended techniques; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>to carry out those research activities necessary to meet the above objectives.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para>In development of this guidance, it was recognised that knowledge and information
        availability is not fixed and that future research and applications will develop new techniques
        and information.  This is particularly relevant in estimation of the uncertainty of a design
        flood characteristics and other areas where techniques have been extrapolated from the region
        of their development to other regions due to the information needs of different problems.      </para>
    
    <para>Therefore, where circumstances warrant, designers have a duty to use other procedures and
        data that are more appropriate for their design flood problem.  The authorship team of this
        edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff believe that the use of new or improved procedures
        should be encouraged, especially where these are more appropriate than the methods
        described in this publication.</para>
</section>