<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b8_ch3" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
  <info>
    <title>Estimation of Very Rare to Extreme Rainfalls</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>3/12/2018 </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_vgrwa">
    <title>General</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_vdby3">
      <title>Overview of Requirements and Sources of Design Rainfall Information</title>
      <para>In general, estimates of Very Rare to Extreme floods are derived using <emphasis
          role="italic">rainfall-based flood estimation methods</emphasis> (possible exceptions to
        this are discussed in <xref linkend="b8_s_dkdq3"/>). Information is required on the average
        depth of rainfall over the catchment for a range of rainfall event durations, its
        distribution in space (spatial pattern) and its distribution in time during the event
        (temporal pattern). Design floods are generally calculated separately for each duration,
        including routing through any reservoirs or other storages, to determine the critical
        rainfall durations that produce the maxima for the flood characteristics of interest (peak
        inflow/outflow, flood volume or possibly duration of flooding). Short duration design
        rainfalls may be required even on large catchments to check that their occurrence on only
        part of the catchment area does not produce a critical flood, and to check that the
        magnitudes of the calculated floods vary in a regular manner as the duration of the rainfall
        increases.</para>
      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch3"/> provides details of <emphasis role="italic">design rainfall
          depths at a grid of points</emphasis> over the whole of Australia for the range of AEPs
        and durations of interest for the estimation of Very Rare to Extreme floods. Except for the
        PMP, these design rainfall depths are point rainfalls at the grid point location; they need
        to be converted to <emphasis role="italic">average catchment rainfalls</emphasis> by
        application of the <emphasis role="italic">areal reduction factors (ARFs)</emphasis>
        provided in <xref linkend="b2_ch4"/>.</para>
      <para>General guidance on <emphasis role="italic">design spatial rainfall patterns</emphasis>
        is provided in <xref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b2_ch6_6"/>. This
        guidance  applies to design spatial patterns for the estimation of Very Rare to Extreme
        floods, with some more specific guidance provided in <xref linkend="b8_s_sborg"/>. The
        limited information available on spatial patterns of extreme storm events generally
        precludes the application of an ensemble of spatial patterns; spatial patterns can be
        sampled in an ensemble fashion in stochastic simulation frameworks, but generally a single
        representative pattern derived from design rainfall fields (or observed storms) in a larger
        region is sufficient for most design purposes.</para>
      <para>The guidance provided in <xref linkend="b2_ch5"/> for the selection of <emphasis
          role="italic">design temporal rainfall patterns</emphasis> also generally applies to the
        range of Very Rare to Extreme floods, with more specific guidance provided in <xref
          linkend="b8_s_4n0lw"/>. Given the sensitivity of flood estimates to the high degree of
        natural variability in the temporal patterns of actual storms, it is recommended that an
        ensemble of temporal patterns rather than a single ‘representative’ temporal pattern is
        applied.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_xczgh">
      <title>Uncertainty in Design Rainfall Estimates</title>
      <para>There is limited detailed information on the uncertainty associated with the rainfall
        estimates provided in <xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>. It should be recognised that the magnitude
        of the uncertainty in design rainfall estimates increases with decreasing AEP (refer to
          <xref linkend="b1_ch2"/>), as model uncertainty plays an increasingly important part in
        the estimation of extreme events, including the PMP. Some information is available on
        uncertainty estimates of Very Rare to Extreme rainfalls (e.g.
          <citation>b8_c_r38+1</citation>; <citation>b8_c_r45+1</citation>), though until formal
        estimates of uncertainties are available probably the most pragmatic approach to
        characterizing uncertainty is to use a parametric bootstrapping approach with at-site maxima
        (e.g. <citation>b8_c_r97+1</citation>), where the effective size of the sample is adjusted
        to represent the degree of pooling used. Estimates of very rare rainfalls were derived using
        a region of influence approach based on a minimum of 2000 years of station data
          <citation>b8_c_r95</citation> and analyses by <citation>b8_c_r96+1</citation> indicate
        that the effective number of independent years in such data sets varies between around 300
        to 500 years, depending on gauge density. The uncertainty of design rainfall estimates
        reflects the level of information available, with significantly increased uncertainty in
        areas of sparse rain gauge coverage, such as mountainous areas.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_8tx6d">
    <title>Estimation of Very Rare Design Rainfalls</title>
    <para>Design rainfall depths for Very Rare events are derived by regional estimation methods,
      such as the regional L-moment method described in <xref
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b2_ch3_s_brsiv"/>.<?oxy_comment_end?>
      <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181120T095758+1100" comment="should be 3.5.3.2. Estimation of L-moments"?>These<?oxy_comment_end?>
      methods pool data from large rainfall events in a region that satisfies basic homogeneity
      criteria. By using a ‘space for time trade-off’, these methods allow estimation of rarer
      events than would be possible by using data from an individual site only.</para>
    <para>The AEP range covered by regional estimates, referred to as the ‘credible range of
      extrapolation’, depends on the number of stations in a region and the length and quality of
      their records. For the relatively well gauged parts of Australia this range has been taken as
      extending to the 1 in 2000 AEP.</para>
    <para>Practitioners should recognise that making available design rainfall estimates for a dense
      grid covering the whole of Australia has been achieved at the cost of potentially reduced
      accuracy at locations for which long and reliable rainfall records are available. However, the
      results of frequency analysis of local records should only be used to fine-tune regional
      design rainfall estimates if there is strong evidence confirmed by peer review. In such a
      situation the shape of the rainfall frequency curve in the range of Very Rare events should
      closely follow the shape indicated by the regional estimate.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_1a1fg">
    <title>Estimation of the Probable Maximum Precipitation Depth</title>
    <para>The theoretical definition of the Probable Maximum Precipitation (PMP) is “the greatest
      depth of precipitation for a given duration that is physically possible over a given size
      storm area at a particular geographical location at a certain time of year”
        <citation>b8_c_r83</citation>. Estimates are derived using generalised methods that are
      based on the analysis of data over a wide region, as described in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s7_0"
      />.</para>
    <para>Estimates of PMP rainfall data have been developed by the Bureau of Meteorology. There are
      three generalised methods appropriate for different locations and durations: <orderedlist
        numeration="lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para>the Generalised Short Duration Method (GSDM) is applicable for durations up to six
            hours and areas up to 1000 km<superscript>2</superscript>
            <citation>b8_c_r7</citation>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the Generalised Tropical Storm Method (GTSMR) is used to estimate PMPs for durations
            up to 120 hours and areas up to 150 000 km<superscript>2</superscript> in the region of
            Australia where tropical storms are the source of the greatest depths of rainfall
              <citation>b8_c_r8</citation>; and </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the Generalised Southeast Australia Method (GSAM) is used for durations up to 96
            hours and areas up to 100 000 km<superscript>2</superscript> for the region of Australia
            where tropical storms are not the source of the greatest depths of rainfall
              <citation>b8_c_r9</citation>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>The zones of application for the GTSM and GSAM methods are shown in <xref
        linkend="b8_f_uat9x"/>. For the west coast of Tasmania, data constraints and the size of
      region have prevented the development of a generalised method, and thus site-specific advice
      should be sought from the Bureau of Meteorology. It should be noted that the PMP estimates
      provided by the Bureau of Meteorology are for design rainfall bursts rather than complete
      storm events, though these can be adjusted to include likely pre-burst rainfalls using
      information provided by <citation>b8_c_r42+1</citation> and <xref linkend="b2_ch5"/>.</para>
    <para>All PMP estimates are based on a set of simplifying assumptions applied when extrapolating
      from the hydrometeorological conditions of observed large events to “maximised conditions”.
      They thus represent operational estimates of the PMP and should not be interpreted as being
      equivalent to a theoretical upper limit on rainfall for that location i.e., there is a very
      small, but finite, probability that the estimates may be exceeded (<xref linkend="b8_s_bb68z"
      />).</para>
    <figure xml:id="b8_f_uat9x">
      <title>Generalised Long-Duration Probable Maximum Precipitation Method Zones 
        <citation>b8_c_r9</citation></title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/8012.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_bb68z">
    <title>Assigning an Annual Exceedance Probability to the Probable Maximum Precipitation</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_n9mfu">
      <title>Background</title>
      <para>Assigning an AEP to the PMP is consistent with the concept of operational PMP estimates
        (as described <xref linkend="b8_s_1a1fg"/> and in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s7_0"/>), which
        should not be regarded as theoretical upper limits of rainfall, as they may conceivably be
        exceeded.</para>
      <para>The method proposed to assign an AEP to the PMP is based on the review by
          <citation>b8_c_r35+1</citation> of the procedures recommended in the 1987 edition of ARR
        and subsequent work conducted in both Australia and overseas. More recent research into
        regional estimates for the inland zone of south-east Australia <citation>b8_c_r52</citation>
        provides some evidence to suggest that the Laurenson-Kuczera recommendations might be
        slightly conservative, though the authors concluded that there is insufficient justification
        to consider changing either the best estimate or the inferred width of the confidence
        intervals.</para>
      <para>Overall it is considered that recommendations provided below represent a reasonable
        basis for design, and that the associated confidence intervals do reflect the true
        uncertainty involved. It should be recognised that this is an area of ongoing research and
        practitioners should take advantage of revised guidance where shown to be more appropriate
        by independent peer review.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_0ndc5">
      <title>Regional Recommendations</title>
      <para>The AEP of PMP estimates are considered to vary solely as a function of catchment area,
        and are similar to the recommendations of <citation>b8_c_r29+1</citation>. These
        recommendations had been adopted as the basis of the guidance provided in ARR 1987, and are
        consistent with the more recent estimates of <citation>b8_c_r57+1</citation> and
          <citation>b8_c_r49+1,b8_c_r52+1</citation>. The relationship recommended by
          <citation>b8_c_r35+1</citation> is shown graphically in <xref linkend="b8_s_9piio"/>. It
        should be noted that these AEP estimates indicate the probability of a PMP event in any part
        of the year (annual PMP). The question of the AEP of a PMP event occurring in a specific
        season (seasonal PMP) is addressed in <xref linkend="b8_s_9piio"/>.</para>
      <para>It should be recognised that there is considerable uncertainty surrounding these
        recommendations as they are for events beyond the realm of experience and are based on a
        limited body of information. The estimates should be interpreted as follows:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the recommended AEP values plus or minus two orders of magnitude of AEP should be
            regarded as the notional upper and lower limits for the true AEP;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the recommended AEP values plus or minus one order of magnitude of AEP should be
            regarded as the confidence limits with about 75% subjective probability that the true
            AEP lies within these limits; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the recommended AEP values should be regarded as the best estimates of the
            AEPs.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The notional 75% confidence and upper and lower limits are shown on <xref
          linkend="b8_f_2386f"/>. While the recommended error bands are undoubtedly wider than is
        desirable, they are regarded as a realistic assessment of the true uncertainty.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b8_f_2386f">
        <title>Recommended Regional Estimates for the AEP of PMP</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/8003.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b8_t_vskyx">
          <caption>Subjective Probability Mass Function for Describing Uncertainty in Regional
            Estimate of the AEP of PMP (Adapted from <citation>b8_c_r35</citation>)</caption>
          <col width="29%"/>
          <col width="34%"/>
          <col width="39%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th colspan="2">Class Interval (log<subscript>10</subscript>(AEP) -
                  log<subscript>10</subscript>(Recommended AEP))</th>
              <th rowspan="2">Subjective probability mass in class interval</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Class bounds</td>
              <td>Mid-point</td>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>-2.00</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-1.875</td>
              <td>0.010</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>-1.75</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-1.625</td>
              <td>0.022</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>-1.50</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-1.375</td>
              <td>0.038</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>-1.25</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-1.125</td>
              <td>0.055</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>-1.00</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-0.875</td>
              <td>0.073</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>-0.75</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-0.625</td>
              <td>0.090</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>-0.50</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-0.375</td>
              <td>0.102</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>-0.25</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>-0.125</td>
              <td>0.110</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>0.00</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>0.125</td>
              <td>0.110</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>0.25</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>0.375</td>
              <td>0.102</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>0.50</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>0.625</td>
              <td>0.090</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>0.75</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>0.875</td>
              <td>0.073</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>1.00</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>1.125</td>
              <td>0.055</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>1.25</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>1.375</td>
              <td>0.038</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>1.50</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>1.625</td>
              <td>0.022</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>1.75</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td/>
              <td>1.875</td>
              <td>0.010</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2.00</td>
              <td/>
              <td/>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>In order to incorporate this uncertainty into a risk analysis,
          <citation>b8_c_r35+1</citation> recommend the construction of a probability mass function
        that provides a 75% chance that the true AEP lies within one-order-of-magnitude of the
        recommended AEP, and a 100% chance that the true AEP lies within two-orders-of-magnitude of
        the recommended AEP. <xref linkend="b8_t_vskyx"/> presents an example of a probability mass
        function which meets these requirements.
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160530T182236+1000" comment="would beneft from being clearer for average practitioner. detail a few more steps"?>For
        example, if the recommended AEP were 1 in 10<superscript>6</superscript>, then there is an
        11.0% chance that the true AEP lies between 1 in 10<superscript>6</superscript> and 1 in
          10<superscript>5.75</superscript>, and there is a 42.4% chance that it lies between 1 in
          10<superscript>5.5</superscript> and 1 in 10<superscript>6.5</superscript>; the first
        example corresponds simply to a single probability interval adjacent to the mid-point of
        0.00 in <xref linkend="b8_t_vskyx"/>, and the second example corresponds to the central four
        probability intervals. Although the probabilities are subjective, they do reflect the
        considerable uncertainty in the AEP estimates.<?oxy_comment_end?> The uncertainty can be
        directly incorporated into a risk analysis by performing an assessment for each of the AEPs
        in <xref linkend="b8_t_vskyx"/> and weighting the results using the associated subjective
        probability.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_0tp5u">
      <title>Site-Specific Estimation</title>
      <para><citation>b8_c_r35+1</citation> included a review of appropriate approaches, and they
        concluded that the most promising avenues of research were based on total probability
        approaches developed and applied by the <citation>b8_c_r54+1</citation>,
          <citation>b8_c_r13+1</citation> and <citation>b8_c_r81+1</citation>. Another promising
        method was demonstrated by <citation>b8_c_r31+1</citation> who developed a
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160530T184039+1000" comment="do you need this word?"?>combinatorial<?oxy_comment_end?>
        approach that considered the joint distributions of the independent components that combined
        to produce PMP, and this was applied to the coastal GSAM methodology by
          <citation>b8_c_r57+1</citation>.</para>
      <para>More recently <citation>b8_c_r52</citation> described the development and application of
        two largely independent methods for deriving site-specific estimates of the AEP of PMP. One
        method uses the total probability theorem to combine the probabilities of extreme storms
        occurring in the
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160530T184314+1000" comment="what is the transposition region"?>transposition
        region<?oxy_comment_end?> with the likelihood that they were positioned in a manner that
        would equal or exceed the estimated target depth on the catchment for the specified
        duration. The other method involved the development of a stochastic regression model to
        estimate catchment rainfalls from point rainfalls at the key sites, and is based on an
        approach developed and applied by Schaefer over a number of years (e.g.
          <citation>b8_c_r41+1</citation>).</para>
      <para>These studies are mentioned to make the point that methods are available to derive
        site-specific estimates that are potentially more defensible than the regional
        recommendations described in the preceding section. While there remain a number of research
        questions which, if resolved, may increase confidence in such estimates, the undertaking of
        site-specific studies does merit practical consideration. Until the required methodology is
        more mature such studies would need to be undertaken by specialists with peer review. It is
        expected that this option is of most relevance to a minority of cases which involve the
        design of infrastructure on large catchments (&gt; 1000 km<superscript>2</superscript>) with
        high potential consequences of failure.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_qmkca">
    <title>Estimation of Extreme Rainfalls</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_80u1c">
      <title>General</title>
      <para>The previous sections provide recommendations on deriving catchment rainfall estimates
        for Very Rare events to the credible limit of extrapolation and for the PMP. In order to
        derive a complete areal rainfall frequency curve it is necessary to interpolate between
        these two limits. The interpolation is necessarily pragmatic as it attempts to link
        estimates based on conceptually different methods and different data sets. As there are no
        independently estimated design rainfalls for this range of AEPs, any specific interpolation
        procedure cannot be supported by direct evidence but it must be able to produce plausible
        and consistent estimates. The practical implication of this is that design rainfall
        estimates for Extreme events have a greater level of uncertainty than the events within the
        credible limit of extrapolation.</para>
      <para>Estimates of rainfalls for Extreme events beyond the credible limit of extrapolation are
        predicated on the following two design rainfall characteristics, namely:</para>
      <para>(i) the magnitude and AEP of the PMP; and,</para>
      <para>(ii) the rainfall depth and slope of the rainfall frequency curve at the credible limit
        of extrapolation.</para>
      <para>As discussed above, estimates of the AEP of the PMP are subject to a high degree of
        uncertainty and are based on the interpretation of the PMP values as operational estimates
        that can be exceeded, rather than upper limiting values of rainfall. This interpretation of
        the PMP implies that the frequency curve should not be asymptotic to the horizontal at the
        estimated PMP, but rather extend through the PMP at a slope consistent with the shape of the
        lower sections of the frequency curve.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_2p9cv">
      <title>Interpolation Procedure</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_yx63s">
        <title>Basis of Interpolation Procedure</title>
        <para><citation>b8_c_r67+1</citation> developed a procedure suited to the interpolation
          between regional estimates of Very Rare rainfalls and the PMP. The procedure was developed
          and tested on Victorian data using design information from the
          <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160530T185430+1000" comment="need to expand term. first time used"?>CRC-FORGE
          <?oxy_comment_end?>(Cooperative Research Centre - Focussed Rainfall Growth Estimation)
          procedure. While it is possible that other procedures may be developed for other regions,
          the procedure developed by Siriwardena and Weinmann is described here as it is considered
          to have generic applicability.</para>
        <para>The procedure is applicable to ‘gaps’ of different ranges corresponding to differences
          in both the AEP of the credible limit of extrapolation and to the assigned AEP of the PMP.
          The procedure involves the fitting of a 2-parameter parabolic function in log-log space to
          ensure a smooth, well-behaved function when design rainfalls are plotted against AEP on
          logarithmic scales. The following boundary conditions are adopted:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>at the starting point of interpolation, the slope of the interpolated curve
              matches the slope defined by design estimates from the upper segment of the frequency
              curve bounded at the upper end by the credible limit of extrapolation; and,</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>the slope of the interpolated curve through the PMP estimate is not constrained to
              the horizontal but is determined by the shape of the frequency curve at AEPs more
              frequent than that assigned to the PMP.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>It needs to be emphasised that the interpolation is entirely determined by estimates
          of the conditions at the two end points; no additional information is introduced in
          fitting the curve. Details on the derivation of the procedure can be found in
            <citation>b8_c_r67+1</citation>.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_g9miz">
        <title>Detailed Steps in Interpolation Procedure</title>
        <para>Application of the procedure is quite straightforward, and design estimates over the
          interpolated range can be easily computed, as described below.</para>
        <para>With reference to <xref linkend="b8_f_59irn"/>, the AEP of 1 in
            Y<subscript>2</subscript> represents the starting point of the interpolation (the
          credible limit of extrapolation), and the AEP of 1 in Y<subscript>1</subscript> represents
          a lower value such that between 1 in Y<subscript>1</subscript> and 1 in
            Y<subscript>2</subscript> the frequency curve can be assumed to be linear in the log-log
          domain. X<subscript>Y1</subscript> and X<subscript>Y2</subscript> represent the design
          rainfalls with AEPs of 1 in Y<subscript>1</subscript> and 1 in Y<subscript>2</subscript>.
          The slope of the frequency curve at the commencement of the transition,
            S<subscript>gc</subscript>, is determined by the slope between the two design values at
          AEPs of 1 in Y<subscript>1</subscript> and 1 in Y<subscript>2</subscript>.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b8_f_59irn">
          <title>Schematic Illustration of Interpolation Procedure</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/8004.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>The end point of the interpolation is the AEP of the PMP, which is denoted 1 in
            Y<subscript>PMP</subscript>. For consistency of nomenclature, the magnitude of the PMP
          is here denoted as X<subscript>PMP</subscript>.</para>
        <para>A design rainfall estimate  of 1 in Y AEP (denoted X<subscript>Y</subscript>) can be
          estimated using:<equation xml:id="b8_e_vzgi4">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                <m:msup>
                  <m:mi>10</m:mi>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                    <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                          <m:mi>Y2</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msup>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation></para>
        <para>where R<subscript>Y</subscript> is defined by the parabola fitted to the coordinates
          of the two end points (ie between X<subscript>Y2</subscript> , Y<subscript>2</subscript>
          and X<subscript>PMP</subscript>, Y<subscript>PMP</subscript>) and the slope of the lower
          end of the frequency curve (ie the straight line between X<subscript>Y1</subscript>,
            Y<subscript>1</subscript> and X<subscript>Y2</subscript>,
          Y<subscript>2</subscript>).</para>
        <equation xml:id="b8_e_ek9ei">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>R</m:mi>
                <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
              <m:mo>=</m:mo>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                    <m:mi>gc</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                    <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                    <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
                <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>gap</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                      <m:mo>-</m:mo>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>gc</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                    <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                  <m:msubsup>
                    <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                    <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                    <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                  </m:msubsup>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>
        <equation xml:id="b8_e_8rmw6">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                <m:mi>d</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
              <m:mo>=</m:mo>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                  <m:mfrac>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>PMP</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                      <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mfrac>
                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>
        <equation xml:id="b8_e_9t97w">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                <m:mi>y</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
              <m:mo>=</m:mo>
              <m:mfrac>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                  <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mfrac>
                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mfrac>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>
        <equation xml:id="b8_e_8n0f1">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                <m:mi>gc</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
              <m:mo>=</m:mo>
              <m:mfrac>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                  <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                    <m:mfrac>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>Y1</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>Y2</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mfrac>
                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                    <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                        <m:mi>Y2</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>⁣</m:mo>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                    <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                      <m:mfrac>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                          <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                          <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                      </m:mfrac>
                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mfrac>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>
        <equation xml:id="b8_e_010fu">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
              <m:msub>
                <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                <m:mi>gap</m:mi>
              </m:msub>
              <m:mo>=</m:mo>
              <m:mfrac>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mfrac>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                          <m:mi>PMP</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>log</m:mi>
                      <m:mo>⁡</m:mo>
                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>X</m:mi>
                          <m:mi>Y2</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mfrac>
                  <m:mo>-</m:mo>
                  <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                  <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mfrac>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:math>
        </equation>
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160530T190658+1000" comment="can this be used for other states?

does this bit belong in the following section"?>
        <para><citation>b8_c_r67+1</citation> recommend that the slope of the frequency curve at the
          commencement of the interpolation should be defined by the 1 in 1000 AEP and 1 in 2000 AEP
          events, i.e. Y<subscript>1</subscript> = 1000 and Y<subscript>2</subscript> = 2000. Thus
          the start point of interpolation is the credible limit of extrapolation obtained from the
          upper limit of design rainfalls obtained from the regional LH-moments approach (<xref
            xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b2_ch3"
          />).<?oxy_comment_end?></para>
        <para>An example describing the application of the above interpolation procedure is provided
          in <xref linkend="b8_s_gpl9k"/>.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_m11gl">
        <title>Range of Application</title>
        <para><citation>b8_c_r67+1</citation> have shown that the procedure performs satisfactorily
          over a range of design situations that specifically include:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>different starting points for interpolation (i.e. the AEP of the credible limit of
              extrapolation may vary);</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>different AEPs assigned to the PMP (ranging from 10<superscript>-4</superscript>
              to 10<superscript>-7</superscript>, as discussed in <xref linkend="b8_s_bb68z"/>);
              and,</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>different ‘shape parameters’ defined by the ratio of the slope of the upper end of
              the directly determined frequency growth curve, S<subscript>gc</subscript>, and the
              slope between the two end points of the ‘gap’, S<subscript>gap</subscript> (the ‘shape
              parameter’ S<subscript>gc</subscript>/S<subscript>gap</subscript> ranges between 0.25
              to 2.0).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>The above concepts are schematically illustrated in <xref linkend="b8_f_59irn"/>.
            <citation>b8_c_r67+1</citation> have tested the above interpolation procedure on 25
          catchments ranging in size from 25 to 15000 km<superscript>2</superscript> with diverse
          characteristics. The resultant frequency curves were shown to be plausible and well
          behaved for all test catchments. However, it is worth noting that
            <citation>b8_c_r22+1</citation> reported that the above interpolation approach did not
          yield plausible results for GSAM-derived storms for 13 small catchments in South
          Australia. They observed that inconsistencies in the relationship between rainfall depth
          and catchment size for short- and long-duration events resulted in physically infeasible
          frequency curves (i.e. values of S<subscript>gc</subscript>/S<subscript>gap</subscript>
          exceeded 2.0). This problem was largely obviated by undertaking the above interpolation
          procedure in the log-Normal domain (i.e. using the standard normal variate of the
          exceedance probabilities rather than the log of the inverse of AEP); in a few cases it was
          also necessary to slightly increase the estimate of the AEP of the PMP, but the degree of
          change was well less than the notional uncertainty involved. Thus, while the recommended
          interpolation procedure has been found to generally yield plausible results, it may be
          necessary to make pragmatic adjustments to the method where dictated by
          circumstances.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_i77bn">
    <title>Estimation of Rainfall Depths for Non-Standard Durations</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_d4ziw">
      <title>General</title>
      <para>The application of generalised methods yields design rainfall depths for a range of
        standard durations. The design rainfalls presented in <xref linkend="book2"/> ensure that
        rainfall depths can be derived for a consistent set of durations for standard AEPs, though
        there are a minority of circumstances where approximate procedures may be required to derive
        estimates for non-standard combinations.</para>
      <para>There are three broad design categories for which non-standard durations may be
        required:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Very Rare event rainfalls for durations intermediate to multiples of 24 hour
            periods;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Very Rare event design rainfalls for durations less than 24 hours; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Design rainfalls for very long durations (ie durations longer than those obtainable
            from any design rainfall database).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Guidance on the above three categories is provided within this section.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_c2k7l">
      <title>Very Rare Rainfalls for Intermediate Durations</title>
      <para>Over a limited range of storm burst durations, the variation of point rainfall depth
        with duration can be closely approximated by a power function relationship.
          <citation>b8_c_r80+1</citation> thus propose that design rainfalls for intermediate
        durations may be estimated by linear interpolation between log-transformed rainfall depths
        and the log-transformed interval between adjacent standard durations (e.g. 24 and 48
        hours).</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_ysol4">
      <title>Very Rare Event Rainfalls for Short Durations</title>
      <para>Sites with daily rainfall records provide a considerably denser spatial coverage and
        longer period of record than is available from the pluviograph network. The majority of
        research effort to date has been focussed on the derivation of Very Rare design rainfalls
        for burst durations of 24 hours and longer (as provided in <xref linkend="book2"/>), and by
        comparison the availability of design information for shorter duration rainfalls is rather
        limited.</para>
      <para>The Bureau of Meteorology is scheduled to produce very rare rainfalls for durations less
        than 24 hours and when available these should be used to estimate rainfall up to the
        credible limit. Until this information is released, the growth factors derived by
          <citation>b8_c_r25+1</citation> should be used. These estimates are based on the analysis
        of data from ten pluviograph sites around Australia. Melbourne had the longest period of
        record at 130 years. Five of the stations used (Darwin, Sydney, Hobart, Adelaide, and Perth)
        had over 80 years of record each. The frequency analysis was undertaken using the simple
        “station year” method as the data satisfied the required assumptions of independence and
        homogeneity (the storms were largely derived from thunderstorm or deeply convective events).
        For the ten stations analysed, this pooled data set represents a sequence of around 800
        station years. Non-dimensional frequency curves were derived for eight durations varying
        between 0.5 and 12 hours. The mean growth curve obtained from these distributions fell well
        within the 90% confidence limits (refer to <xref linkend="b8_t_hk25s"/>).</para>
      <para>Pending the outcome of more comprehensive analyses, it is recommended that the growth
        curve factors in <xref linkend="b8_t_hk25s"/> be used for design purposes. Rainfall depths
        for durations between 0.5 and 12 hours can be obtained by simply multiplying the relevant 1
        in 100 AEP design rainfall by the frequency factors shown in <xref linkend="b8_t_hk25s"/>.
        It should be noted that these factors represent the characteristics of events that are
        associated with thunderstorms, or deeply convective, storm activity and are derived from
        analyses that are largely independent of the data and procedures described in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3"/>. Accordingly, in some locations there may be the potential for
        significant discontinuity in growth factors between the values in <xref linkend="b8_t_hk25s"
        /> and those for longer duration events (24 hours and longer). If this is the case then it
        may be necessary to smooth the growth factors to ensure that the tails of the frequency
        curves do not cross, and that the rainfall depths vary in a consistent manner across storm
        duration and exceedance probability.</para>
      <para>
        <table frame="void" xml:id="b8_t_hk25s">
          <caption>Growth Curve Factors for Derivation of Sub-Daily Design Rainfalls Standardised by
            the 1 in 100 AEP Rainfall Depth)</caption>
          <col width="16%"/>
          <col width="16%"/>
          <col width="16%"/>
          <col width="16%"/>
          <col width="16%"/>
          <col width="16%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>AEP (1 in Y)</th>
              <th>100</th>
              <th>200</th>
              <th>500</th>
              <th>1000</th>
              <th>2000</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Growth Factor</td>
              <td>1.00</td>
              <td>1.140</td>
              <td>1.344</td>
              <td>1.513</td>
              <td>1.698</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_ob5bq">
      <title>Rainfalls for Very Rare to Extreme Events of Very Long Durations</title>
      <para>For dams with very large storage volumes relative to the volumes of inflow floods or
        dams with little or no spillway provision, or for some very large catchments, it is possible
        that the critical duration of interest may be longer than available from the generalised
        design rainfall information. The longest available storm duration using <xref
          linkend="book2"/> procedures is 168 hours (7 days). This duration generally relates to the
        meteorological limits associated with single storm events, and thus longer duration design
        events involve the consideration of storm sequences.</para>
      <para>The approach to solving design problems involving long critical durations is in essence
        a joint probability problem. In special circumstances the problem may involve the assessment
        of joint probabilities of extreme storm sequences, but when considering issues associated
        with reservoir outflow floods, the issue of storm sequences over extended periods may be
        implicitly solved by undertaking a joint probability analysis of inflow floods
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160531T184118+1000" comment="rory- in this section you talk about inflow floods but the section this sections links to (7.2.3) is just called inflows. "?>and<?oxy_comment_end?>
        initial reservoir volume (<xref linkend="b8_s_no8ga"/>).</para>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_gq7fn">
        <title>Storm Sequences in South-Eastern Australia</title>
        <para>Analysis of storm data in south-eastern Australia <citation>b8_c_r42</citation>
          indicates that about 40% of large storms are preceded by a rainfall event in the 15 days
          prior to the storm. Based on their magnitude, these antecedent rainfall events appear to
          comprise two different populations: most (32% of all large storms) had accumulated
          rainfall totals of less than 30% of the subsequent large storm, but a small proportion (8%
          of all large storms) had accumulated rainfall totals of between 30% and 80% of the
          subsequent large storm.</para>
        <para>In addition, <citation>b8_c_r65+1</citation> undertook an analysis of areal antecedent
          rainfalls in the inland GSAM region for periods ranging between 7 days and 24 months using
          113 years of gridded data. The analysis was undertaken for storm areas of 750
            km<superscript>2</superscript> and 1860 km<superscript>2</superscript>. They concluded
          that there is no correlation between pre-storm rainfalls and storm severity for the
          extremes considered, and thus the two processes could be treated independently in joint
          probability analyses.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_2zu4i">
        <title>Storm Sequences in Tropical Regions</title>
        <para>The nature of rainfall sequences for Rare to Extreme events in the tropical region is
          not as well understood. Limited evidence on the dependence of antecedent rainfalls is
          provided by <citation>b8_c_r65+1</citation> based on an analysis of areal rainfalls in the
          coastal GSTMR region. <citation>b8_c_r65+1</citation> undertook the analysis  for a storm
          area of 750 km<superscript>2</superscript> and  found that total rainfalls in the three
          months prior to the most extreme maxima on record were larger than the 20% percentile
          values. However, little correlation was found between the severity of the event and 7 day
          maxima within the preceding three months. Overall, it might be expected that the
          conditions prior to Extreme events are typically wetter than more frequent events, but
          further analysis would be required for specification of dependencies on initial reservoir
          level.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_9piio">
    <title>Seasonal Estimates of Rare to Extreme Rainfalls</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_8725x">
      <title>Theoretical and Practical Issues</title>
      <para>The derivation of the design rainfall data as discussed in <xref linkend="b8_s_8tx6d"/>
        to <xref linkend="b8_s_i77bn"/> is based on the assumption that rainfall is independent of
        the season in which it occurs, or at least that its seasonal variation does not have a
        significant influence on the design outcome. However, there are situations where the
        seasonal variation of rainfall characteristics is significant and may need to be taken into
        account in design flood estimation. As an example, severe thunderstorms may occur
        predominantly during the summer season. Where other design factors (such as initial loss or
        initial reservoir level) are also characterised by significant seasonal variation, it may be
        necessary to combine seasonal design rainfalls with the corresponding seasonal values of
        these other design factors, rather than with their average annual values. For this purpose,
        a season is defined as a period of one to several months during which the rainfall
        conditions (and other design factors) can be assumed to be the same.</para>
      <para><xref linkend="b8_s_9piio"/> describes typical design situations where seasonal
        estimates of design rainfalls for  Rare to Extreme events may be required. While it would
        appear sensible in these design situations to deal explicitly with seasonal effects, there
        are a number of practical and theoretical issues that are not easily resolved. Some of the
        issues related to the derivation of seasonal design rainfalls are discussed.</para>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_oub4v">
        <title>Seasonal Rainfall Estimates for Rare Events</title>
        <para>Seasonal design rainfalls for AEPs equal to or more frequent than 1 in 100 AEP cannot
          be obtained directly from information provided in <xref linkend="book2"/>. One approach is
          to extract seasonal maxima from rainfall records at a particular site, and then undertake
          a frequency analysis to derive seasonal rainfalls (the Bureau of Meteorology can provide
          these estimates if required). However, this approach can provide inconsistent seasonal
          estimates for the rarer events because of the inherent uncertainties in fitting the tails
          of the distribution to observed data, though theoretically this could be overcome by
          developing a fitting procedure that jointly fits all the seasonal distributions. In
          addition, the seasonal design rainfalls derived from the at-site data will need to be
          adjusted to ensure that the annual design rainfalls are consistent with the <xref
            linkend="book2"/> estimates.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_dnv6d">
        <title>Seasonal Rainfall Estimates for Very Rare events</title>
        <para>At present regional frequency estimates of seasonal rainfalls for AEPs rarer than 1 in
          100 AEP are only available for regions in Western Australia
            <citation>b8_c_r10,b8_c_r11</citation>. Similar analyses could be undertaken using
          seasonally censored data for other hydrometeorologically homogeneous regions, where the
          likelihood of rainfalls occurring in different seasons could then be applied to the Very
          Rare design rainfalls which have been derived on an annual basis (as described in <xref
            xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b8_s_xkt95"/>).</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_a6ftc">
        <title>Seasonal Probable Maximum Precipitation Estimates</title>
        <para>The PMP definition quoted in <xref linkend="b8_s_1a1fg"/> allows different PMP
          estimates to be derived for different parts of the year, i.e. seasonal PMPs. A procedure
          for estimating seasonal PMPs for short duration storms on areas up to 1000
            km<superscript>2</superscript> in southern Australia is given in the GSDM method
            <citation>b8_c_r11</citation>. Approximate seasonal estimates for four seasons are
          available for longer duration events in south-east Australia using the GSAM procedure, but
          it should be recognised that these estimates are based on a biased seasonal sample as the
          storms were selected on the basis of magnitude rather than season. Seasonal PMP estimates
          for longer duration storms in tropical areas (i.e. GTSMR estimates) are available for
          summer and winter seasons.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_opmsl">
        <title>Annual Exceedance Probability of the Seasonal Probable Maximum Precipitation</title>
        <para>At present there is no generally accepted procedure for assigning an AEP to a seasonal
          PMP. <citation>b8_c_r34+1</citation> give two alternative approaches to derive the AEP of
          seasonal PMP estimates.</para>
        <para>The first approach is based on the assumption that factors other than dew point (and
          factors deriving from that) affecting the value of PMP do not significantly vary with
          season. This is consistent with the Bureau of Meteorology’s assumption that each season
          has its own PMP; in other words, the magnitude of the seasonal PMP is different for
          different months of the year. It also follows that the probability of experiencing a PMP
          event of different magnitude in any month of the year is equal.</para>
        <para>This interpretation means that the exceedance probability of a PMP event occurring
            <emphasis role="italic">in a specific season</emphasis> of the year is proportional to
          the fraction of the year occupied by that season, but it does not yield directly an
          estimate of the exceedance probability of a seasonal PMP. The additional constraint to be
          considered follows from an argument based on extreme value theory, namely that the sum of
          the exceedance probabilities of events of <emphasis role="italic">the same magnitude
          </emphasis>for the different seasons should add to the AEP of the annual rainfall event of
          that magnitude.</para>
        <para>In practice, an iterative approach needs to be adopted, using the product of the AEP
          of the annual PMP and the fraction of the year occupied by the season as an initial (lower
          bound) estimate of the exceedance probability of the seasonal PMP estimates. These initial
          estimates are shown as hollow circles in <xref linkend="b8_f_06jbo"/>. A segment of the
          complete design rainfall frequency curve for each season then needs to be drawn between
          the rainfall depths of the largest and smallest seasonal PMP estimates (indicated by
          broken lines in <xref linkend="b8_f_06jbo"/>). Over the upper range of the seasonal
          rainfall magnitudes, the curve segments can be assumed to be parallel to the annual
          frequency curve. The addition of the AEPs corresponding to the annual PMP estimated from
          each seasonal rainfall curve will generally yield an AEP less than the AEP assigned to the
          annual PMP. The ratio of these two AEP estimates defines the correction factor (&gt; 1.0)
          that needs to be applied to each of the initially estimated AEPs of the seasonal PMP. This
          correction is indicated by arrows in <xref linkend="b8_f_06jbo"/>, and the final AEP
          estimates of seasonal PMPs are shown as filled in circles.</para>
        <figure xml:id="b8_f_06jbo">
          <title>Hypothetical Frequency Curves for Seasonal and Annual Design Rainfalls Based
            on the AEP Assigned to the Annual PMP (adapted from <citation>b8_c_r34+1</citation>,
            using Four Seasons of Relative Lengths 0.33, 017. 0.33, 0.17 and Relative Seasonal
            PMP Depths of 1.0, 0.85, 0.6, 0.85, for Summer, Autumn, Winter, and Spring,
            respectively)</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/8005.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>The second approach proposed by <citation>b8_c_r34+1</citation>, which is not fully
          developed at this stage, does not use the upper limit concept, but recommends the
          derivation of separate extreme rainfall frequency curves for each season, using the joint
          probability method <citation>b8_c_r57</citation>.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_6163d">
      <title>Derivation of Seasonal Design Rainfalls</title>
      <para>The procedure required to derive a complete seasonal frequency curve of design rainfalls
        is not straightforward, and is subject to differences in interpretation, particularly in
        respect to assigning an AEP to the seasonal PMP. The basic criterion to be satisfied by any
        procedure for estimating seasonal rainfall frequencies is that, for any given rainfall
        magnitude, the seasonal frequencies over all seasons should add up to the AEP of the
        rainfall magnitude determined from the analysis of annual rainfalls.</para>
      <para>In the absence of better design information, and noting the foregoing discussion, the
        following recommendations should prove adequate for most design problems where seasonal
        effects are important.</para>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_xkt95">
        <title>Rare Events</title>
        <para>Both seasonal and annual frequency analyses should be undertaken using rainfall data
          obtained from sites relevant to the study area. When applied in conjunction with seasonal
          PMP estimates, the adopted seasons should correspond to the seasons used in the derivation
          of the seasonal PMP depths, and the seasonal rainfall estimates should be expressed as
          fractions of the annual estimates. The seasonal fractions can then be converted to design
          rainfall depths by multiplying by the (annual) design rainfall values obtained from the
          standard information provided in <xref linkend="book2"/>. Note that the inherent
          uncertainties in fitting the tails of the distributions to observed seasonal data may mean
          that for a given rainfall magnitude the sum of the seasonal exceedance probabilities do
          not equal the annual exceedance probability. If this problem occurs one or more of the
          seasonal frequency curves will need to be adjusted to ensure that the seasonal and annual
          exceedance probabilities are consistent.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_vol5j">
        <title>Very Rare Events</title>
        <para>Unless specific regional estimates are available, the seasonal fractions corresponding
          to design rainfalls at the credible limit of extrapolation may be obtained by an
          interpolation procedure similar to that used for losses (e.g. linear interpolation on a
          log-log frequency plot – <xref linkend="b8_e_4dyk0"/>). The lower and upper end points
          used in the interpolation are defined, respectively, by the seasonal fractions derived for
          the 1 in 100 AEP and PMP design rainfalls. Once the seasonal fractions have been obtained
          by interpolation, seasonal design rainfalls for Very Rare events are derived by
          multiplying the fractions by the (annual) design rainfall values at the credible limit of
          extrapolation.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_cn47n">
        <title>Probable Maximum Precipitation Events</title>
        <para>Seasonal estimates of the PMP should be obtained from the Bureau of Meteorology. When
          plotted with Very Rare event seasonal design rainfalls for the corresponding season, the
          seasonal PMP estimates should be assigned an AEP equal to the product of the AEP of the
          annual PMP (from <xref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b8_f_sw31s"/>)
          and the fraction of the year occupied by the season. These AEPs need to be adjusted to
          ensure that the sum of the exceedance probabilities of events of <emphasis role="italic"
            >the same magnitude </emphasis>for the different seasons add to the AEP of the annual
          rainfall event of that magnitude (as discussed in <xref linkend="b8_s_6163d"/>, and
          illustrated in <xref linkend="b8_f_sw31s"/>). It is important to recognise that the
          uncertainty associated with the currently available seasonal PMP estimates is higher than
          that for the annual estimates.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_4n0lw">
    <title>Temporal Patterns</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_kz4c8">
      <title>General</title>
      <para>The temporal patterns provided in <xref linkend="book2"/> relate to the time
        distribution of design rainfall depths within rainfall bursts. Additional rainfall occurring
        immediately before the start of the burst, as part of a complete storm event, can be
        accounted for by ‘pre-burst’ temporal patterns.</para>
      <para><?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160531T205005+1000" comment="check - tp chapter recommends 10 patterns. "?>The
        concept of a single ‘representative’ temporal pattern that allows a probability neutral
        transformation of design rainfall inputs to flood outputs of the same AEP is basically
        flawed, as this transformation is quite sensitive to the routing characteristics of the
        catchment.<?oxy_comment_end?> This sensitivity can best be allowed for by applying an
        ensemble of typical temporal patterns rather than a single design temporal pattern, as can
        be done in the Ensemble Event and Monte Carlo Event approaches.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_isy73">
      <title>Specific Recommendations</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_qty0r">
        <title>Selection of Patterns for Design Bursts</title>
        <para><xref linkend="b8_t_kjsmh"/> summarises the recommended application of different
          temporal patterns for design rainfall bursts in the range of Very Rare to Extreme events.
          There are three main sources of design information:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>short duration point rainfall patterns from GSDM
                  <citation>b8_c_r7,b8_c_r25</citation>;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>long duration rainfall patterns for use across Australia (<xref
                  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b2_ch5"/>); and</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>areal temporal patterns developed for the generalised GSAM and GTSM-R PMP
                methods.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>Ensemble sets of areal temporal patterns are available for the latter two sources of
          data and there are advantages and limitations to using both sets. The prime advantage to
          using areal temporal patterns derived for use with PMP estimates is that they are based on
          careful hydrometeorological analysis of storms that are known to be the most extreme in
          the historical record. The disadvantage of them is that more extreme storms may have
          occurred since development of the methods, and – particularly in the inland GSAM region –
          there are a disparate number of patterns in the different combinations of storm areas and
          durations. Conversely, as described by <citation>b8_c_r98+1</citation> the areal patterns
          provided in <xref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b2_ch5"/> are based
          on the largest storms that have occurred in eleven regions across Australia. The
          limitation of these patterns with respect to extreme events is that they were selected on
          the basis of the depth (rather than rarity) of their associated rainfalls, and also that
          they were derived for smaller regions than used in development of the PMP methods. As
          such, it is likely that these patterns are associated with events that are less severe
          than those considered in the PMP analyses. Conversely, their main advantage is that they
          may have included extreme events that have occurred since completion of the PMP analyses,
          and also that they provide a consistent set of ten patterns for a more comprehensive range
          of storm area and duration combinations.</para>
        <para>Further analysis of the efficacy of these different data sets for application to Very
          Rare and Extreme event is warranted, but at present it is recommended that the PMP method
          areal temporal patterns be used to derive all design events rarer than 1 in 100 AEP. That
          said, it may be appropriate to use the <xref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
            linkend="b2_ch5"/> areal patterns in lieu of the PMP patterns to reconcile flood
          estimates with independently derived design flood estimates (as described in <xref
            xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/>). If so, it may be
          prudent to adopt a changing mix of areal temporal patterns from both sources of data over
          the Very Rare range to ensure a smooth transition in flood response over this range of
          exceedance probabilities. Also, where there is a paucity of information on areal temporal
          patterns – such as for some durations in the inland GSAM zone – it may be necessary to
          supplement the adopted ensembles using the patterns provided in <xref
            xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/>. At present, the
          best source of ensemble temporal patterns for use with short duration Very Rare to Extreme
          events are those derived by <citation>b8_c_r25+1</citation>; these patterns were derived
          specifically from storms associated with thunderstorm or deeply convective events.</para>
        <para>An issue requiring specific mention is the absence of temporal patterns in
          south-eastern Australia for use with storm durations between the upper limit of GSDM (3 or
          6 hours) and the lower limit of the GSAM method (generally 24 hours). A pragmatic solution
          to this problem is to apply both sets of temporal patterns and to adopt a weighted average
          peak flow, where the weighting is based on storm duration. The weighted average peak flow
          is then used to scale the hydrograph obtained using the most relevant generalised method;
          weighting all the ordinates of the hydrograph is not recommended as the resulting
          hydrograph may exhibit a lower peak than either of the individual hydrographs.</para>
        <para>In the transition zone between the GTSMR and GSAM regions, temporal patterns from both
          the GSAM and GTSMR methods should be applied separately (in conjunction with the
          corresponding spatial patterns), and the largest flood adopted.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_s3oeh">
        <title>Patterns for Complete Storms</title>
        <para>The design information required to define the design rainfall depths and temporal
          patterns for complete Very Rare and Extreme storms is available nationally (<xref
            linkend="b2_ch5"/>). These pre-burst patterns might be suitable for scaling to more
          extreme events, but it should be noted that the patterns provided are for point not areal
          storms, and will need censoring to ensure that the patterns selected are from
          appropriately rare events. <xref linkend="b2_ch5"/> outlines the principles for
          constructing complete storms from design bursts using dimensionless pre-burst temporal
          patterns. Guidance on the determination of rainfall excess for complete storms is provided
          in <xref linkend="b8_s_kprjg"/>.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_k55yh">
        <title>Dealing with Inconsistencies and Smoothing of Results</title>
        <para>In practice, the simplistic use of single design temporal patterns for different
          durations and AEPs can yield flood estimates that do not vary in a consistent manner. In
          extreme cases, this can result in design flood magnitudes that decrease with decreasing
          AEP. More typically, the patterns may result in critical storm durations that vary
          inconsistently with AEP; such a variation will impact upon the volume of design
          hydrographs which, when routed through a reservoir, may produce inconsistent results. The
          judicious use of simulation results using ensembles of temporal patters will largely avoid
          such inconsistencies. Problems are more likely to occur with the transition between
          temporal patterns for more frequent events and those derived for PMP events. If problems
          arise consideration should be given to filtering out (or excluding) embedded bursts of
          lower AEP by re-distributing rainfalls of high intensity to other time increments
          proportionally to their magnitude (e.g. <citation>b8_c_r18</citation>). Where significant
          inconsistencies remain, practitioners will need to apply judicious smoothing of results
          for different durations and AEPs.<table frame="void" xml:id="b8_t_kjsmh">
            <caption>Selection of Design Burst Temporal Patterns for Different Regions, Durations
              and AEPs</caption>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col span="2" width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <col width="16%"/>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Descriptive Event Class</th>
                <th>Range of AEP</th>
                <th colspan="5">Storm Duration and Source of Design Information</th>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <th/>
                <th/>
                <td>Short Durations for Whole of Australia</td>
                <td colspan="2">Long Durations in South-East Australia</td>
                <td colspan="2">Long Durations in Tropical Regions</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <th/>
                <th/>
                <td>Up to 3 or 6 hours duration</td>
                <td>Intermediate durations</td>
                <td>24 hours and longer</td>
                <td>Intermediate durations</td>
                <td>24 hours and longer</td>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td><emphasis role="bold">Very Rare</emphasis></td>
                <td><emphasis role="bold">Beyond 1 in 100 up to 1 in 2000 AEP</emphasis></td>
                <td colspan="5">
                  <para>Use patterns as for Extreme range below, though consideration should be
                    given to including areal temporal patterns as described in <xref
                      linkend="b2_ch5"/> and <citation>b8_c_r98+1</citation>. These areal patterns
                    are likely to be from more frequent storms than those available from the PMP
                    methods. As such, they may be more suited to reconciliation with other
                    independently derived design flood estimates (as described in <xref
                      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b5_ch5_s_ppgv2"/>) rather
                    than for deriving design estimates.</para>
                </td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td><emphasis role="bold">Extreme</emphasis></td>
                <td><emphasis role="bold">Rarer than 1 in 2000 AEP</emphasis></td>
                <td>Deterministic areal patterns from GSDM method, ensemble patterns from
                    <citation>b8_c_r25+1</citation></td>
                <td>24 hour GSAM and longest duration GSDM areal rainfall patterns</td>
                <td>GSAM areal rainfall patterns (single and ensemble)</td>
                <td>Both 24 hour GTSMR areal patterns and longest duration GSDM patterns</td>
                <td>GTSMR areal patterns (single and ensemble)</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table></para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_sborg">
    <title>Spatial Patterns</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_oghg9">
      <title>Basis of Adopted Patterns</title>
      <para>Design spatial rainfall patterns are also required to fully define design rainfall
        events, and general guidance on this is provided in <xref linkend="book2"/>. The source of
        spatial patterns as a function of burst duration and AEP is broadly similar to that adopted
        for temporal patterns (except for the Very Rare rainfall category), and is summarised in
          <xref linkend="b8_t_r78ov"/>. As discussed in <xref linkend="b8_s_5ahbu"/> there are four
        main sources of design information: patterns based on the spatial distribution of design
        rainfalls for Very Rare events, spatial patterns for use in south-eastern Australia
          <citation>b8_c_r43</citation>, GSDM thunderstorm patterns <citation>b8_c_r7</citation>,
        and tropical storm patterns <citation>b8_c_r8</citation>. As with temporal patterns, the
        last three sets of patterns were originally derived for application to PMP events, but in
        the absence of any more relevant information they are applied to the range of Very Rare to
        Extreme events.</para>
      <para>Except for catchments with marked rainfall gradients, the spatial distribution of
        rainfall generally has less influence on the shape and size of the resulting hydrograph than
        temporal patterns. Thunderstorm and tropical patterns can have an appreciable effect on
        flood magnitude, particularly if the catchment contains extensive drowned reaches resulting
        from reservoir inundation. For such catchments, small variations in the spatial distribution
        of design rainfall may have a marked impact on the magnitude of the flood peak. It is worth
        assessing the sensitivity of the catchment floods to variations in spatial patterns, and if
        this is not easily resolved then it would be necessary to include spatial patterns as an
        ensemble in Monte Carlo analyses.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_5ahbu">
      <title>Specific Recommendations</title>
      <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Very Rare events.</emphasis>- Spatial rainfall trends may be
            characterised by dividing the catchment into two or more sub-catchments, and deriving
            design rainfalls separately for each.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Extreme short duration events.</emphasis>- The GSDM
            thunderstorm patterns <citation>b8_c_r7</citation> should be used. The spatial pattern
            should generally be centred over the catchment and orientated in such a way as to
            overlap the catchment boundary with the smallest possible ellipse.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Extreme long duration events in south-eastern
              Australia.</emphasis>-  The spatial patterns provided with GSAM estimates
              <citation>b8_c_r43</citation> should be applied to all Very Rare to Extreme events.
            The spatial patterns are based on modified 72 hour 50 year ARI intensity fields of
            design rainfalls from <xref linkend="book2"/>, and they incorporate the combined effect
            of variations in elevation, slope, aspect and geographical location. These patterns
            should not be rotated or translated.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Extreme long duration events in tropical
            regions.</emphasis>-The spatial patterns provided with GTSMR estimates
              <citation>b8_c_r8</citation> should be applied to all Very Rare to Extreme events. The
            spatial pattern should be positioned to maximise the rainfall depth within the
            catchment.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Extreme long duration events in the transition
              zone.</emphasis> In the transition zone between the GSAM and GTSMR regions, both sets
            of spatial patterns should be used (in conjunction with the corresponding temporal
            patterns) and the highest resulting flood should be adopted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b8_t_r78ov">
        <caption>Selection of Design Spatial Patterns for Different Regions, Durations and
          AEPs</caption>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Descriptive event class</th>
            <th>Range of AEP</th>
            <th colspan="5">Storm duration and source of design information</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>
              <para>Short durations for Wwhole of Australia</para>
              <para> (GSDM)</para>
            </td>
            <td colspan="2">Long durations in southeast Australia (GSAM method)</td>
            <td>Long durations in tropical regions (GTSMR method)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td/>
            <td/>
            <td>Up to 3 or 6 hours duration</td>
            <td>Intermediate durations between GSDM and GSAM</td>
            <td>24 hours and longer</td>
            <td>Longer than 6 hours</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Very Rare</emphasis></td>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Beyond 1 in 100 to the credible limit of
                extrapolation</emphasis></td>
            <td colspan="4">Based on design rainfalls for Very Rare events derived separately for
              each sub-catchment</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Extreme</emphasis></td>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Beyond the credible limit of extrapolation</emphasis></td>
            <td>GSDM spatial patterns</td>
            <td>Both GSAM and GSDM spatial patterns</td>
            <td>GSAM spatial patterns</td>
            <td>GTSMR spatial patterns</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </section>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
  
</chapter>



