<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b3_ch2_s1"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>Flood frequency analysis refers to procedures that use recorded and
  related flood data to identify the underlying probability model of flood
  peaks at a particular location in the catchment. The flood probability model
  can then be used to perform risk-based design and flood risk assessment and
  to provide input to regional flood estimation methods.</para>

  <para>The primary purpose of this chapter is to present guidelines on
  performing flood frequency analyses<footnote>
      <para>The chapter represents an substantial revision of Chapter 10 of
      the 3rd Edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff (Pilgrim and Doran,
      1987). Where appropriate the original contribution by Pilgrim and Doran
      has been retained. The major changes include introduction of
      non-homogeneous probability models, replacement of product log-moments
      with more efficient estimation methods, use of Bayesian methods to make
      better use of available flood information (such as censored flow data,
      rating error and regional information), reduced prescription about the
      choice of flood probability model, improved identification of
      potentially influential low flows and guidance on fitting frequency
      curves to “difficult” data sets.</para>
    </footnote>. Often judgment will need to be exercised. To inform such
  judgments, this chapter describes the key conceptual foundations that
  underpin flood frequency analysis – the reader will need an understanding of
  elementary probability theory and statistics to get maximum benefit. In
  addition a number of worked examples are provided to provide deeper insight
  with the implied caveat that the examples are not exhaustive in their scope.
  While it is expected that most users will use software written by others to
  implement the methods described in this chapter, sufficient information is
  provided to enable users to develop their own software applications.</para>
</section>
