<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section status="In Preparation" xml:id="b3_ch2_s7"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>FITTING FLOOD PROBABILITY MODELS TO POT SERIES</title>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_3pnks">
    <title>Probability Plots</title>

    <para>As with the analysis of annual maximum series it is recommended that
    a probability plot of the POT data series be prepared. The plot involves
    plotting an estimate of the observed ARI against the discharge. The ARI of
    a gauged flood can be estimated using</para>

    <equation xml:id="b3_ch2_e_8fo4w">
      <m:math display="block">
        <m:mrow>
          <m:msub>
            <m:mi>T</m:mi>

            <m:mi>(i)</m:mi>
          </m:msub>

          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

          <m:mfrac>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>n</m:mi>

              <m:mo>+</m:mo>

              <m:mi>0.2</m:mi>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

              <m:mo>-</m:mo>

              <m:mi>0.4</m:mi>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mfrac>
        </m:mrow>
      </m:math>
    </equation>

    <para>where i is the rank of the gauged flood (in descending order) and n
    is the number of years of record.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_gzz1z">
    <title>Fitting POT Models</title>

    <para>In some cases, it may be desirable to analytically fit a probability
    distribution to POT data. Two general approaches have been used.</para>

    <para>In the first, the annual flow series distribution has been estimated
    from the POT series on the basis that the latter considers all of the
    relevant data and should thus provide a better estimate. The basis for the
    procedure is <xref linkend="???"/> eqn (5) which links Poisson arrivals of
    flood peaks with a distribution of flood magnitudes above some threshold.
    Jayasuriya and Mein (1985), Ashkar and Rousselle (1983) and Tavares and da
    Silva (1983) explored this approach using the exponential distribution.
    The approach has been fairly successful, but some results have diverged
    from the distribution derived directly from the annual series. At this
    stage, the approach cannot be recommended as a replacement for the
    analysis of annual series data. If possible, the base discharge for this
    approach should be selected so that the number of floods in the POT series
    K is at least 2 to 3 times the number of years of record N. However, it
    may be necessary to use a much lower value of K in regions with low
    rainfall where the number of recorded events that could be considered as
    floods is low.</para>

    <para>The second approach uses a probability distribution as an arbitrary
    means of providing a consistent and objective fit to POT series data. For
    example, McDermott and Pilgrim (1982), Adams and McMahon (1985) and
    Jayasuriya and Mein 1985) used the LP3 distribution – they found that
    selecting a threshold discharge such that K equalled N was best. Example
    11 illustrates this approach using L moments to fit an exponential
    distribution to a POT series.</para>
  </section>
</section>
