<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section status="In Preparation" xml:id="b3_ch2_s8"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>References</title>

  <para>Adams, C.A. (1987) Design flood estimation for ungauged rural
  catchments in Victoria Road Construction Authority, Victoria. Draft
  Technical Bulletin.</para>

  <para>Adams, C.A. and McMahon, T.A. (1985) Estimation of flood discharge for
  ungauged rural catchments in Victoria. Hydrol. and Water Resources Symposium
  1985, Inst Engrs Aust., Natl Conf. Publ. No. 85/2, pp. 86-90.</para>

  <para>Alexander, G.N. (1957) Flood flow estimation, probability and the
  return period. Jour. Inst. Engrs Aust, Vol. 29, pp. 263-278.</para>

  <para>Allan, R.J. (2000) ENSO and climatic variability in the last 150
  years, in El Nino and the Southern Oscillation, Multi-scale variability,
  Global and Regional Impacts, edited by H.F. Diaz and V. Markgraf, Cambridge
  University Press, Cambridge, uk, p3-56.</para>

  <para>American Society of Civil Engineers (1949) Hydrology Handbook</para>

  <para>Ashkanasy, N.M. and Weeks, W.D. (1975) Flood frequency distribution in
  a catchment subject to two storm rainfall producing mechanisms. Hydrol.
  Symposium 1975, Inst Engrs Aust, Natl Conf. Publ. No. 75/3, pp.
  153-157.</para>

  <para>Ashkar, F. and Rousselle, J. (1983) Some remarks on the truncation
  used in partial flood series models. Water Resources Research, Vol. 19, pp.
  477-480.</para>

  <para>Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A guide to flood estimation (1987)
  Pilgrim, D.H. (ed), The Institution of Engineers, Australia,
  Canberra.</para>

  <para>Baker, V. (1984) Recent paleoflood hydrology studies in arid and
  semi-arid environments (abstract). EOS Trans. Amer. Geophys. Union, Vol. 65,
  p. 893.</para>

  <para>Baker, V., Pickup, G. and Polach, H.A. (1983) Desert paleofloods in
  central Australia. Nature, Vol. 301, pp. 502-504.</para>

  <para>Beard, L.R (1960) Probability estimates based in small
  normal-distribution samples. Jour. of Geophysical Research, Vol.65, pp.
  2143-2148.</para>

  <para>Beard, L.R (1974) Flood flow frequency techniques Univ. of Texas at
  Austin, Center for Research in Water Resources, Tech. Report CRWR119,
  October.</para>

  <para>Beran, M., Hosking, J.RM. and Arnell, N. (1986) Comment on
  "Two-component extreme value distribution for flood frequency analysis."
  Water Resources Research Vol.22, pp. 263-266.</para>

  <para>Blom, G. (1958) Statistical Estimates and Transformed Beta-Variables.
  Wiley, New York, 176 p.</para>

  <para>Clarke-Hafstad, K. (1942) Reliability of station-year
  rainfall-frequency determinations. Trans. Amer. Soc. Civ. Engrs, Vol.107,
  pp. 633-652.</para>

  <para>Cohn, T. A., England, J.F., Berenbrock, C.E., Mason, R.R., Stedinger,
  J.R. and Lamontagne, J.R. (2013), A generalized Grubbs-Beck test statistic
  for detecting multiple potentially influential low outliers in flood series,
  Water Resour. Res., 49, 5047–5058, doi:10.1002/wrcr.20392.</para>

  <para>Conway, K.M. (1970) Flood frequency analysis of some N.S.W. coastal
  rivers. Thesis (M.Eng Sc.), Univ.NSW.</para>

  <para>Costa, J.E. (1978) Holocene stratigraphy in flood frequency analysis.
  Water Resources Research, Vol.14, pp. 626-632.</para>

  <para>Costa, J.E. (1983) Palaeohydraulic reconstruction or flashflood peaks
  from boulder deposits in the Colorado Front Range. Geol. Soc. America
  Bulletin, Vol. 94, AP. 986-1004.</para>

  <para>Costa, J.E. (1986) A history of paleoflood hydrology in the United
  States, 1800-1970. EOS Trans. Aoler Geophysical Union, Vol. 67, No. 17, pp.
  425-430.</para>

  <para>Cunnane, C. (1978) Unbiased plotting positions - a review. Jour. of
  Hydrology, Vol. 37, pp. 205-222.</para>

  <para>Cunnane, C. (1985) Factors affecting choice of distribution for flood
  series. Hydrological Sciences Journal, Vol. 30, pp. 25-36.</para>

  <para>Dalrymple, T. (1960) Flood-frequency analyses. Manual of Hydrology:
  Section 3. Flood-flow Techniques. U.S. Geological Survey Water Supply Paper
  1543-A, 79 p.</para>

  <para>DeGroot, M.H., Optimal statistcal decisions, McGraw-Hill, 1970.</para>

  <para>Doran, D.G. and Irish, J.L. (1980) On the nature and extent of bias in
  flood damage estimation. Hydrol. and Water Resources Symposium 1980, Inst.
  Engrs Aust, Natl Conf. Publ. No. 80/9, pp. 135-139.</para>

  <para>Duan, Q., Sorooshian, S. and V. Gupta, Effective and efficient global
  optimization for conceptual rainfall-runoff models, Water Resources
  Research, 28(4), 1015-1031, 1992.</para>

  <para>Erskine, W. D., and Warner, R.F. (1988), Geomorphic effects of
  alternating flood and drought dominated regimes on a NSW coastal river, in
  Fluvial Geomorphology of Australia, edited by R.F. Warner, pp. 223-244,
  Academic Press, Sydney.</para>

  <para>Fiering, M.B. (1963) Use of correlation to improve estimates of the
  mean and variance. U.S. Geological estimates of the mean and variance. U.S.
  Geological Survey Professional Paper 434-C.</para>

  <para>Fiorentino, M., Versace, P. and Rossi, F. (1985) Regional flood
  frequency estimation using the two-component extreme value distribution.
  Hydrol. Sciences Jour., Vol. 30, pp. 51-64.</para>

  <para>Flavell, D.J. (1983) The Rational Method applied to small rural
  catchments in the south west of Western Australia Civ. Engg Trans., Inst.
  Engrs Aust., Vol. CE25, pp. 121-127.</para>

  <para>Folland, C. K., Renwick, J.A., Salinger, M.J. and Mullan, A.B. (2002),
  Relative influences of the Interdecadal Pacific Oscillation and ENSO on the
  South Pacific Convergence Zone, Geophys. Res. Lett., 29(13),
  doi:10.1029/2001GL014201.</para>

  <para>Franks, S.W. and Kuczera, G. (2002) Flood Frequency Analysis: Evidence
  and Implications of Secular Climate Variability, New South Wales, Water
  Resources Research, 38(5), 10.1029/2001WR000232.</para>

  <para>Franks, S.W. (2002a), Identification of a change in climate state
  using regional flood data, Hydrol. Earth Sys. Sci., 6(1), 11-16.</para>

  <para>Franks, S.W. (2002b), Assessing hydrological change: deterministic
  general circulation models or spurious solar correlation? Hydrol. Proc., 16,
  559-564.</para>

  <para>Gelman, A., Carlin, J.B., Stren, H.S. and Rubin, D.B. (1997) Bayesian
  data analysis, Chapman and Hall, p.526.</para>

  <para>Hosking, J.R.M. (1990) L-moments: Analysis and estimation of
  distributions using linear combinations of order statistics, J. Roy.
  Statist. Soc., Ser. B 52(2), 105-124.</para>

  <para>Hosking, J.R.M. and Wallis, J.R (1986) Paleoflood hydrology and flood
  frequency analysis. Water Resources Research, Vol. 22, pp. 543-550.</para>

  <para>Houghton, J.C. (1978) Birth of a parent: The Wakeby distribution for
  modeling flood flows. Water Resources Research, Vol. 14, pp.
  1105-1109.</para>

  <para>Interagency Advisory Committee on Water Data (1982) Guidelines for
  determining flood flow frequency. Bulletin 17B of the Hydrology
  Sub-committee, Office of Water Data Coordination, Geological Survey, U.S.
  Dept of the Interior.</para>

  <para>Jayasuriya, M.D.A. and Mein, RG. (1985) Frequency analysis using the
  partial series. Hydrol. and Water Resources Symposium 1985, Inst. Engrs
  Aust., Natl Conf. Publ. No. 85/2, pp. 81-85.</para>

  <para>Kiem, A. S., and Franks, S.W. (2004) Multidecadal variability of
  drought risk - eastern Australia, Hydrol. Proc., 18,
  doi:10.1002/hyp.1460.</para>

  <para>Kiem, A.S., Franks, S.W. and Kuczera, G. (2003) Multi-decadal
  variability of flood risk, Geophysical Research Letters, 30(2), 1035,
  DOI:10.1029/2002GL015992.</para>

  <para>Kochel. RC., Baker, V.R and Patton, P.C. (1982) Paleohydrology of
  southwestern Texas. Water Resources Research, Vol. 18, pp. 1165-1183.</para>

  <para>Kopittke, RA., Stewart, B.J. and Tickle, K.S. (1976) Frequency
  analysis of flood data in Queensland. Hydrol. Symposium 1976, Inst Engrs
  Aust., Natl Conf. Publ. No. 76/2, pp. 20-24.</para>

  <para>Kuczera, G., Correlated rating curve error in flood frequency
  inference, Water Resources Research, 32(7), 2119-2128, 1996.</para>

  <para>Kuczera, G. (1999) Comprehensive at-site flood frequency analysis
  using Monte Carlo Bayesian inference, Water Resources Research, 35(5),
  1551-1558.</para>

  <para>Kuczera, G., Lambert, M.F., Heneker, T. Jennings, S., Frost, A. and
  Coombes, P. (2006) Joint probability and design storms at the crossroads,
  Australian Journal of Water Resources, 10(2), 5-21.</para>

  <para>Lee, P.M. (1989) Bayesian statistics: An introduction, Oxford
  University Press (NY).</para>

  <para>Laurenson, E.M. (1987) Back to basics on flood frequency analysis.
  Civ. Engg Trans., Inst Engrs Aust, Vol. CE29, pp. 47-53.</para>

  <para>Mantua, N. J., S. R. Hare, Y. Zhang, J. M. Wallace, and R. C. Francis
  (1997), A Pacific interdecadal climate oscillation with impacts on salmon
  production, Bull. Amer. Meteorol. Soc., 78(6), 1069-1079.</para>

  <para>Matalas, N.C. and Jacobs, B. (1964) A correlation procedure for
  augmenting hydrologic data. U. S. Geological Survey Professional Paper
  434-E.</para>

  <para>McDermott, G.E. and Pilgrim, D. H. (1982) Design flood estimation for
  small catchments in New South Wales. Dept of National Development and
  Energy, Aust Water Resources Council Tech. Paper No. 73, 233 p.</para>

  <para>McDermott, G.E. and Pilgrim, D.H. (1983) A design flood method for
  arid western New South Wales based on bankfull estimates. Civ. Engg Trans.,
  Inst Engrs Aust, Vol. CE25, pp. 114-120.</para>

  <para>McIllwraith, J.F. (1953) Rainfall intensity-frequency data for New
  South Wales stations. Jour. Inst Engrs Aust, Vol. 25, pp. 133-139.</para>

  <para>McMahon, T.A. (1979) Hydrologic characteristics of Australian streams.
  Civ. Engg Research Reports, Monash Univ., Report No. 3/1979.</para>

  <para>McMahon, T.A. and Srikanthan, R (1981) Log Pearson III distribution-
  is it applicable to flood frequency analysis of Australian streams? Jour. of
  Hydrology, Vol.52, pp. 139-147.</para>

  <para>Micevski, T., Kiem, A.S., Franks, S.W. and Kuczera, G. (2003)
  Multidecadal Variability in New South Wales Flood Data, Hydrology and Water
  Resources Symposium, Institution of Engineers, Australia, Wollongong.</para>

  <para>Natural Environment Research Council (1975) Flood Studies Report, Vol.
  1, Hydrological Studies. London</para>

  <para>O’Connell, D.R., Ostemaa, D.A., Levish, D.R. and Klinger, R.E. (2002)
  Bayesian flood frequency analysis with paleohydrologic bound data, Water
  Resources Research, 38(5), 1058, DOI:10.1029/2000WRR000028.</para>

  <para>Pedruco, P., Nielsen, C., Kuczera, G. and Rahman, A. (2014) Combining
  regional flood frequency estimates with an at site flood frequency analysis
  using a Bayesian framework: Practical considerations, Hydrology and Water
  Resources Symp., Perth, Engineers Australia.</para>

  <para>Pilgrim, D.H. and Doran, D.G. (1987) Flood frequency analysis, in
  Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A guide to flood estimation, Pilgrim, D.H.
  (ed), The Institution of Engineers, Australia, Canberra.</para>

  <para>Pilgrim, D.H. and McDermott, G.E. (1982) Design floods for small rural
  catchments in eastern New South Wales. Civ. Engg Trans., Inst Engrs Aust.,
  Vol. CE24, pp. 226-234.</para>

  <para>Potter, D.J. and Pilgrim, D.H. (1971) Flood estimation using a
  regional flood frequency approach. Final Report, Vol. 2, Report on Analysis
  Components. Aust. Water Resources Council, Research Project 68/1, Hydrology
  of Small Rural Catchments. Snowy Mountains Engg Corporation, April.</para>

  <para>Potter, K.W. and Walker, J.F. (1981) A model of discontinuous
  measurement error and its effects on the probability distribution of flood
  discharge measurements, Water Resources Research, 17(5), 1505-1509.</para>

  <para>Potter, K.W. and Walker, J.F. (1985) An empirical study of flood
  measurement error, Water Resources. Research, 21(3), 403-406.</para>

  <para>Power, S., F. Tseitkin, S. Torok, B. Lavery, R. Dahni, and B. McAvaney
  (1998), Australian temperature, Australian rainfall and the Southern
  Oscillation, 1910-1992: coherent variability and recent changes, Aust. Met.
  Mag., 47(2), 85-101.</para>

  <para>Power, S., T. Casey, C. Folland, A. Colman, and V. Mehta (1999),
  Inter-decadal modulation of the impact of ENSO on Australia, Climate
  Dynamics,15(5), 319-324.</para>

  <para>Rossi, F., Fiorentino, M. and Versace, P. (1984) Two-component extreme
  value distribution for flood frequency analysis. Water Resources Research,
  Vol.20, pp.847-856.</para>

  <para>Slack, J.R., Wallis, J.R. and Matalas, N.C. (1975) On the value of
  information in flood frequency analysis, , Water Resources. Research, 11(5),
  629-648.</para>

  <para>Stedinger, J.R. (1983) Design events with specified flood risk, Water
  Resources Research, 19(2), 511-522.</para>

  <para>Stedinger, J.R., Vogel, R.M. and Foufoula-Georgiou, E. (1993)
  Frequency analysis of extreme events in Handbook of Hydrology, Maidment,
  D.R. (ed.), McGraw-Hill, NY.</para>

  <para>Stedinger, J.R and Cohn, T.A. (1986) Flood frequency analysis with
  historical and paleoflood information. Water Resources Research, Vol. 22,
  pp. 785-793.</para>

  <para>Tavares, L.V. and da Silva, J.E. (1983) Partial series method
  revisited. Jour. of Hydrology, Vol. 64, pp. 1-14.</para>

  <para>Wallis, J.R and Wood, E.F. (1985) Relative accuracy log Pearson III
  procedures. Proc. Amer. Soc. Civ. Engrs. Jour. of Hydraulic Engg, Vol. lll,
  No.7, pp.1043-10</para>

  <para>Wang, Q. J. (1996) Direct sample estimators of L-moments, Water
  Resources Research, 32(12), 3617-3619, 1996.</para>

  <para>Wang, Q. J. (1997) LH moments for statistical analysis of extreme
  events, Water Resources Research, 33(12), 2841-2848.</para>

  <para>Wang, Q. J. (1998) Approximate goodness-of-fit tests of fitted
  generalized extreme value distributions using LH moments, Water Resources
  Research, 34(12), 3497-3502.</para>

  <para>Wang, Q.J. (2001) A Bayesian joint probability approach for flood
  record augmentation, Water Resources Research, 37(6), pp. 1707-1712.</para>
</section>
