<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section status="In Preparation" xml:id="b3_ch2_s7"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Fitting Flood Probability Models to Peak Over Threshold
  Series</title>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_3pnks">
    <title>Probability Plots</title>

    <para>As with the analysis of Annual Maximum
      series<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151022T172253+1100"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      it is recommended that a probability plot of the POT data series be prepared. The plot
      involves plotting an estimate of the observed AEP against the discharge. The AEP of a gauged
      flood can be estimated using:</para>

    <equation xml:id="b3_ch2_e_8fo4w">
      <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>T</mi>

            <mi>(i)</mi>
          </msub>

          <mo>=</mo>

          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <mi>n</mi>

              <mo>+</mo>

              <mi>0.2</mi>
            </mrow>

            <mrow>
              <mi>i</mi>

              <mo>-</mo>

              <mi>0.4</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </mrow>
      </math>
    </equation>

    <para>where i is the rank of the gauged flood (in descending order) and n
    is the number of years of record.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_gzz1z">
    <title>Fitting Peak-Over-Thresholds  Models</title>

    <para>In some cases, it may be desirable to analytically fit a probability
    distribution to POT data. Two general approaches have been used.</para>

    <para>In the first<?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151022T172810+1100"?>
      approach<?oxy_insert_end?>, the annual flow series distribution has been estimated from the
      POT series on the basis that the latter considers all of the relevant data and should thus
      provide a better estimate. The basis for the procedure is <xref linkend="b3_ch2_e_dds1u"
      /><?oxy_insert_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151022T172912+1100"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
      which links Poisson arrivals of flood peaks with a distribution of flood magnitudes above some
      threshold. <citation>b3_c2_r39+1</citation>, <citation>b3_c2_r7+1</citation> and
        <citation>b3_c2_r72+1</citation> explored this approach using the exponential distribution.
      The approach has been fairly successful, but some results have diverged from the distribution
      derived directly from the annual series. Given the concern that the fit to the right tail of
      the annual maximum series may be compromised by the leverage exerted by the low flows, this
      approach cannot be recommended as a replacement for the analysis of annual series data. If
      possible, the base discharge for this approach should be selected so that the number of floods
      in the POT series <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> is at least 2 to 3 times the number of
      years of record <emphasis role="italic">n</emphasis>. However, it may be necessary to use a
      much lower value of <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> in regions with low rainfall where
      the number of recorded events that could be considered as floods is low.</para>

    <para>The second approach uses a probability distribution as an arbitrary means of providing a
      consistent and objective fit to POT series data. For example,
      <citation>b3_c2_r51+1</citation>, <citation>b3_c2_r2+1</citation> and
        <citation>b3_c2_r39+1</citation> used the LP III distribution – they found that selecting a
      threshold discharge such that <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> equalled <emphasis
        role="italic">n</emphasis> was best.<xref linkend="b3_ch2_s_01343"/> illustrates this
      approach using L-moments to fit an exponential distribution to a POT series.</para>
  </section>
</section>
