<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b3_ch2_s2"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Conceptual Framework</title>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_8ez98">
    <title>Definition of Flood Probability Model</title>

    <para>In flood frequency analysis flood peaks are considered to be random
    variables. Following convention the random variable denoting the flood
    peak discharge is denoted by an upper-case symbol (e.g. Q) whereas a
    specific realisation (or sample) is denoted by the lower-case symbol (e.g.
    q) – where there is no ambiguity lower-case symbols will be used.</para>

    <para>It is assumed that each realisation q is statistically independent
    of other realisations. This is the standard assumption in flood frequency
    analysis and is believed to be widely applicable (e.g. Stedinger
    <emphasis>et al</emphasis>. 1993).</para>

    <para>In its most general form, the flood probability model can be
    described by its Probability Density Function (pdf) <inlineequation>
        <m:math display="inline">
          <m:mi>p(q| θ(x))</m:mi>
        </m:math>
      </inlineequation> where <inlineequation>
        <m:math display="inline">
          <m:mi>θ(x)</m:mi>
        </m:math>
      </inlineequation> is the vector (or list) of parameters dependent on x,
    a vector of exogenous or external variables such as climate indices. The
    symbol ‘|’ is interpreted as follows: the variable to the left of ‘|’ is a
    random variable, while the variables to the right of ‘|’ are known
    values.</para>

    <para>The distribution function of Q is defined as the non-exceedance
    probability <inlineequation>
        <m:math display="inline">
          <m:mi>P(Q≤q)</m:mi>
        </m:math>
      </inlineequation> and is related to the pdf by:</para>

    <equation xml:id="b3_ch2_e_lbfua">
      <m:math display="block">
        <m:semantics>
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mi>P</m:mi>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mo>(</m:mo>

              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mo>≤</m:mo>

                <m:mi>q</m:mi>

                <m:mo>|</m:mo>

                <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>

              <m:mo>)</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mstyle displaystyle="true">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msubsup>
                  <m:mo>∫</m:mo>

                  <m:mn>0</m:mn>

                  <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                </m:msubsup>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mi>s</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>|</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>θ</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                        <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>s</m:mi>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:mstyle>
          </m:mrow>

          <m:annotation
          encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=faaagCart1ev2aaaKnaaaaWenf2ys9wBH5garuavP1wzZbqedmvETj2BSbqefm0B1jxALjharqqtubsr4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8FesqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=xfr=xb9Gqpi0dc9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamiuamaabmaabaGaamyuaiabgsMiJkaadghacaGG8bGaeqiUde3aaeWaaeaacaWG4baacaGLOaGaayzkaaaacaGLOaGaayzkaaGaeyypa0Zaa8qmaeaacaWGWbWaaeWaaeaacaWGZbGaaiiFaiabeI7aXnaabmaabaGaamiEaaGaayjkaiaawMcaaaGaayjkaiaawMcaaiaadsgacaWGZbaaleaacaaIWaaabaGaamyCaaqdcqGHRiI8aaaa@48A6@</m:annotation>
        </m:semantics>
      </m:math>
    </equation>

    <para>Empirically the pdf of q is the limiting form of the histogram of q
    as the number of samples approaches infinity. Importantly, <xref
    linkend="b3_ch2_e_lbfua"/> shows that the area under the pdf is
    interpreted as probability.</para>

    <para>Homogeneous flood probability model</para>

    <para>The simplest form of the flood probability model arises when the
    parameters <inlineequation>
        <m:math display="inline">
          <m:mi>θ</m:mi>
        </m:math>
      </inlineequation> does not depend on an exogenous vector x. In that case
    each flood peak is considered to be a random realisation from the same
    probability model <inlineequation>
        <m:math display="inline">
          <m:mi>p (q | θ)</m:mi>
        </m:math>
      </inlineequation>. Under this assumption flood peaks form a homogeneous
    time series.</para>

    <para>Non-homogeneous flood probability model</para>

    <para>A more complicated situation arises when flood peaks do not form a
    homogeneous time series. This may arise for a number of reasons including
    the following:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Rainfall and flood mechanisms may be changing over time. For
        example, long-term climate change due to global warming, land use
        change and river regulation may render the flood record
        non-homogeneous.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Climate may experience pseudo-periodic shifts that persist over
        periods lasting from several years to several decades. There is
        growing evidence that parts of Australia are subject to such forcing
        and that this significantly affects flood risk (for example, Franks
        and Kuczera, 2002; Franks, 2002a,b; Kiem <emphasis>et al</emphasis>.,
        2003; Micevski <emphasis>et al</emphasis>., 2003)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The user needs to assess the significance of such factors and
    identify appropriate exogenous variables x to condition the flood
    probability model. Although this chapter will provide some guidance it is
    stressed that this is an area of continuing research – users are therefore
    advised to keep abreast of new developments.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_gt55y">
    <title>Annual Maximum and Peak-Over-Threshold Perspectives</title>

    <para>Flood frequency analysis deals with the probability distribution of
    significant flood peaks. Throughout the year, there are typically many
    flood peaks associated with individual storm events. This is illustrated
    in <xref linkend="b3_ch2_f_fig1"/> which illustrates a time series record
    of continuous streamflow discharge. Two types of flood data can be
    extracted from such a record. In turn two measures of flood risk can be
    estimated:</para>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_msqcx">
      <title>Annual Maximum (AM) Series</title>

      <para>The AM series is formed by extracting the maximum discharge in
      each year. This yields the series
      {w<subscript>1</subscript>,..,w<subscript>n</subscript>} where
      w<subscript>i</subscript> is the maximum discharge in the
      i<superscript>th</superscript> year of the n-year record.</para>

      <para>The data in the AM series can be used to estimate the probability
      that the maximum flood discharge in a year exceeds a particular
      magnitude w. In ARR this probability is called the Annual Exceedance
      Probability AEP(w) and is formally defined as:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch2_e_nfd16">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>AEP(w)</m:mi>

              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

              <m:mi>P(W&gt;w∣θ(x))</m:mi>
            </m:mrow>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:munderover>
                <m:mo>∫</m:mo>

                <m:mi>q</m:mi>

                <m:mi>∞</m:mi>
              </m:munderover>

              <m:mi>p(s∣θ(x))ds</m:mi>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where w is the maximum flood discharge in a year. Often it is
      convenient to express the AEP as a percentage X% or alternatively for
      rare events as a ratio 1 in Y. For example, the 1% AEP is equivalent to
      an AEP of 1 in 100 or 0.01.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_0sy4a">
      <title>Peak-Over-Threshold (POT) series</title>

      <para>The POT series is formed by extracting from the record every
      statistically independent peak discharge (that exceeds a threshold
      discharge). This yields the series
      {q<subscript>1</subscript>,..,q<subscript>m</subscript>} where
      q<subscript>i</subscript> is the peak discharge associated with the
      i<superscript>th</superscript> statistically independent flood event in
      the n-year record. Typically the threshold discharge is selected so that
      m is about 2 to 3 times greater than n.</para>

      <para>The data in the POT series can be used to estimate the probability
      distribution of the time to the next peak discharge that exceeds a
      particular magnitude:</para>

      <equation xml:id="b3_ch2_e_0qvta">
        <m:math display="block">
          <m:mrow>
            <m:mtext>P (Time to next exceeding q≤ t)</m:mtext>

            <m:mo>=</m:mo>

            <m:mrow>
              <m:mi>1</m:mi>

              <m:mo>-</m:mo>

              <m:msup>
                <m:mi>e</m:mi>

                <m:mi>-EY(q)t</m:mi>
              </m:msup>
            </m:mrow>
          </m:mrow>
        </m:math>
      </equation>

      <para>where t is time expressed in years and EY(q), the number of
      exceedances per year, is the expected number of times in a year that the
      peak discharge exceeds q.<figure xml:id="b3_ch2_f_fig1">
          <title>Peak-Over-Threshold series</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figures/Figure1.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure></para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_u56ub">
      <title>When to use AM and POT Series</title>

      <para>The risk measures AEP and Exceedances per Year (EY) are intimately
      connected. The analysis presented in <xref linkend="b3_ch2_s_k55h9"/>
      shows that:</para>

      <para><equation>
          <m:math display="inline">
            <m:mtable>
              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>EY(w)</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>-log</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>e</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mtext>[1-AEP(w)]</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>

              <m:mtr>
                <m:mtd>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi/>

                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>-log</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>e</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>[</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>1-</m:mi>

                            <m:mfrac>
                              <m:mi>1</m:mi>

                              <m:mi>Y(w)</m:mi>
                            </m:mfrac>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>

                        <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mtd>
              </m:mtr>
            </m:mtable>
          </m:math>
        </equation></para>

      <para>where AEP(w) is expressed as the ratio 1 in Y(w). This
      relationship is plotted in <xref linkend="b3_ch2_f_qs0z6"/>. For AEPs
      less than 10% ( 0.1 or 1 in 10), EY and AEP are numerically the same
      from a practical perspective. However, as the AEP increases beyond 10%
      (0.1), EY increases more rapidly than AEP. This occurs because in years
      with a large annual maximum peak, the smaller peaks of that year may
      exceed the annual maximum peak in other years.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b3_ch2_f_qs0z6">
        <title>AEP-EY relationship</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figures/Figure2.JPG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The question arises when should one use AM or POT approaches.
      Consistent with the guideance provided in Book 1 of ARR, the following
      guideline is offered:</para>

      <para>(i) AEP of interest ≤ 10%</para>

      <para>AEPs in this range are generally required for estimation of a
      design flood for a structure or works at a particular site. Use of AM
      series is generally preferred because it yields virtually identical
      answers to POT series in most cases, provides a more robust<footnote>
          <para>In a POT series there are typically 2 to 3 times more peaks
          than in the corresponding AM series. The additional peaks are
          largely smaller peaks. In the case when the data is not well fitted
          by the chosen probability model, the fit to the upper part of the
          distribution may be compromised in order to obtain a good fit to the
          smaller peaks where the bulk of the data lies.</para>

          <para>Use of POT series is generally preferred because all floods
          are of interest in this range, whether they are the highest in the
          particular year of record or not. The AM series may omit many floods
          of interest. The POT series is appropriate for estimating design
          floods with a relatively high EY in urban stormwater contexts and
          for diversion works, coffer dams and other temporary structures.
          However, in practice, flow records are not often available at sites
          where minor works with a design EY greater than 0.2 EY is
          required.</para>
        </footnote> estimate of low AEP floods and is easier to extract and
      define.</para>

      <para>(ii) EY of interest ≥ 0.2 Events per Year</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_dh3wa">
    <title>Advantages and Disadvantages of Flood Frequency Analysis</title>

    <para>Users need to be aware of the advantages and disadvantages of Flood
    Frequency Analysis.</para>

    <para>Flood peaks are the product of a complex joint probability process
    involving the interaction of many random variables associated with the
    rainfall event, antecedent conditions and rainfall-runoff transformation.
    Peak flood records represent the integrated response of the storm event
    with the catchment. They provide a direct measure of flood exceedance
    probabilities. As a result Flood Frequency Analysis is not subject to the
    potential for bias, possibly large, that can affect alternative methods
    based on design rainfall (Kuczera <emphasis>et al</emphasis>.,
    2006).</para>

    <para>Other advantages of Flood Frequency Analysis include its comparative
    simplicity and capacity to quantify uncertainty arising from limited
    information.</para>

    <para>Offsetting these significant advantages are several
    disadvantages:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The true probability distribution family is unknown.
        Unfortunately, different models can fit the flood data with similar
        capability, yet can diverge in the right hand tail when extrapolated
        beyond the data.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Short records may compromise the utility of flood estimates.
        Confidence limits inform the user about the credibility of the
        estimate.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>It may be difficult or impossible to adjust the data if the
        catchment conditions under which the flood data were obtained have
        changed during the period of record, or are different to those
        applying to the future economic life of a structure or works being
        designed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Considerable extrapolation of rating curves is necessary to convert
    recorded stage to discharge for the largest flood peaks at most Australian
    gauging stations. Also the probability of the malfunction of recording
    instruments is increased during major floods. Suspect floods and the years
    in which they occurred may be omitted in analysis of Annual Maximum
    series, but this reduces the sample size and may introduce bias if the
    suspect floods are all major events. These problems are inherent to the
    calibration of all methods employing major flood peaks. At this stage it
    is not clear whether Flood Frequency Analysis is more sensitive to such
    problems than other methods.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b3_ch2_s_fw1lx">
    <title>Range of Application</title>

    <para>As noted the true flood probability family is unknown. In practice
    the choice of model is guided by goodness of fit to the observed data.
    Therefore, use of the fitted frequency curve for AEPs reflected in the
    data is regarded as an interpolation exercise deemed to be reliable in the
    sense that confidence limits capture the uncertainty. However, when the
    frequency curve is extrapolated well beyond the observed data, confidence
    limits which quantify the effect of sampling variability on parameter
    uncertainty may underestimate the true uncertainty - model bias may be
    significant and even dominant. Example 1 demonstrates the need to
    understand the processes affecting flood peaks beyond the observed record
    and illustrates the pitfall of blind extrapolation.</para>

    <para>Large extrapolation of a flood frequency curve is not recommended.
    It is acknowledged that prescribing strict limits on the minimum AEP does
    not have a strong conceptual foundation. The limits to extrapolation
    should be guided by consideration of confidence limits, which are affected
    by the information content of the data and choice of flood model, and by
    judgments about model bias which cannot be quantified. In situations where
    the analyst is prepared to make the judgment that the processes operating
    in the range of the observed record continue to operate for larger floods,
    model bias may be deemed to be manageable – of course the effects of
    sampling uncertainty may be so amplified under significant extrapolation
    to render the frequency estimate of little value.</para>

    <para>In the absence of user analysis about the degree of model bias when
    extrapolating, the following guidelines are offered to promote consistency
    with previous practice: As discussed further in ARR 1987 Book 8 Section
    1.2, the 1% (1 in 100) AEP flood is the largest event that should be
    estimated by direct frequency analysis for important work. The maximum
    flood that should be estimated by this means under any circumstances is
    the 0.2% (1 in 500) AEP event. Where a regional flood frequency method is
    used, the limiting AEP should be the 1% AEP. ARR 1987 Book 8 Section 1
    describes procedures for estimating floods beyond the probabilities noted
    above. These procedures interpolate flood magnitudes between the 1% AEP
    event and the Probable Maximum Flood. While these procedures involve some
    arbitrary assumptions, they provide a consistent approach and overcome
    many of the problems involved in extrapolation of Flood Frequency Analysis
    arising from the choice of probability model and estimation method.</para>
  </section>
</section>
