<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xml:id="b3_ch2-4" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Choice of Flood Probability Model</title>
    
    <section>
        <title>General</title>
        
        <para>As noted in Section <emphasis role="bold"> linkend="WPGeneratedID_Xref_ConceptualFrameworkSection_1"</emphasis> of this
            Chapter, it is assumed that each flood peak in an annual or POT series
            is statistically independent of other flood peaks in the series. In
            addition the flood probability model, described by its probability
            density function (pdf) p(q | θ, x, M), must be specified.</para>
        
        <para>There is no universally accepted flood probability model. Many
            types of probability distributions have been applied to flood frequency
            analysis. Unfortunately, it is not possible to determine the true or
            correct form of distribution (see, for example, Cunnane, 1985), and
            there is no rigorous analytical proof that any particular probability
            distribution for floods is the correct theoretical distribution. The
            appropriateness of these distributions can be tested by examining the
            fit of each distribution to observed flood data. Various empirical tests
            of different distributions have been carried out with recorded data from
            many catchments but conclusive evidence is not possible as a result of
            the wide range of samples that can be realised from a given population.
            Examples of sampling experiments illustrating this problem are given by
            Alexander (1957) and Benson in Dalrymple (1960). The choice of flood
            probability model is further exacerbated by recent evidence that in
            certain parts of Australia the flood record is not homogeneous due to
            variations in long-term climate controls.</para>
        
        <para>Given these considerations it is considered inappropriate to be
            prescriptive with regard to choice of flood probability model. As a
            general rule the selected probability distribution family M should be
            consistent with available data. It is recognized that more than one
            probability distribution family may be consistent with the data. One
            approach to deal with this problem is to select the distribution family
            on the basis of best overall fit to a range of catchments within a
            region or landscape space. One approach for assessing overall goodness
            of fit is based on the use of L moment diagrams (see Stedinger <emphasis
                role="italic">et al</emphasis>., 1993 and, in particular, Section 18.3.3
            of that publication for more details).</para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Choice of Distribution Family for Annual Series</title>
        
        <section>
            <title>General</title>
            
            <para>Two distribution families are suggested as reasonable initial
                choices, namely:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>generalized extreme value (GEV); and</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>log Pearson III (LP3) families.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>These families have been shown to fit most flood data
                adequately. Nonetheless the user is reminded that there is no rigorous
                justification for these families, which is particularly important when
                extrapolating. Demonstrated in Example <emphasis role="bold">
                    linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_35">1</emphasis> is the importance of
                understanding the mechanisms controlling flood response.</para>
            
            <para>The following sections describe the GEV and LP3 distributions
                and also some other distributions which may be more appropriate in
                certain circumstances.</para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Generalized Extreme Value (GEV) Distribution</title>
            
            <para>Listed in Table 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">
                linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_17">1</emphasis> are the pdf p(q | θ),
                distribution function P( Q ≤ q | θ) and product moments for the
                generalized extreme value (GEV) distribution. It has three parameters
                which are:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>τ - the location parameter;</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>α - the scale parameter; and</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>κ - the shape parameter.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>When the shape parameter κ equals 0, the GEV simplifies to the
                Gumbel distribution whose details are provided in Table 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_17">1</emphasis> also. For positive values of
                κ there exists an upper bound, while for negative values of κ there
                exists a lower bound.</para>
            
            <para>Of the widely used distribution families, the GEV distribution
                has the strongest theoretical appeal because it is the asymptotic
                distribution of extreme values for a wide range of underlying parent
                distributions. In a flood frequency context, suppose there are N flood
                peaks in a year. Provided N is large and the flood peaks are
                identically and independently distributed, the distribution of the
                largest peak flow in the year approaches the GEV under quite general
                conditions. Unfortunately, hydrologic reality does not always fit
                comfortably with these assumptions. First, the number of independent
                flood peaks in any year may not be sufficient to ensure asymptotic
                behaviour. Second, it remains unclear whether the within-year
                independent flood peaks are random realizations from the same
                probability distribution.</para>
            
            <para>The GEV has gained widespread acceptance (for example, Natural
                Environment Research Council, 1975; Wallis and Wood, 1985; Handbook of
                Hydrology, Stedinger <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>.,
                1993)</para>
            
            <para>Table 1.1.1 - - Selected homogeneous probability models families
                for use in flood frequency analysis</para>
            
            <para>&lt;Table&gt;</para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Log Pearson III (LP3) Distribution</title>
            
            <para>Listed in Table 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">
                linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_17">1</emphasis> are the pdf p(q | θ) and
                product moments for log Pearson III (LP3) distribution. The LP3
                distribution has three parameters:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>τ - the scale parameter; and</para>
                </listitem>
                
                <listitem>
                    <para>α and β - the shape parameters.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>When the skew of log q is zero, the distribution simplifies to
                the log normal whose details are provided in Table 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">
                    linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_17">1</emphasis>.</para>
            
            <para>The LP3 distribution has been widely accepted in practice
                because it consistently fits flood data as well if not better than
                other probability families. It has performed best of those that have
                been tested on data for Australian catchments (Conway, 1970; Kopittke
                <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>., 1976; McMahon, 1979; and
                McMahon and Srikanthan, 1981). Furthermore, it is the recommended
                distribution for the United States in Bulletin 17B of the Interagency
                Advisory Committee on Water Data (1982).</para>
            
            <para>The distribution, however, is not well-behaved from an inference
                perspective. Direct inference of the parameters α, β and τ can cause
                numerical problems. For example, when the skew of log q is close to
                zero, the shape parameter α tends to infinity. Experience shows that
                the parameters can be estimated reasonably using the first three
                moments of log(q). Note that τ is a lower bound for positive skew and
                an upper bound for negative skew.</para>
            
            <para>A problem arises when the absolute value of the skew of log q
                exceeds 2; that is, when α &lt; 1. When α &gt; 1, log q has a
                gamma-shaped density. When α ≤ 1, the density of log q changes to a
                J-shaped function. Indeed when α = 1, the pdf of log q degenerates to
                that of an exponential distribution with scale parameter β and
                location parameter τ. For α ≤ 1, the J-shaped density seems to be
                over-parameterized with three parameters. In such circumstances, it is
                pointless to use the LP3. It is suggested either the GEV or the
                generalized Pareto distributions be used as a substitute.</para>
            
            <para>An analytical form of the distribution function is not available
                for the LP3 and log-normal distributions. To compute the quantile
                q<subscript>Y</subscript> (that is, the discharge with a 1 in Y AEP)
                the following equation may be used:</para>
            
            <equation>
                <m:math display="block">
                    <m:mi/>
                    
                    <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>log q</m:mi>
                        
                        <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                    </m:msub>
                    
                    <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                    
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                            <m:mi>m + K</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>(g)s</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <para>where m, s and g are the mean, standard deviation and skewness
                of the log discharge and K<subscript>Y</subscript> is a frequency
                factor well-approximated by the Wilson-Hilferty transformation</para>

            <equation>
                <m:math display="block">
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                                <m:mi/>
                                
                                <m:mi>y</m:mi>
                            </m:msub>
                            
                            <m:mi>(g)</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                    
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>{</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mtable>
                                    <m:mtr>
                                        <m:mtd>
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mfrac>
                                                            <m:mi>2</m:mi>
                                                            
                                                            <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                                                        </m:mfrac>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:mo>[</m:mo>
                                                            
                                                            <m:mrow>
                                                                <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                                                
                                                                <m:mrow>
                                                                    <m:mfrac>
                                                                        <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                                                                        
                                                                        <m:mi>6</m:mi>
                                                                    </m:mfrac>
                                                                    
                                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                                            <m:mrow>
                                                                                <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                                                                
                                                                                <m:mrow>
                                                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                                                            <m:msub>
                                                                                                <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                                                                                                
                                                                                                <m:mi>Y</m:mi>
                                                                                            </m:msub>
                                                                                            
                                                                                            <m:mo>-</m:mo>
                                                                                            
                                                                                            <m:mrow>
                                                                                                <m:mfrac>
                                                                                                    <m:mi>g</m:mi>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    <m:mi>6</m:mi>
                                                                                                </m:mfrac>
                                                                                            </m:mrow>
                                                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                                                        
                                                                                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                                                    
                                                                                    <m:msup>
                                                                                        <m:mi>+ 1</m:mi>
                                                                                        
                                                                                        <m:mi/>
                                                                                    </m:msup>
                                                                                </m:mrow>
                                                                                
                                                                                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                                            </m:mrow>
                                                                            
                                                                            <m:mrow>
                                                                                <m:msup>
                                                                                    <m:mi/>
                                                                                    
                                                                                    <m:mi>3</m:mi>
                                                                                </m:msup>
                                                                                
                                                                                <m:mo>- 1</m:mo>
                                                                            </m:mrow>
                                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                                </m:mrow>
                                                            </m:mrow>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                                
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mi/>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mi>if | g | &gt; 0</m:mi>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mtd>
                                    </m:mtr>
                                    
                                    <m:mtr>
                                        <m:mtd>
                                            <m:mi>0 if g = 0</m:mi>
                                        </m:mtd>
                                    </m:mtr>
                                </m:mtable>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                    
                    <m:mi/>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <para>for |g| &lt; 2 and AEPs ranging from 0.99 to 0.01. The term
                z<subscript>Y</subscript> is the frequency factor for the standard
                normal distribution which has a mean of zero and standard deviation of
                1. In other words, z<subscript>Y</subscript> is the value of the
                standard normal deviate with exceedance probability 1/Y. Listed in
                Table 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_18">2</emphasis> are the
                values of z<subscript>Y</subscript> for selected exceedance
                probabilities. Comprehensive tables of KY can be found in Pilgrim
                (1987, p.208).</para>

            <table>
                <title>Frequency factors for standard normal distribution</title>
                
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">Y in AEP of 1 in Y</entry>
                            
                            <entry align="center">z<subscript>Y</subscript></entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>2</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>5</entry>
                            
                            <entry>0.8416</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>10</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.2816</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>20</entry>
                            
                            <entry>1.6449</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>50</entry>
                            
                            <entry>2.0537</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>100</entry>
                            
                            <entry>2.3263</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>200</entry>
                            
                            <entry>2.5758</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>500</entry>
                            
                            <entry>2.8782</entry>
                        </row>
                        
                        <row>
                            <entry>1000</entry>
                            
                            <entry>3.0902</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Generalized Pareto Distribution</title>
            
            <para>In POT modelling the generalized Pareto (GP) distribution is
                often found to satisfactorily fit the data. Listed in Table 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">
                    linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_17">1</emphasis> lists the pdf p ( q | θ),
                distribution function P ( Q ≤ q | θ) and product moments for the GP
                distribution. This distribution has three parameters:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>q<subscript>*</subscript> - the location parameter;</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>β - the scale parameter; and</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>κ - the shape parameter.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>When κ equals zero, the distribution simplifies to the
                exponential distribution which is summarized in Table 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">
                    linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_17">1</emphasis>.</para>
            
            <para>The GP distribution has an intimate relationship with the GEV.
                If the GP describes the distribution of peaks over a threshold, then
                for Poisson arrivals of the peaks with ν being the average number of
                arrivals per year, it can be shown that the distribution of annual
                maximum peaks is GEV with shape parameter ,κ scale parameter αβν-κ and
                location parameter</para>
            
            <equation>
                <m:mi>τ</m:mi>
                
                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                
                <m:mrow><m:msub><m:mi>q</m:mi><m:mi>*</m:mi></m:msub><m:mrow><m:mi>+</m:mi><m:mrow><m:mfrac><m:mi>β</m:mi><m:mi>κ</m:mi></m:mfrac></m:mrow></m:mrow></m:mrow>
            </equation>
            
            <para>(see Stedinger <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>., 1993,
                p18.39 for more details). Likewise when peaks over a threshold follow
                an exponential distribution then for the Poisson arrival the
                distribution of annual maxima follows a Gumbel distribution.</para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Threshold Mixture Model</title>
            
            <para>In certain parts of Australia annual maximum flood series may
                contain one or more years of zero or negligible flow. This causes a
                lumpiness in the flood probability model which is best handled by
                generalizing the pdf to the threshold mixture form</para>
            
            <para/>
            
            <equation>
                <title/>
                
                <m:math display="block">
                    <m:mi>p( q |</m:mi>
                    
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>θ, M )</m:mi>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>= P</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                    
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                    
                                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                </m:mrow>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mi>δ</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                            
                                            <m:msub>
                                                <m:mi>q - q</m:mi>
                                                
                                                <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                            </m:msub>
                                            
                                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                        
                                        <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                                        
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mo>[</m:mo>
                                                
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mi>1 -</m:mi>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:mrow>
                                                                <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                                                
                                                                <m:msub>
                                                                    <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                                                                    
                                                                    <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                                </m:msub>
                                                                
                                                                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                            </m:mrow>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                                
                                                <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                            
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mi>p( q | q &gt;</m:mi>
                                                
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:msub>
                                                        <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                    </m:msub>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mi>, θ</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:mi>M )</m:mi>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                    
                    <m:mi/>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <equation>
                <m:math display="block">
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                            
                                            <m:msub>
                                                <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                                                
                                                <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                            </m:msub>
                                            
                                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                        
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mi>δ</m:mi>
                                            
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                                    
                                                    <m:msub>
                                                        <m:mi>q - q</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                    </m:msub>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                                
                                                <m:mo>+</m:mo>
                                                
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mo>[</m:mo>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:mi>1 -</m:mi>
                                                            
                                                            <m:mrow>
                                                                <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                                                                
                                                                <m:mrow>
                                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                                        <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                                                        
                                                                        <m:msub>
                                                                            <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                                                                            
                                                                            <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                                        </m:msub>
                                                                        
                                                                        <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                                </m:mrow>
                                                            </m:mrow>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mfrac>
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mi>p( q |</m:mi>
                                                
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mi>θ,</m:mi>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mi>M ) I</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:mrow>
                                                                <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                                                
                                                                <m:msub>
                                                                    <m:mi>q, q</m:mi>
                                                                    
                                                                    <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                                </m:msub>
                                                                
                                                                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                            </m:mrow>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                            
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                                                
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:msub>
                                                                <m:mi>q &gt; q</m:mi>
                                                                
                                                                <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                            </m:msub>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mo>|</m:mo>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:mi>θ, M</m:mi>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mfrac>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <para>where P(q<subscript>*</subscript>) is the probability of a flow
                less than or equal to q<subscript>*</subscript>, the threshold value
                and p( q | q &gt; q<subscript>*</subscript>, θ, M) is the conditional
                pdf of a flood peak exceeding the threshold
                q<subscript>*</subscript></para>
            
            <para>The mixture model is interpreted as follows:</para>
            
            <para>There is a probability P(q<subscript>*</subscript>) of the
                annual maximum flow being less than or equal to the threshold
                q<subscript>*</subscript> in any year. If the annual maximum flood
                exceeds the threshold its value is randomly sampled from the
                conditional pdf p(q | q &gt; q<subscript>*</subscript>, θ, M).</para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Multi-component or Mixture Models</title>
            
            <para>In some areas, flooding may be affected by different types of
                meteorological events (for example, intense tropical cyclones and
                storms characterized by more usual synoptic conditions) or by changing
                hydraulic controls (e.g., see Example <emphasis role="bold">
                    linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_35">1</emphasis>), causing abnormal slope
                changes in the frequency curve. In such cases the GEV or LP3 families
                may not adequately fit the data. This type of problem may be of
                particular importance in northern Australia, and an example is
                described by Ashkanasy and Weeks (1975).</para>
            
            <para>Where components affecting flooding have distinctly different
                distributions one can separate the data by cause and analyse each set
                separately using simple distributions. Ashkanasy and Weeks (1975) used
                a combination of two log Normal distributions. Waylen and Woo (1982)
                considered separately summer runoff and winter snowmelt floods. They
                showed that separation of the flood record into separate series can
                result in a better estimate of the probability of extreme events
                because the data that describes phenomena that produce those large
                events is better represented in the analysis.</para>
            
            <para>A two-component extreme value (TCEV) distribution has been
                described by Rossi <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>. (1984)
                and Fiorentino <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>. (1985), and
                developed and applied to U.K. data by Beran <emphasis role="italic">et
                    al</emphasis>. (1986). It corresponds to the maximum of two
                independent Gumbel distributions. Generally, one of the two
                distributions is thought of as describing the bulk of the data, and
                the other as the outlier distribution. Because the TCEV has four
                parameters, it is very flexible (Beran <emphasis role="italic">et
                    al</emphasis>., 1986). However, if only annual maximum series are
                available, regional estimation methods must be used to help estimate
                the parameters.</para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Non-Homogeneous Models</title>
            
            <para>If the evidence suggests that flood risk is affected by
                multi-decadal climate persistence, the use of non-homogeneous
                probability models may need to be investigated. The concern is that
                ignoring the non-homogeneity of the flood record may lead to biased
                estimates of long-term flood risk.</para>
            
            <para>If a non-homogeneous probability model with pdf p(q | θ, x, M)
                is identified this cannot be used to estimate long-term or marginal
                flood risk. This is because the flood risk is dependent on the
                exogenous climate-related variables x. To estimate long-term flood
                risk the dependence on x must be removed using total probability to
                give</para>
            
            <equation>
                <title/>
                
                <m:math display="block">
                    <m:mi/>
                    
                    <m:mi>P( Q</m:mi>
                    
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>≤</m:mo>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>| θ, M )</m:mi>
                                
                                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:munderover>
                                            <m:mo>∫</m:mo>
                                            
                                            <m:mi mathvariant="normal">∞</m:mi>
                                            
                                            <m:mi/>
                                        </m:munderover>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                                            
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:munderover>
                                                        <m:mo>∫</m:mo>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                                                    </m:munderover>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mi>p (</m:mi>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                                
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mi>z</m:mi>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mi>| θ</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:mi>, x, M )dz</m:mi>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                            
                                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                        
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:mi>p(x) dx</m:mi>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <para>where p(x) is the pdf of the exogenous variables.</para>
            
            <para>If the gauged record adequately samples the distribution of x,
                it is not necessary to identify a non-homogeneous model. It suffices
                to fit a probability model to all the record to estimate the long-term
                flood risk.</para>
            
            <para>However, if the gauged record does not adequately sample the
                exogenous variable x, significant bias in long-term flood risk may
                result. In such instances, it is possible to:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Use a regional frequency method based on sites with
                        sufficiently long records to fully sample x; or</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Extend the flood record using nearby sites which have more
                        fully sampled the exogenous variable x.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>Example <emphasis role="bold">linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_49">6</emphasis>
                illustrates the impact on flood risk arising from multi-decadal
                persistence in climate state as represented by the IPO index. It
                demonstrates the serious bias in flood risk that can arise if short
                records do not adequately sample different climate states. It also
                demonstrates use of equation 1.1.<emphasis role="bold">
                    linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_20">14</emphasis>.</para>
            
            <para>In the future, it is expected regional frequency methods
                explicitly dealing with non-homogeneity will be developed. This will
                allow combining regional and site information (see Example <emphasis role="bold">
                    linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_44">4</emphasis>) to yield the most accurate
                frequency analysis.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Choice of Distribution for POT Series</title>
        
        <para>In some cases, it may be desirable to analytically fit a
            probability distribution to POT data. Distributions that have been used
            to describe the flood peak above a threshold include exponential, GP and
            LP3.</para>
    </section>
</section>


