<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xml:id="b3_ch2-8" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>WORKED EXAMPLES</title>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>EXAMPLE 1: EXTRAPOLATION AND PROCESS UNDERSTANDING</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>The importance of process understanding when extrapolating beyond
        the observed record is illustrated by a simple Monte Carlo experiment. A
        Poisson rectangular pulse rainfall model is used to generate a long record
        of high resolution rainfall. This rainfall record is routed through a
        rainfall-runoff model to generate runoff into the stream system. The
        storage-discharge relationship for the stream is depicted by the bilinear
        relationship shown in Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_36">8</link>. A feature of this relationship
        is the activation of significant flood terrace storage once a threshold
        discharge is exceeded.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Bilinear Channel Storage-Discharge Relationship</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_8.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>The routing model parameters were selected so that major flood
        terrace storage is activated by floods with an ARI in excess of 100 years.
        This situation was chosen to represent a river with multiple flood
        terraces with the lowest terraces accommodating the majority of floods and
        the highest terrace only inundated by extreme floods.</para>
    
    <para>Presented in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_37">9</link> is the flood frequency curve
        based on 30,000 simulated years. As shown in this figure, there is a clear
        break in slope around the 100 year ARI corresponding to the activation of
        major flood terrace storage. Indeed the flood frequency curve displays
        downward curvature despite that the fact the rainfall frequency curve
        displays upward curvature in the 100 to 1000 year ARI range. In contrast
        the flood frequency curve based on 100 years of “data” has no evidence of
        downward curvature. This result is because in a 100-year record there is
        little chance of the major flood terrace storage being activated. Indeed
        without knowledge of the underlying hydraulics, an analyst would be
        tempted to extrapolate the 100-year flood record using a straight line
        extrapolation. Such an extrapolation would rapidly diverge from the “true”
        frequency curve.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Simulated Rainfall and Flood Frequency Curves with Major
            Floodplain Storage Activated at a Threshold Discharge of
            3500m3/s</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_9.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>Although the dominant rainfall-runoff dynamics are idealised in this
        example, a very strong message is obtained from interpretation of the
        results. Extrapolation of flood frequency curves fitted to gauged flow
        records requires the exercise of hydrologic judgment backed up by
        appropriate modelling. Furthermore, the problem of extrapolation is more
        general. For example, in this example, if a rainfall-runoff catchment
        modelling approach were used with the catchment model calibrated only to
        small events (ie events less than 100 year ARI), the simulated data used
        for development of the flood frequency curve are likely to be compromised
        in a similar way.</para>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>EXAMPLE <anchor id="WPGeneratedID_Xref_FFAEx2_1"/>2: FITTING A
                PROBABILITY MODEL TO GAUGED DATA</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>Illustrated in this example is the fitting of a probability model to
        gauged annual maximum flood data. Listed in Table 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_39">6</link> are 31 years of gauged annual
        maximum discharges (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s) for the Hunter river
        at Singleton.</para>
    
    <table>
        <title>Annual Series for the Hunter River at Singleton</title>
        
        <tgroup cols="8">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>76.19</entry>
                    
                    <entry>171.7</entry>
                    
                    <entry>218.0</entry>
                    
                    <entry>668.2</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1373.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>124.0</entry>
                    
                    <entry>276.0</entry>
                    
                    <entry>894.8</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>1373.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>279.9</entry>
                    
                    <entry>202.4</entry>
                    
                    <entry>4049.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>2321.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>2534.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>3313.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1231.</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>1390.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>12515</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1098.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>447.4</entry>
                    
                    <entry>478.5</entry>
                    
                    <entry>180.3</entry>
                    
                    <entry>164.2</entry>
                    
                    <entry>229.3</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>2123.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>965.5</entry>
                    
                    <entry>2749.</entry>
                    
                    <entry>48.98</entry>
                    
                    <entry>76.45</entry>
                    
                    <entry>911.7</entry>
                    
                    <entry>925.9</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>An LP3 probability distribution was fitted to these data using a
        Bayesian approach. Presented in Table 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_40">7</link> are the posterior mean, standard
        deviation and correlation for the LP3 parameters m, s and g which are
        respectively the mean, standard deviation and skewness of
        log<subscript>e</subscript> q.</para>
    
    <table>
        <title>LP3 Parameters Determined by Bayesian Approach</title>
        
        <tgroup cols="6">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">LP3 Parameter</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Mean</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Std Deviation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Correlation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Correlation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Correlation</entry>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>m</entry>
                    
                    <entry>6.426</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.236</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1.000</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>loge s</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.350</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.127</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.046</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1.000</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>g</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.146</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.643</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.000</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.068</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>Plotted in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_41">10</link> on a log normal probability
        plot are</para>
    
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>the gauged flows;</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>the 1 in Y AEP quantile curve (derived using the posterior mean
                parameters);</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>the 90% quantile confidence limits; and</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>the expected probability curve.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Bayesian LP3 Fit to 31 Years of Gauged Annual Maximum Flow in the
            Hunter River at Singleton</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_10.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>The good fit to the gauged data and the tight confidence limits
        needs to be tempered by the fact that the logarithm of the flood peaks are
        plotted in Figure 1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_41">10</link>.
        The table of selected 1 in Y AEP quantiles q<subscript>Y</subscript> and
        their 90% confidence limits presents a more sobering perspective. For
        example, for the 1 in 100 AEP flood the 5% and 95% confidence limits are
        respectively 38% and 553% of the quantile q<subscript>Y</subscript>! The 1
        in 500 AEP confidence limits are so wide as to render estimation
        meaningless. Note the expected AEP for the quantile
        q<subscript>Y</subscript> consistently exceeds the nominal 1 in Y AEP. For
        example, the 1 in 100 AEP quantile of 19548
        m<superscript>3</superscript>/s has an expected AEP of 1 in 74.</para>
    
    <table>
        <title/>
        
        <tgroup cols="5">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">1 in Y AEP</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile qY</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile Confidence Limits</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Expected AEP for qY</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">5% limit</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">95% limit</entry>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>
                    
                    <entry>3888</entry>
                    
                    <entry>2222</entry>
                    
                    <entry>8287</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/9.9</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>50</entry>
                    
                    <entry>12729</entry>
                    
                    <entry>5537</entry>
                    
                    <entry>52157</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/43</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>100</entry>
                    
                    <entry>19548</entry>
                    
                    <entry>7372</entry>
                    
                    <entry>108144</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/74</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>500</entry>
                    
                    <entry>47366</entry>
                    
                    <entry>11799</entry>
                    
                    <entry>549773</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/210</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><emphasis role="bold">EXAMPLE</emphasis><anchor
                id="WPGeneratedID_Xref_FFAEx3_1"/>3: USE OF CENSORED HISTORICAL
                DATA</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>This example is a continuation of Example <link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_38">2</link>. The benefit of using historical
        flood information Is illustrated. The gauged record spanned the period
        1938 to 1969. The biggest flood in that record occurred in 1955. An
        examination of historic records indicates that during the ungauged period
        1820 to 1937 there was only one flood that exceeded the 1955 flood and
        that this flood occurred in 1820. This information is valuable even though
        the magnitude of the 1820 flood is not reliably known. This is an example
        of censored data. Over the ungauged period 1820 to 1937 there was one
        flood above and 117 floods below the threshold discharge corresponding to
        the 1955 flood.</para>
    
    <para>An LP3 distribution was fitted to gauged and censored data using the
        Bayesian approach. Presented in the table below are the posterior mean,
        standard deviation and correlation for the LP3 parameters: m, s and g
        which are respectively the mean, standard deviation and skewness of
        log<subscript>e</subscript>q. Comparison with Example <link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_38">2</link> reveals that inclusion of the
        censored data has reduced by almost 30% the uncertainty in the skewness g,
        which is the parameter that controls the shape of the distribution,
        particularly in the tail region.</para>
    
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="6">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">LP3 Parameter</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Mean</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Std Deviation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Correlation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Correlation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Correlation</entry>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>m</entry>
                    
                    <entry>6.359</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.226</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1.000</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>loge s</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.304</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.116</entry>
                    
                    <entry>-0.139</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1.000</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>g</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.001</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.458</entry>
                    
                    <entry>-0.261</entry>
                    
                    <entry>-0.487</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1.000</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>Plotted in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_43">11</link> on a log normal probability
        plot are the gauged flows, the 1 in Y AEP quantile curve (derived using
        the posterior mean parameters), the 90% quantile confidence limits and the
        expected probability curve. Compared with Example <link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_38">2</link> the tightening of the confidence
        limits is most noticeable.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Bayesian LP3 fit to 31 Years of Gauged Annual Maximum
            Floods</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_11.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>The table of selected 1 in Y AEP quantiles q<subscript>Y</subscript>
        and their 90% confidence limits illustrates the benefit of the information
        contained in the censored data. For example, for the 1 in 100 AEP flood
        the 5% and 95% confidence limits are respectively 57% and 200% of the
        quantile q<subscript>Y</subscript>! This represents a major reduction in
        quantile uncertainty compared with Example <link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_38">2</link> which yielded limits of 38% and
        553%.</para>
    
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="5">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">1 in Y AEP</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile q<subscript>Y</subscript></entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile Confidence Limits</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Expected AEP for qY</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">5% limit</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">95% limit</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>
                    
                    <entry>3281</entry>
                    
                    <entry>2188</entry>
                    
                    <entry>5006</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/9.6</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>50</entry>
                    
                    <entry>9351</entry>
                    
                    <entry>5786</entry>
                    
                    <entry>16416</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/48</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>100</entry>
                    
                    <entry>13535</entry>
                    
                    <entry>7751</entry>
                    
                    <entry>27100</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/93</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>500</entry>
                    
                    <entry>28615</entry>
                    
                    <entry>12790</entry>
                    
                    <entry>87327</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1/363</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>Highlighted in this example are the significant reductions in
        uncertainty that inclusion of historical data can offer. However, care
        must be exercised ensuring the integrity of the historic information – see
        Section <xref linkend="WPGeneratedID_Xref_HistoriticalDataSect_1"/> of
        this Chapter in Book 1 of Australian Rainfall and Runoff for more
        details.</para>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><emphasis role="bold">EXAMPLE</emphasis><anchor
                id="WPGeneratedID_Xref_FFAEx4_1"/>4: USE OF REGIONAL
                INFORMATION</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>As with the previous example, this example is a continuation of
        Example <link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_38">2</link>. In Example <link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_38">2</link>, the posterior mean of the
        skewness was estimated to be 0.146 with a posterior standard of 0.643. The
        uncertainty in the 1 in 100 AEP quantile was large.</para>
    
    <para>Suppose hypothetically that a regional analysis of skewness was
        conducted. Furthermore, suppose the expected regional skew is 0.00 with a
        standard deviation of 0.35. Following Section <xref
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_Xref_PriorDistSect_1"/> of this Chapter in Book 1
        of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, this information can be approximated as
        a normally distributed prior distribution for the skewness. A probability
        plot for the LP3 model fitted to the gauged data with prior information on
        the skewness is shown in Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_45">12</link>. Comparison with Figure
        1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_41">10</link> reveals substantially
        improved accuracy in the right hand tail.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Bayesian LP3 Fit to 31 Years of Gauged Annual Maximum Floods with
            Prior Information on Skewness</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_12.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>A comparison of the LP3 distribution fitted with and without prior
        information on skewness is shown in the table below. The posterior
        uncertainty on the skewness is about 88% of the prior standard deviation
        indicating the gauged data are not very informative about the shape
        parameter of the flood distribution.</para>
    
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="5">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">LP3</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">No Prior Information</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">With Prior Information</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">Parameter</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Mean</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Std Deviation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Mean</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Std Deviation</entry>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>m</entry>
                    
                    <entry>6.426</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.236</entry>
                    
                    <entry>6.423</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.236</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>loge s</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.350</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.127</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.322</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.127</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>g</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.146</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.643</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.028</entry>
                    
                    <entry>0.305</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>Consideration of the table below where selected 1 in Y AEP quantiles
        q<subscript>Y</subscript> and their 90% confidence limits are shown
        further illustrates the benefit of incorporating regional information. For
        example, the 1 in 100 AEP flood 5% and 95% confidence limits are
        respectively 38% and 553% of the quantile q<subscript>100</subscript> when
        no prior information is used. These confidence limits are reduced to 45%
        and 321% of the quantile q<subscript>100</subscript> using prior regional
        information.</para>
    
    <para/>
    
    <para>&lt;Table&gt;</para>
    
    <para/>
    
    <table>
        <title/>
        
        <tgroup cols="7">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">1 in Y AEP</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">No Prior Information</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">With Prior Information</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile qY</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile Confidence Limits</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile qY</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Quantile Confidence Limits</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">5% Limit</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">95% Limit</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">5% Limit</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">95% Limit</entry>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>10</entry>
                    
                    <entry>3888</entry>
                    
                    <entry>2222</entry>
                    
                    <entry>8287</entry>
                    
                    <entry>3619</entry>
                    
                    <entry>2184</entry>
                    
                    <entry>6933</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>50</entry>
                    
                    <entry>12729</entry>
                    
                    <entry>5537</entry>
                    
                    <entry>52157</entry>
                    
                    <entry>10677</entry>
                    
                    <entry>5294</entry>
                    
                    <entry>29104</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>100</entry>
                    
                    <entry>19548</entry>
                    
                    <entry>7372</entry>
                    
                    <entry>108144</entry>
                    
                    <entry>15670</entry>
                    
                    <entry>7050</entry>
                    
                    <entry>50274</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>EXAMPLE <anchor id="WPGeneratedID_Xref_FFAEx5_1"/>5: IMPROVING
                POOR FITS USING CENSORING OF LOW FLOW DATA</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>The standard probability models such as GEV and LP3 may not
        adequately fit flood data for a variety of reasons. Often the poor fit is
        associated with a sigmoidal probability plot as illustrated in Figure
        1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_47">13</link>. In such cases it is
        possible to employ four or five-parameter distributions which have
        sufficient degrees of freedom to track the data in both the upper and
        lower tails of the sigmoidal curve or adopt a calibration approach that
        gives less weight to the smaller floods. The latter approach is
        illustrated in this example which considers 50 annual maximum floods for
        the Albert River at Broomfleet.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Bayesian Fit to All Gauged Data</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_13.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>These 50 annual maximum floods comprising the data series for the
        Albert River at Broomfleet are</para>
    
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="10">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>13.02</entry>
                    
                    <entry>15.57</entry>
                    
                    <entry>15.85</entry>
                    
                    <entry>16.7</entry>
                    
                    <entry>22.36</entry>
                    
                    <entry>36.51</entry>
                    
                    <entry>72.73</entry>
                    
                    <entry>78.11</entry>
                    
                    <entry>87.73</entry>
                    
                    <entry>88.30</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>95.65</entry>
                    
                    <entry>99.90</entry>
                    
                    <entry>113.77</entry>
                    
                    <entry>116.88</entry>
                    
                    <entry>124.52</entry>
                    
                    <entry>131.03</entry>
                    
                    <entry>156.22</entry>
                    
                    <entry>156.50</entry>
                    
                    <entry>190.74</entry>
                    
                    <entry>210.55</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>95.65</entry>
                    
                    <entry>249.61</entry>
                    
                    <entry>249.61</entry>
                    
                    <entry>271.68</entry>
                    
                    <entry>285.83</entry>
                    
                    <entry>302.81</entry>
                    
                    <entry>305.64</entry>
                    
                    <entry>362.24</entry>
                    
                    <entry>384.88</entry>
                    
                    <entry>461.29</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>466.95</entry>
                    
                    <entry>676.37</entry>
                    
                    <entry>752.78</entry>
                    
                    <entry>761.27</entry>
                    
                    <entry>761.27</entry>
                    
                    <entry>860.32</entry>
                    
                    <entry>863.15</entry>
                    
                    <entry>865.98</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1086.72</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1177.28</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>1185.77</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1214.07</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1273.5</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1327.27</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1341.42</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1364.06</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1468.77</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1652.72</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1689.51</entry>
                    
                    <entry>1765.92</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>Displayed in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_47">13</link> is the GEV distribution on a
        Gumbel probability plot fitted using the Bayesian approach. Although the
        observed floods are largely contained within the 90% confidence limits,
        the fit, nonetheless, should be considered poor. The data has a sigmoidal
        trend with reverse curvature occurring for floods less than 1 in 2 AEP. It
        appears that the confidence limits have increased because the GEV fit
        provides a poor representation of the data.</para>
    
    <para>To deal with this problem, low flows can be censored to obtain a fit
        that favours the right hand tail (the high flows) of the distribution. The
        main idea is to force the assumed distribution to fit only the probability
        of low flows falling below a threshold rather than the low flow part of
        the distribution. As a result, the fitting of the assumed distribution is
        focussed on the right hand tail where the high flows occur. The censoring
        threshold can be obtained by trial-and-error but is better obtained by
        fitting LH moments as in Example <link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_57">8</link>.</para>
    
    <para>Illustrated in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_48">14</link> is one such fit. To
        de-emphasize the left hand tail the floods below the threshold of
        250m<superscript>3</superscript>/s were censored. This means the GEV
        distribution was fitted to a data record consisting of:</para>
    
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>a gauged record comprising the 27 floods above
                250m<superscript>3</superscript>/s; and</para>
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
            <para>a censored record comprising the 23 floods below the threshold
                of 250m<superscript>3</superscript>/s and 0 floods above this
                threshold.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Bayesian Fit with Floods Below 250m3/s Threshold Treated as
            Censored Observations</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_14.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>The censored record provides an anchor point for the GEV
        distribution. It ensures that the chance of an annual maximum flood being
        less than 250m<superscript>3</superscript>/s is about 0.46 without forcing
        the GEV to fit the annual peak flows below the
        250m<superscript>3</superscript>/s threshold. The fit effectively
        disregards floods lower than 1 in 2 AEP and provides a good fit to the
        high flow tail. As shown in Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_48">14</link>, another benefit is the
        substantially reduced 90% confidence range.</para>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><emphasis role="bold">EXAMPLE</emphasis><anchor
                id="WPGeneratedID_Xref_FFAEx6_1"/>6: EXAMPLE OF A NON-HOMOGENEOUS
                FLOOD PROBABILITY MODEL</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>The work of Micevski <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>.
        (2003) can be used to illustrate an example of a non-homogeneous model. An
        indicator time series based on the IPO time series (Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_16">6</link>) was used to create the
        exogenous vector x which is given by</para>
    
    <equation>
        <title/>
        
        <m:math display="block">
            <m:msub>
                <m:mi>x = {I</m:mi>
                
                <m:mi>t</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
            
            <m:mo>, t = 1, ... n}</m:mo>
            
            <m:mi/>
        </m:math>
    </equation>
    
    <para>where the indicator I<subscript>t</subscript> is given by</para>
    
    <equation>
        <title/>
        
        <m:math display="block">
            <m:msub>
                <m:mi>I</m:mi>
                
                <m:mi>t</m:mi>
            </m:msub>
            
            <m:mo>=</m:mo>
            
            <m:mrow>
                <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>{</m:mo>
                    
                    <m:mtable>
                        <m:mtr>
                            <m:mtd>
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mi>1,</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:msub>
                                            <m:mi>if IPO</m:mi>
                                            
                                            <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                        </m:msub>
                                        
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mo>≥</m:mo>
                                            
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:msub>
                                                    <m:mi>IPO</m:mi>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mi>thresh</m:mi>
                                                </m:msub>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mtd>
                        </m:mtr>
                        
                        <m:mtr>
                            <m:mtd>
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>0, if IPO</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>t</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                    
                                    <m:mo>&gt;</m:mo>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:msub>
                                            <m:mi>IPO</m:mi>
                                            
                                            <m:mi>thresh</m:mi>
                                        </m:msub>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mtd>
                        </m:mtr>
                    </m:mtable>
                </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
            
            <m:mi/>
        </m:math>
    </equation>
    
    <para>IPO<subscript>t</subscript> is the IPO index for year t and
        IPO<subscript>thresh</subscript> is a threshold value equal to
        –0.125.</para>
    
    <para>At each of the 33 NSW sites considered by Micevski <emphasis
        role="italic">et al</emphasis>. (2003) the annual maximum peak flows were
        stratified according to the indicator I<subscript>t</subscript>. A
        2-parameter log-normal distribution was fitted to the gauged flows with
        indicator equal to 1; this is the IPO+ distribution. Likewise, a
        2-parameter log-normal distribution was fitted to the gauged flows with
        indicator equal to 0; this is the IPO- distribution. Presented in Figure
        1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_50">15</link> is the histogram for
        the ratio of the IPO- and IPO+ floods for selected 1 in Y AEPs. If the the
        IPO+ and IPO- distributions were homogeneous then about half of the sites
        should have a flood ratio &lt; 1; consideration of the data shown in
        Figure 1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_50">15</link> suggests
        otherwise.</para>
    
    <para>Presented in Figures 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_51">16</link> and 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_52">17</link> are the fitted log-normal
        distributions for the IPO+ and IPO- annual maximum flood data for the
        Clarence river at Lilydale respectively. Though the adequacy of the
        log-normal model for high floods may be questioned, in the range of 1 in 2
        AEP to 1 in 10 AEP, the IPO- floods are about 2.6 times the IPO+ floods
        with the same AEP.</para>
    
    <para>To avoid bias in estimating long-term flood risk it is essential
        that the gauged record adequately span both IPO+ and IPO- years. In this
        example, the IPO+ record is 43 years and the IPO- record is 33 years in
        length. With reference to Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_16">6</link>, it would appear that this
        length of record has an adequate sample from both IPO epochs. As a result,
        fitting a distribution to all the data will yield an unbiased estimate of
        the long-term flood risk. Shown in Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_53">18</link> is a log normal distribution
        fitted to all the data.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Histogram of IPO- and IPO+ Flood Ratios</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_15.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Log-Normal Fit to 43 Years of IPO+ Data for the Clarence River at
            Lilydale</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_16.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Log-Normal Fit to 33 Years of IPO- Data for the Clarence River at
            Lilydale</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_17.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Log-Normal Fit to 76 Years of Data for the Clarence River at
            Lilydale</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_18.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>Better appreciation of the differences in flood risk can be gleaned
        by considering Figure 1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_54">19</link>
        which where the fitted log-normal distributions to the IPO+, IPO- and all
        the data are presented. During an IPO+ period a flood with peak discharge
        of 100m<superscript>3</superscript>/s has a 1 in 20 AEP while during an
        IPO- period it has a 1 in 4 AEP. Likewise a flood with peak discharge of
        200m<superscript>3</superscript> /s has AEPs of 1 in 100 and 1 in 10 for
        IPO+ and IPO- periods respectively. The differences in flood risk are
        considerable. If a short gauged record falling largely in the IPO+ period
        was used, a standard flood frequency analysis could seriously
        underestimate the long-term or marginal flood risk.</para>
    
    <para>The marginal flood risk can be derived by combining the IPO+ and
        IPO- distribution using equation 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_20">14</link> to give</para>
    
    <para/>
    
    <equation>
        <title/>
        
        <m:math display="block">
            <m:mo>P(Q≤q</m:mo>
            
            <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>| θ ) = P(x = 0)</m:mi>
                
                <m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:munderover>
                            <m:mo>∫</m:mo>
                            
                            <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                        </m:munderover>
                        
                        <m:mi>p(z |</m:mi>
                    </m:mrow>
                    
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>θ, x</m:mi>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>= 0)dz + P(x = 1)</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:munderover>
                                        <m:mo>∫</m:mo>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>q</m:mi>
                                    </m:munderover>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>P(z |</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>
                                
                                <m:mi>θ, x = 1) dz</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
            
            <m:mi/>
        </m:math>
    </equation>
    
    <para>The exogenous variable x can take two values, 0 or 1, depending on
        the IPO epoch. P(x = 0), the probability of being in an IPO- epoch, is
        assigned the value 33/76 based on the observation that 33 of the 76 years
        of record were in the IPO- epoch. Likewise P(x = 1), the probability of
        being in an IPO+ epoch, is assigned the value 43/76.</para>
    
    <para/>
    
    <para>The derived marginal distribution is plotted in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_54">19</link>. It almost exactly matches the
        log normal distribution fitted to all the data.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Marginal, IPO+ and IPO+ Log-Normal Distributions for the Clarence
            River at Lilydale</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_19.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para/>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><emphasis role="bold">EXAMPLE</emphasis><anchor
                id="WPGeneratedID_Xref_FFAEx7_1"/>7: L MOMENTS FIT TO GAUGED
                DATA</term>
            
            <listitem>
                <para/>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>Illustrated in this example is the fitting of a GEV distribution to
        gauged data using L moments. The 47 ranked annual maximum flood series for
        the Styx River at Jeogla are:</para>
    
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="8">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>878</entry>
                    
                    <entry>541</entry>
                    
                    <entry>521</entry>
                    
                    <entry>513</entry>
                    
                    <entry>436</entry>
                    
                    <entry>411</entry>
                    
                    <entry>405</entry>
                    
                    <entry>8.18</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>309</entry>
                    
                    <entry>300</entry>
                    
                    <entry>294</entry>
                    
                    <entry>258</entry>
                    
                    <entry>255</entry>
                    
                    <entry>235</entry>
                    
                    <entry>221</entry>
                    
                    <entry>220</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>206</entry>
                    
                    <entry>196</entry>
                    
                    <entry>194</entry>
                    
                    <entry>190</entry>
                    
                    <entry>186</entry>
                    
                    <entry>177</entry>
                    
                    <entry>164</entry>
                    
                    <entry>220</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>117</entry>
                    
                    <entry>111</entry>
                    
                    <entry>108</entry>
                    
                    <entry>105</entry>
                    
                    <entry>92.2</entry>
                    
                    <entry>88.6</entry>
                    
                    <entry>79.9</entry>
                    
                    <entry>74</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>71.9</entry>
                    
                    <entry>62.6</entry>
                    
                    <entry>61.2</entry>
                    
                    <entry>60.3</entry>
                    
                    <entry>58</entry>
                    
                    <entry>88.6</entry>
                    
                    <entry>39.1</entry>
                    
                    <entry>26.7</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>26.1</entry>
                    
                    <entry>23.8</entry>
                    
                    <entry>22.4</entry>
                    
                    <entry>22.1</entry>
                    
                    <entry>18.6</entry>
                    
                    <entry>13</entry>
                    
                    <entry>8.18</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>Reported in the following table are the results obtained. The GEV
        parameters are estimated by substituting the L moment estimates in
        equation 1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_31">45</link> to obtain κ
        and then using the equations in Table 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_29">3</link> to estimate τ and α. The
        standard deviation and correlation were derived from 5000 bootstrapped
        samples following the procedure described in Section 6.4.6 of this Chapter
        in Book 1 of Australian Rainfall and Runoff.</para>
    
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="8">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry align="center">L Moment Estimates</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">GEV Parameter Estimates</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Std Deviation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center">Correlation</entry>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                    
                    <entry align="center"/>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry>189.238</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry>100.66</entry>
                    
                    <entry>17.657</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry>92.476</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry>104.157</entry>
                    
                    <entry>15.554</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry>29.264</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry>-0.219</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry/>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>Presented in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_56">20</link> is a probability plot of the
        gauged data along with GEV 1 in Y AEP quantiles and their 90% confidence
        limits. The confidence limits widen appreciably for the bigger floods;
        this is due largely to there being insufficient information to accurately
        infer the shape parameter κ.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Probability Plot for Styx River at Jeogla</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_20.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>EXAMPLE <anchor id="WPGeneratedID_Xref_FFAEx8_1"/>8: IMPROVING
                POOR FITS USING LH MOMENTS</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>This example is a continuation of Example 5. The GEV distribution
        was fitted to the gauged data for the Albert River at Broomfleet using LH
        moments.</para>
    
    <para>Displayed in Figure 1.1.<link
        linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_58">21</link> the GEV L moment fit on a
        Gumbel probability plot. Although the observed floods are largely
        contained within the 90% confidence limits, the fit, nonetheless, is poor
        with systematic departures from the data which exhibit reverse
        curvature.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>L Moment Fit</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_21.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>To deal with this poor fit, an LH moment search was conducted to
        find the optimal value of the shift parameter η using the procedure
        described in Section 6.4.5. The optimal value of the shift parameter was
        found to be 4. Presented in Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_59">22</link> are the LH moment fit with
        shift η equal to 4. The fit effectively disregards floods with an AEP in
        excess of 1 in 2 and provides a very good fit to upper tail.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>LH Moment Fit with Shift η = 4</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_22.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>The very significant reduction in the width of the quantile
        confidence intervals is largely due to the shape parameter κ changing from
        –0.17 to 0.50. The L moment fit in Figure 1.1.<link
            linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_58">21</link> was a compromise with the bulk
        of the small and medium-sized floods suggesting an upward curvature in the
        probability plot. As a result, the GEV shape parameter κ had to be
        negative to enable upward curvature. In contrast, the LH moment fit
        favoured the large-sized floods which exhibit a downward curvature
        resulting in a positive shape parameter. For positive κ the GEV has an
        upper bound. In this case the upper bound is about
        2070m<superscript>3</superscript>/s which is only 17% greater than the
        largest observed flood.</para>
    
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>EXAMPLE 9: FITTING A PROBABILITY MODEL TO POT DATA</term>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
    <para>An exponential distribution is fitted to a POT series based on
        gauged data for the Styx River at Jeogla. Listed in the table below are
        all the independent peak flows recorded over a 47 year period that
        exceeded a threshold of 74 m<superscript>3</superscript>/s; the total
        number of independent peaks obtained was 47. Comparison with the annual
        maximum flood peaks in Example 7 reveals that in 15 of the 47 years of
        record the annual maximum peak was below the threshold of 74
        m<superscript>3</superscript>/s.</para>
    
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="8">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>878</entry>
                    
                    <entry>541</entry>
                    
                    <entry>521</entry>
                    
                    <entry>91.7</entry>
                    
                    <entry>436</entry>
                    
                    <entry>411</entry>
                    
                    <entry>405</entry>
                    
                    <entry>315</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>309</entry>
                    
                    <entry>301</entry>
                    
                    <entry>300</entry>
                    
                    <entry>294</entry>
                    
                    <entry>283</entry>
                    
                    <entry>258</entry>
                    
                    <entry>255</entry>
                    
                    <entry>255</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>238</entry>
                    
                    <entry>235</entry>
                    
                    <entry>221</entry>
                    
                    <entry>294</entry>
                    
                    <entry>206</entry>
                    
                    <entry>196</entry>
                    
                    <entry>194</entry>
                    
                    <entry>190</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>186</entry>
                    
                    <entry>164</entry>
                    
                    <entry>150</entry>
                    
                    <entry>294</entry>
                    
                    <entry>134</entry>
                    
                    <entry>129</entry>
                    
                    <entry>129</entry>
                    
                    <entry>126</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>119</entry>
                    
                    <entry>118</entry>
                    
                    <entry>117</entry>
                    
                    <entry>117</entry>
                    
                    <entry>111</entry>
                    
                    <entry>108</entry>
                    
                    <entry>105</entry>
                    
                    <entry>98</entry>
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry>92.2</entry>
                    
                    <entry>92.2</entry>
                    
                    <entry>91.7</entry>
                    
                    <entry>117</entry>
                    
                    <entry>85.2</entry>
                    
                    <entry>79.9</entry>
                    
                    <entry>74</entry>
                    
                    <entry/>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    <para>A GP distribution with distribution function</para>
    
    <equation>
        <title/>
        
        <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
                <m:mo>P(Q ≤</m:mo>
            </m:mrow>
            
            <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>q | θ)</m:mi>
                
                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                
                <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>1 -</m:mo>
                    
                    <m:mrow>
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>(</m:mo>
                            
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>1 -</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mfrac>
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mi>κ(</m:mi>
                                            
                                            <m:mrow>
                                                <m:msub>
                                                    <m:mi>q - q</m:mi>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                </m:msub>
                                                
                                                <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                            </m:mrow>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>β</m:mi>
                                    </m:mfrac>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:msup>
                                            <m:mi/>
                                        </m:msup>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                            
                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:msup>
                                <m:mi/>
                                
                                <m:mfrac>
                                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mi>κ</m:mi>
                                </m:mfrac>
                            </m:msup>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
            
            <m:mi/>
        </m:math>
    </equation>
    
    <para>was fitted to the POT data yielding the following estimates of the
        parameter values:</para>
    
    <para>β = 148.7,</para>
    
    <para>κ = -0.024, and</para>
    
    <para>q<subscript>*</subscript> = 73.999.</para>
    
    <para>Using equation 1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_7">7</link>,
        the average recurrence interval between two peaks exceeding a magnitude of
        w is</para>
    
    <para/>
    
    <equation>
        <title/>
        
        <m:math display="block">
            <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                    
                    <m:mi>p</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
            </m:mrow>
            
            <m:mo>(w) =</m:mo>
            
            <m:mrow>
                <m:mfrac>
                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                    
                    <m:mi>vP(Q &gt; w)</m:mi>
                </m:mfrac>
                
                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                
                <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mo>v</m:mo>
                            
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mo>[</m:mo>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mi>1 -</m:mi>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mfrac>
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:mrow>
                                                        <m:mi>κ (</m:mi>
                                                        
                                                        <m:mrow>
                                                            <m:msub>
                                                                <m:mi>w- q</m:mi>
                                                                
                                                                <m:mi>*</m:mi>
                                                            </m:msub>
                                                            
                                                            <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                                                        </m:mrow>
                                                    </m:mrow>
                                                </m:mrow>
                                                
                                                <m:mi>β</m:mi>
                                            </m:mfrac>
                                            
                                            <m:mo>]</m:mo>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                        
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:msup>
                                                <m:mi/>
                                                
                                                <m:mfrac>
                                                    <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                                                    
                                                    <m:mi>κ</m:mi>
                                                </m:mfrac>
                                            </m:msup>
                                        </m:mrow>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mrow>
                        </m:mrow>
                    </m:mfrac>
                </m:mrow>
            </m:mrow>
            
            <m:mi/>
        </m:math>
    </equation>
    
    <para>where ν is the average number of flood peaks above the threshold
        q<subscript>*</subscript> per year. Given that 47 peaks above the
        threshold occurred in 47 years, the best estimate of ν equals 1.0. Shown
        in Figure 1.1.<link linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_60">23</link> is a plot
        of the fitted POT exponential model against the observed POT series
        obtained using equation 1.1.?.</para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>POT Probability Plot for Styx River at Jeogla</title>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="Figures/Figure1_1_23.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
</section>

<section>
    <title>REFERENCES</title>
    
    <para>Adams, CA, (1987), Design flood estimation for ungauged rural
        catchments in Victoria Road Construction Authority, Victoria, Draft
        Technical Bulletin.</para>
    
    <para>Adams, CA and McMahon, TA, (1985), Estimation of flood discharge for
        ungauged rural catchments in Victoria, <emphasis role="italic">Proceedings
            1985 Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium</emphasis>, IEAust Natl Conf.
        Publ. No. 85/2, pp 86-90.</para>
    
    <para>Alexander, GN, (1957), Flood flow estimation, probability and the
        return period. Journal of Institution of Engineers Australia,
        29:263-278.</para>
    
    <para>Al-Futaisi, A, and Stedinger, JR, (1999), Hydrologic and Economic
        Uncertainties in Flood Risk Project Design, ASCE, Journal of Water
        Resources Planning and Management, 125(6):314-324.</para>
    
    <para>Allan, RJ, (2000), ENSO and Climatic Variability in the last 150
        years, in <emphasis role="italic">El Nino and the Southern Oscillation,
            Multi-Scale Variability, Global and Regional Impacts</emphasis>, edited by
        HF Diaz and V Markgraf, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, UK,
        p3-56.</para>
    
    <para>American Society of Civil Engineers, (1949), Hydrology Handbook,
        <emphasis role="bold">publisher ?</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Ashkanasy, NM and Weeks, WD, (1975), Flood Frequency Distribution in
        A Catchment Subject to Two Storm Rainfall Producing Mechanisms,
        Proceedings 1975 Hydrology Symposium, IEAust Natl Conf. Publ. No. 75/3, pp
        153-157.</para>
    
    <para>Ashkar, F and Rousselle, J, (1983), Some remarks on the truncation
        used in partial flood series models. Water Resources Research,
        19:477-480.</para>
    
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A Guide to
        Flood Estimation, (1987), Pilgrim, D.H. (ed), The Institution of
        Engineers, Australia, Canberra.</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Baker, V, (1984), Recent paleoflood hydrology studies in arid and
        semi-arid environments (abstract). EOS Trans. Amer. Geophys. Union, 65:893
        - <emphasis role="bold">should we be referencing an abstract when people
            are unlikely to be able to obtain the full paper</emphasis>.</para>
    
    <para>Baker, V, Pickup, G and Polach, HA, (1983), Desert Paleofloods in
        Central Australia, <emphasis role="italic">Nature</emphasis>,
        301:502-504.</para>
    
    <para>Beard, LR, (1960), Probability Estimates Based in Small
        Normal-distribution Samples, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of
            Geophysical Research</emphasis>, 65:2143-2148.</para>
    
    <para>Beard, LR, (1974), Flood Flow Frequency Techniques, <emphasis
        role="italic">Tech. Report CRWR119</emphasis>, Center for Research in
        Water Resources, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX, USA.</para>
    
    <para>Beran, M, Hosking, JRM and Arnell, N, (1986), Comment on
        "Two-component extreme value distribution for flood frequency analysis",
        <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        22:263-266.</para>
    
    <para>Blom, G, (1958), <emphasis role="italic">Statistical Estimates and
        Transformed Beta-Variables</emphasis>, Wiley, New York, NY, USA.</para>
    
    <para>Brown, JAH, (1983), <emphasis role="italic">Australia's Surface
        Water Resources - Water 2000: Consultants Report 1</emphasis>, Australian
        Government Publishing Service, Canberra.</para>
    
    <para>Clarke-Hafstad, K, (1942), Reliability of station-year
        rainfall-frequency determinations.,. Trans. ASCE, 107:633-652.</para>
    
    <para>Conway, KM, (1970), Flood Frequency Analysis of Some NSW Coastal
        Rivers, Unpublished M.Eng.Sc. Report, School of Civil Engineering, UNSW,
        Kensington, NSW, Australia.</para>
    
    <para>Costa, JE, (1978), Holocene stratigraphy in flood frequency
        analysis, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        14:626-632.</para>
    
    <para>Costa, JE, (1983), Palaeohydraulic reconstruction or flashflood
        peaks from boulder deposits in the Colorado Front Range, Geol. Soc.
        America Bulletin, 94:AP986-1004.</para>
    
    <para>Costa, JE, (1986), A History of Paleoflood Hydrology in the United
        States, 1800-1970. EOS Trans. AGU, 67(17):425-430.</para>
    
    <para>Cunnane, C, (1973), A Particular Comparison of Annual Maxima and
        Partial Duration Series Methods for Flood Frequency Prediction, Journal of
        Hydrology, 18:257-271.</para>
    
    <para>Cunnane, C, (1978), Unbiased Plotting Positions - A Review,
        <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>,
        37:205-222.</para>
    
    <para>Cunnane, C, (1985), Factors Affecting Choice of Distribution for
        Flood Series, <emphasis role="italic">Hydrological Sciences
            Journal</emphasis>, 30:25-36.</para>
    
    <para>Dalrymple, T, (1960), Flood-Frequency Analyses, Manual of Hydrology:
        Section 3 - Flood-Flow Techniques, <emphasis role="italic">U.S. Geological
            Survey Water Supply Paper 1543-A</emphasis>, <emphasis
                role="bold">?????</emphasis>, 79 p.</para>
    
    <para>DeGroot, MH, (1970), <emphasis role="italic">Optimal Statistcal
        Decisions</emphasis>, McGraw-Hill, <emphasis
            role="bold">?????</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Doran, DG and Irish, JL, (1980), on the Nature and Extent of Bias in
        Flood Damage Estimation, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 1980 Hydrology and
            Water Resources Symposium</emphasis>, IEAust Natl Conf. Publ. No. 80/9, pp
        135-139.</para>
    
    <para>Duan, Q, Sorooshian, S and Gupta, V, (1992), Effective and Efficient
        Global Optimization for Conceptual Rainfall-runoff Models, <emphasis
            role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 28(4):1015-1032.</para>
    
    <para>Erskine, WD, and Warner, RF, (1988), Geomorphic Effects of
        Alternating Flood and Drought Dominated Regimes on a NSW Coastal River,
        <emphasis role="italic">in Fluvial Geomorphology of Australia</emphasis>,
        edited by R.F. Warner, Academic Press, Sydney, NSW, Australia, pp.
        223-244.</para>
    
    <para>Fiorentino, M, Versace, P and Rossi, F, (1985), Regional Flood
        Frequency Estimation Using the Two-component Extreme Value Distribution,
        Hydrological Sciences Journal, 30:51-64.</para>
    
    <para>Flavell, DJ, (1983), the Rational Method Applied to Small Rural
        Catchments in the South West of Western Australia, IEAust Civil
        Engineering Transactions, CE25:121-127.</para>
    
    <para>Franks, SW and Kuczera, G, (2002), Flood Frequency Analysis:
        Evidence and Implications of Secular Climate Variability, New South Wales,
        <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        38(5):<emphasis role="bold">10.1029/2001WR000232</emphasis>.</para>
    
    <para>Gelman, A, Carlin, JB, Stern, HS and Rubin, DB, (1995), <emphasis
        role="italic">Bayesian Data Analysis</emphasis>, Chapman and Hall,
        p.526.</para>
    
    <para>Grayson, RB, Argent, RM, Nathan, RJ, McMahon, TA and Mein, RG,
        (1996), <emphasis role="italic">Hydrologic Recipes: Estimation Techniques
            in Australian Hydrology</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">CRC for
                Catchment Hydrology, ????.</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Grygier, J C, Stedinger, JR and Yin, H-B, (1989), A Generalized
        Maintenance of Variance Extension Procedure for Extending Correlated
        Series, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        25(3):345-349.</para>
    
    <para>Harvey, F, Doran, DG, Cordery, I, and Pilgrim, DH, (1991), Regional
        Flood Frequency Characteristics in Rural New South Wales, <emphasis
            role="italic">Proc. 1991 International Hydrology and Water Resources
            Symposium</emphasis>, Perth, Australia, IEAust NCP 91/19, pp
        775-780.</para>
    
    <para>Hatfield, ER and Muir, GL, (1984), Surface Water Resources
        Assessment in New South Wales, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. Workshop on
            Surface Water Resources Data</emphasis>, AWRC Conference Series No. 10, pp
        263-292.</para>
    
    <para>Hirsch, RM, (1982), A Comparison of Four Record Extension
        Techniques, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        18(4):1081-1088.</para>
    
    <para>Hosking, JRM, (1990), L-Moments: Analysis and Estimation of
        Distributions Using Linear Combinations of Order Statistics, <emphasis
            role="italic">Journal of Royal Statistical Society, Series B</emphasis>,
        52(2):105-124.</para>
    
    <para>Hosking, JRM and Wallis, JR, (1986), Paleoflood Hydrology and Flood
        Frequency Analysis, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
            Research</emphasis>, 22:543-550.</para>
    
    <para>Houghton, JC, (1978), Birth of a Parent: the Wakeby Distribution for
        Modeling Flood Flows, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
            Research</emphasis>, 14:1105-1109.</para>
    
    <para>Interagency Advisory Committee on Water Data, (1982), Guidelines for
        Determining Flood Flow Frequency, <emphasis role="italic">Bulletin 17B of
            the Hydrology Sub-Committee</emphasis>, Office of Water Data Coordination,
        Geological Survey, US Dept of the Interior, ????</para>
    
    <para>Jayasuriya, MDA and Mein, RG, (1985), Frequency Analysis Using the
        Partial Series, <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 1985 Hydrology and Water
            Resources Symposium</emphasis>, IEAust. Natl. Conf. Publ. No. 85/2, pp.
        81-85.</para>
    
    <para>Jin, M and Stedinger, JR, (1989), Flood Frequency Analysis with
        Regional and Historical Information, <emphasis role="italic">Water
            Resources Research</emphasis>, 25(5):925-936.</para>
    
    <para>Kiem, A S, and Franks, SW, (2004), Multi-decadal Variability of
        Drought Risk - Eastern Australia, <emphasis role="italic">Hydrological
            Processes</emphasis>, 18:<emphasis
                role="bold">doi:10.1002/hyp.1460.</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Kiem, AS, Franks, SW and Kuczera, G, (2003), Multi-decadal
        Variability of Flood Risk, <emphasis role="italic">Geophysical Research
            Letters</emphasis>, 30(2):<emphasis role="bold">1035,
                DOI:10.1029/2002GL015992.</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Kochel. RC, Baker, VR and Patton, PC, (1982), Paleohydrology of
        Southwestern Texas, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
            Research</emphasis>, 18:1165-1183.</para>
    
    <para>Kopittke, RA., Stewart, BJ and Tickle, KS, (1976), Frequency
        Analysis of Flood Data in Queensland. <emphasis role="italic">Proc. 1976
            Hydrology Symposium</emphasis>, IEAust. Natl Conf. Publ. No. 76/2, pp.
        20-24.</para>
    
    <para>Kuczera, G, (1999), Comprehensive At-site Flood Frequency Analysis
        Using Monte Carlo Bayesian Inference, <emphasis role="italic">Water
            Resources Research</emphasis>, 35(5):1551-1558.</para>
    
    <para>Kuczera, G, Lambert, M, Heneker, T, Jennings, S, Frost, A and
        Coombes, P, (2003), Joint Probability and Design Storms at the Crossroads,
        <emphasis role="italic">Proc 2003 Hydrology and Water Resources
            Symposium</emphasis>, IEAust, Wollongong, pp <emphasis
                role="bold">????</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Lee, PM, (1989), <emphasis role="italic">Bayesian Statistics: An
        Introduction</emphasis>, Oxford University Press, New York, NY,
        USA.</para>
    
    <para>Laurenson, EM, (1987), Back to Basics on Flood Frequency Analysis,
        IEAust Civil Engineering Transactions, CE29:47-53.</para>
    
    <para>Madsen, H, Pearson, CP, Rasmussen, PF and Rosbjerg, D, (1997),
        Comparison of Annual Maximum Series and Partial Duration Series Methods
        for Modeling Extreme Hydrologic Events 1 - At-Site Modeling, <emphasis
            role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 33(4):747-758.</para>
    
    <para>Mantua, NJ, Hare, SR, Zhang, Y, Wallace, JM and Francis, RC, (1997),
        A Pacific Interdecadal Climate Oscillation with Impacts on Salmon
        Production, Bulletin American Meteorological Society,
        78(6):1069-1079.</para>
    
    <para>Martins, E S and Stedinger, JR, (2000), Generalized Maximum
        Likelihood GEV Quantile Estimators for Hydrologic Data, <emphasis
            role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 36(3):737-744.</para>
    
    <para>Martins, E S and Stedinger, JR, (2001), Generalized Maximum
        Likelihood Pareto-Poisson Flood Risk Analysis for Partial Duration Series,
        Water Resources Research, 37(10):2559-2567.</para>
    
    <para>Matalas, NC and Jacobs, B, (1964), A Correlation Procedure for
        Augmenting Hydrologic Data, <emphasis role="italic">US Geological Survey
            Professional Paper 434-E</emphasis>, <emphasis
                role="bold">????</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>McDermott, GE and Pilgrim, DH, (1982), Design Flood Estimation for
        Small Catchments in New South Wales, <emphasis role="italic">Australian
            Water Resources Council Technical Paper No. 73</emphasis>, Dept of
        National Development and Energy, <emphasis role="bold">???</emphasis>, 233
        p.</para>
    
    <para>McDermott, GE and Pilgrim, DH, (1983), A Design Flood Method for
        Arid Western New South Wales Based on Bankfull Estimates, <emphasis
            role="italic">IEAust, Civil Engineering Transaction</emphasis>,
        CE25:114-120.</para>
    
    <para>McIllwraith, JF, (1953), Rainfall Intensity-Frequency Data for New
        South Wales Stations. Journal Institution of Engineers Australia,
        25:133-139.</para>
    
    <para>McMahon, TA, (1979), Hydrologic Characteristics of Australian
        Streams, <emphasis role="italic">Report No. 3/1979</emphasis>, Civil
        Engineering Research Reports, Monash University, Clayton, Vic,
        Australia.</para>
    
    <para>McMahon, TA and Srikanthan, R, (1981), Log Pearson III Distribution
        - is it Applicable to Flood Frequency Analysis of Australian Streams?,
        <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>,
        52:139-147.</para>
    
    <para>Micevski, T, Kiem, AS, Franks, SW and Kuczera, G, (2003),
        Multidecadal Variability in New South Wales Flood Data, <emphasis
            role="italic">Proc. 2003 Hydrology and Water Resources
            Symposium</emphasis>, Institution of Engineers, Australia, Wollongong, pp
        ?.</para>
    
    <para>Micevski T, Kuczera, G, Franks, SW, (2005), Flood Frequency
        Censoring Errors Associated with Daily-read Flood Observations, <emphasis
            role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 41:?</para>
    
    <para>Natural Environment Research Council (1975), Flood Studies Report,
        1, Hydrological Studies. London.</para>
    
    <para>O'Connell, DR, Ostemaa, DA, Levish, DR and Klinger, RE, (2002),
        Bayesian Flood Frequency Analysis with Paleohydrologic Bound Data,
        <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        38(5):1058-?</para>
    
    <para>Pilgrim, DH and Doran, DG, (1987), Flood Frequency
        Analysis,<emphasis role="italic"> in Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A
            Guide to Flood Estimation</emphasis>, Pilgrim, DH (ed), The Institution of
        Engineers, Australia, Canberra.</para>
    
    <para>Pilgrim, DH and McDermott, GE, (1982), Design Floods for Small Rural
        Catchments in Eastern New South Wales, <emphasis role="italic">IEAust
            Civil Engineering Transactions</emphasis>, CE24:226-234.</para>
    
    <para>Potter, DJ and Pilgrim, DH, (1971), Flood Estimation Using A
        Regional Flood Frequency Approach, Final Report, Vol 2: Report on Analysis
        Components, Australian Water Resources Council, Research Project 68/1,
        Hydrology of Small Rural Catchments, Snowy Mountains Engineering
        Corporation.</para>
    
    <para>Potter, KW and Walker, JF, (1981), A Model of Discontinuous
        Measurement Error and its Effects on the Probability Distribution of Flood
        Discharge Measurements, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
            Research</emphasis>, 17(5):1505-1509.</para>
    
    <para>Potter, KW and Walker, JF, (1985), An Empirical Study of Flood
        Measurement Error, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources.
            Research</emphasis>, 21(3):403-406.</para>
    
    <para>Power, S, Tseitkin, F, Torok, S, Lavery, B, Dahni, R, and McAvaney,
        B, (1998), Australian Temperature, Australian Rainfall and the Southern
        Oscillation, 1910-1992: Coherent Variability and Recent Changes, <emphasis
            role="italic">Australian Meteorology Magazine</emphasis>,
        47(2):85-101.</para>
    
    <para>Power, S, Casey, T, Folland, C, Colman, A and Mehta, V, (1999),
        Inter-Decadal Modulation of the Impact of ENSO on Australia, <emphasis
            role="italic">Climate Dynamics</emphasis>, 15(5):319-324.</para>
    
    <para>Rosbjerg, D, Madsen, H and Rasmussen, PF, (1992), Prediction in
        Partial Duration Series with Generalized Pareto-Distributed Exceedances,
        <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        28(11):3001-3010.</para>
    
    <para>Rossi, F, Fiorentino, M and Versace, P, (1984), Two-Component
        Extreme Value Distribution for Flood Frequency Analysis, <emphasis
            role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, 20:847-856.</para>
    
    <para>Slack, JR, Wallis, JR and Matalas, NC, (1975), on the Value of
        Information in Flood Frequency Analysis, <emphasis role="italic">Water
            Resources. Research</emphasis>, 11(5):629-648.</para>
    
    <para>Stedinger, JR, (1983), Design Events with Specified Flood Risk,
        <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        19(2):511-522.</para>
    
    <para>Stedinger, JR, Vogel, RM and Foufoula-Georgiou, E, (1993), Frequency
        Analysis of Extreme Events in <emphasis role="italic">Handbook of
            Hydrology</emphasis>, Maidment, DR (ed.), McGraw-Hill, New York, NY,
        USA.</para>
    
    <para>Stedinger, JR and Cohn, TA, (1986), Flood Frequency Analysis with
        Historical and Paleoflood Information, <emphasis role="italic">Water
            Resources Research</emphasis>, 22:785-793.</para>
    
    <para>Stedinger, JR, (1998), Expected Probability and Annual Damage
        Estimators, <emphasis role="italic">ASCE, Journal of Water Resources
            Planning and Management</emphasis>, 123(2):125-35 (with discussion, LR
        Beard (1998), <emphasis role="italic">ASCE, Journal of Water Resources
            Planning and Management</emphasis>, 124(6):365-366).</para>
    
    <para>Tavares, LV, and da Silva, JE, (1983), Partial Series Method
        Revisited, <emphasis role="italic">Journal of Hydrology</emphasis>,
        64:1-14.</para>
    
    <para>Wallis, JR and Wood, EF, (1985), Relative Accuracy Log Pearson III
        Procedures. <emphasis role="italic">ASCE, Journal of Hydraulic
            Engineering</emphasis>, lll(7):1043-10<emphasis
                role="bold">??</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Wang, QJ, (1996), Direct Sample Estimators of L-Moments, <emphasis
        role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        32(12):3617-3619.</para>
    
    <para>Wang, QJ, (1997), LH Moments for Statistical Analysis of Extreme
        Events, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        33(12):2841-2848.</para>
    
    <para>Wang, QJ, (1998), Approximate Goodness-of-Fit Tests of Fitted
        Generalized Extreme Value Distributions Using LH Moments, <emphasis
            role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>,
        34(12):3497-3502.</para>
    
    <para>Wang, QJ, (1999), <emphasis role="bold">????</emphasis></para>
    
    <para>Wang, QJ, (2001), A Bayesian Joint Probability Approach for Flood
        Record Augmentation, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
            Research</emphasis>, 37(6):1707-1712.</para>
    
    <para>Waylen, P and Woo, M-K, (1982), Prediction of Annual Floods
        Generated by Mixed Processes, <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources
            Research</emphasis>, 18(4):1283-1286.</para>
    
    <para/>
</section>

