<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xml:id="b3_ch2-7" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>FITTING FLOOD PROBABILITY MODELS TO POT SERIES</title>
    
    <para>In Section 2.2.X it was noted that when interest is in events with
        T<subscript>A</subscript> &lt; 10 years generally it is recommended that a
        POT series is used rather than an annual series. This recommendation
        arises because all floods (above some threshold) are of interest in this
        range, whether they are the highest in the particular year of record or
        not. The annual maximum series may omit many floods of interest; Examples
        7 and 9 show examples of this. Outlined in this section are procedures for
        fitting a probability model to a POT series.</para>
    
    <section>
        <title>Probability Plots</title>
        
        <para>As with the analysis of the annual maximum series, it is
            recommended that a probability plot of the POT data series be prepared.
            This involves plotting an estimate of the observed ARI against the
            observed discharge. The ARI of a gauged flood can be estimated
            using</para>
        
        <para/>
        
        <equation>
            <title/>
            
            <m:math display="block">
                <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                    
                    <m:mi>(i)</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
                
                <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                
                <m:mrow>
                    <m:mfrac>
                        <m:mi>n + 0.2</m:mi>
                        
                        <m:mi>i - 0.4</m:mi>
                    </m:mfrac>
                </m:mrow>
                
                <m:mi/>
            </m:math>
        </equation>
        
        <para>where i is the rank of the gauged flood (in descending order) and
            n is the number of years of record.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Fitting POT Models</title>
        
        <para>In some cases, it may be desirable to analytically fit a
            probability distribution to POT data. Two approaches can be
            employed.</para>
        
        <para>The first employs the following steps:</para>
        
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>For a given threshold q<subscript>0</subscript>, fit a
                    probability distribution with pdf p(q | q &gt;
                    q<subscript>0</subscript>, θ) to the POT series;</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>Estimate ν the average number of POT events per unit;</para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>The expected time interval between peaks that exceed w is
                    given by equation 1.1.<emphasis role="bold"> linkend="WPGeneratedID_TOC_1_7">7</emphasis>
                    as</para>
                
                <equation>
                    <title/>
                    
                    <m:math display="block">
                        <m:msub>
                            <m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>T</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                            
                            <m:mi>P</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>(w)</m:mi>
                            
                            <m:mo>=</m:mo>
                        </m:mrow>
                        
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:mfrac>
                                <m:mi>1</m:mi>
                                
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:msub>
                                        <m:mi>vP(Q &gt; w | q</m:mi>
                                        
                                        <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                                    </m:msub>
                                    
                                    <m:mrow>
                                        <m:mi>, θ)</m:mi>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:mfrac>
                        </m:mrow>
                        
                        <m:mi/>
                    </m:math>
                </equation>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>Check that the fitted distribution is consistent with the POT
                    data using the probability plot described in Section 4.2.7.1.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        
        <para>A number of authors have investigated the proposition that it is
            better to infer the annual flow series distribution from the POT series
            on the grounds that the POT series considers all relevant data. For the
            exponential-Poisson POT model with an average arrival rate ν &gt; 1.65
            floods per year, Cunnane (1973) showed that the sample variance of
            T-year quantiles (T &gt; 10 years) is less than that obtained for a
            Gumbel distribution fitted to annual maximum series. Jayasuriya and Mein
            (1985), Ashkar and Rousselle (1983) and Tavares and da Silva (1983)
            noted that the exponential-Poisson POT model was fairly successful, but
            some results diverged from the distribution derived directly from the
            annual series. Madsen <emphasis role="italic">et al</emphasis>. (1997)
            investigated this issue using a GP-Poisson POT model. They concluded
            that for negative shape parameters κ the POT model generally was
            preferable for at-site quantile estimation. However, this conclusion is
            dependent on the choice of estimator. Martins and Stedinger (2001)
            showed for negative κ that the generalized maximum likelihood estimator
            performs better than method of moments and L moments. Significantly,
            they found that the precision of flood quantiles derived from a POT
            model is insensitive to the arrival rate ν and for the 100-year quantile
            is similar to the precision obtained fitting a GEV model to annual
            maximum data.</para>
        
        <para>At this stage, the POT approach cannot be recommended as a
            replacement for the analysis of annual series data. If possible, the
            threshold for the exponential-Poisson POT model should be selected so
            that the number of floods in the POT series K is at least 2 to 3 times
            the number of years of record N. For the GP-Poisson POT model it
            suffices that exceed N. However, it may be necessary to use a much lower
            value of K in regions with low rainfall where the number of recorded
            events that could be considered as floods is low.</para>
        
        <para>The second approach uses a probability distribution as an
            arbitrary means of providing a consistent and objective fit to POT
            series data. For example, McDermott and Pilgrim (1982), Adams and
            McMahon (1985) and Jayasuriya and Mein (1985) used the LP3 distribution
            and found that selecting a threshold discharge such that K equalled N
            was best.</para>
    </section>
</section>


