<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b8_ch6" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <info>
    <title>Derivation of Design Floods</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Advanced draft</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_wai7d">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_rxooc">
      <title>Selection of Basic Procedure</title>
      <para>The available procedures can be divided into two main groups: those based on fitting a
        frequency curve to flood maxima, and those based on design rainfalls. Flood frequency
        methods (<xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>) are used to provide estimates of peak discharge, but
        perhaps their most valuable role in the context of this Book is to provide information that
        can be used to validate, or even calibrate, rainfall-based procedures. The limit of credible
        extrapolation for
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T073146+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T073145+1000" content="f"?>lood
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T073149+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T073148+1000" content="f"?>requency
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T073152+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T073151+1000" content="a"?>nalysis
        based on regional gauged data is perhaps 1 in 500 AEP (<xref linkend="b8_t_tbdlw"/>), though
        paleoflood analysis (<xref linkend="b8_s_aaq3x"/>) can be used to considerably extend this
        limit. The credible limit of flood frequency analysis that can be typically obtained using
        at-site data is perhaps only 1 in
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T170910+1000" comment="changed as per email discussion with gk and rn
"?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T170853+1000" content="5"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T170854+1000"?>10<?oxy_insert_end?>0<?oxy_comment_end?>
        AEP (<xref linkend="b8_t_tbdlw"/>).</para>
      <para>Rainfall-based procedures use loss models and hydrograph models to transform design
        rainfall inputs into design flood estimates. Final design estimates of Very Rare to Extreme
        floods, beyond the credible limit of extrapolation (of either rainfall or floods), should be
        derived using rainfall-based procedures. The design details in the following sections relate
        mainly to rainfall-based procedures. As discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch3-1e"/>,
        event-based approaches are generally more applicable to the estimation of Very Rare to
        Extreme floods than are approaches based on continuous simulation; accordingly, the
        procedures as outlined in <xref linkend="book4"/> are generally applicable to the estimation
        of design floods for Very Rare and Extreme events.</para>
      <para><xref linkend="b8_s_30ly4"/> briefly discusses issues related to the specification of
        design flood characteristics. <xref linkend="b8_s_48x5y"/> introduces a number of special
        design considerations that are covered in more detail in <xref linkend="b8_ch7"/>.
        Subsequent sections (<xref linkend="b8_s_e0h7b"/> to <xref linkend="b8_s_gbk9t"/>) provide
        guidance on final design procedures, while <xref linkend="b8_s_21g0w"/> discusses the
        treatment of uncertainties associated with flood estimates derived by these
        procedures.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_30ly4">
      <title>Design Flood Characteristics</title>
      <para>In many cases, the flood hydrograph is required as well as the peak discharge and in
        some cases may be more important. For the design of a dam spillway or a detention basin,
        floods calculated from a range of design rainfall durations should be routed through the
        storage for a variety of combinations of spillway and gate configurations, operating
        procedures and dam crest heights to determine the optimum design. Different durations of
        design rainfalls may be critical for different configurations and combinations of
        conditions, which should all conform with the recommendations of
          <citation>b8_c_r1+1</citation>. The complete hydrograph of the design flood is also
        required for flood studies where flow profiles in natural or constructed channels are to be
        calculated by unsteady flow procedures.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_g9d58">
      <title>Expected Probability Adjustment</title>
      <para>The concept of ‘expected probability’ and its application in practical design problems
        is explained in <xref linkend="b3_ch2_s5"/>. It denotes the expected value of the AEP of a
        given flood magnitude. The expected probability is influenced by the uncertainty in
        parameters used to estimate the flood magnitude. Where the expected probability has not been
        implicitly determined in the
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T183830+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T183830+1000" content="f"?>lood
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T183833+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T183833+1000" content="f"?>requency
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T183836+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T183836+1000" content="a"?>nalysis,
        an ‘expected probability adjustment’ to estimates of AEP can be applied subsequently to
        correct for any systematic bias in the estimated risk arising from parameter
        uncertainty.</para>
      <para>In principle, the issue of expected probability is of considerable importance to the
        estimation of Very Rare to Extreme floods, as the magnitude of the adjustment is greatest
        for design flood magnitudes that involve significant extrapolation beyond the flood sizes in
        the sample being analysed. Furthermore, in many applications, the interest is directly on
        the AEP of a given flood magnitude (e.g. the spillway capacity of an existing dam), rather
        than on the flood magnitude for a given design AEP (relevant to design of new structures
        with a standards-based approach).</para>
      <para>However, as indicated in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>, the question of when it is
        appropriate to apply an expected probability adjustment is a complex one, and the decision
        depends on a number of theoretical and practical considerations. In general, the estimates
        of risk for Rare to Extreme floods are not used in an absolute sense, but to allow
        comparison with established levels of acceptable risk, or to establish risk-based economic
        costs for comparative evaluation of options.</para>
      <para>It should be noted that use of the Total Probability Theorem to derive flood quantiles
        using Monte Carlo Event procedures as described in <xref linkend="book4"/> yields expected
        probability quantiles. This approach ensures probability<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184020+1000" content="-"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184021+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>neutrality, at least for the set of hydrologic inputs used in its
        application. If estimates are derived from a blend of approaches, comments on the likely
        magnitude and importance of expected probability adjustments for different flood ranges are
        as follows:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Rare
              <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184621+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184619+1000" content="f"?>loods</emphasis>
            – significant extrapolation may be involved where these floods are estimated from
            frequency analysis of at-site data. The recommendations on the adjustment of <xref
              linkend="b3_ch2_s5"/> should thus be followed.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Very Rare
              <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184627+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184625+1000" content="f"?>loods</emphasis>
            – design rainfalls are estimated from regional analysis of large data sets. Generally
            this does not involve extrapolation beyond the probability plotting positions of the
            largest events, and any expected probability adjustment would thus be relatively minor
            for the rainfall frequency distribution. However, there is usually significant
            extrapolation of the rainfall-runoff model. In such cases, parameter uncertainty in
            rainfall-runoff model parameters may lead to a significant expected probability
            adjustment. At present, there are no accepted methods for making this adjustment.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">PMP Flood</emphasis> – adjustment for expected probability
            may be appropriate in principle. However, current methods for estimation of the AEP of
            the PMP involve large uncertainties and are not sufficiently well developed to
            meaningfully apply expected probability.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Extreme
              <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184631+1000"?><?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184700+1000" comment="rory- should this dot point go above PMP"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T184630+1000" content="f"?>loods<?oxy_comment_end?></emphasis>
            – these are derived by methods of interpolation from other estimates for which an
            adjustment may have been made. Therefore separate adjustment is not required.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_48x5y">
      <title>Applications Requiring Special Considerations</title>
      <para>The recommendations in this section apply only to the direct estimation of floods for
        the most common design applications without the consideration of other complicating factors.
        However, there may be some cases where some other set of circumstances may be critical for
        design. One example is dams with very large storages where it is necessary to take explicit
        account of initial storage level or rainfall sequences over very long durations. Another is
        the need to assess the likely rate of lake level rise to assist planning for emergency
        response purposes. The assessment of consequences on communities downstream of a dam may
        require consideration of concurrent floods in adjacent catchments. Also, a series of dams
        along a given stream requires special consideration, as failure of an upstream dam could
        impose more severe conditions on a downstream dam than its normal design flood. It is the
        responsibility of the
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T185908+1000" content="designer "?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T185908+1000"?>practitioner
        <?oxy_insert_end?>to consider all circumstances that are critical for design. A number of
        issues related to these and other special design considerations are discussed in <xref
          linkend="b8_ch7"/>.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_e0h7b">
    <title>Flood Data Based Estimates</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_qy5nn">
      <title>General</title>
      <para>The recommended methods for frequency analysis of Australian flood data are outlined in
          <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>. When selecting suitable data and methods for flood frequency
        analyses in the context of this Book, it should be kept in mind that the specific interest
        is on the upper tail of flood frequency distributions. This requires careful scrutiny of the
        accuracy of the largest flood observations in relation to possible data problems, in
        particular the accuracy of rating curves in the extrapolated range. Analysis of annual flood
        series would generally be more appropriate than partial series and, where available, data on
        large historical floods should be incorporated in the analysis. Similarly, the value of
        limited flood data at the site of interest may be enhanced by combining the results of
        at-site<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190351+1000"?> Flood<?oxy_insert_end?>
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190355+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190355+1000" content="f"?>requency
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190359+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190358+1000" content="a"?>nalysis
        and regional flood frequency
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190449+1000" comment="should this be estimation rather than analysis given p5 is regional flood frequency estimation"?>analysis<?oxy_comment_end?>,
        using data from a number of sites within a homogeneous region. The special case of
        incorporating paleoflood data in the analysis is discussed briefly in <xref
          linkend="b8_s_aaq3x"/>.</para>
      <para>In principle, it is also possible to derive design flood estimates for a site downstream
        of a reservoir directly from
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190503+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190502+1000" content="f"?>lood
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190506+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190505+1000" content="f"?>requency
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190509+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190508+1000" content="a"?>nalysis
        of flood data available at that site. However, for reservoirs with large storage capacity
        compared to typical flood volumes, and with significant inter-event variability of reservoir
        flood storage, a much longer data series is required to adequately sample the combined
        effects of inflow and storage content variability. In these cases, the scope for
        extrapolation of directly determined flood frequency curves to the range
        of<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190604+1000" content=" Large"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190604+1000"?>
        Rare<?oxy_insert_end?> to
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190612+1000"?>Very
        <?oxy_insert_end?>Rare events is severely limited. <xref linkend="b8_s_q68kr"/> gives
        further guidance on the derivation of reservoir outflow frequency curves.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_0zdby">
      <title>Applications of Results of Flood Frequency Analysis</title>
      <para>There are four different cases of how flood estimates based directly on
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190629+1000" content="f"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190630+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?>lood
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190632+1000" content="f"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190633+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?>requency
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190635+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190635+1000" content="a"?>nalysis
        can contribute to the estimation of Rare to Extreme design floods:</para>
      <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">as direct basis for estimating Rare floods for final design
              applications:</emphasis> where the range of AEPs is limited to 1 in 100 (perhaps 1 in
            200 AEP for analysis of at-site and regional data);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">as direct basis for estimating Rare to Very Rare floods for
              preliminary design or performance checks:</emphasis> where the lowest AEP of interest
            is around 1 in 200 (for analysis of at-site flood data only) or perhaps 1 in 500 (for
            analysis of at-site and regional flood data);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">as a basis for determining the lower end of a complete flood
              frequency curve:</emphasis> where an estimate of the PMP Flood is available but no
            rainfall-based estimates of Rare to Very Rare floods;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">as basis for independent checking of rainfall-based design
              flood estimates and possible adjustment of model parameters:</emphasis> where
            rainfall-based design floods are to be determined for the full range of design floods,
            from Rare to Extreme.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>Cases (i) and (ii) only involve extension of the flood frequency curve to the credible
        limit of extrapolation, but case (iii) requires the estimation of the PMP Flood and the
        application of an interpolation procedure for intermediate events (<xref
          linkend="b8_s_3o5gi"/>). Case (iv) requires detailed consideration of how the flood
        estimates from different sources can best be reconciled (<xref linkend="b8_s_20a81"
        />).</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_aaq3x">
      <title>Incorporation of Paleohydrological Estimates</title>
      <para>Paleohydrological estimates of floods are based on the study of the geomorphic and
        stratigraphic record of past floods, as well as evidence of past floods and streamflow
        derived from historical, archeological, dendrochronologic, or other sources. The advantage
        of paleohydrologic data <citation>b8_c_r73</citation> is that it is often possible to
        develop records that are 10 to 100 times longer than conventional or historical records from
        other data sources. This information thus has the potential to provide estimates of Very
        Rare flood peaks that are independent of rainfall-based procedures. Such information can
        provide estimates of design floods directly, or else can be used to help select probability<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190905+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T190904+1000" content="-"?>neutral
        design inputs for rainfall-based procedures (<xref linkend="b8_s_ghmj4"/>).</para>
      <para>Overall, it is recognised that paleohydrological techniques have received little
        attention in Australia to date, but their potential for providing useful information on Very
        Rare floods has been demonstrated in other countries (most notably the Western United
        States). In view of the potential benefits, it is recommended that the use of paleoflood
        data should be considered where expenditure of the additional resources can be justified.
        Further information on the incorporation of paleoflood data in flood frequency analysis is
        provided in <xref linkend="b3_ch2_s3"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_laqj1">
      <title>Preliminary Estimate of Rare to Extreme Events</title>
      <para>There are some design situations where it is desirable to derive approximate design
        flood estimates by applying a “quick” method. Examples of situations where preliminary
        estimates are desirable include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>flood estimates for preliminary assessment of spillway adequacy of existing
            dams;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>determination of priorities for the undertaking of detailed studies;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>estimation of concurrent floods of minor importance for the analysis of incremental
            consequences arising from dam failure;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>preliminary evaluation of different dam sites for planning studies; and,</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>determination of hydrologic loads in a portfolio risk analysis of a group of
            storages.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The overall requirement for these types of analyses is that estimates can be derived
        quickly, and that given the large uncertainty the flood estimates should be biased towards
        conservatively high values.</para>
      <para>Preliminary estimates should not be used for final design purposes, nor should the
        results be relied upon for making decisions about long term levels of acceptable risk.
        Practitioners are encouraged to use any information and methods that they consider
        appropriate, and the following recommendations are provided for general guidance
        only.</para>
      <para>Generally two types of preliminary design estimates are required:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Peak
            discharge</emphasis><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T191112+1000" content=" "?>:
            estimates of peak discharge are directly suitable for the preliminary design of bridge
            waterways and spillways for those storages where it can be conservatively assumed that
            only minor attenuation of the inflow hydrograph occurs;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Flood
            hydrograph</emphasis><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T191115+1000" content=" "?>:
            estimates of the hydrograph are required where it is necessary to obtain an estimate of
            flood volume as well as peak discharge, for example the sizing of detention basins or
            the assessment of spillway adequacy for storages which appreciably attenuate the inflow
            hydrograph.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_9wuy4">
        <title>Preliminary Estimates of Peak Discharge</title>
        <para>One possible approach to deriving a frequency curve of peak discharges is to derive
          preliminary estimates of Rare events from
          <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210053+1000" content="f"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210038+1000"?>Fl<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210049+1000" content="l"?>ood
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210041+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210040+1000" content="f"?>requency
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210043+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210043+1000" content="a"?>nalysis
          and regional methods (<xref linkend="b3_ch2"/> and <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>), and for the
          PMP Flood. Preliminary estimates of the PMP Flood can be conservatively approximated by
          estimates of the PMF. Regional prediction equations for the PMF are available for some
          regions (e.g<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210142+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
          <citation>b8_c_r48,b8_c_r56,b8_c_r37,b8_c_88<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181004T121021+1000"?>,b8_c_r99<?oxy_insert_end?></citation>),
          though envelope curves for world floods may also provide useful information
            <citation>b8_c_r17</citation>. The preliminary estimates of the PMP Flood are plotted at
          the relevant AEP of PMP for the catchment using the recommendations provided in <xref
            linkend="b8_s_bb68z"/>. These flood estimates can then be used to construct a frequency
          curve based on a log-Normal approximation,
          i.e<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210243+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
          by fitting a straight line through the flood peaks in the logarithmic domain and
          probability as a standardised normal variate. Previous guidance
            <citation>b8_c_r49</citation> recommended use of shape factors to define intermediate
          quantiles, but use of a simple log-Normal relationship should be sufficient as long as due
          regard is given to the large uncertainties involved.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_gi5wf">
        <title>Preliminary Estimates of Design Hydrographs</title>
        <para>Estimates of the complete design hydrograph can also be obtained in a variety of ways.
          Such estimates generally require more time and effort in application than estimates of
          peak discharge, particularly as the estimated inflow hydrographs often need to be routed
          through a structure to assess the degree of attenuation.</para>
        <para>Estimates of the volume of the hydrographs can easily be determined from estimates of
          design rainfalls and losses. The volume of the hydrograph can simply be determined as the
          average depth of rainfall excess over the catchment multiplied by the catchment area.
          Appropriate hydrograph shapes can be derived by scaling hydrographs obtained from either
          detailed studies on similar catchments or from suitable at-site records, though
          hydrographs obtained from rainfall-based models (using regional parameters) can be scaled
          to suit the preliminary peaks derived
          <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210357+1000" content="as described above"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210357+1000"?>in
            <?oxy_insert_end?><xref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b8_s_9wuy4"
          />.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_ghmj4">
    <title>Rainfall Based Estimates</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_ce00a">
      <title>General</title>
      <para>General guidance on the estimation of design flood hydrographs using rainfall-based
        procedures is provided in <xref linkend="b4_ch2"/> and <xref linkend="b4_ch3"/>. The
        following sub-sections provide guidance of specific relevance to the estimation of Very Rare
        to Extreme design floods, and should be read in conjunction with the guidance provided in
          <xref linkend="book4"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_of1ah">
      <title>Surface Runoff Hydrographs</title>
      <para>The key input to the procedures is the appropriate design rainfall information from
          <xref linkend="b8_ch3"/>. Rainfall excess must be estimated from the design rainfalls
        after due allowance is given to catchment losses (<xref linkend="b8_ch4"/>). A
        rainfall-runoff model must then be used to convert the rainfall excess into the design
        hydrograph of direct runoff (<xref linkend="b8_ch5"/>).</para>
      <para>Where suitable rainfall and runoff data are available, the model selected should be
        calibrated using observed floods on the catchment of interest and, where appropriate, the
        parameter values should be adjusted to help reconcile differences between design values
        derived from
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210602+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210600+1000" content="f"?>lood
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210604+1000" content="f"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210605+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?>requency
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210607+1000" content="a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210607+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?>nalysis
        and rainfall-based methods (<xref linkend="b8_s_20a81"/>). In other cases, design values for
        the model parameters must be estimated from calibration on adjacent gauged catchments,
        regional relationships, or other relevant information. Where a concentrated
        storage<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210650+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210650+1000" content="&lt;emphasis role=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;,&lt;/emphasis&gt;"?>
        such as a reservoir or lake, can have a significant impact on the catchment response to
        rainfall, allowance must be made for its effect (<xref linkend="b8_s_e7p2b"/>). Design
        hydrographs usually need to be estimated for a range of design rainfall durations and AEPs
        in order to derive a complete flood frequency curve, and this is discussed in <xref
          linkend="b8_s_3o5gi"/>.</para>
      <para>The rainfall-based procedure described above provides estimates of design floods that
        are comprised solely of direct runoff,
        i.e<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210723+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
        that portion of the hydrograph that is derived from event-based rainfall excess. To derive
        design floods that reflect the total volume of the hydrographs, it is necessary to add
        baseflow<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210737+1000"?>
          (<?oxy_insert_end?><xref linkend="b8_s_fzd4a"
        /><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210737+1000"?>)<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T210732+1000" content=", as discussed below"?>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_fzd4a">
      <title>Incorporation of Baseflow</title>
      <para>The hydrograph models generally only give the direct storm runoff, and some baseflow
        must be added to obtain the total hydrograph. While the proportion of baseflow is generally
        small compared with direct runoff, especially for Very Rare to Extreme floods, it may be of
        significance when simulating long duration events in volume-dependent problems
        (e.g<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T171436+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
        dam outflows).</para>
      <para>Baseflow estimates for Rare events should be based on procedures described in <xref
          linkend="b5_ch4"/>. Where there is clear evidence that initial baseflow increases with
        flood magnitude a constant baseflow 20% to 50% greater than the maximum value estimated in
        observed floods may be appropriate for Extreme events. If the difference between these two
        baseflow values is of minor importance then a representative, fixed value could be used for
        all intermediate AEPs.
        However<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T171516+1000"?>,<?oxy_insert_end?>
        if deemed appropriate, the magnitude of the baseflow could be varied linearly on a plot of
        baseflow versus log(AEP) between the value adopted for the 1 in 100 AEP event and that
        adopted for the flood resulting from the PMP (alternatively <xref linkend="b8_e_4dyk0"/>
        could be used).</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_zdb5x">
      <title>Simulation Framework</title>
      <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch3_s_ccenm"/>, event-based models can be applied in a
        deterministic fashion (“simple event” simulation), where key inputs are fixed at
        representative values that minimise the probability bias in the transformation of rainfall
        into runoff. Alternatively, stochastic techniques can be used to explicitly resolve the
        joint probabilities of key hydrologic interactions; ensemble techniques provide simple (and
        approximate) means of minimising the bias associated with a single hydrologic variable,
        whereas Monte Carlo techniques represent a more rigorous solution that can be expanded to
        consider interactions from a range of natural and anthropogenic factors.</para>
      <para>There seems little justification for use of <emphasis role="italic">simple
          event</emphasis> approaches for the estimation of Very Rare to Extreme floods as the
        dominant source of natural variability that influences flood magnitude for this class of
        events (other than rainfall depth) is typically the temporal pattern of
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T172028+1000" comment="rory- is this word correct?"?>incident
        <?oxy_comment_end?>rainfall. The <emphasis role="italic">ensemble event</emphasis> method
          (<xref linkend="b3_ch3_s_ynzmg"/>) represents a modest increase in computational
        requirements, whereby a representative sample of temporal patterns is used to provide a
        centrally tended estimate (either the arithmetic mean or the median) of the peak flow
        associated with the AEP of the input rainfall. A representative hydrograph from the ensemble
        can be scaled to match the derived peak for design purposes.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">Monte Carlo event</emphasis> approaches provide the additional
        attraction that losses can be sampled (where designs are sensitive to long-duration events),
        along with other factors which may have a significant influence on the design outcome (such
        as reservoir drawdown, or spatial patterns of rainfall).</para>
      <para>The general issues involved in the selection of the simulation framework are discussed
        in <xref linkend="book4"/>, though it should be noted that the estimation of extreme events
        can involve more significant degrees of non-linearity than present in the estimation of more
        frequent floods. For example, use of an ensemble event method to assess the influence of
        initial reservoir level on outflow floods is likely to provide highly biased estimates,
        which is avoided if a Monte Carlo scheme based on the Total Probability Theorem is
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T172604+1000" comment="or similar?"?>used<?oxy_comment_end?>
          (<xref linkend="book4"/>).</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_3o5gi">
      <title>Derivation of Complete Design Flood Frequency Curve</title>
      <para>The shape of the complete flood frequency curve in the Rare to Extreme event is largely
        determined by the shape of the design rainfall frequency curve described in <xref
          linkend="b8_ch3"/>. Design rainfall inputs for specified AEPs are then converted to flood
        outputs in a probability<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T180630+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T180629+1000" content="-"?>neutral
        fashion,
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181031+1000" comment="need a specific reference"?>as
        discussed above<?oxy_comment_end?>. For each AEP, flood outputs for a range of different
        durations have to be determined, and the one that gives the highest peak discharge
        (corresponding to the critical duration) is generally adopted. Minor adjustment of design
        inputs or smoothing of derived design floods for different critical durations may be
        required to obtain a smooth flood frequency curve. It is expected that estimates of Rare to
        Very Rare floods represent the “best estimate” obtained from multiple methods, as described
        in
        the<?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181137+1000" comment="need a specific section"?>
        preceding section<?oxy_comment_end?>.</para>
      <para>While the focus of the guidance in this Book is on Very Rare to Extreme flood events, it
        is important to check that the models yield estimates that are consistent with available
        evidence. Estimates of Rare floods provide the “anchor point” for derivation of more extreme
        events, and it is advisable to select a best estimate by weighting the estimates obtained
        from different methods by their uncertainty. In practice, however, the information required
        to do this is limited and it is recommended that where possible rainfall-based estimates are
        reconciled with independent estimates from
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181219+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181219+1000" content="f"?>lood
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181222+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181221+1000" content="f"?>requency
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181224+1000" content="a"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181224+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?>nalysis
        or regional flood
        m<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181416+1000" content="odels "?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181416+1000"?>ethod
        <?oxy_insert_end?>estimates (<xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181425+1000"?>and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181424+1000" content="&amp;amp;"?>
        <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>).</para>
      <para>An example of such reconciliation is illustrated in <xref linkend="b8_f_sw31s"/>. In
        this example the independent estimates are obtained from
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181439+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181439+1000" content="f"?>lood
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181442+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181441+1000" content="f"?>requency
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181445+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181444+1000" content="a"?>nalysis
        of observed annual maxima; the initial rainfall-based estimates were obtained from
        calibration of model parameters to historical floods (dashed <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181556+1000" content="red"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181556+1000"?>blue<?oxy_insert_end?>
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181653+1000" comment="changed to reflect the colours on the redrawn figure"?>line<?oxy_comment_end?>,
          <xref linkend="b8_f_sw31s"/>), and the loss parameters were then adjusted within their
        expected range to better align with the results obtained from
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181458+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181457+1000" content="f"?>lood
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181501+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181500+1000" content="f"?>requency
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181504+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181503+1000" content="a"?>nalysis
        (solid
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181604+1000" content="red"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181604+1000"?>blue<?oxy_insert_end?>
        line). As discussed in <xref linkend="b8_s_20a81"/>, reconciliation is best achieved by
        adjustment of the loss parameters within reasonable limits where routing parameters are
        obtained from fitting to historical floods. Ideally, the loss parameters should be
        reconciled jointly with quantiles based on flood peaks as well as flood volumes, where the
        duration over which flood volumes are calculated correspond to the critical duration of
        interest
        (e.g<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T182152+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
        the duration of a storm that yields maximum levels in a storage). The objective of such
        reconciliation is to adjust loss parameters within reasonable bounds to achieve a result
        that is reasonably consistent with both flood peak and flood volume quantiles, allowing for
        uncertainty in these estimates and the final best estimates based on consideration of both
        approaches should reflect the relative weight given to each approach for the range of AEPs
        of interest.</para>
      <para>In reconciling differences in flood estimates from rainfall–based and flood frequency
        procedures, the assumptions behind each procedure should be carefully examined. For example
        with rainfall-based procedures, there is very little known about the manner in which
        non-linearity changes with flood magnitude, and the differences between design flood
        estimates may easily be explained by different assumptions regarding non-linearity.
        Similarly, certain assumptions will be inherent in the available period of flood record and
        quality of the rating curve. Ideally, the uncertainties should be explicitly evaluated to
        determine confidence limits, but in practice, sensitivity analysis of design
        inputs/parameters within expected limits will need to suffice.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b8_f_sw31s">
        <title>Illustration of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181836+1000"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181836+1000" content="d"?>erived
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181839+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181838+1000" content="f"?>requency
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181841+1000"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181841+1000" content="c"?>urve
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181843+1000"?>B<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181843+1000" content="b"?>ased
          on
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181846+1000"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181845+1000" content="r"?>econciliation
          with
          <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181848+1000" content="f"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181848+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?>lood
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181850+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181850+1000" content="f"?>requency
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181853+1000"?>Q<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181852+1000" content="q"?>uantiles<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181857+1000" content="."?></title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/8006.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_gbk9t">
    <title>Estimation of the Probable Maximum Flood</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_6e5at">
      <title>Design Context</title>
      <para>The Probable Maximum Flood (PMF) is a hypothetical flood estimate relevant to a specific
        catchment whose magnitude is such that there is negligible chance of
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T181925+1000"?>it
        <?oxy_insert_end?>being exceeded. It represents a notional upper limit of flood magnitude
        and no attempt is made to assign a probability of exceedance to such an event. The concept
        of the PMF has been an important element in design flood standards for dams in the United
        States and Australia over the past 60 to 70 years
          <citation>b8_c_r44,b8_c_r6,b8_c_r1</citation>. It is commonly used in many other countries
          <citation>b8_c_r90</citation>, though there are some countries, such as Russia, with
        little experience of the method and where preference is given to probabilistic methods
          <citation>b8_c_r86</citation>.</para>
      <para>The PMF is also used to define the extent of flood-prone land
          <citation>b8_c_89</citation>. The extent, nature and potential consequences of flooding
        associated with a range of events up to and including the PMF event is considered in some
        floodplain management studies. The PMF causes the largest scale of flood emergency and is
        also therefore often used for emergency management planning
        <citation>b8_c_89</citation>.</para>
      <para><citation>b8_c_r61+1</citation> defined the PMF as the limiting value of flood that
        could <emphasis role="italic">reasonably</emphasis> be expected to occur. Superimposing
        risks of very low probabilities was not considered reasonable, but it was considered prudent
        to incorporate some degree of conservatism. While it is possible to estimate an upper
        limiting value of flood magnitude, the estimation of its AEP is subject to even greater
        uncertainty than that of the PMP. Conservatively estimated (reasonably possible) values of
        the factors involved in the transformation of the PMP to the PMF introduce a shift in
        probability but, because the phrase “reasonably possible” is a qualitative description of
        probability, the AEP of the resulting flood varies depending on the degree of conservatism
        adopted. In practice, the magnitude of the PMF will be greater than the magnitude of the
        flood derived from the PMP using a transformation based on probability<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182131+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182130+1000" content="-"?>neutral
        objectives, but its AEP will be smaller.</para>
      <para>Concerns around the difficulties of estimating the PMF in a consistent manner have been
        recognised for a long
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182209+1000" content="while "?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182209+1000"?>time
        <?oxy_insert_end?>(eg, <citation>b8_c_r91,b8_c_r3,b8_c_r92</citation>). While the notion of
        a “probable maximum” flood standard appears a simple enough concept, in practice its
        estimation is confounded by a number of key problems <citation>b8_c_r51</citation>,
        namely:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The lack of established criteria to determine the “reasonableness” with which to
            combine the various flood producing factors;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The level of subjectivity inherent in assigning limiting maxima;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Limited understanding of physical factors that constrain extrapolation of flood<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182242+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182241+1000" content="-"?>producing
            processes and their representation in models;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Differential availability of relevant design information across the country;
            and,</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Poor selection of model structure and calibration of model parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Accordingly, the intention of the recommendations
        here<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182301+1000"?>in<?oxy_insert_end?>
        is to retain the concept that the PMF represents the limiting value of flood that could
        reasonably be expected to occur, but to provide additional considerations that reduce the
        scope for inconsistency.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_9ywyy">
      <title>General Guidance</title>
      <para>In the derivation of the PMF, the probability<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182318+1000" content="-"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182318+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>neutral objective for selection of design inputs is explicitly rejected in
        favour of adopting conservatively high estimates. With regard to losses, the general
        recommendations provided in <xref linkend="b8_s_zl6ib"/> should be adopted, i.e. losses
        should be equal to or possibly a little less than the minimum value in large floods observed
        on the catchment. In all cases, losses are likely to be low; in many regions of Australia a
        burst initial loss value of zero and a continuing loss rate of 1 mm/hr will be appropriate.
        If pre-burst temporal patterns are used to represent complete storms, then it would be
        expected that the storm initial losses would be greater than zero, but at the lower end of
        the range of losses adopted for estimation of the PMP Flood.</para>
      <para>The temporal patterns used to derive the PMF should be selected from an ensemble of
        patterns appropriate for use with the Generalised PMP (<xref linkend="b8_s_4n0lw"/>).
        Rearrangement of rainfall intensities within the patterns to give the highest possible flood
        peak may yield rainfall patterns with implausible serial correlation structure and is at
        variance with the objective of deriving a limiting value of flood that could reasonably
        occur. An estimate of a reasonable upper limiting value of floods may be derived by using
        the temporal (or spatially varying
        temporal<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182606+1000"?>
        (space-time<?oxy_insert_end?>) pattern from the available ensemble that yields the maximum
        flood characteristic of interest. It should be recognised that temporal and space-time
        patterns of rainfall based on historical events (<xref linkend="b2_ch4"/>) are usually based
        on a limited number of pluviometers; when scaled to PMP storms over large catchments such
        patterns may yield embedded bursts of rainfall that are quite unrealistic. Accordingly, the
        characteristics of the PMF derived using a single temporal (or space-time) pattern should be
        checked against the results obtained from other patterns in the available ensemble. If the
        difference between the maximum adopted pattern and other results is anomalously large, then
        it may be appropriate to adopt a less severe pattern so as not to superimpose inputs of very
        low probabilities.</para>
      <para>The hydrograph models used to transform the PMP to the PMF should follow the general
        recommendations provided in <xref linkend="b8_s_zvvef"/> and <xref linkend="b8_s_cd813"/>.
        Parameter values should be selected in accordance with the recommendations provided in <xref
          linkend="b8_s_tbwiz"/>. The selection of other design inputs, such as initial reservoir
        level or snowpack depth, should be representative of the more extreme conditions that could
        reasonably be expected to occur.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_r5m2j">
      <title>Assessment of Reasonableness</title>
      <para>The derivation of a PMF in floodplain management studies is
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182724+1000" content="quite"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182724+1000"?>relatively<?oxy_insert_end?>
        straightforward as generally the information is only used to assess the upper bound of
        potential inundation. In Australia, the 1 in 100 AEP flood is often used to define levels of
        tolerable risk, and floodplain management activities are thus largely insensitive to the
        level of conservatism used to derive the PMF.</para>
      <para>However, PMFs are most often used in the context of assessing dam safety. The cost
        implications of upgrading dams may well be very sensitive to the degree of conservatism
        adopted by practitioners when assessing the “reasonableness” of assumptions used to derive
        the PMF. For example, as illustrated in <xref linkend="b8_f_xy0k6"/>a (dashed curve), the
        costs of providing additional flood capacity may increase monotonically with flood
        magnitude; under such a scenario there is no obvious point where the upgrade costs increase
        disproportionally with the degree of conservatism adopted. However, if there is a step
        function involved in the relationship between flood capacity and cost – for example if an
        additional spillway is required because the practical limit of extending a wave wall has
        been reached (solid curve in <xref linkend="b8_f_xy0k6"/>a) – then a small difference in
        subjective judgement may have a significant impact on the costs and feasibility of an
        upgrade.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b8_f_xy0k6">
        <title>(a) Differential
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182836+1000"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182835+1000" content="i"?>mportance
          of
          “<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182839+1000"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182838+1000" content="r"?>easonableness”
          in PMF
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182842+1000"?>A<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182841+1000" content="a"?>ssumptions
          on
          <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182844+1000" content="d"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182845+1000"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?>am
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182847+1000"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182847+1000" content="s"?>afety
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182850+1000"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182849+1000" content="d"?>ecision-<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182852+1000" content="m"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182853+1000"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?>aking,
          and (b)
          <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182855+1000" content="u"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182858+1000"?>U<?oxy_insert_end?>se
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182901+1000"?>S<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182900+1000" content="s"?>imple
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182903+1000"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182903+1000" content="e"?>xtrapolation
          to
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182906+1000"?>I<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182905+1000" content="i"?>nfer
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182909+1000"?>D<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182909+1000" content="d"?>egree
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182913+1000"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182913+1000" content="r"?>easonableness<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182915+1000" content="."?></title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/8007.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>It is clearly undesirable that small differences in subjective assessments of
        “reasonableness” might have a large impact on design costs. Accordingly, in some situations
        it will be prudent to explicitly examine the impact of any subjective hydrological
        judgement, and the final decision regarding the appropriate level of conservatism should be
        made in consultation with the wider dam safety engineering team involved.</para>
      <para>To this end, the following steps may be warranted when providing an estimate of the
        PMF:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Derive the estimate of the PMP Flood under probability<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182956+1000" content="-"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T182956+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?>neutral
            assumptions<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T183003+1000" content="."?></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Then, derive a deterministic estimate of the PMF using:<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>0 mm burst initial and 1 mm/hr continuing loss rates (or higher as justified
                  for such regions as the south west of
                  <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T183030+1000" content="w"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T183030+1000"?>W<?oxy_insert_end?>estern
                  Australia);</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>the temporal (or space-time) pattern from a sample of ten that yields the
                  highest magnitude flow;</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>if the design is for a dam, then adopt an initial storage at Full Supply
                  Level.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Estimate the shift in AEP associated with the difference in magnitude between the
            PMP Flood and the PMF (by simple extrapolation as shown in <xref linkend="b8_f_xy0k6"
            />b).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>If a deterministic modelling framework is used to estimate the PMP Flood, then
            undertake a number of simulations using inputs selected from a plausible range of values
            to understand the catchment<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T183110+1000"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T183110+1000" content="-"?>specific
            impacts of the PMF assumptions made.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>If a Monte Carlo framework is used to estimate the PMP Flood, then also calculate
            the proportion of samples in which the PMF is exceeded given the PMP
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181004T121327+1000"?>depth
            <?oxy_insert_end?>as input. If the shift in AEP (as shown in <xref linkend="b8_f_xy0k6"
            />b) is greater than one order of magnitude, or the conditional probability that the PMF
            is exceeded is less than
            <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20181004T121340+1000"?>around 10% to
            <?oxy_insert_end?>1%, then revisit assumptions used to derive the PMF and relax as
            appropriate.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Finally, check the sensitivity of any decisions that are to be based on the PMF
            estimate – if there is a marked difference in outcome within a range of estimates that
            could be considered to be based on a “reasonable” set of assumptions, then reach
            agreement with the wider engineering team on the appropriate degree of conservatism to
            adopt.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>It is expected that the above steps will only be required in a small proportion of cases
        in which design and or mitigation costs increase disproportionally with the degree of
        conservatism adopted.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_21g0w">
    <title>Treatment of Uncertainty</title>
    <para>Uncertainties in the estimation of extreme floods have important economic and social
      consequences, and thus recognition of the impacts of uncertainty should be incorporated into
      advice given to management and political decision makers. If there are significant differences
      in outcome within the range of uncertainty then the likely range of consequences should be
      explicitly considered when developing mitigation strategies and advice. An under-estimate of
      the flood magnitude will lead to the infrastructure being under-designed, thus potentially
      resulting in increased flood damage costs and possible loss of life. Conversely, an
      over-estimate of the flood magnitude will lead to extra costs from the over-design of the
      infrastructure.</para>
    <para>General guidance on techniques for characterising uncertainty is presented in <xref
        linkend="book7"/>. In the context of this Book, it should be stressed that the uncertainty
      or flood estimation error increases with increasing size of flood (or reducing AEP) and the
      relative impacts of different sources of uncertainty also change with flood magnitude.
      Uncertainty in the AEP of the PMP becomes increasingly important beyond the credible limit of
      extrapolation, and so does the epistemic uncertainty associated with the increasing lack of
      evidence to support the process descriptions of salient factors
      (e.g<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T183330+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
      temporal and spatial characteristics of rainfall) and model structure
      (e.g<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160614T183334+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?>
      degree of non-linearity in flood behaviour).</para>
    <para>The estimation of Very Rare to Extreme floods is a region where “the computation of
      hydrologic probabilities is based on arbitrary assumptions about the probabilistic behaviour
      of hydrologic processes rather than on empirical evidence or theoretical knowledge and
      understanding of these processes” <citation>b8_c_r31</citation>. Improving the consistency of
      the manner in which such assumptions are applied in practice will thus minimise the potential
      for differences in the results obtained by different hydrologists. The main strategy available
      for reducing the impact of this form of uncertainty is to ensure that the practitioners
      undertaking the work are appropriately qualified and supervised. In addition, prescriptive
      procedures relating to the estimation of floods beyond the credible limit of extrapolation are
      justifiable as without empirical evidence or scientific justification there can be little
      rational basis for departing from a consensus approach.</para>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
  
</chapter>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>