<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS/DTD Docbook XML V4.2//EN" "c:/program%20files%20(x86)/corel/wordperfect%20office%20x6/languages/en/XML/DTD/DocBook4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- Generated by WordPerfect(R) X6 -->
<book>
<chapter label="Chapter1">
<title></title>
<section label="heading1">
<title>INTRODUCTION</title>
<para></para>
<para>Flood frequency analysis refers to procedures that use recorded and related flood data to
select and fit a probability model of flood peaks at a particular location in the catchment.  The
flood probability model can then be used to perform risk-based design and flood risk
assessment and to provide input to regional flood estimation methods.</para>
<para></para>
<para>This chapter considers the issues and techniques useful when undertaking a flood frequency
analysis using flood data at a single site.  It represents an evolutionary update of Chapter 10 in
the 3<superscript>rd</superscript> Edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff (Pilgrim and Doran, 1987).  Nonetheless,
where appropriate the original contribution by Pilgrim and Doran has been retained.  The
major changes include introduction of non-homogeneous probability models to account for
long-term climate variability, abandonment of product log-moments with the log-Pearson III
distribution, use of Bayesian methods to make better use of available flood information (such
as censored flow data, rating error and regional information) and reduced prescription about
the choice of flood probability model.</para>
<para></para>
<para>The primary purpose of this chapter is to present guidelines on performing flood frequency
analyses.  Often judgment will need to be exercised.  To inform such judgments, the key
conceptual foundations that underpin flood frequency analysis are described; a reader,
however, will need an understanding of elementary probability theory and statistics to get
maximum benefit from this description.  In addition a number of worked examples are
provided to provide deeper insight with the implied caveat that the examples are not
exhaustive in their scope.  It is expected that users of at site flood frequency analysis will
encounter problems different to those explored in the examples.  While it is expected that
most users will use software written by others to implement the methods described in this
chapter, sufficient information is provided to enable users to develop their own software for
their applications.</para>
</section>
</chapter>
</book>
