<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<set version="5.0" xml:id="arr_style_guide"  xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    
    <title>ARR Style Set</title>
    
    <book status="Draft for Review">
        <title>Australian Rainfall and Runoff Style Guide</title>
        
        <chapter>
            <title>Introduction</title>
            
            <xi:include href="version.xml">
                <xi:fallback>
            	</xi:fallback>
            </xi:include>
                
            
            <para>If you follow the format of this document faithfully you will make our job easier and help ensure that all contributions in the final draft Australian Rainfall and Runoff look professional and consistent. Please take a minute or two to read through the following instructions before beginning your contribution.</para>
            
            <para>Many people seem to object to using a style prepared by others. Some feel that their paper would be better if the style was just a little bit different from the template. We all like to feel creative. Please understand that it is much easier in assembling the draft Australian Rainfall and Runoff if the same style is used for all papers. While this template may not result in your favourite style and it probably wouldn’t be mine, but it is OK, and the draft Australian Rainfall and Runoff will look much better if we go for consistency rather than a mixture of tastes in elegance.</para>
        </chapter>
        
        <chapter status="Internal Draft">
            <info>
                <title>Titles</title>
                
                <xi:include href="../common/authors/ball_james.xml" />
                
                <xi:include href="../common/authors/kuczera_george.xml" />
                
                <xi:include href="../common/authors/franks_stewart.xml" />
            </info>
            
            <para>Nota Bene: when using the XML in docbook please enter formal titles using title case, for example "This is a Sample Title".  The stylesheet will then handle the different capitalisation as required.</para>
            
            <para>The font for the chapter title should 16pt bold Times New Roman in Upper Case. Additionally the chapter title should be centred.  As shown in this document.</para>
            
            <para>Author(s) names and affiliations follow the chapter title. The format for the author names is a 14pt bold Times New Roman font, centred on the page while the format for the affiliations is 12pt Times New Roman font, centred on the page.  Shown above is an example.</para>
            
            <para>Formats for three levels of heading are provided. These formats are:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>level 2 - 14pt bold Times New Roman, Upper Case</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>level 3 - 14pt bold Times New Roman, mixed Upper and Lower Case</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>level 4 - 11pt bold Times New Roman, mixed Upper and Lower Case</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>Examples of these formats are:</para>
            
            <section>
                <title>Level 2 Section</title>
                <para>Nisl consequat eum at ut iriure facilisi eum tation in eu. Illum feugait nostrud feugiat ad. In et euismod quis nisl dolore vel, dolore illum ex sit dolore.</para>
                <para>Duis nostrud lobortis tation eros qui blandit duis at nisl laoreet, nibh delenit, nulla enim molestie exerci, consequatvel feugait. Molestie velit ut nulla veniam quis iusto velit minim duis eum. Commodo nisl laoreet aliquip eum dolore in et feugiat ea crisare duis suscipit ut consectetuer, vel et, sciurus nulla quis lobortis. Facilisis, exerci sed iriuredolor ut sit delenit, elit velit eu delenit ad nisl at, nisl augue qui duis eu.</para>
                <para>Veniam, dignissim hendrerit nostrud luptatum vulputate illum ut duis exerci dolore. Eros praesent te ea veniam, tation ea facilisis et. Vel enim! Dignissim illum commodo molestie esse volutpat hendrerit duis molestie delenit.</para>
                <para>Qui sed delenit vel ad minim ipsum, lorem lobortis dolore ullamcorper, in at? Duis laoreet nonummy diam, vel exerci facilisis suscipit, et consectetuer. Facilisi ullamcorper et, iusto velit lobortis quis aliquam ut eu vel eum illum sciurus. Nostrud, ad nibh vulputate, te ex laoreet vero dolore duis quis exerci.</para>
                <para>Erat at quis amet illum enim nisl facilisi, illum amet aliquam vulputate, euismod ut facilisi crisare eros. Delenit wisi ut, accumsan suscipit, iusto te, eu ut dignissim! Crisare delenit lobortis, molestie tation velit ut elit sit crisare lorem in molestie, feugiat aliquip.</para>
                
                <section>
                    <title>Level 3 Section</title>
                    <para>Feugait ullamcorper iusto amet augue laoreet, dolore ullamcorper vero eros, consequatvel autem. Nisl feugiat vulputate vel. Consectetuer et augue volutpat dolore ut nostrud consequatvel ad vulputate ad odio.</para>
                    <para>Iriure eros dolore suscipit vero commodo autem vero in iusto nulla accumsan amet hendrerit illum vero ut. Nostrud, tation augue consequat ut eu vulputate dignissim, duis blandit praesent! Vero nisl sciurus tation iusto dolor nulla feugait duis tation ullamcorper nulla tation, te laoreet. Feugiat, erat consequatvel dignissim duis facilisi autem aliquam wisi consequat?</para>
                    <para>Praesent esse praesent eum nostrud iriure ad vulputate amet magna ex erat ex, exerci volutpat euismod ex amet. Consequat nulla ut ad esse, ex iriure hendrerit? Ullamcorper minim blandit molestie eros ad feugait illum consequat dolor duis. Et nostrud consequatvel eu feugiat nulla aliquip in duis sed, erat lobortis feugait facilisi odio?</para>
                    <para>Wisi qui et in nostrud ut ullamcorper velit facilisi feugait. Eros blandit, erat delenit praesent vel vulputate dignissim delenit.</para>
                    <para>Ad delenit tation volutpat augue ex autem, aliquam elit ad praesent enim in laoreet molestie, dolore sit quis hendrerit minim. Consequatvel odio exerci volutpat lobortis exerci in erat eu nostrud suscipit crisare. Euismod vero tation ullamcorper, in exerci, molestie delenit dignissim vero eu ea veniam! Exerci wisi, erat enim nibh dignissim et dolor hendrerit, aliquam blandit?</para>
                    
                    <section>
                        <title>Level 4 Heading</title>
                        <para>Duis euismod, dignissim in velit qui tincidunt in eros aliquam lobortis nisl facilisis ea. Ut quis accumsan aliquip dolore ea qui, in hendrerit odio euismod. Te euismod aliquip praesent, velit tincidunt suscipit diam tincidunt ipsum enim consectetuer facilisis enim vel facilisi, nonummy consequatvel eu et nostrud ut. Ullamcorper luptatum exerci sed eu veniam nulla wisi duis consequatvel dolor!</para>
                        <para>Diam te eros nisl augue, wisi vulputate in at nulla nostrud ad lorem facilisis accumsan? Dolor te consequatvel euismod aliquip nulla ut nostrud quis molestie aliquip nibh eu illum ut velit. Facilisi, minim nisl in iusto duis feugiat feugait velit facilisis luptatum accumsan illum feugiat eu duis, quis luptatum erat in. Ut aliquam ipsum enim nisl diam ut dolore nisl, in luptatum esse feugait iriure minim.</para>
                        <para>Feugait lobortis augue blandit, praesent autem ex eu duis ut vero. Tincidunt commodo facilisis aliquip wisi vel duis eu suscipit, nulla hendrerit facilisi dignissim veniam praesent nulla iriure ullamcorper nulla nisl, tincidunt wisi facilisis. Amet, blandit illum at ullamcorper wisi illum amet velit vero, accumsan ex feugiat lobortis!</para>
                        <para>Autem tincidunt et tation adipiscing, feugait esse consequat facilisi sed lorem duis at ut! Wisi, aliquam illum et vulputate ut autem dolor exerci quis facilisis lobortis et vel iriuredolor ut volutpat autem. Feugiat elit erat nulla facilisi wisi dolore eu enim at elit luptatum.</para>
                        <para>Ipsum, nulla at volutpat vel wisi duis aliquam vero. Qui nisl facilisis in ea laoreet te facilisis consequatvel. Illum accumsan nulla ex ipsum tation eu tincidunt minim iusto minim, consequat nisl?</para>
                    </section>
                </section>
            </section>
            
        </chapter>
        
        <chapter>
            <title>Text Conventions</title>
            
            <para>The format for standard text is:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>The font is Times New Roman 11pt.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>Full justification of text.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>Line spacing should be 1.5 with zero spacing prior to and post paragraphs.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>The first line of paragraphs is not indented.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>A single line should be inserted between paragraphs.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>Two blank spaces should be inserted between sentences.</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </chapter>
        
        <chapter>
            <title>Equations</title>
            
            <para>Equations should be centred on the line and numbered consecutively. Equations should be located as close as possible to the location of the cite. The cite should take the form of Equation book.chapter.number. It is worth noting that the final book and chapter number may be defined later after completion of the draft. Examples for both single line and multi-line equations are:</para>
            
            <equation xml:id="eq.dummy_single_line">
                <m:math display='block'>
                    <m:semantics>
                        <m:mrow>
                            <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mi>i</m:mi><m:mi>m</m:mi><m:mi>p</m:mi>
                                </m:mrow>
                            </m:msub>
                            <m:mo>=</m:mo><m:mfrac>
                                <m:mrow>
                                    <m:mstyle displaystyle='true'>
                                        <m:mo>&#x2211;</m:mo> <m:mrow>
                                            <m:mi>L</m:mi><m:mi>U</m:mi><m:msub>
                                                <m:malignmark/>
                                                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                            </m:msub>
                                            <m:msub>
                                                <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                                                <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                            </m:msub>
                                            
                                        </m:mrow>
                                    </m:mstyle>
                                </m:mrow>
                                <m:mi>A</m:mi>
                            </m:mfrac>
                            
                        </m:mrow>
                        <m:annotation encoding='MathType-MTEF'>MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=faaagCart1ev2aaaKnaaaaWenf2ys9wBH5garuavP1wzZbqedmvETj2BSbqefm0B1jxALjharqqtubsr4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8FesqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=xfr=xb9Gqpi0dc9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaamyqamaaBaaaleaacaWGPbGaamyBaiaadchaaeqaaOGaeyypa0ZaaSaaaeaadaaeabqaaiaadYeacaWGvbGaaCjaVpaaBaaaleaacaWGPbaabeaakiaadgeadaWgaaWcbaGaamyAaaqabaaabeqab0GaeyyeIuoaaOqaaiaadgeaaaaaaa@3C10@</m:annotation>
                    </m:semantics>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <equation>
                <m:math display='block'>
                    <m:semantics>
                        <m:mtable columnalign='left'>
                            <m:mtr>
                                <m:mtd>
                                    <m:mi>&#x03B1;</m:mi><m:mo>=</m:mo><m:mfrac>
                                        <m:mrow>
                                            <m:msqrt>
                                                <m:mrow>
                                                    <m:msub>
                                                        <m:mi>S</m:mi>
                                                        <m:mn>0</m:mn>
                                                    </m:msub>
                                                    
                                                </m:mrow>
                                            </m:msqrt>
                                            
                                        </m:mrow>
                                        <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                                    </m:mfrac>
                                    
                                </m:mtd>
                            </m:mtr>
                            <m:mtr>
                                <m:mtd>
                                    <m:mi>&#x03B2;</m:mi><m:mo>=</m:mo><m:mfrac>
                                        <m:mn>5</m:mn>
                                        <m:mn>3</m:mn>
                                    </m:mfrac>
                                    
                                </m:mtd>
                            </m:mtr>
                        </m:mtable>
                        
                        <m:annotation encoding='MathType-MTEF'>MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=faaagCart1ev2aaaKnaaaaWenf2ys9wBH5garuavP1wzZbqedmvETj2BSbqefm0B1jxALjharqqtubsr4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8FesqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=xfr=xb9Gqpi0dc9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGceaqabeaacqaHXoqycqGH9aqpdaWcaaqaamaakaaabaGaam4uamaaBaaaleaacaaIWaaabeaaaeqaaaGcbaGaamOBaaaaaeaacqaHYoGycqGH9aqpdaWcaaqaaiaaiwdaaeaacaaIZaaaaaaaaa@37D3@</m:annotation>
                    </m:semantics>
                </m:math>
            </equation>
            
            <para>Details for the equation captions are given in the section on Captions.</para>
        </chapter>
        
        <chapter>
            <title>Tables</title>
            
            <para>The tables are designed to have a uniform style throughout the paper. It does not matter how you choose to place the inner lines of the table, but we would prefer the border lines to be of the style shown in the example table. For the inner lines of the table, it looks better if they are kept to a minimum. Internal borders should be 1mm vertical (top and bottom) and 2mm horizontal (left and right).</para>
            
            <para>Tables should be placed as close as practical to the first cite. An example of a table and the associated caption is</para>
            
            <table>
                <caption>Example Table</caption>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Y in AEP of 1 in Y</td>
                        <td>Zy</td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2</td>
                        <td>0.000</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>5</td>
                        <td>0.8416</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>10</td>
                        <td>1.2816</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>20</td>
                        <td>1.6449</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>50</td>
                        <td>2.0537</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>100</td>
                        <td>2.3263</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>200</td>
                        <td>2.5758</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>500</td>
                        <td>2.8782</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>10000</td>
                        <td>3.0902</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </chapter>
        
        <chapter>
            <title>Figures</title>
            
            <para>Authors are advised to prepare their figures in high resolution (300 dpi) for half-tone illustrations or images. Half-tone pictures must be sharp enough for reproduction. These figures should be transmitted as separate files even if a version is embedded in the document.</para>
            
            <para>It is best to embed the figures in the text where they are first cited or to note the preferred location. Please ensure that all labels in the figures are legible regardless of whether they are drawn electronically or manually. The caption heading for a figure should be placed below the figure and centred on the figure.</para>
            
            <para>An example of a figure is:</para>
            
            <figure>
                <title>Sample Image</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/sample_image.png" />
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </chapter>
        
        <chapter>
            <title>Captions</title>
            
            <para>Formats for the captions of figures, tables, and equations are:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>Equations - right hand side of the page and vertically centred on the equation. The equation number should be “(book.chapter.number)” in 11pt Times New Roman.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>Figures - centred below the figure. The figure number should be “book.chapter.number” in 11pt Times New Roman.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>Tables - centred above the table. The table number should be “book.chapter.number” in 11pt Times New Roman.</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
        </chapter>
        
        <chapter>
            <title>References</title>
            
            <para>The Harvard system should be used for all referencing. References should be presented in the body of the text as follows: Barker (1992) or (Barker, 1992) for one author, (Jones and Smith, 1998) for two, and Feugard et al. (1994) for multiple authors. References should be listed in alphabetical order. Where the original author’s words are repeated verbatim, references should include the page number for the quote, e.g., ‘... this is the quote’ (Black, 1996: 38). Quotes that are less than three lines should be enclosed in quotation marks. Larger quotes should be placed in a separate paragraph, indented 15mm left and right and use 11pt Times New Roman font. References for large quotes should follow immediately after the quote, right justified and indented 15mm, or be placed in the text immediately preceding the quote.</para>
            
            <para>The papers in the reference list must be cited in the text.</para>
            
            <para>An example citation is: <xref linkend="Kites75" xreflabel="test" /> and <biblioref linkend="AhoSethiUllman96" /></para>
        </chapter>
        
        <bibliography>
            <title>Bibliography</title>
            <bibliomixed xml:id="Kites75" />
            <bibliomixed xml:id="AhoSethiUllman96" />
        </bibliography>
    </book>
</set>
