<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<appendix status="In Preparation" xml:id="b5_a_mdnb7"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
          xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
          xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
          xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
          xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
          xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
          xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Calculation of the Timing of the Baseflow Peak</title>

  <para>Analyses undertaken to develop most of the method outlined in <xref
  linkend="section_75228116"/> is described in detail in separate technical
  documents, available online at the ARR website (SKM, 2010, available online
  http://www.arr.org.au/p7.html). However, the background behind the
  calculation of the timing of the baseflow peak is not captured in those
  documents. A full description of the development of <xref
  linkend="equation_56532397"/> is provided below. The description below
  assumes that the reader has an understanding of the work presented in the
  separate technical documents, and a full background of the broader study
  concepts is not provided here.</para>

  <para>More than 230 suitable catchments across Australia were identified for
  analysis for ARR Revision Project 7, and hourly streamflow data was collated
  for each of these locations. A baseflow time series was generated from each
  flow record using the Lyne and Hollick digital filter, modified to suit
  hourly streamflow data. The top 4N flood events were identified in the
  hourly time series data for each catchment, generating a data set of more
  than 30,000 flood events across the 236 catchments. For each of these
  events, the magnitude and timing of the total streamflow peak and baseflow
  peak were identified. The time to these peaks was calculated from the start
  of the event. At each location, the average time to the streamflow and
  baseflow peaks were then calculated based on the 4N events.</para>

  <para>For the purposes of this assessment, it was assumed that the total
  streamflow and surface runoff peaks would coincide. This is considered a
  reasonable assumption since surface runoff is generally the main component
  of the total streamflow hydrograph.</para>

  <para>Analysis of the average time to peak data identified a strong
  relationship between the time to the surface runoff (and streamflow) and
  baseflow peaks, as presented in <xref linkend="figure_74876507"/>. This
  relationship provides a direct calculation from which to estimate the timing
  of the baseflow peak, based upon knowledge of the surface runoff event
  generated using a flood event model. That is, the time to the baseflow peak
  (in hours from the start of the event) can be calculated as:</para>

  <equation xml:id="equation_08366567">
    <m:math display="block">
      <m:mrow>
        <m:msub>
          <m:mi>T</m:mi>

          <m:mi>Peak baseflow</m:mi>
        </m:msub>

        <m:mo>=</m:mo>

        <m:mrow>
          <m:msub>
            <m:mi>0.92 T</m:mi>

            <m:mi>Peak surface runoff</m:mi>
          </m:msub>

          <m:mo>+ 33.4</m:mo>
        </m:mrow>
      </m:mrow>
    </m:math>
  </equation>

  <figure xml:id="figure_74876507">
    <title>Comparison of Average Time to Surface Runoff Peak and Time to
    Baseflow Peak, Based on Analysis of more than 30,000 Flood Events from
    Catchments across Australia.</title>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="../figures/5013.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
</appendix>
