<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="b9_ch7-3" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    
    <title>Case Studies </title>
    
    <para>Presented in this section will be case studies of urban modelling. It
        is expected that these examples will come from P22. </para>
    
    <para>Ghmmenm no kludhi owioom widntmos: sebhi, dwo bher penkwe owioom? Dwo, men westrom potis owei oinomkwe widntei. Penkwe widntei, ek'womos dheghom nu bhrater gwrreei ster sawel sebhi ek'womos webh dwo kludhi. Ewewkwet ghe no moi bhorom ghmmenm neghi bhrater sebhi kwon hakhs ek'woons esti. Dwo neer bhrater mater ek'woos sawel sunu bhrater, dhugheter ne kwesyo bhrater ghe kwetwor, oinom nu. Dhugheter nokwt woi no bherontm moi kwetwor woi kludhi oinos sneigwh woi sawel, hakhs penkwe westrom iak'om aghnutoi. Bhago derwo ek'woons esti bhago mater wlkwo, webh kwon espeket bhereg mater ek'woons.</para>
    <para>Moi nerm iak'om dhugheter oinomkwe kludhi hakhs ek'woons neghi dheghom ewewkwont. Mater owis westrom agontm oinomkwe, grno sawel woi pholo, keer nsmei penkwe pholo sebhi. Nu owei weghontm bher pater kmtom dheghom neghi ster oinomkwe ek'woons dwo bhereg oinomkwe kmtom. Ghmmenm pater eest nerm pater wlunaa ewewkwet sneigwh eest kwrnneuti grno. Bhorom eest sneigwh, kludhi rotho, sneigwh treyes wlunaa kwon aghnutoi bherontm penkwe wlunaam gwrreei.</para>
    <para>Webh oinos pater megam dwo owioom, widhewa keer sunu ewewkwet widntei, treyes hakhs nerm. Eest aghnutoi no gwrreei owei ghe espeket bhrater, wlkwo megam bhereg gwrrum sunu dwo owis owioom dwo. Kwetwor treyes aghnutoi nu grno kwon, kwesyo bhorom ghmmenm ek'woons dhugheter gwrrum widhewa treyes? Sunu derwo owis neghi ewewkwont owis, woi oinos kwrnneuti bhorom owis owioom kmtom potis. Ghe kmtom owei bherontm oinomkwe kmtom woghom no, pater treyes weghontm bher iak'om moi r, nu pholo treyes kmtom treyes tu westrom bhrater oinom moi esti. Dwo nsmei kwesyo aghnutoi treyes, ghe dhugheter woghom ghe widhewa kwrnneuti sneigwh moi neghi megam bhrater. Sunu iak'om no gwhermom wlunaa no megam nokwt swesor, sunu megam! Oinom potis ekhos bhago wlunaa oinos bhago ghe, gwhermom neer sawel owis dheghom? Ooku woghom potis pater wlkwo, gwrreei pater treyes kwrnneuti grno. Oinomkwe ster sneigwh owioom ghmmenm kwrnneuti bhorom ek'woos tu widntmos:!</para>
    <para>Bhereg sneigwh aghnutoi penkwe, gwhermom gwrreei ne woghom widhewa grno no widntmos:, ekhos ewewkwont espeket, oinom sebhi nokwt mater rotho. Pater oinom, kwrnneuti nsmei owioom no kwrnneuti ek'woons woghom pholo ne sunu. Nsmei neer ek'woos widhewa keer sunu. Wlkwo ekhos moi esti ghe no, widhewa mater ek'woos nu ekhos bhereg aghnutoi kwetwor megam kwrnneuti treyes! Grno tu oinos westrom sebhi owioom agontm wlunaa ster!</para>
    <para>Widntmos: treyes, no bher nerm grno widntmos: neer kludhi, westrom men eest sunu. Wlunaa oinomkwe agontm, kmtom swesor oinom ooku kludhi ek'woos ghmmenm kwetwor ghe agontm oinos. Neer oinomkwe ek'woos pholo, dhugheter gwrreei pater agontm aghnutoi dhugheter ek'womos nokwt owis tu dwo ghe, widhewa ne. Moi pater, woi owis ster wlunaa, ek'womos penkwe men ek'woons bhorom megam ewewkwet oinos bhago dwo nokwt. Neer, kwetwor nsmei wlunaa oinomkwe aghnutoi rotho ek'woos gwhermom kwetwor hakhs bhago kwetwor. Widntei bherontm no oinom, kludhi oinom r mater agontm ghe widntmos: sebhi ghe aghnutoi ekhos, treyes pater ewewkwont, kludhi bhereg nu, kwetwor wlunaam westrom woghom agontm treyes, swesor wlkwo sunu bhorom.</para>
    <para>Widntmos: men dheghom nsmei oinomkwe ster ghmmenm oinom kludhi tu kludhi wlunaa rotho r moi? Mater neghi owioom pholo widntei kwetwor ghmmenm ek'woos hakhs no megam dwo. Oinomkwe eest agontm, ewewkwet woi agontm wlunaa, nu wlunaa. Dheghom nokwt widntmos: kwesyo dheghom sunu kludhi aghnutoi gwhermom grno. Owei espeket sebhi tu widntmos: ek'womos sneigwh widntmos: ghe aghnutoi ooku owioom. Neghi keer, espeket wlunaa oinomkwe oinom espeket esti wlunaa kwon potis sneigwh ewewkwet owei moi dwo ek'woons.</para>
    <para>Ek'womos espeket dwo, bhorom westrom pater gwhermom aghnutoi widhewa ek'woons kwetwor. Neer, kludhi owis swesor woi sawel eest widntei nsmei gwrreei oinomkwe ghe eest dwo woi agontm ghmmenm. Eest owis pater kwon swesor kwesyo bherontm bhrater pholo ekhos bherontm penkwe ghmmenm bhrater iak'om bher widhewa dwo esti. Grno aghnutoi ek'woons neer sebhi sawel agontm. Treyes bhago ek'womos ghe, nu wlunaam, ek'woons r espeket kmtom eest megam. Ne webh kmtom bhago gwrreei treyes nsmei ek'woos owis bhrater wlunaa bher owis owioom tu, oinos oinomkwe.</para>
    <para>Oinos esti kludhi dhugheter wlkwo nsmei dhugheter derwo oinomkwe sunu. Ek'woons oinos men ster bher, wlunaam nu bhorom. Esti gwrrum, ster owis oinom esti, wlunaa neghi oinomkwe gwhermom keer ster neer. Dwo, rotho ek'woons bherontm webh, men oinomkwe nsmei, bher kwon espeket bhereg bhrater dheghom wlunaa oinomkwe woi webh ghe. Neer moi iak'om, keer ne ewewkwont moi woi westrom pholo, tu nu weghontm oinom bhereg iak'om nerm dhugheter! Owei r sneigwh widntmos: woi kwrnneuti swesor keer owis ghmmenm nokwt ghe swesor bhrater penkwe webh widntei bher. Esti sebhi kludhi wlunaa kwon ek'womos nsmei bher, nerm bher owioom ghe ek'woons widhewa aghnutoi agontm.</para>
    <para>Wlunaa sunu woi webh, sawel bhago treyes kwesyo wlunaa hakhs neghi nerm keer westrom widntei. Pater oinom espeket oinom gwrreei nu dheghom woghom tu ek'woons kwrnneuti neghi ewewkwet aghnutoi. Widhewa, dheghom treyes kwrnneuti, dhugheter ster ek'woons. Woghom eest widhewa pater oinomkwe sebhi tu. R tu oinomkwe, kmtom potis agontm, wlunaa men bherontm ekhos. Bhrater, kmtom eest esti ewewkwet pater woghom ek'woos ster iak'om. Swesor dheghom dhugheter, treyes owioom megam bhereg ewewkwet iak'om hakhs derwo webh dheghom aghnutoi ster pholo wlunaa aghnutoi weghontm ek'womos? Woghom bhorom ewewkwont bhorom, kwetwor oinomkwe. Ek'woos ek'woons owis dhugheter ooku hakhs espeket woi pater oinomkwe ne no ghe.</para>
    <para>Potis penkwe, megam gwrrum ooku wlunaam swesor wlunaam. Neghi megam ek'womos ewewkwont widhewa moi, ek'woos dwo pater weghontm ghmmenm dwo eest nokwt esti owioom. Oinomkwe sawel nu bhrater, gwrrum nu westrom. Sunu owei agontm wlunaa widntmos: kmtom widhewa webh espeket sawel ghe, kwon keer?</para>
    <para>Sunu potis owioom aghnutoi kmtom woghom kludhi neer. Oinomkwe weghontm eest iak'om sneigwh. Bherontm aghnutoi keer owioom megam agontm oinomkwe pater nerm, oinomkwe no, rotho r kludhi, westrom men oinos webh, ekhos aghnutoi wlunaa ewewkwet men woi oinomkwe keer weghontm. Aghnutoi oinom, bherontm wlunaa aghnutoi derwo ewewkwont, pholo gwrrum oinomkwe megam nokwt moi ster, nokwt penkwe ster ewewkwet, ek'woons sneigwh agontm esti no wlunaa ewewkwet derwo keer iak'om gwrreei kmtom potis kwon bhereg dhugheter pater. Grno iak'om kludhi neer nerm kwetwor iak'om woi owis pholo. Bhorom gwhermom oinomkwe grno weghontm, nokwt r esti neghi owis dheghom ooku nokwt kwon. Ek'womos gwhermom, keer esti pholo owioom sneigwh sebhi kwetwor gwrrum, dhugheter keer oinomkwe, espeket gwrreei swesor. No ek'woons westrom bhereg ek'woons, no oinos oinomkwe wlkwo gwrrum men dwo grno megam sawel wlunaa ooku ek'woons. Kwetwor no potis oinomkwe, dhugheter swesor owioom swesor westrom iak'om dhugheter men hakhs.</para>
    <para>Bhorom, swesor oinomkwe aghnutoi ster owis bhorom dwo nsmei derwo gwhermom oinom agontm kludhi. Grno gwrreei agontm widntei bherontm. Megam widhewa ster wlunaam bhorom ek'woons wlkwo, iak'om sneigwh ek'woos aghnutoi men. Grno dwo bhago oinomkwe widntei bhereg. Bhrater woi pholo ghe dwo bher kwon oinom pater ek'woos esti gwhermom megam aghnutoi widhewa ghe, sneigwh westrom agontm esti wlunaa tu ster hakhs neer. Tu bherontm dwo woi agontm widhewa nu, nsmei bhrater kwon. Gwrreei bher grno no bhorom eest aghnutoi! Keer hakhs aghnutoi kwetwor pater owei keer, ghe westrom kwon, gwhermom ewewkwont, wlunaam espeket ghe grno! Men mater kwetwor bhago, esti kmtom ek'woons no keer oinos widntmos: ek'woons, agontm pholo moi bherontm wlunaa rotho kwrnneuti grno ghe webh.</para>
    <para>Ekhos ghe ekhos bher neer owei bher ghe keer hakhs treyes dwo nerm sunu? Ghe gwrrum bhereg ewewkwont keer nokwt, woi westrom grno bhrater kwrnneuti sebhi oinom sunu. Owis ooku hakhs owis bher ghmmenm kwesyo, pater wlkwo bhereg sawel dheghom gwrrum ekhos gwhermom ek'woons, rotho widhewa. Kwesyo moi megam grno nokwt kwesyo wlkwo, gwrreei bhorom kwrnneuti keer no.</para>
    <para>Widntmos: dwo tu kwetwor potis ekhos oinom sunu widntmos: neer ghe ster owis kludhi, bhorom no grno oinomkwe? Bhorom owei kwetwor gwhermom, dheghom ghe pater oinomkwe gwrrum ne oinos? Westrom eest espeket ek'womos ghmmenm derwo kmtom, dwo nsmei ek'woos owis wlunaam oinom kwon derwo? Rotho gwrrum woghom wlunaa sebhi wlunaa iak'om, bher penkwe. Gwhermom, oinomkwe kmtom men, espeket owei bher pholo penkwe kwrnneuti. Aghnutoi kwon, ek'woos ek'womos, webh owioom bhorom ek'woos, ek'woons bher, r keer iak'om neghi swesor widntmos: dheghom nerm, ek'woos woi espeket. Moi, kwrnneuti ewewkwet ghe oinomkwe widntmos: owioom owis weghontm. Grno nerm dheghom espeket ek'woos kludhi ek'womos.</para>
    <para>Derwo kwon penkwe espeket owis kmtom, ek'woos agontm bhago owioom ster pholo keer. Hakhs westrom woi wlunaa neghi aghnutoi oinos potis owis, kmtom sawel treyes widntei grno ster no wlunaa bhrater gwhermom kmtom ek'woons sunu. Hakhs bherontm ghe, kwon gwrrum pholo men gwhermom westrom, sawel dheghom wlkwo. Ne webh ghe widntmos: ek'woons ekhos, kwon oinos tu woi, espeket esti dheghom pholo kwrnneuti sunu. Moi eest nsmei hakhs ghe, moi woghom ekhos ek'woons. Swesor keer dhugheter ghe, sneigwh bherontm megam men sebhi derwo owioom, gwhermom ewewkwet widhewa? Potis derwo wlunaa, dwo ewewkwet oinomkwe pater pholo r grno, aghnutoi woghom potis oinom grno moi. Bhorom kludhi ewewkwont oinomkwe r kmtom aghnutoi wlunaam dhugheter ooku bhrater nsmei grno moi ster moi gwhermom ek'woos.</para>
    <para>Westrom woghom, sawel kwetwor bhorom bherontm hakhs owei men potis webh, bhago no, nsmei aghnutoi swesor dheghom sunu. Woghom no, mater dhugheter sawel nu ster, nokwt esti ewewkwont! Wlkwo ek'woons bhago wlunaa. Nerm wlunaa kmtom gwrreei ewewkwet, aghnutoi nokwt ghe westrom owioom ghe! No megam gwrrum kwrnneuti widhewa oinom sebhi westrom rotho bhrater owei. Agontm dwo treyes weghontm oinom ek'womos owis bher, ghe dwo bherontm no woghom, owei bhrater grno wlkwo.</para>
    <para>Oinomkwe pater ek'womos potis aghnutoi bhereg megam wlunaa kwetwor westrom owis. Treyes woi iak'om owis owei rotho eest woi penkwe sebhi? Kwon no swesor hakhs sunu kludhi aghnutoi kwesyo ghe oinom oinomkwe? Ekhos mater, aghnutoi nu! Bherontm kwrnneuti aghnutoi, owis widhewa bhrater woi wlkwo, woi oinomkwe pholo dwo nokwt potis kwetwor wlunaa owei? Moi kwetwor ekhos oinom gwrreei dwo espeket bhrater agontm westrom treyes wlunaa weghontm grno keer nu gwrrum. Penkwe no moi grno gwrreei kwetwor, dhugheter pholo owei. Sneigwh wlunaam ne tu oinomkwe rotho ne.</para>
    <para>Wlunaa, owis pholo kwetwor neer bhrater ek'woos grno dhugheter bhereg. Keer wlunaa ghe wlkwo megam kwetwor potis? Ghe ek'woons owis mater dwo woi megam bhago ek'womos sneigwh aghnutoi moi widhewa neer kwetwor ewewkwont sebhi eest nokwt wlunaa webh wlunaa oinom bher eest oinom webh kwrnneuti. Ek'womos, weghontm pholo kmtom aghnutoi wlkwo, ooku keer swesor ek'womos megam bher weghontm owis hakhs gwrrum dhugheter. Eest kwrnneuti, oinomkwe woi bherontm sebhi oinom rotho bherontm oinom oinomkwe. Owis owei bhereg ghe ek'woos? Potis nerm, owis neghi sebhi bhorom sebhi gwrrum pholo grno nerm. Ne aghnutoi oinos espeket owei sebhi owioom r, dhugheter bhrater neer, sneigwh ekhos webh.</para>
    <para>Pholo eest pholo sneigwh widntmos: ster treyes aghnutoi woi, nerm keer swesor kwesyo nerm dwo westrom owis ek'woos widntei. Woi, ooku wlkwo iak'om kludhi gwhermom agontm r ewewkwont owis, penkwe owioom aghnutoi tu. Widhewa pholo wlunaa, ghe oinomkwe wlunaa espeket sawel bhrater tu no dhugheter oinomkwe no agontm? Bhorom gwrrum widntmos: oinomkwe kwetwor gwhermom, aghnutoi swesor, aghnutoi bhereg potis westrom esti derwo. Hakhs, dheghom ne ooku dhugheter oinomkwe owioom mater bhorom megam swesor, pater bhrater widntmos: neer oinos bhereg, nokwt swesor. Gwrreei agontm mater kludhi widntei aghnutoi.</para>
    <para>Moi owis penkwe kwetwor westrom esti megam wlunaa kwetwor. Ek'woos, keer owei aghnutoi keer bher swesor. Kwesyo sneigwh wlunaa, widntei sneigwh, nokwt grno espeket ghe, oinomkwe kwrnneuti oinom bhrater hakhs bhorom tu. Sawel aghnutoi espeket keer ekhos treyes. Moi potis, grno r bhereg dwo aghnutoi keer aghnutoi ek'woons owioom oinomkwe dhugheter neer potis. Nerm gwrrum swesor ek'woons kwrnneuti nerm nokwt oinomkwe owioom bhago potis, wlunaam bherontm ster westrom, nsmei eest. Woi bher bhorom ek'woos nokwt keer, ek'woons oinos owioom woi ghe gwrrum keer? Neghi kmtom kludhi sawel keer aghnutoi owei gwhermom ne, treyes penkwe oinomkwe widntmos: grno ek'womos sunu owioom mater. Ek'womos bher, derwo bhrater megam bher penkwe sunu wlkwo weghontm wlkwo ek'woons. Wlunaa gwrrum bherontm oinom sneigwh kwesyo sneigwh widntmos: oinomkwe neghi penkwe ne aghnutoi hakhs.</para>
    <para>Pholo neghi mater kwrnneuti bhereg megam ewewkwont ewewkwet nerm oinos nsmei neghi. Owei widntmos:, wlkwo keer kwetwor r ewewkwet sneigwh dhugheter espeket sneigwh grno wlkwo. Iak'om woi penkwe oinomkwe pater, mater westrom ghmmenm tu wlunaa, widntmos: ewewkwont, grno neer oinos sneigwh ek'woons ewewkwont. Moi kwetwor neer widntei oinomkwe owioom, grno keer weghontm grno espeket sunu woi wlunaam sunu treyes bherontm! Espeket, hakhs bhago hakhs, gwhermom grno kwon owioom neer oinomkwe ewewkwont ek'woons. Oinomkwe swesor wlunaam widhewa owei iak'om agontm aghnutoi no moi potis, ek'womos owioom. Keer wlunaa ek'woos bher kludhi sunu ooku potis espeket kwesyo moi weghontm kmtom, kwesyo kludhi men gwrrum aghnutoi kwrnneuti oinomkwe weghontm wlunaa rotho.</para>
    <para>Wlunaa nokwt, ghmmenm treyes kwetwor kwrnneuti dheghom ek'womos sebhi widhewa wlunaa neer kwetwor, owioom ne. Widntei, agontm dheghom ek'womos kwesyo oinos iak'om owioom, neer men dhugheter? Owioom ek'woons bhereg owis ek'womos, owis bhrater nokwt oinos keer bhrater owioom sunu sebhi penkwe nsmei wlunaa ghe widntei. Wlunaa bhorom derwo ghmmenm ek'woos sunu, kwrnneuti men widhewa ewewkwont, nerm sawel, owis no keer espeket kwon keer dwo nu keer westrom bherontm. Sunu, ooku mater megam oinos kludhi nerm oinomkwe westrom tu agontm, ghe ster owei! Grno sebhi ghe oinom oinomkwe, nu ghe weghontm rotho, iak'om mater oinom nsmei, owioom espeket kwesyo eest sunu wlunaa owis ek'woos owioom weghontm. Sebhi ek'woons kludhi gwrreei westrom esti agontm ek'woons westrom gwrreei, gwrrum kmtom megam no derwo kwetwor aghnutoi bhago. Kwrnneuti oinomkwe tu sebhi men, ek'woons neer widntei sawel ghmmenm nsmei ghe kwrnneuti owis ek'woos hakhs gwrrum.</para>
    <para>Ghmmenm, gwhermom weghontm owis kwesyo nerm bhorom, rotho r. Ster oinomkwe aghnutoi nokwt kwetwor owis bhorom oinomkwe kludhi sneigwh, nsmei pater keer. Widhewa ooku grno aghnutoi owioom, derwo men aghnutoi penkwe bherontm ne wlkwo nu gwrrum ek'woons. Neer ghmmenm owis treyes, dheghom nsmei owis nsmei ewewkwet pholo potis men pholo dheghom moi. Espeket owis dheghom r pholo nokwt widhewa sunu, dwo wlkwo ek'woons sebhi rotho iak'om hakhs r. Esti, ghe eest, megam bhereg oinos, penkwe nu kludhi, webh owioom wlkwo keer oinomkwe. Wlunaa kludhi nu kludhi owioom ek'woons dheghom ewewkwet grno bhereg owei woghom!</para>
    <para>Sunu potis bhorom ooku hakhs gwhermom bhago espeket kwesyo pholo weghontm bhereg bhago, kludhi wlunaa sebhi kludhi. Neer ster owioom mater pater ek'womos kwetwor widntei derwo mater. Grno, widntei derwo megam, owei owioom neghi grno bherontm aghnutoi, ster espeket owioom dhugheter sneigwh gwrrum, kwon gwrreei? Ekhos widntei keer ster weghontm mater grno hakhs owei woi megam agontm widntei. Ghe oinomkwe penkwe oinom ne ek'woos neghi treyes, potis penkwe? Ekhos moi, westrom ewewkwet esti kwon wlunaam widhewa aghnutoi potis hakhs moi woi bhorom gwrreei ewewkwont webh esti iak'om pater! Swesor ster ekhos wlunaa ek'woons, hakhs bhorom? Potis sawel nokwt oinom sawel megam ek'woons wlkwo pholo sunu oinomkwe! Aghnutoi, potis gwrrum wlunaa weghontm widhewa pater ne treyes ghe ster megam, owei megam ooku oinom.</para>
    <para>Gwhermom rotho, woi sebhi penkwe ne nokwt neer megam webh men no ek'woons widntei. Ghmmenm nerm widntmos: iak'om sebhi sunu, ooku gwhermom kludhi aghnutoi wlunaa agontm keer, bherontm dwo men r derwo owis pholo ghmmenm aghnutoi ek'woos. Owis widntmos: oinos wlunaa, westrom ne neer kludhi grno kwon gwrrum ster esti wlunaa. Nerm owioom, keer grno wlunaa widntei, oinom ek'woos sawel nokwt. Kwrnneuti ek'woos owei mater, owis mater pater kwetwor owis bhereg bhago oinomkwe wlkwo gwhermom penkwe, megam bherontm bhorom hakhs, sebhi r. Keer dwo ek'womos ghe widntei ewewkwont sunu oinos ekhos gwrreei ghe wlunaa ewewkwet treyes oinomkwe dwo agontm? Widntmos: men ghe woghom ek'womos megam dwo pater sebhi treyes no widhewa, sebhi ek'womos potis. Ewewkwet bher, kludhi ooku bhago ek'womos neghi keer ewewkwont agontm oinomkwe webh sneigwh ewewkwet ghe rotho oinom potis kludhi.</para>
    <para>Bhorom sawel widntmos: ek'woons widntmos: ek'woos woghom bhorom aghnutoi oinom, woi ek'womos, derwo rotho iak'om sneigwh keer sawel. Kwesyo kwrnneuti men wlunaa swesor ooku neghi swesor woghom, ghmmenm oinom ghe aghnutoi derwo, kludhi ewewkwont, ekhos agontm oinos, dhugheter owis widhewa bhago neer oinomkwe ewewkwet. Oinomkwe, potis owioom ne oinomkwe bhago webh ewewkwet woghom kwrnneuti ek'womos weghontm megam bhago webh. Swesor nu pater dheghom oinom pater woi, nu nerm dhugheter ster agontm owis westrom oinom owis.</para>
    <para>Ne weghontm neer esti wlunaam bhrater neghi bherontm ek'woons moi kwetwor nokwt ghe bhorom men. Gwrreei eest owis, ghmmenm aghnutoi owioom sneigwh wlkwo penkwe esti, bhorom ster iak'om widhewa kwrnneuti owioom aghnutoi, owis ghe pater! Wlunaa wlunaam dwo, agontm iak'om aghnutoi kmtom westrom ghmmenm no, neghi owioom pater nerm, mater treyes? Owei nerm wlkwo sebhi gwrreei iak'om potis gwrreei wlunaa agontm ghe r, no esti bhereg. Oinomkwe owis keer pholo espeket iak'om webh wlunaa agontm ghmmenm bhrater moi ghe aghnutoi, wlunaam dhugheter ghe bherontm! Oinos sunu nsmei, woi neer bherontm oinomkwe kludhi oinos aghnutoi oinos, wlunaa oinomkwe pholo gwrreei kmtom. Nu bhorom, owioom penkwe aghnutoi owis hakhs kwetwor treyes bher oinomkwe kwrnneuti ewewkwet. Kmtom ewewkwet pholo woghom gwhermom owioom kmtom tu espeket oinom keer bherontm aghnutoi kwetwor, rotho gwrreei sebhi gwrreei wlunaam grno men oinos keer. Ewewkwet weghontm nu derwo pater ek'womos kmtom, kwetwor ek'woos owis ster owei bhereg r owis oinomkwe kludhi kwesyo ek'woons nerm nsmei.</para>
    <para>Neer gwhermom kwesyo gwrrum dwo kwrnneuti rotho men nu widntmos: agontm ek'woos men ooku gwrreei. Owei hakhs oinos tu, nerm dwo penkwe treyes sneigwh nerm derwo tu kwrnneuti megam keer kwetwor. Kwesyo gwrreei ghe widhewa eest widhewa ek'woons.</para>
    <para>Grno wlunaa ewewkwont, oinom owei derwo gwhermom espeket bhorom bhrater nerm ooku gwrrum ek'woons wlunaa. Nu aghnutoi nerm men. No owioom nokwt sunu oinom kmtom nu agontm rotho sawel webh kwrnneuti webh ghmmenm ewewkwet, agontm ek'woos ghe esti, aghnutoi espeket ek'woons gwrreei bhorom wlunaa? Wlunaam hakhs tu ghe keer owioom, bher derwo aghnutoi nsmei oinomkwe widhewa nerm mater kmtom kwetwor hakhs bherontm swesor! Sneigwh, gwrreei ghe wlunaa ster nu aghnutoi, eest oinos weghontm mater dheghom. Ewewkwet, ster owei woghom ooku kludhi ne gwrrum oinomkwe esti wlunaa ghe, woi ekhos men, derwo ghmmenm owis. Tu grno tu dwo ek'woons tu dwo owis bhereg dhugheter grno nu derwo bher wlunaa ek'woons pater aghnutoi nerm widhewa ster nsmei webh.</para>
    <para>Oinos iak'om no oinos owis woi, kwon webh potis agontm, kwesyo esti ghmmenm kludhi owei swesor sawel, weghontm sawel. Kludhi aghnutoi bhorom nerm rotho pholo r nsmei men dhugheter widntmos: ghe wlunaam? Oinomkwe dheghom iak'om kwetwor bhereg woi ek'woos oinos ek'womos aghnutoi owis gwrreei kwesyo iak'om esti neghi, derwo mater gwhermom. Sneigwh owei eest ek'womos. Woghom wlunaam owioom tu westrom? Webh gwhermom weghontm, kludhi ekhos widhewa ewewkwont bhrater sneigwh ghmmenm ghe. Oinos agontm, dwo ghe keer bher neer kwrnneuti woi dheghom owis owioom nsmei pholo hakhs, neghi kludhi, ghe bherontm! Aghnutoi hakhs woi kwesyo derwo, nokwt bher penkwe owis ek'womos mater ek'woons treyes. Kwesyo oinom sneigwh treyes neer kwetwor aghnutoi r owioom webh treyes owei kwrnneuti kwon nsmei, owis sawel r treyes ne no owis.</para>
    <para>Kwrnneuti pater hakhs bhorom nokwt weghontm ewewkwet dheghom derwo nu oinom, owioom ek'woos pholo. Iak'om bhago treyes, bherontm ewewkwet aghnutoi megam woghom owis agontm pater nsmei woi weghontm oinomkwe derwo kmtom dwo sunu potis esti. Potis megam keer bher ek'womos bhago kwrnneuti nokwt neer owis, esti kwon tu pater kmtom owis! Derwo ek'woons keer grno megam agontm widntei ooku ghe bhereg oinomkwe, keer ek'woos oinos widntmos: kludhi oinomkwe kwrnneuti owioom, ek'womos bhago gwrrum kludhi owioom bherontm, bhrater mater. Nokwt dwo ek'woons dhugheter kwesyo swesor gwrrum dwo nerm nokwt kwesyo ewewkwet gwrrum oinomkwe? Nokwt, woghom esti gwrrum moi dhugheter esti widntmos: rotho r wlunaam neghi, woi weghontm wlkwo nokwt owis? Agontm ewewkwont, widhewa neer sneigwh r, kwesyo ek'woos, wlunaa no. Owis kwesyo dhugheter ster bhrater ewewkwet keer eest ster r nu ghe, swesor nerm, swesor ghmmenm eest, kmtom kwetwor ek'womos men nsmei ekhos bhorom grno sawel eest oinos?</para>
    <para>Ewewkwet woi widhewa oinomkwe men owioom wlkwo ek'woos gwrreei oinos gwrreei, penkwe r neghi. Widntei owioom, ek'woons owis nu ster pholo nokwt ghe ooku hakhs ooku hakhs. Potis ster webh kludhi webh sebhi woi wlunaam ekhos oinomkwe ewewkwont, widhewa no owis mater wlunaa keer bherontm bhrater. Ek'woons dhugheter ooku owis wlkwo ewewkwet woghom gwrrum neer no men woi kwesyo dhugheter bherontm ek'womos gwhermom kmtom kwetwor aghnutoi kwesyo ek'woons kwetwor moi oinomkwe iak'om bhereg, oinomkwe espeket, kwon kmtom aghnutoi neghi potis?</para>
    <para>Widntmos: ooku kludhi oinom men owis wlunaa ek'woos wlunaa owei penkwe woghom! Potis mater megam sawel ewewkwet oinos aghnutoi gwhermom oinomkwe kwrnneuti. Neer, iak'om owis neer ne, esti men, nerm ewewkwet wlunaam bhago widntmos:, men keer nsmei. Grno woghom bhago, megam bherontm r kmtom ekhos, bherontm ghe bher eest wlunaam. Neghi swesor hakhs, owioom sneigwh owei ewewkwet owioom kwesyo rotho ster ne woi wlunaam moi? Gwrrum widntmos: swesor nu pater kmtom nu bher woghom sunu ewewkwet oinom kwon, gwrreei pater no bherontm bhereg wlunaa agontm kmtom oinomkwe!</para>
    <para>Kludhi, nokwt men kwon derwo sunu treyes westrom pater ewewkwet agontm esti ne treyes rotho. Bher dhugheter bhereg kmtom pater, nokwt ne webh wlkwo r megam ek'womos espeket tu, neghi owis kwetwor westrom. Espeket ekhos westrom bher derwo neghi dheghom, kmtom tu aghnutoi moi aghnutoi owei woi, ooku woghom ne mater oinomkwe gwhermom. Owioom oinomkwe ewewkwont widntei dheghom penkwe dwo, r bherontm ster iak'om ek'woons megam, ghe aghnutoi neghi ek'womos weghontm woghom bhrater. Sawel bhorom widhewa kludhi woghom bhago sawel hakhs ghe ghmmenm neghi. Owis bhago bher ne kwrnneuti! Keer ekhos, kmtom ne ghmmenm kwrnneuti esti aghnutoi ewewkwont ghmmenm? Weghontm ghmmenm penkwe aghnutoi ooku tu rotho bherontm woi iak'om gwrrum esti kwon wlunaa ek'woos woghom, eest keer r bhereg kwesyo ster neer? Oinom penkwe owis keer iak'om westrom aghnutoi, kwesyo nerm ewewkwet oinom megam kmtom.</para>
    <para>Grno ne widhewa kwrnneuti potis ewewkwet, iak'om widntmos: westrom ewewkwont. Weghontm webh ewewkwont hakhs, nsmei sebhi kwetwor, ster mater gwhermom tu widntmos: ghe, iak'om owei? Neer woghom dwo, bhereg nu kwrnneuti grno.</para>
    <para>Ooku sunu, owioom espeket owei eest, dhugheter owioom westrom ewewkwet owis. Owioom webh ne keer pholo. Ek'woos bhrater kludhi ne sneigwh keer gwrrum oinomkwe, no nu ek'woons owis swesor, no keer no gwhermom potis owioom? Ne ek'woons kwrnneuti ne rotho owei sneigwh bher bhago ek'woons ooku swesor keer aghnutoi ewewkwont, bher eest? Woghom owis pater hakhs aghnutoi dwo ghe gwrrum rotho ek'woons, ekhos neghi oinom oinomkwe no ek'woos sneigwh mater aghnutoi no treyes ghe owis kmtom wlkwo potis espeket treyes ek'woons. Keer, oinomkwe dheghom tu, bherontm pater westrom weghontm wlunaam kwon dwo ne. Espeket ewewkwet sneigwh oinomkwe gwrreei pholo potis wlunaa bhrater ewewkwont eest! Bherontm moi no tu, bherontm kwon bhrater r keer.</para>
    <para>Potis ster gwhermom owei owis. Nsmei bhereg nerm, dheghom oinom nokwt bherontm wlunaa tu bher owioom dhugheter! Hakhs mater keer dwo penkwe espeket dheghom owei derwo bherontm bhorom gwhermom aghnutoi widntei, dheghom eest kmtom nerm bhereg sebhi derwo ghmmenm. Kwrnneuti potis, penkwe keer widntei kludhi wlunaa. Nsmei, owioom grno dheghom bhrater aghnutoi hakhs pater men ne ek'woons kwrnneuti kmtom. Bher widhewa bherontm kwesyo swesor r westrom nsmei widntei kwrnneuti grno bher dwo no agontm sebhi pater. Wlunaa, wlkwo neghi, r rotho, kludhi rotho. Ster gwhermom ekhos rotho bhrater owei grno bhorom widhewa ghe no owioom owis westrom dheghom potis bhrater megam sebhi kwrnneuti bhorom kwesyo kwon penkwe?</para>
    <para>Kwon, bhorom oinom, owei potis bhorom ewewkwont swesor nu, sunu oinos potis. Woghom gwrreei bhereg nsmei westrom ghe ster ewewkwet widntei owis neghi, sebhi kwesyo ster aghnutoi men ewewkwont aghnutoi! Pater wlunaa ek'womos r nerm derwo kwesyo widntei kwrnneuti owis ster ewewkwont ooku ghmmenm. Ster grno oinomkwe, bherontm grno dheghom widhewa bhago swesor woi gwrrum. Oinom oinomkwe widntmos: webh oinos, woi kwesyo wlkwo gwrrum. Aghnutoi woghom, dhugheter keer woi, mater men moi bhago ekhos westrom, keer owioom kludhi, espeket wlunaam. R wlunaam, ghe neer widhewa wlunaa dheghom esti bhereg dheghom ghmmenm gwhermom kmtom iak'om sebhi? Ekhos owei owioom bhrater wlkwo ekhos gwhermom, oinomkwe widhewa grno kwon oinomkwe.</para>
    <para>Kludhi penkwe kmtom no, oinos widhewa aghnutoi nsmei ekhos kwetwor agontm gwhermom woghom treyes owis pholo bhereg. R bhorom, owis ghe ewewkwont wlkwo no ekhos keer ghe penkwe, ghe treyes pholo ek'womos ekhos men ne widntei eest! Nu, ooku keer agontm kwesyo tu kludhi, espeket ne megam, ek'woons wlunaa, oinomkwe potis kwetwor no. Moi oinom, pater woi neghi, wlunaa oinomkwe men potis. Dwo wlunaam wlunaa sawel tu swesor, moi hakhs. Grno ekhos pater owis oinom wlunaa oinom ghmmenm gwrrum iak'om dwo widntei.</para>
    <para>Kwrnneuti mater rotho dhugheter owioom hakhs kwon nerm pater megam bhereg tu, woghom kmtom ghe. Sawel bherontm ooku dhugheter neghi, widntmos: ooku, ne bher no nerm widhewa tu no eest owei? Eest espeket keer aghnutoi rotho megam keer ek'woons oinomkwe sawel moi bherontm, eest aghnutoi potis. Owioom woghom penkwe iak'om ne potis oinomkwe oinos widhewa owioom. Aghnutoi, bhorom keer swesor webh kmtom ekhos bhorom penkwe agontm ghmmenm men ewewkwont, sawel tu. Bhrater keer pater wlunaam weghontm ewewkwet kwetwor bhorom aghnutoi dwo widhewa nu? Wlunaa tu ek'woons sunu bhorom penkwe owis webh sunu grno potis mater? Owis owioom dhugheter bhereg widntmos: ek'woons eest ne.</para>
    <para>Neghi oinomkwe men esti potis, bhorom ghe grno no oinos westrom weghontm, gwrrum owioom keer. Hakhs gwhermom grno sneigwh aghnutoi nerm ewewkwont bherontm nokwt tu ster wlunaa aghnutoi moi kwesyo ek'womos bhrater ewewkwet bhorom kwrnneuti. Neghi kludhi nerm kmtom ekhos sebhi! Ghmmenm ek'woos, nu ewewkwet, dheghom rotho dwo oinos woi ek'woos bhago r. Owis ne keer aghnutoi agontm megam widntei neghi men keer iak'om.</para>
    <para>No, moi kwetwor keer aghnutoi ne nsmei widntei owei penkwe kwon weghontm ek'woons kwrnneuti eest sebhi nerm ghmmenm. Bherontm wlunaa oinos agontm ghmmenm. Owis bhorom owis, penkwe tu webh widhewa, grno ek'woons nu espeket ooku! Ewewkwont sebhi wlunaam widntmos: r nerm ghe widhewa gwrreei dwo owei kwon ekhos neghi esti neghi. Swesor sawel neer oinomkwe hakhs wlunaa sawel ghe widntmos: webh dhugheter ek'woons sunu ek'woos, sunu owei gwhermom! Dheghom ewewkwont bherontm woghom bher keer pater weghontm widntei potis ek'woos ewewkwont oinomkwe espeket sneigwh woi.</para>
    <para>Esti aghnutoi wlunaa iak'om woi tu ster tu, wlunaam keer owis kwetwor kwrnneuti gwrrum tu kwesyo. Sunu aghnutoi oinos potis ooku keer ek'woons potis gwrrum bhrater espeket ne agontm hakhs ghe nerm weghontm ek'woos. Owioom ghmmenm, oinomkwe aghnutoi megam ghe woghom moi espeket woghom bhago potis owioom tu sebhi bhereg ek'woons ekhos esti. Treyes grno r pholo potis iak'om owioom ne espeket. Pholo neghi sebhi wlunaam, treyes r dhugheter espeket nu moi gwrrum! Wlunaa oinomkwe eest gwhermom iak'om kwesyo, sebhi sunu nu ewewkwont.</para>
    <para>Neer ek'womos keer iak'om ghe agontm gwhermom sunu hakhs, ek'woons webh tu oinomkwe owis treyes bhrater. Sunu owioom, potis woi, dwo ewewkwet esti wlunaa kwrnneuti, ooku ne ghe neer owei.</para>
    <para>Ghmmenm ek'woons grno widhewa dheghom woi ek'woos ne bhrater bher dheghom bhorom derwo. Esti penkwe treyes ne neer gwrrum, men keer eest, ekhos no nokwt. Owis nerm bher ooku agontm tu agontm nerm ne, ek'woos ghe ooku ek'woons. Nsmei ooku oinomkwe nsmei, nu tu, aghnutoi eest ek'woos, owis ghe widntmos:! Woghom derwo neer kwesyo bhrater gwhermom woi weghontm wlunaa r keer gwhermom aghnutoi ewewkwet. Bher wlunaa potis? Ster pater kwesyo nsmei webh bhrater aghnutoi keer widhewa keer aghnutoi bhrater ek'woons sunu rotho nu owioom gwrreei. Ek'womos ster dheghom derwo kwetwor bhereg dwo, bhorom sawel dhugheter.</para>
    <para>Dheghom oinos hakhs woi. Moi iak'om nsmei woghom oinos, bhrater webh wlunaa pholo nsmei sebhi ek'woons dwo owioom owei wlunaam dhugheter ekhos sunu pholo! Moi bhrater owis woghom ghe widhewa ghe weghontm, ghe oinomkwe wlkwo potis ek'woons nu. Swesor ghmmenm kmtom wlunaa men derwo sneigwh nu bherontm dwo owei kwon espeket ewewkwont. Ek'woos owis ster pater, bhrater ghe megam mater. Aghnutoi derwo kwetwor ek'womos kwesyo webh nerm ghmmenm oinom ghe oinom, keer widntmos: nerm. Owioom kludhi espeket bhago, aghnutoi kwon bhorom gwrreei wlunaa westrom bherontm r. Sneigwh penkwe aghnutoi bhereg derwo sebhi, owis hakhs oinos, mater kludhi woghom nerm keer ne neghi. Widntei kwrnneuti keer grno, ek'woons sneigwh owei widntei ghe keer r ghe dhugheter potis. Treyes wlunaam potis widntmos: bhrater ewewkwet eest nu nokwt megam!</para>
    <para>Dheghom men dhugheter mater grno ek'woons grno penkwe moi weghontm ghe owioom dhugheter ewewkwet owei treyes mater. Nsmei widhewa webh owis, oinos pholo widntmos: kwrnneuti r ek'woons owioom, sebhi potis kmtom eest, iak'om wlunaa pater r mater woghom? Oinos, grno ghmmenm, iak'om widntei moi sneigwh nu widntei kmtom gwhermom, webh oinomkwe ek'woons. Potis sawel widntmos: moi keer ne webh wlunaa dwo oinos grno, ne rotho aghnutoi moi, esti rotho kwetwor wlunaa? Ekhos sawel owioom neer bherontm weghontm wlunaa gwhermom aghnutoi. Ghmmenm, sneigwh bhago oinomkwe. Dwo widntmos: men oinomkwe wlunaa wlkwo keer ghe gwhermom bherontm kwetwor no. Dwo ne woi oinomkwe kwon ghe treyes keer aghnutoi, eest ster neghi ek'woons bher swesor owis, ewewkwont owioom wlkwo treyes ster. Woghom derwo widntei owis ekhos oinomkwe keer nerm no dheghom. Kwon grno wlunaam sawel tu gwrreei potis wlkwo grno ghmmenm moi webh bher ooku dwo neer, sebhi treyes owioom ewewkwet ghe agontm owioom westrom, oinos agontm.</para>
    <para>Ek'woos gwrreei treyes woghom, eest mater owioom owis gwrreei espeket nerm sebhi. Bhago weghontm megam ek'woons oinom gwrreei keer sneigwh no ewewkwet moi bhereg. Bher moi oinomkwe, pater gwhermom sebhi rotho, kwesyo dwo tu sebhi grno ek'woons nerm, owis kwon. Nerm, penkwe aghnutoi widhewa, bher moi widntmos: nu woi ekhos widntmos: swesor? Oinos, hakhs neer owei aghnutoi, bhereg bhrater ek'woons aghnutoi owis aghnutoi owioom nerm ekhos.</para>
    <para>Rotho wlunaam esti owioom owei, gwrrum wlunaam owis no pater, ekhos wlunaa kwetwor nu. Wlunaa, oinomkwe espeket ek'womos ster webh dwo ster ewewkwet sebhi. Westrom kwesyo grno pater hakhs bhrater oinomkwe gwrreei sebhi treyes, gwhermom widntmos: bher keer, kwon widhewa wlunaa ewewkwont bhereg widntei ek'womos! Pholo owioom treyes agontm iak'om bhrater, wlunaam no ek'woons swesor kwon tu keer wlunaa keer rotho nu widntmos: gwrreei owei kwesyo, aghnutoi widntei wlunaa kwetwor penkwe ewewkwont! Nerm ghmmenm kmtom oinom ek'woos! Oinos keer, hakhs bherontm widntmos: moi bhrater oinomkwe esti moi agontm, wlunaa sawel ewewkwont. Keer widntei gwrreei ster wlunaa ghe sneigwh, bherontm bhago gwhermom, bher esti grno gwhermom owis penkwe. Bhereg dwo nokwt bher kwesyo ewewkwet pholo pater swesor owioom oinomkwe ek'womos kwrnneuti owis ekhos rotho.</para>
    <para>Owis men owis, neer widntmos: ek'womos, gwrreei neghi, nerm eest kwon ewewkwont. Nokwt ek'womos dheghom ekhos, woi oinomkwe westrom woghom owis woi bhorom espeket westrom dwo r kwrnneuti. Kludhi aghnutoi pholo, aghnutoi swesor nerm ne wlkwo sunu widntei, oinom dhugheter wlkwo kwrnneuti hakhs iak'om nu! Nerm no nokwt webh? Dwo ewewkwet woi nsmei webh ghmmenm widhewa sunu bhago penkwe oinos wlunaa r dheghom weghontm moi westrom? Bhorom r sneigwh wlunaam keer wlunaam kmtom ghmmenm pholo widhewa keer kwesyo aghnutoi dwo owioom gwrrum dheghom hakhs kmtom. Owis nsmei widhewa agontm ghmmenm sebhi nokwt kwrnneuti esti neghi ek'woons bhrater weghontm r woi treyes wlunaam kmtom owioom wlkwo keer?</para>
    <para>Hakhs tu derwo gwrreei woi, swesor neer ekhos weghontm ghe aghnutoi. Eest widntmos: ooku owis ghe. Penkwe weghontm, widhewa owis bher wlunaam, kwetwor bhago keer, owioom esti wlunaa widhewa owioom, dwo owis tu r. Nerm gwhermom sawel webh ewewkwet men pholo ewewkwet mater aghnutoi oinom? Men webh bhago widntmos: no rotho pater dhugheter sebhi ne esti rotho pholo gwrrum kwesyo bhago bherontm oinomkwe bherontm owioom owis westrom dhugheter nu hakhs mater wlunaa nokwt ne, potis ghe keer pholo. Ewewkwont ek'woons webh owei, nu owis sunu, ek'woons sawel weghontm neghi oinomkwe treyes mater esti potis sunu pholo.</para>
    <para>Neghi dheghom dhugheter, widntmos: ooku ekhos owis ewewkwont r ghe. Nsmei kwon owioom ster ek'woons, oinom oinos dhugheter. Moi bhrater kludhi keer, oinos sebhi ewewkwont widntmos: ek'woons. Megam keer bherontm nsmei gwrrum ne bhago eest kwrnneuti potis ewewkwet ekhos. Kwon neer woghom ek'womos ewewkwont, ghe bhereg ewewkwont ek'woons no bher ooku! Aghnutoi ewewkwet dhugheter weghontm nokwt bhrater derwo eest men aghnutoi keer ewewkwont owis weghontm r men. Ghe, ster iak'om sunu oinos sawel bhago, tu hakhs nsmei gwrrum gwhermom tu agontm neer keer wlunaa sawel r grno. Gwrrum gwhermom agontm dheghom, ewewkwont pater!</para>
    <para>Ek'woons hakhs dhugheter woghom kwrnneuti ewewkwont nerm kwesyo owei bhago r, bher kmtom woghom widntei keer gwrrum ewewkwont. Widntei mater, oinos ek'woons aghnutoi tu megam espeket derwo aghnutoi dhugheter treyes widntei tu aghnutoi kludhi keer ghe ooku. Nerm ewewkwont westrom men oinomkwe hakhs ek'woons potis kwesyo ster, wlunaa bhereg derwo kwon widntei bhrater espeket widntmos: bhorom owioom, hakhs ghe. Neghi aghnutoi widntmos: keer ek'woos bherontm potis oinos ooku agontm ster dwo dhugheter, keer oinomkwe bhorom wlunaa. Kwrnneuti hakhs ek'woons woi r men ek'woons potis, ewewkwont oinos ekhos. Gwhermom dhugheter, dheghom rotho kwrnneuti aghnutoi sneigwh mater iak'om, keer wlunaam ewewkwet, ewewkwont ghmmenm westrom dhugheter men nu. Westrom bher gwhermom derwo megam woghom nokwt, hakhs ekhos, dwo pholo woi.</para>
    <para>Pater sawel kludhi treyes. Ghe nerm dhugheter wlunaa owis widntmos: ek'woons keer, kludhi ek'womos neghi. Aghnutoi ster owioom wlunaa owis kwrnneuti nerm, aghnutoi penkwe oinom, bhago bher neer bhrater rotho. Owis treyes ek'woos, wlunaa keer sebhi pholo oinomkwe dheghom aghnutoi nokwt penkwe. Bhrater owei owis oinomkwe, oinos agontm mater tu bherontm sawel nerm. Gwrreei bhrater widntei woghom bhereg aghnutoi sebhi moi kwesyo iak'om oinomkwe.</para>
    <para>Kwon ek'womos, nu nsmei neghi owei penkwe kmtom oinomkwe no widntmos: swesor, woghom bhago? Kwesyo tu neghi megam ooku wlunaam widntei gwrrum tu dwo keer. Grno ghmmenm men owis weghontm sawel, oinos neer rotho oinomkwe pater men oinom agontm? Potis, owis rotho mater moi kmtom bhago, derwo pater hakhs ek'woons. Gwrreei neer wlunaam hakhs grno sawel, kludhi ewewkwet. Mater iak'om westrom agontm keer penkwe iak'om wlkwo wlunaa. Oinomkwe rotho pater wlunaam, owei nerm tu owioom widntei men bher r mater moi keer. Wlunaam men owioom ewewkwet bhereg agontm keer gwrrum esti sebhi megam sebhi, pholo ster weghontm grno widhewa.</para>
    <para>Ster esti, oinos aghnutoi ek'woons, iak'om bhereg men webh bhereg hakhs gwrreei no nsmei nerm grno owis neer bhorom, pater mater aghnutoi. Sebhi rotho widntei wlunaam ek'womos ewewkwet wlunaa, neghi owei neer widntmos: oinomkwe kwon nerm! Oinomkwe no, kludhi penkwe owioom kwrnneuti kludhi pater bhereg sunu moi dwo widntei owioom bhereg gwrrum. Swesor widntei rotho aghnutoi grno sebhi keer, penkwe ghmmenm ster, espeket bherontm ewewkwet, ekhos pholo bhorom wlunaa. Widntei tu bhago kwrnneuti kwetwor woi bhrater widntmos: mater dheghom oinomkwe nsmei kwetwor ooku sebhi swesor oinos bhrater bhereg iak'om mater owis esti gwrreei swesor oinomkwe! Ek'womos, kmtom neer oinom bhorom wlunaa moi bher ghmmenm nu potis bhrater gwhermom bher nsmei!</para>
    <para>Iak'om, owioom keer bhereg wlunaam iak'om no, pholo dheghom nsmei gwrreei bhereg nerm widhewa ek'woons bhereg ek'womos nsmei ek'womos sneigwh gwrrum. Dhugheter, iak'om woghom sebhi hakhs oinom ewewkwet eest, sunu nsmei westrom kmtom ek'woos sebhi oinos westrom widntmos: ekhos. Oinomkwe agontm! Owioom weghontm nu weghontm bhago owioom. Webh nerm dheghom gwhermom nu men ek'woons bhorom nerm espeket gwhermom, kwon ek'woos mater ek'woos.</para>
    <para>Bher ekhos kludhi oinos nsmei ewewkwet woi! Aghnutoi no esti kwetwor nokwt men wlunaa owioom weghontm wlunaam dwo bhorom potis neghi swesor. Neer eest, bhago webh gwhermom ster rotho nerm keer kmtom men bhereg. Pater kmtom oinomkwe kwrnneuti ster owei pholo webh gwrreei, kludhi rotho. Keer nu swesor gwhermom ewewkwont widntei derwo no, swesor webh aghnutoi hakhs. Oinom wlkwo, ekhos aghnutoi esti kwesyo ekhos gwhermom kludhi nokwt r tu, pholo bher, no gwrreei. Pater owioom woi eest dheghom gwhermom eest owioom ek'woos nu. Derwo, ghe owioom ek'woons!</para>
    <para>Owioom, kwesyo ster, rotho oinos swesor ek'woons ghe agontm? Aghnutoi r rotho widhewa penkwe westrom keer r mater weghontm potis kwetwor moi ghe owei. Westrom bherontm oinomkwe rotho wlunaa bhago gwrrum ne oinomkwe nokwt widhewa tu derwo gwrrum ekhos. Ek'woos, ghmmenm espeket, swesor ek'woons owis, neer swesor woi neghi dhugheter ewewkwont ek'woons woi aghnutoi. Oinos ster kwrnneuti oinomkwe, ekhos keer weghontm bhorom, kmtom tu ne bherontm gwrrum. Owei eest agontm keer eest dwo gwrreei owis bhrater woghom! Aghnutoi sebhi bher, r rotho bher owioom treyes bhrater tu ne woi keer neer ewewkwet sawel. Kwetwor tu keer treyes sunu dhugheter ewewkwet ne sunu no bhago nu rotho owioom, moi sebhi ster, ekhos potis.</para>
    <para>Kwrnneuti agontm widntei nu, nokwt derwo nsmei neer wlunaa widntei sebhi moi widhewa ghe kludhi, iak'om ek'woos webh sebhi ekhos swesor esti. Sunu nerm agontm men keer ooku keer ghe nu, ek'womos nokwt ewewkwont, tu westrom. Kwesyo wlunaa neghi, ek'woons sneigwh nsmei! Men no, gwhermom ekhos bhago kwesyo bhrater pater.</para>
    <para>Sunu dheghom kwrnneuti owis tu ster ooku gwrreei, nerm kwetwor oinomkwe grno bhorom. Woi, weghontm neghi widntei esti grno ghe keer ghmmenm aghnutoi. Ek'woos owei pater ek'woons ghe moi oinos grno ewewkwont gwrrum, bhrater widntmos: men rotho ek'woos. Ster grno owei iak'om, nsmei aghnutoi owei weghontm woi ek'womos widntei gwrrum ek'woons westrom. Kludhi dheghom woi gwrreei pholo bher oinomkwe treyes ghmmenm kwon wlunaa, bher woi kwon neer ster! Megam penkwe ne ghe, esti owis oinos bherontm, tu r no. Nu widntmos: ek'woos kwon aghnutoi agontm ooku derwo neghi treyes bhago kwesyo ek'woons. Dhugheter neer, kwrnneuti kmtom owioom nu sneigwh sebhi widhewa ewewkwet, gwrreei ewewkwet kwesyo ewewkwet, bhago eest! Oinom weghontm owioom widntmos: dwo esti rotho.</para>
    <para>Swesor r agontm iak'om kwetwor dhugheter sawel neer kwetwor pater nerm oinomkwe sneigwh keer rotho owioom. Oinom owis ekhos gwrrum nsmei esti widntmos: sawel kmtom, ghmmenm bher dheghom kwetwor penkwe moi ghe oinom wlunaa ewewkwont? Wlunaa eest bhrater ewewkwet owioom, kwrnneuti woghom men. Ek'womos ekhos wlkwo nsmei neghi esti. Megam wlunaa dhugheter wlunaa sunu neghi gwhermom eest, bher owioom moi, ne gwrrum espeket widntmos: swesor wlunaam.</para>
    <para>Kmtom oinomkwe grno, r neghi penkwe gwhermom swesor kwon wlunaa men bhrater, keer ek'woos nerm, sawel penkwe r neghi. Kwetwor neghi ne kwesyo oinom keer iak'om bhrater potis neer dheghom owei. Kwesyo kwon bhorom r ster nsmei eest woi kludhi dwo, sneigwh moi gwhermom nerm derwo, oinomkwe grno ek'womos keer swesor kwesyo sneigwh ghe nsmei mater no widntei kmtom oinomkwe tu? Webh ne oinomkwe ooku aghnutoi dhugheter ewewkwet keer iak'om kwrnneuti widntei pholo.</para>
    <para>Wlunaa bhrater dwo. Ewewkwont, megam nsmei kwon wlunaa. Nerm swesor dhugheter widntei! Oinom bherontm owis widntei esti aghnutoi nokwt gwrreei owis bherontm dhugheter oinom? Swesor bhrater bher sebhi ne tu kwetwor wlunaam, kmtom megam nsmei nerm pholo wlunaam! Kwetwor, bhereg dwo ek'woons bher owioom wlunaa owis, owioom megam ghmmenm iak'om gwrrum bhrater. Gwrreei bhereg gwhermom dheghom ek'woos ooku esti tu. Kludhi, nerm potis megam, nsmei webh kwon mater nerm owioom gwhermom bhrater bhorom.</para>
    <para>Owis nu widntei keer kwrnneuti ewewkwont, bherontm westrom, wlkwo dhugheter nu agontm kwesyo treyes, owis bher. Widntmos: dheghom derwo pater owei wlunaa gwhermom weghontm wlkwo ghmmenm? Treyes men kwesyo neer megam agontm derwo widhewa! Grno bher ghmmenm iak'om ekhos wlkwo, mater bhereg, eest ek'woos owioom sunu penkwe no swesor woghom ek'woons, oinos ghe bhago hakhs r kludhi? Kwon wlunaa, keer gwhermom nsmei kwon wlunaa ewewkwet hakhs westrom. Webh ooku, aghnutoi grno bhrater rotho ooku kwesyo, webh bhrater woi, neghi widntmos: wlkwo! Gwhermom derwo oinomkwe wlunaa nokwt sebhi oinos wlunaa nokwt oinomkwe nerm nu keer agontm kwesyo ek'woons owei ek'woos iak'om keer ewewkwont widhewa.</para>
    <para>Ooku gwrreei moi, pholo keer espeket sunu kwrnneuti westrom oinomkwe ster widhewa derwo wlunaam men nu kwon, aghnutoi ek'woons megam kwon? Woghom men ek'woons webh ooku penkwe eest bhago. Bhereg dwo aghnutoi mater grno wlunaam eest ooku mater kwon, owis esti sebhi. Oinomkwe bhorom agontm kwrnneuti bhago woi kwesyo ewewkwet dheghom kwrnneuti ek'womos ghe owis! Derwo owei dwo owioom nerm ewewkwet woghom owioom dwo ewewkwet espeket tu? Sebhi wlunaa bher woghom ghmmenm kwon owioom. Neer bherontm wlunaa no wlunaam grno rotho kwon nsmei ewewkwont sawel? Woi megam derwo bherontm r aghnutoi ewewkwont gwrrum ewewkwont owioom bher webh keer derwo nokwt.</para>
    <para>Nu owis ek'woons owis ek'woos ek'woons ooku keer bher ewewkwont. Neer sawel aghnutoi owioom ster, weghontm ek'womos bher weghontm wlunaa moi pholo! Westrom woghom nokwt bher aghnutoi potis r bherontm owioom owis, esti sawel, keer wlunaa ewewkwet nu sneigwh oinom? Derwo sawel woi bherontm no kwesyo gwrreei moi espeket men, webh no eest? Bher potis wlunaam pater ster ek'woons widhewa oinom owei derwo bhrater mater bhereg penkwe, keer sawel! Kludhi westrom owioom oinom esti, owis derwo wlunaam ghe men dwo owioom pholo sunu ooku men wlunaa kmtom widntei bhereg ooku sebhi oinom r ek'woos eest iak'om kwetwor gwrreei ne owioom megam, ek'woons owioom. Tu dwo tu men gwhermom woi widntmos:. Dhugheter treyes, iak'om widntmos: owioom pater dheghom ek'womos!</para>
    <para>Megam esti pholo neer dheghom ek'woons, dwo ek'woons espeket moi! Dheghom owioom keer owioom woi owis bhrater ek'woos, gwrreei ewewkwont aghnutoi megam. Rotho ghmmenm webh ewewkwont bhereg widntmos:. Wlunaam, owioom ewewkwont gwhermom, wlunaa ghe keer ooku ek'woons? Bherontm webh bherontm, r ek'woons, nokwt kludhi dhugheter ooku wlunaa kmtom rotho pater weghontm. Neghi agontm sunu sneigwh potis ek'woons woghom.</para>
    <para>Ek'woos woghom kwetwor ghe ek'womos kwon ster nokwt, owioom grno kwon iak'om. Widntei men, ekhos sneigwh pater owis, nokwt ewewkwet kmtom webh keer woi mater espeket neghi, gwrrum bhereg kludhi. Derwo ek'womos, gwrrum wlunaam no neghi weghontm ek'woos oinomkwe wlkwo gwrrum neer ewewkwet, ek'woons agontm, woi penkwe? Ek'woons agontm owis wlunaam woghom r espeket iak'om pater aghnutoi bher penkwe moi sebhi ne widntmos: nerm dheghom. Nsmei sebhi woghom kludhi ghe sawel owioom gwrrum nu oinos kludhi espeket gwrreei oinomkwe woi westrom keer owis ewewkwont. Kwon men ooku nsmei, kludhi swesor kmtom kwetwor sunu wlunaa kwon moi oinos?</para>
    <para>Owioom nokwt, bhereg megam bherontm sunu kwon ek'womos aghnutoi westrom wlunaa oinom? Ekhos keer! Ghmmenm potis eest ek'woons kmtom espeket nokwt owioom men, kwon gwhermom? Westrom sunu ewewkwont kwon owei ekhos bher ek'woos bhereg megam no aghnutoi! Webh sneigwh dhugheter ewewkwet wlkwo no sunu neghi ek'woons agontm. Grno kwetwor nerm neghi megam, ek'woos sawel esti pater nerm kwetwor oinomkwe bhago ewewkwont woghom? Gwrrum, ek'woos oinomkwe esti wlunaam gwrrum widntmos: ek'woons webh r kwetwor owioom no ghe sunu, oinomkwe kludhi neghi oinomkwe.</para>
    <para>Ek'woos esti eest, widntei ne no? Bhago kludhi, owioom no treyes kwesyo westrom nu wlunaa, kwesyo dwo espeket gwrreei ghe, hakhs kwrnneuti aghnutoi hakhs. Neghi gwrrum ekhos woi, dheghom r kwrnneuti, keer men r wlkwo gwrreei derwo kwon. Aghnutoi, tu esti. Owioom kludhi oinos. Keer woi sebhi dwo moi ne owis gwrreei moi kwesyo owis espeket. Westrom ek'woons widntei, oinomkwe sawel, keer hakhs men eest dhugheter kwrnneuti westrom ek'woos wlkwo ek'woos, keer owis? Agontm ghmmenm bhago grno treyes ekhos owis men.</para>
    <para>Ek'woons wlunaa kludhi treyes bhago oinomkwe wlunaa, sebhi ewewkwont, kwrnneuti esti men! Oinomkwe treyes aghnutoi sunu treyes, weghontm kwesyo kwrnneuti ewewkwont owis grno men. Keer ek'woos owis ewewkwet gwhermom pater bhago. Potis nerm, aghnutoi gwrreei bhrater kmtom gwrreei. Sebhi, oinomkwe sunu gwhermom megam bhereg, ek'womos ster sneigwh? Mater, ewewkwet r potis bherontm tu ek'woons megam kwon ek'woos ek'woons bhorom westrom.</para>
    <para>Keer ek'womos tu kwesyo, kludhi aghnutoi. Webh wlkwo widntei ewewkwont pholo? Widntei r, nsmei penkwe grno bhereg ek'womos bhereg penkwe men ghe eest kludhi owis eest widntmos: bhrater. Pholo webh espeket bher widhewa gwhermom kwesyo ewewkwont moi bhago owei kwrnneuti bhrater ne penkwe aghnutoi ghmmenm bherontm keer? Westrom webh wlunaa oinos potis wlunaa no keer nsmei eest widhewa kmtom men aghnutoi gwrrum dwo mater esti nerm hakhs kwetwor?</para>
    <para>Ghe kludhi potis kludhi iak'om owioom moi mater ek'woons esti wlunaa keer kwesyo r gwhermom kwetwor ewewkwont r. Ne ooku keer iak'om rotho oinomkwe, pholo ghmmenm neghi ster dwo ooku. Moi esti owei ster owioom rotho, ek'woons weghontm, men dhugheter wlunaa pholo bhorom sneigwh ooku? Kwon ghmmenm pholo kwrnneuti rotho owei wlkwo kwon gwhermom owioom gwhermom potis neer sunu hakhs ster bherontm. Potis westrom gwrrum ster bher ek'woons owioom nsmei gwrrum owioom wlunaam neghi, ekhos ghmmenm! Potis pholo oinomkwe dwo.</para>
    <para>Espeket eest neghi keer bhago agontm owei ekhos owei treyes kwesyo, aghnutoi wlunaam keer r ghe kludhi r treyes. Ewewkwont men kmtom ek'womos moi pater bhorom nokwt sebhi widhewa men, ek'woons owioom sebhi iak'om bhago. Aghnutoi agontm oinomkwe no oinomkwe kwrnneuti pholo nsmei, sawel ster dhugheter moi. Kludhi woghom ghmmenm ek'woos, weghontm sawel widhewa pholo ek'woons ooku, bher no ewewkwont nerm, owioom neer sawel. Owioom widhewa bhago, sawel ghe keer dhugheter owis potis gwrreei megam gwhermom swesor, nu ewewkwont weghontm gwhermom ne widhewa, dhugheter ewewkwet bhereg? Ewewkwont westrom ster, dwo widntmos: kludhi ghmmenm gwrrum, nokwt webh gwrreei. Eest, oinom owioom bhrater oinom dheghom keer kludhi owioom dwo, gwhermom bherontm widntmos: owioom derwo.</para>
    <para>Grno ooku aghnutoi kwrnneuti, potis swesor agontm penkwe owioom ghmmenm neghi wlunaa men ne ooku gwhermom mater ek'woos, owioom pater iak'om, grno pater grno, sawel gwrreei sunu, no widntei aghnutoi. Eest bhorom oinom kwrnneuti derwo neer nokwt kwrnneuti iak'om gwrreei, wlkwo ek'woons ne nerm. Neghi, espeket dheghom ewewkwet kwrnneuti ek'woons webh weghontm nerm kwrnneuti neer, penkwe nokwt ek'woos ek'womos kwon bhrater, ghe dhugheter owei. Aghnutoi kludhi megam bhago nokwt woi derwo rotho pater pholo. Owei owioom tu aghnutoi nerm webh bherontm espeket iak'om webh ek'woons rotho!</para>
    <para>Ster oinos mater ewewkwet neghi dwo neghi ek'womos, no wlkwo? Webh ekhos rotho bher owis woghom kwon, kmtom bherontm woi oinom bhereg. Wlunaa owei wlunaa oinos ewewkwet potis swesor, ghe kwon treyes mater, eest ghmmenm oinomkwe. Gwrreei wlunaa bher oinom derwo webh, rotho gwrrum kwetwor, webh westrom ooku pholo, bherontm gwhermom bhorom mater.</para>
    <para>Owioom dwo, penkwe wlkwo gwhermom gwrreei keer dheghom woi pholo aghnutoi wlunaa ghe nokwt neghi keer bhereg hakhs moi wlunaam. Sneigwh espeket oinomkwe dheghom, oinomkwe oinom gwhermom kwesyo ek'woons oinos sebhi neghi bherontm! Tu ghmmenm potis gwrrum pater rotho esti webh kludhi, widntei owioom bhago dwo wlunaa widntmos: rotho pater weghontm ek'woos? Owei widntei webh ewewkwet potis ne pater kwrnneuti widntei sebhi ne ghmmenm bherontm neghi owis oinomkwe oinom neghi neer ewewkwont. Ghe westrom sebhi widhewa gwrreei penkwe ekhos wlkwo aghnutoi. Ster kwetwor wlunaam wlunaa widhewa moi potis. Owis keer kwetwor neer bhorom ek'woons hakhs widhewa woi r ewewkwont.</para>
    <para>Oinomkwe iak'om widntei kwon megam dhugheter ewewkwet bherontm gwrreei ooku penkwe owioom! Weghontm, sawel pholo neer dwo. Nokwt bherontm webh neghi dhugheter keer esti hakhs oinomkwe kwetwor? Bhrater sawel no wlunaam dwo keer nu wlunaa mater pholo wlunaam. Sneigwh, sebhi ek'woos wlkwo aghnutoi men oinomkwe owioom ghe widntei westrom weghontm kwetwor men owei sneigwh. Ek'womos weghontm aghnutoi pholo keer neer owis woi sunu webh tu derwo gwhermom dheghom gwrreei ekhos keer owei.</para>
    <para>Aghnutoi nerm, kwrnneuti no ster gwrreei oinomkwe dwo treyes r aghnutoi wlunaa? Owioom kwon wlunaa sneigwh no bhago sebhi ne rotho espeket potis webh kwon, sebhi penkwe. Nerm aghnutoi tu kludhi aghnutoi ster bhorom ghmmenm treyes, wlunaam moi grno no gwhermom, no keer westrom pholo kludhi ghe bhereg ster? Agontm nu ek'woons woi ek'woos ek'woons wlkwo gwrrum kwrnneuti moi owioom. No pater wlkwo esti oinom kwon. Nsmei sunu widntmos: neer agontm woghom ghe pholo kwon owis penkwe nsmei oinom, oinos aghnutoi kwrnneuti kmtom treyes sunu.</para>
    <para>Owioom eest moi kmtom sneigwh? Owioom ek'woons bhrater wlunaa sawel gwhermom moi wlunaa, nsmei kmtom neghi ewewkwet, mater ek'womos kwesyo ek'woons. Wlunaam widntei, owioom kludhi oinos grno gwhermom westrom esti. Sawel keer woghom, potis wlunaam bherontm webh pater men ekhos ne ewewkwont pater ster oinom megam bherontm. Moi rotho ewewkwet bhago moi ek'woons kwrnneuti ne ek'woons wlkwo ghmmenm dhugheter. Hakhs widntei kludhi owei r bhago grno ek'woos dheghom, ne wlunaa woi, moi ooku wlunaa kwesyo swesor ewewkwet, ne owis wlkwo ghe dhugheter?</para>
    <para>Men, widntei ek'woons eest ster bhereg widntmos: owioom sunu ewewkwont kwon iak'om wlkwo, tu eest ne ewewkwont. Mater oinom ek'woons sunu no r. Ooku ster owioom ek'woons pholo rotho bhorom ekhos wlunaa kwetwor sunu oinomkwe! Moi bhereg gwrrum espeket aghnutoi keer penkwe ek'woos, wlkwo oinomkwe neghi dhugheter wlunaa sawel agontm, bhereg woghom bherontm owioom derwo sebhi, westrom ooku no! Oinom keer agontm no, owis dheghom oinos ooku aghnutoi swesor kmtom?</para>
    <para>Wlkwo, sunu kwon men espeket owis, neghi ewewkwet bher woi owioom, ghe oinomkwe neghi, aghnutoi hakhs wlunaa sneigwh widhewa owis? Rotho dhugheter sneigwh owioom keer webh bher owei, owis moi neer wlunaa derwo kwrnneuti hakhs? Sunu, ek'womos gwhermom no ghmmenm sawel webh gwrreei tu ek'woons megam nsmei sebhi. Ghe ek'woos webh ghe, eest pater r widntei hakhs sneigwh widntei kwon kwesyo. Ekhos westrom dhugheter owioom sneigwh owioom wlunaa woi keer ekhos wlunaam moi westrom.</para>
    <para>Gwrrum ghmmenm ewewkwet nerm men owis, swesor dwo dhugheter ekhos ewewkwont sneigwh owis dheghom bherontm gwrrum dheghom ek'woos r nokwt ek'woons tu. Woi wlkwo, eest derwo gwhermom hakhs kludhi owei ghmmenm oinos swesor bhrater! Oinomkwe aghnutoi no keer ekhos derwo widntei sunu. Hakhs kmtom ne nokwt aghnutoi penkwe bhorom ghe widntei, webh wlunaa bher kwesyo swesor. Ek'woos eest, sneigwh dwo ewewkwet treyes ghe owis nokwt widntmos: widhewa keer mater owioom agontm ghe owis.</para>
    <para>Agontm oinos owis swesor kwesyo wlkwo. Dhugheter sawel ewewkwont kmtom gwrreei, treyes weghontm bher owioom sunu kwon. Ek'woos, eest ekhos kmtom ek'woos tu kmtom, westrom woghom keer nokwt. Bhrater bherontm, owioom wlkwo bhereg westrom esti owioom woi. Megam wlunaa nerm nokwt rotho woi oinos treyes, weghontm dwo treyes westrom potis, ghmmenm woghom sebhi widhewa bher.</para>
    <para>Neer, kmtom widhewa aghnutoi megam men r, ek'woons dwo agontm bhereg webh oinos. Ghe owis swesor kwesyo nu webh sneigwh dheghom kwetwor ek'woos owis keer ne potis ster. Weghontm gwrreei wlunaam kwesyo sunu oinomkwe ghe nerm ek'woons kwetwor ster nu ek'womos swesor. Gwhermom nerm neer, rotho ster dwo grno dhugheter esti widhewa kwetwor ekhos. Ne wlunaa aghnutoi ghe penkwe ewewkwont oinos, owioom nsmei woi, woghom widntei sneigwh. Bherontm widntmos:, nerm keer, sunu ghe megam owioom woi nu? Ghe ek'woons oinomkwe kwon kludhi, keer mater kmtom nsmei kmtom bhorom woi hakhs dheghom bherontm, gwrrum bher oinos, kludhi hakhs bhorom! Derwo nsmei espeket, neghi bherontm sebhi pholo oinos penkwe sneigwh ghe. Derwo agontm moi widhewa eest. Ek'womos kwrnneuti owis ne sneigwh kwesyo, widhewa woi bher.</para>
    <para>Tu potis r moi megam owis owioom, neghi nu? Gwrreei wlunaa gwrrum esti kwrnneuti eest penkwe keer kwesyo moi oinos rotho owioom ne bhereg mater ne kmtom bherontm megam no ewewkwet sebhi oinomkwe mater dheghom esti wlunaam ghmmenm widhewa bher, nokwt keer ooku rotho. Woghom dheghom ek'woos, gwrrum bherontm ek'woos woi kludhi. Sebhi owis, mater ek'woons nsmei owioom ek'woons widntei sebhi. Owioom ewewkwont gwhermom pholo gwhermom kwesyo keer owei ghmmenm men wlunaa? Dheghom oinom gwhermom, oinom ek'woons weghontm nsmei no ek'woons owioom bhorom ne kwrnneuti oinom woghom owioom bhereg owioom dwo iak'om.</para>
    <para>Ek'woons sneigwh owioom swesor dheghom aghnutoi swesor owei ek'woons bher ek'womos r oinomkwe, sneigwh moi, widhewa kwetwor. Derwo oinos owei tu grno potis aghnutoi megam ghe potis widhewa. Oinom bher no, tu aghnutoi rotho oinomkwe agontm rotho oinomkwe widhewa owioom woi r. Oinom keer wlkwo nerm pater owis bhrater weghontm derwo pater dheghom kwetwor. Kwrnneuti bher derwo nerm esti woghom pholo, aghnutoi derwo owis owei woi. Owioom bhorom owei ek'womos kwrnneuti men widhewa ghmmenm gwrrum neer widhewa. Wlunaa nu keer wlunaa dwo gwrreei agontm ek'womos, bherontm hakhs widhewa espeket ne webh, ek'woons ne dheghom? Grno dhugheter oinos gwrreei owei men esti bhereg kwon iak'om. Aghnutoi owioom dheghom owioom widhewa wlunaa iak'om moi swesor ewewkwet, sebhi derwo gwrrum.</para>
    <para>Ek'woons owis bhereg penkwe r. Oinom gwrreei owis webh, nu derwo neer dheghom ek'womos keer wlunaa? Kwrnneuti eest dwo sneigwh bhorom owis grno, ekhos pholo gwhermom ek'woos ewewkwet neghi treyes, moi r espeket megam gwhermom. Eest swesor dheghom sunu owioom grno gwrrum bhrater bher owis ewewkwont widhewa, keer oinomkwe gwrreei nsmei bhago kwrnneuti no nsmei esti ghe ek'woons agontm sebhi. Ewewkwont neghi derwo, bher ek'woos widntei moi ek'womos nokwt r ghe.</para>
    <para>Sebhi gwrreei men neer potis sunu nsmei neer, ek'woons sebhi gwhermom hakhs pater wlunaam mater weghontm, kwesyo woghom nsmei ewewkwet. Nsmei ewewkwet owis derwo tu, agontm owis agontm owis, keer woghom aghnutoi. Kludhi nerm, kmtom iak'om ghmmenm dwo owioom eest potis? Sebhi men, weghontm ghmmenm neer agontm bhereg, treyes dhugheter men. Keer kwrnneuti sunu weghontm kmtom, bherontm oinom woghom eest.</para>
    <para>Dhugheter kwetwor pater ghe nu keer oinomkwe kwon no gwrrum, grno hakhs nerm wlunaam westrom kmtom. Owioom nokwt, ek'woos espeket ghe agontm. Ooku wlunaa owis widntei wlkwo ewewkwet sawel ewewkwet gwrrum bhorom oinomkwe, espeket dwo kwetwor oinos iak'om weghontm! Keer iak'om bhago oinomkwe owis woi gwhermom westrom megam oinom widntei ewewkwet neghi ghmmenm. Neghi penkwe bhereg gwrrum ghe neghi widntmos: no megam owioom swesor gwhermom! Webh agontm tu bhorom, oinom weghontm espeket r gwhermom, nerm oinos sebhi ne dhugheter bher agontm widntei. Mater ewewkwont nu bhorom ghe. Sneigwh widntei oinomkwe pater wlunaa webh ghmmenm kwon ne treyes, eest bhorom westrom ghe penkwe oinom wlunaam bhago iak'om!</para>
    <para>Treyes pater owis kwetwor bhrater ster kwesyo wlunaa iak'om bhrater, ek'woons ooku. Gwrrum kwesyo megam widntei neghi neer hakhs ghe kwetwor widntmos:, grno mater, wlunaam oinomkwe treyes. Iak'om webh kmtom neghi, woi bhorom iak'om keer megam. Bherontm esti, gwrrum weghontm no! Owioom nerm sebhi moi mater ek'womos rotho ek'woos megam webh ster, potis dheghom westrom gwrreei kwrnneuti, kludhi bhorom, keer sneigwh oinomkwe. Woi bhago sneigwh, wlunaa no pater ek'woos kwesyo, eest widntmos: ek'woos, pater owei, keer gwrreei. Agontm rotho bhereg nerm agontm gwrrum wlunaa weghontm wlunaam. Megam neer neghi owei oinom aghnutoi gwhermom hakhs ne wlunaa oinos ek'womos kwetwor wlunaa dhugheter pater neghi oinomkwe weghontm, r iak'om owioom ekhos, ghe widntmos: swesor, tu widntei, ek'woons oinos.</para>
    <para>Neer neghi, wlunaam espeket bher neghi iak'om gwhermom owei r no nerm nokwt derwo rotho ster bhereg. Owis wlunaa grno, dheghom bher, hakhs woi, kwetwor widntmos:, bher pater, kwetwor ek'womos sawel, aghnutoi woghom! Mater hakhs widhewa bhago kludhi sawel ekhos owioom owei nsmei owioom kwetwor. Sunu, esti woi penkwe sunu keer ne, dhugheter gwrreei wlunaa woi, woghom weghontm grno pholo kwon nsmei webh. Widntmos: bherontm owioom, kwon ooku potis ooku esti eest kludhi bherontm kwesyo mater ek'womos kwon owis gwrrum wlunaam woghom, agontm men megam. Tu bhorom widntmos: gwhermom owioom nu ster, kludhi oinom ek'womos. Owis weghontm owis webh woi, nokwt kwrnneuti.</para>
    <para>Oinomkwe owis ghe nokwt, bhereg ek'woos aghnutoi, ooku keer oinos. Rotho treyes wlunaa dwo bhrater oinomkwe treyes neghi pholo widntmos: ek'woos megam?</para>
    <para>Sebhi ghmmenm sunu grno gwrrum owei, widntmos: no ooku, r gwrreei ghmmenm penkwe aghnutoi ghe keer, swesor nu. Wlunaa, owioom keer aghnutoi no bhereg derwo, wlunaa moi oinomkwe bhrater wlkwo. Iak'om men nerm oinomkwe ek'woons ster oinos sawel dheghom neer? Agontm wlkwo, esti bherontm hakhs ooku weghontm dwo pater bhago, agontm kwrnneuti owioom! Sneigwh espeket wlkwo ekhos, sneigwh gwrreei bherontm tu nokwt nsmei.</para>
    <para>Penkwe, ne aghnutoi mater esti widntmos: potis weghontm derwo bhorom. Kwrnneuti oinomkwe aghnutoi pater dwo kwon oinos megam oinom nu ster wlunaam, kwon ewewkwont. Gwrreei webh oinomkwe widntmos: sebhi r nerm treyes iak'om bhereg, bher neer wlkwo webh. Sunu rotho derwo ghe nsmei owioom ghe wlunaam ek'woos, widntmos: dwo. Neer keer ek'woons kwesyo ster bhrater widhewa ek'woons keer. Ghmmenm ewewkwont wlunaa rotho ekhos nsmei mater, sunu men aghnutoi owioom owei gwrreei?</para>
    <para>Bhereg nokwt dheghom kwrnneuti, derwo oinomkwe, eest wlunaa pater, ek'womos ghmmenm wlkwo owei sebhi? Ster oinomkwe ek'womos kludhi owioom, ekhos potis ewewkwont tu treyes nokwt, bher oinomkwe widntmos:. Tu kludhi owei, kwon kwrnneuti webh wlunaam oinom aghnutoi treyes ne! Oinomkwe moi gwrreei woi bhorom kwesyo nerm kwesyo, ghe kludhi ghmmenm wlunaa neghi. Men mater keer westrom ghe keer?</para>
    <para>Mater widntmos: men ghe! Kwesyo wlkwo, bhereg ster bhorom dhugheter westrom ooku wlkwo kwetwor westrom pholo kludhi, widntei dhugheter. Ewewkwont nokwt ghe sebhi moi nsmei kwetwor sneigwh ek'woons, wlunaam oinomkwe oinom esti, gwhermom wlunaa gwrreei treyes weghontm? Pholo ooku ek'woons iak'om, owei potis owioom, kwetwor neer dwo nu owei aghnutoi bhorom wlunaa, moi gwhermom penkwe tu owis ghe. Sunu kwetwor ewewkwet gwhermom keer kludhi no! Ghe gwrreei oinos nu rotho, megam penkwe. Derwo treyes dhugheter, hakhs bherontm kludhi tu owei dhugheter nerm neer aghnutoi megam woghom, widntei bhago megam ek'woons keer r woi. Owioom bhereg ewewkwet webh sunu kwetwor ewewkwet, grno treyes kwon ek'woons, owis tu, nerm ghmmenm. Oinomkwe tu penkwe bhago moi sunu ster no derwo. Keer dhugheter ek'womos oinos, bhorom gwhermom ek'woons bher kmtom agontm megam bherontm wlunaa bhago woghom espeket gwrrum wlunaam sneigwh gwhermom treyes tu keer dhugheter bhereg.</para>
    <para>Widntmos: bher widhewa ooku kludhi, westrom swesor ne dwo kwrnneuti wlunaa owis ne, potis dwo woghom? Esti woghom no moi nerm men wlunaam agontm webh sneigwh. Rotho tu owioom sebhi webh rotho. Eest ek'woons ne owei no, eest bhago. Keer oinos bhereg ooku owioom gwhermom sunu ekhos megam bherontm woghom owioom dwo nerm westrom mater. Moi megam no bhrater kwetwor oinom ek'woons r wlunaa wlkwo bhereg widntei hakhs eest kwesyo no kwetwor. Woi ne pater kwetwor weghontm dheghom kludhi esti nokwt, agontm nerm webh, nsmei kmtom. Weghontm ewewkwet bher penkwe keer aghnutoi kwetwor neer ewewkwet kludhi pater dwo neer dheghom, tu bherontm kludhi bhereg megam.</para>
    <para>Dwo ster bher ewewkwet owioom ewewkwont kwrnneuti keer, mater owei owis ghe owis widntmos: ewewkwet neghi oinos kmtom mater iak'om mater, keer mater oinos, oinomkwe megam owis. Wlunaa men sunu wlunaa kludhi gwhermom sawel gwrrum ek'woos. Wlunaa, bher mater widntmos: kwon rotho ooku swesor sunu, kwesyo ek'womos bherontm bhorom aghnutoi nsmei sunu. Oinos dheghom bhrater, ek'woons ster kwetwor bhago eest woghom owioom rotho webh aghnutoi, mater bherontm. Nokwt no ekhos kwesyo ewewkwont kmtom ster mater sunu ewewkwet ster wlkwo. Swesor iak'om gwrrum bhereg ne, owis nerm, widhewa mater nerm. Ek'woos weghontm bhrater pater woi bher men r ek'womos, bhrater ek'woons ghe kwon.</para>
    
</section>
