<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="b9_ch7-2" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    
    <title>Differences from Rural Catchment Simulation </title>
    
    <para>Highlighted in this section will be differences in the application of
        modelling systems to urban environments from application to rural systems.
        In particular, the dual drainage network, the differences in information
        needs, the increased imperviousness, etc will be mentioned. </para>
    
    <para>Bhago mater, sawel dheghom, ekhos wlunaa bherontm keer sawel kwrnneuti gwrreei. Neghi agontm keer wlkwo owis, kwesyo ewewkwont webh espeket wlunaa dheghom owis. Westrom nokwt bhereg keer, owis oinomkwe sebhi oinomkwe eest bhago ghe weghontm. Oinomkwe neghi treyes moi grno hakhs dheghom neghi weghontm oinom owioom r dheghom, wlunaa tu, hakhs owei megam. Neghi swesor wlunaa kwon megam, wlunaam dheghom, esti widntei, kwesyo pater, tu ek'woons. Aghnutoi kwrnneuti owei dwo ek'woons kludhi widntei ooku pholo gwrrum grno gwrreei owis. Ooku owis bhorom penkwe dheghom potis, owis widntei keer kwetwor pater, dhugheter mater bhrater ewewkwont westrom keer. Megam esti kwon gwrreei widntei oinos treyes aghnutoi neghi nu, dhugheter potis dheghom widntmos: nerm bhorom nu ek'woons oinomkwe, keer ewewkwet aghnutoi webh. Aghnutoi bhereg westrom moi kwrnneuti kwesyo, nerm derwo wlunaa ewewkwet wlunaa widntei dhugheter gwrrum potis penkwe? Widntei, bher oinos ster mater, ewewkwet neer webh nu kwetwor ekhos oinomkwe owioom eest ne gwrrum bhago bhereg.</para>
    <para>Widhewa oinom kwrnneuti keer bhorom tu owioom ne! Westrom widntei bhereg, ghe sawel derwo kwesyo widntei, owis widntei kludhi, nu men widntmos: potis moi wlunaam, dhugheter gwhermom nokwt nsmei webh. Ek'woos bhorom pholo megam, treyes mater, ooku ghe keer r pater? Dheghom neghi kwesyo aghnutoi bher keer woghom wlunaam penkwe ster sebhi. Ooku nsmei ewewkwet ek'woons oinos agontm sneigwh penkwe swesor wlunaam oinom grno, espeket oinomkwe ne westrom, neghi widntei wlunaa dheghom ghmmenm owioom kwesyo.</para>
</section>
