<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b2_ch1"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
         <info><title>Introduction</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>

         </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Advanced draft</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section>
    <title>Scope and Intent</title>
    <para>Nearly all design flood estimation techniques rely on rainfall inputs to estimate flood
      quantiles. These methods use catchment modelling techniques to estimate the flood quantiles
      that would be derived from Flood Frequency Analysis if a long-term gauge record was available.
      While simple methods just use rainfall intensity frequency duration data more complex
      approaches require temporal and spatial rainfall information and continuous simulation
      approaches require long-term rainfall sequences. Irrespective of the approach, it is important
      to understand how the design rainfall inputs were derived and how they vary from observed
      events. </para>
    <para>Despite the advances in flood estimation many design inputs are assumed to be much simpler
      than real or observed events. The more complex methods continue to make assumptions including
      the use storm burst instead of a complete storm and spatial uniform temporal patterns. For
      these reasons actual rainfall events tend to show considerably more variability than design
      events and often have different probabilities at different locations. </para>
    <para>This book describes the different rainfall inputs can be derived and how they can be used.
        <xref linkend="b2_ch2"/> provides an introduction to rainfall models. <xref linkend="b2_ch3"
      /> details the development of the design rainfalls (Intensity Frequency Duration data) by the
      Bureau of Meteorology. <xref linkend="b2_ch4"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch5"/> discuss the
      spatial and temporal distributions of rainfall respectively. <xref linkend="b2_ch6"/> covers
      the development of continuous rainfall time series for use in continuous simulation
      models.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Application of these Guidelines </title>
    <para>The application of the design inputs discussed in this Book to Very Rare and Extreme
      floods is discussed in <xref linkend="book8"/>.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Climate Change </title>
    <para>These guidelines apply to the current climate. Statistically significant increases in
      rainfall intensity have been detected in Australia for short duration rainfall events and are
      likely to become more evident towards the end of the 21st century
        <citation>b2_c5_r33</citation>. Changes in long duration events are expected to be smaller
      and harder to detect, but projections analysed by <citation>b1_c2_r7+1</citation> show that an
      increase in daily precipitation intensity is likely under climate change. It is worth noting
      that a warming climate can lead to decreases in annual rainfall along with increases in flood
      producing rainfall.</para>
    <para>The IFD’s presented in this chapter can be adjusted for future climates using the method
      outlined in <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/> Which recommends an approach based on temperature scaling
      using temperature projections from the CSIRO future climates tool. Scaling based on
      temperature is recommended, as climate models are much more reliable at producing temperature
      estimates than individual storm events. </para>
    <para>The impact of climate change on storm frequency, mechanism, spatial and temporal behaviour
      is less understood. Work by <citation>b1_c4_r1 </citation> suggests that increases are likely
      to be more pronounced in areas with strong orographic enhancement. There is insufficient
      evidence to confirm whether this result is applicable to other parts of Australia. Work by
        <citation>b2_c5_r30</citation> analysing historical storms found that, regardless of the
      climate region or season, temperature increases are associated with patterns becoming less
      uniform, with the largest fractions increasing in rainfall intensity and the lower fraction
      decreasing.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Terminology</title>
    <para>The terminology for frequency descriptor described in <xref linkend="arr_pref_term_table"
      /> applies to all chapters of this book other than <xref linkend="b2_ch3"/> Design Rainfall.
    </para>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  

</chapter>
