<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b8_ch5" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <info>
    <title>Selection, Configuration, and Calibration of Hydrograph Models</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td>Chapter Status</td>
      <td>Final</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>14/5/2019</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_pn0kr">
    <title>General</title>
    <para>In Australia, both unit hydrograph models and runoff-routing models have traditionally
      been applied for event-based flood hydrograph estimation but over the last decade there has
      been a shift to almost exclusive use of runoff-routing models. In recent times attention has
      also been given to the use of “rain-on-grid” approaches with two dimensional (2D) hydraulic
      models. Discussion on the general catchment modelling concepts and the application of
      hydrograph and catchment models to the estimation of design floods is provided in <xref
        linkend="book4"/>, <xref linkend="book5"/> and <xref linkend="book7"/>.</para>
    <para>The following discussion is focussed on the application of event-based runoff-routing
      models to estimate Very Rare to Extreme floods, i.e. those design situations in which models
      are used to estimate floods well beyond the range for which they can be calibrated or their
      performance tested against observed floods. The principal purpose of these flood estimates is
      to support risk-based or standards-based design decisions. In some situations, such as
      floodplain management, extreme floods are estimated to provide a notional upper bound of the
      flood extent or as a performance check, and it is likely that the more rigorous considerations
      provided in this book are not justified.</para>
    <para>Guidance on the use of rain-on-grid approaches for estimation of Very Rare to Extreme
      floods is not provided here for two reasons: firstly, as discussed in <xref linkend="book5"/>,
        <xref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="book6"/> and <xref linkend="book7"
      />, the techniques have not been well researched or validated at this point in time and their
      use to simulate overland flow routing raises a number of difficulties which are likely to be
      exacerbated under extreme event conditions; secondly, such models are generally focussed on
      applications in floodplain management where the design risks of interest are at the lower
      range of events relevant to the guidance presented in this Book. However, the use of hydraulic
      models to simulate extreme floods does have some theoretical merit, and it is hoped that with
      further research guidelines can be developed that better integrate the benefits of these two
      approaches.</para>
    <para>For event-based models, the quality of the modelled flood hydrographs depends on three
      components of the modelling process: (i) the basic model capabilities and constraints, (ii)
      the quality of the catchment representation in the model, and (iii) the appropriateness of the
      selected parameter values in the flood range of interest. General recommendations for these
      three components in the context of estimating Very Rare to Extreme floods are provided
      separately in <xref linkend="b8_s_zvvef"/> to <xref linkend="b8_s_fxgci"/>, but it should be
      recognised that the components are closely linked. The theoretical advantages of a more
      flexible model that allows a more accurate representation of the important catchment features
      can only be realised if suitable data or design information exists to identify appropriate
      model parameter values.</para>
    <para>In the application of runoff-routing models, a distinction needs to be made between
      essentially rural catchments and substantially urbanised catchments. <xref
        linkend="b8_s_tbwiz"/> deals with the determination of model parameters for essentially
      rural catchments, while the special aspects of model parameterisation for urban catchments are
      dealt with in <xref linkend="b8_s_fxgci"/>.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_zvvef">
    <title>Model Features and Capabilities Required to Estimate Very Rare to Extreme  Events</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_q4tp3">
      <title>Considerations in Model Selection</title>
      <para>The functionalities of a hydrograph modelling package for estimating Very Rare to
        Extreme floods can be divided into basic and enhanced modelling capabilities. The basic
        capabilities indicated in <xref linkend="b8_s_jxz2e"/> are regarded as essential for a
        modelling package that will allow satisfactory reproduction of runoff response
        characteristics over a range of catchments with different features for use in final design
        applications. Small catchments and catchments with reasonably uniform characteristics are
        less demanding in their basic model requirements. The enhanced model capabilities discussed
        in <xref linkend="b8_s_f8tz9"/> represent desirable model extensions required for
        applications in situations where the complexity of the catchment or the importance of the
        results warrants more detailed modelling. The enhanced models form a sounder basis for
        extrapolation to extreme events. The importance of these modelling capabilities is somewhat
        dependent upon catchment size, and judgement is required to determine the extent to which
        the following issues need to be considered.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_jxz2e">
      <title>Basic Model Requirements</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_6yccz">
        <title>Representation of Catchment Routing Elements</title>
        <para>Significant variation of routing characteristics over the catchment, particularly in
          larger catchments, will require at least a semi-distributed representation of routing
          elements in the catchment (refer to <xref linkend="book5"/>). The model should have the
          ability to reflect changes in the routing response of specific elements resulting from
          modification of catchment, channel, or storage components.</para>
        <para>While there is evidence of non-linear routing response over the range of observed
          floods in most natural catchments, it is unclear to what extent this effect persists to
          the range of Very Rare to Extreme floods. In this range of flood magnitudes the routing
          response depends on how the efficiency of flow and the available flood storage change with
          increasing flood magnitude (or reducing flood frequency). The recommended procedures in
            <xref linkend="b8_s_wh2h5"/> are based on this assumption. The degree of non-linearity
          of catchment behaviour and its effects are discussed by <citation>b8_c_r59+1</citation>,
          together with the background to the recommended procedures.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_icpld">
        <title>Spatial Variation of Rainfall Excess</title>
        <para>Where it is necessary to apply design rainfalls non-uniformly across the catchment
          (refer to <xref linkend="b8_s_sborg"/>) the model should be able to represent spatial
          variations in rainfall inputs. A semi-distributed rather than a lumped model is thus
          required in most cases.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_46y27">
        <title>Distributed Output</title>
        <para>Flood estimates are often required at different points of interest within a catchment.
          The model should thus adequately represent the progressive routing effects through the
          catchment, i.e. it should be internally consistent to allow matching of observed
          hydrographs at the catchment outlet and at required internal points. It should be noted
          that some of the simple hydrograph models in current use only provide an adequate
          representation of internal flows for locations near the catchment outlet. For other
          internal locations it may be necessary to increase the degree of catchment sub-division
          (and re-calibrate the model) to conform with the recommendations for the minimum number of
          upstream sub-areas (<xref linkend="book5"/>).</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_f8tz9">
      <title>Enhanced Model Capabilities</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_g65o9">
        <title>Separation of Routing Elements with Different Non-Linearities</title>
        <para>Different catchment elements (e.g. overland flow, well-defined stream/channel flow,
          floodplain and concentrated storage elements) may be characterised by different
          non-linearities in their routing response. A model structure that allows the separate
          representation of routing elements with different non-linearity characteristics (e.g.
            <citation>b8_c_r27</citation>) offers distinct advantages, as extrapolation of the
          routing characteristics for individual elements to model more extreme events can be
          achieved in a more controlled fashion than for the lumped response of a combination of
          different elements.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_pbf43">
        <title>Distributed Modelling of Baseflow</title>
        <para>Baseflow would generally only make a minor contribution to Very Rare to Extreme floods
          (refer to <xref linkend="b8_s_fzd4a"/>); nevertheless the capability to define baseflow
          contributions at subcatchment level, for subsequent combined routing with surface runoff
          to the point(s) of interest, is desirable. Further comments regarding this issue can be
          found in <citation>b8_c_r12+1</citation>.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_cd813">
    <title>Model Configuration</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_tethf">
      <title>General Considerations</title>
      <para>Most hydrograph models are highly conceptual in nature; in setting up a model
        representation of the catchment, the modeller should therefore try to define conceptual
        model elements that match the routing response of the main components of the real catchment,
        without necessarily attempting to exactly match all physical catchment features (e.g.
        individual drainage lines, drainage divides) in detail. How this can best be achieved will
        depend on the specific features of the selected model. However, the most important factor
        determining the quality of the modelling results is the modeller’s understanding of the
        routing functions incorporated in the modelling package and the practitioner's appreciation
        of the catchment response under major to extreme flood conditions. More specific guidance on
        selected model configuration issues is provided in <xref
          xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" linkend="b8_s_e7p2b"/></para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_e7p2b">
      <title>Specific Issues</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_3oz4x">
        <title>Degree of Catchment Homogeneity</title>
        <para>The model should be subdivided into as many separate subcatchments as required to
          represent the broad variation in flood response resulting from differences in topographic,
          drainage system, land cover and land-use attributes (refer to recommendations on the
          minimum number of subcatchments provided in <xref linkend="book7"/>). For the estimation
          of Very Rare to Extreme floods, the variation in parameter sets for the different
          subcatchments should, as far as possible, be directly related to differences in measurable
          catchment characteristics.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_ktt36">
        <title>Representation of Significant Catchment Features</title>
        <para>Major catchment features may have a significant influence on catchment flood response,
          and may exhibit significantly different routing characteristics compared to the rest of
          the catchment, particularly when extrapolated to extreme events. All the significant
          natural storage areas (e.g. swamps, extensive flood plains, off-channel storage areas) and
          distributary or effluent channel systems should be identified and adequately represented.
          Consideration should also be given to the modelling of anthropogenic features, such as the
          specification of diversion channel capacities, or road/rail crossings that may act as
          retarding basins during extreme events.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_egfsi">
        <title>Representation of Catchment Areas Close to a Reservoir</title>
        <para>In the vicinity of a reservoir, the routing response varies from near zero delay for
          rainfall on the inundated areas, to significant delays for rainfall excess from the less
          directly connected areas draining to the storage. The modelled hydrographs and the
          calibrated model parameters can be quite sensitive to the representation of these areas,
          particularly when the inundated area constitutes a large part of the total catchment.
          Considerable care should be exercised in ensuring that the routing characteristics of the
          inundated parts of the catchment and the areas close to it have been realistically
          represented.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_tj73m">
        <title>Modelling of Changed Catchment Conditions</title>
        <para>The effects of likely changes to the catchment during the design life of the structure
          need to be considered. Urbanisation and removal of vegetation by clearing or fire may
          reduce the response time of the catchment and increase the peak flow, while soil
          conservation measures over a large portion of a catchment may have the opposite effect.
          The impacts of these changed catchment conditions on the formation and propagation of
          extreme floods is currently not well researched. Generally, a rather arbitrary allowance
          must be made for these effects. Construction of a reservoir may inundate appreciable
          lengths of streams in the catchment and can lead to large decreases in travel time and
          increases in flood peaks, despite the attenuation resulting from the routing effect of the
          reservoir. This effect is discussed and examples are given by
            <citation>b8_c_r78+1</citation>, <citation>b8_c_r6+1</citation> and
            <citation>b8_c_r77+1</citation>. The last two references give examples where the inflow
          flood peak is increased by 85% by the construction of a dam. It is therefore important to
          consider this effect when using a model to derive design floods for a dam if it has been
          calibrated to pre-dam conditions.</para>
        <para>In general, allowance for different catchment conditions can be made more easily by
          runoff--routing than by unit hydrograph models. In runoff-routing models the different
          routing characteristics of existing or future catchment conditions can be incorporated by
          the judicious selection of parameters and the types of routing elements.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_tbwiz">
    <title>Determination of Model Parameter Values for Rural Catchments</title>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_v4rha">
      <title>General</title>
      <para>The provisions of the 1987 edition of ARR addressed the question of hydrograph model
        parameter selection for Large to Extreme events, based on the research results and
        experience available at that time <citation>b8_c_r59</citation>. There has been limited
        research since then to resolve the issue of the appropriate degree of model non-linearity
        for the estimation of Extreme flood events. Given the lack of strong research evidence,
        specific design recommendations for this range of events must be based on a consensus
        approach. The following considerations and recommendations are based on the broad range of
        views expressed by different groups of practitioners and current practice in
        Australia.</para>
      <para>The key factor to be considered when selecting parameters for modelling Very Rare to
        Extreme events is that the parameters found from calibration to a relatively narrow range of
        observed flood events cannot be assumed to apply to the range of more extreme events. As the
        magnitude of the event to be modelled increases significantly beyond the range of the
        largest observed events, the parameter selection process has to be guided more strongly by
        physical/hydraulic consideration of how the response of the catchment is expected to change
        when exposed to more extreme rainfall events. This will depend on the physical
        characteristics of hillslopes and on-stream and floodplain characteristics such as breakout
        points, threshold levels and the availability of significant off-stream storage areas in the
        lower part of the catchment.</para>
      <para>It is necessary to provide recommendations for design situations in which suitable
        streamflow information may or may not be available. Accordingly, guidance on both these
        situations is provided in the following two sections. Subsequent sections provide specific
        guidance on other aspects of parameter determination, and are aimed at minimising the
        uncertainties in the selection of design parameter values. Guidance on the selection of
        parameter values for estimation of Very Rare to Extreme design floods in ungauged catchments
        is provided in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_20a81">
      <title>Parameter Determination for Gauged Catchments</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_14l19">
        <title>Calibration to the Largest Observed Flood Events</title>
        <para>The simplified conceptual representation of catchment response in the commonly used
          flood hydrograph models means that these models rely heavily on appropriately calibrated
          parameter values. While calibration of a model provides valuable information on the flood
          response of a catchment within the range of observations, caution is needed when applying
          the model to estimate design floods of much larger magnitude. Extrapolation of model
          parameter values beyond the range of calibration events will introduce considerable
          uncertainty into flood estimates.</para>
        <para>The model should thus be calibrated to events over a range of flood magnitudes up to
          the largest observed event, and the results analysed for the presence of any trends. If
          appropriate data are not available at the site of interest, consideration should be given
          to transferring parameters from a calibrated model of a nearby catchment with similar
          characteristics, with appropriate adjustments for differences in catchment size and
          characteristics.</para>
        <para>The examination of log-log plots of storage versus discharge for particular routing
          elements may be helpful in the assessment of calibration results and in identifying
          parameter variation with flood magnitude. In assessing the calibration results, it should
          be borne in mind that the calibrated parameter values for individual events reflect not
          only the catchment response to actual rainfall, but also any errors in the estimated
          catchment rainfall, in the rating curve used to establish the observed flood hydrograph,
          and in the adopted baseflow separation procedure. The first two types of errors tend to
          increase with event magnitude.</para>
        <para>Before applying any calibrated parameter values to modelling of more extreme events,
          they should be checked for consistency with the recommendations as discussed <xref
            linkend="b8_s_8e47f"/>.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_8e47f">
        <title>Adjusted Parameter Values from Reconciliation with Flood Frequency Estimates</title>
        <para>In catchments where a long series of at-site or regional flood data is available, the
          comparison of rainfall-based estimates with flood frequency based estimates can provide
          important information on the variation of flood response characteristics with flood
          magnitude. With this approach, in accordance with the general guidance provided in <xref
            linkend="book7"/>, the initial model parameter values found from calibration are
          adjusted to achieve reasonable agreement between the rainfall based estimate for a
          selected AEP and the flood frequency analysis based estimate of corresponding AEP.
          Adjustment of hydrograph model parameters is only necessary if satisfactory agreement of
          flood estimates from the two methods cannot be achieved by varying loss parameters within
          reasonable limits. It may also be required, if the comparison indicates that the rainfall
          based method cannot satisfactorily reproduce the slope of the flood frequency curve. In
          that case, adjustment of the non-linearity parameter of the selected model would be
          appropriate.</para>
        <para>The approach is particularly suited to catchments with a good flood peaks record but
          only limited hydrograph information. It can also be applied to reconcile rainfall based
          flood estimates with flood estimates obtained from paleohydrological procedures (<xref
            linkend="b8_s_aaq3x"/>). Before applying any adjusted parameter values to modelling of
          more extreme events, they should be checked for consistency with the recommendations in
            <xref linkend="b8_s_3iboy"/>.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_nzl1i">
        <title>Evidence From Very Rare Floods in Similar Catchments</title>
        <para>The lack of data on very large floods in the catchment of interest could be partly
          compensated by analysis of flood observations for very large events in catchments with
          similar characteristics. The interpretation of calibration results from such catchments
          should be guided by the considerations in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/>.</para>
        <para>There are relatively few published hydrograph modelling studies of very large
          Australian flood events <citation>b8_c_r82,b8_c_r59,b8_c_r68</citation>. The available
          evidence points towards reducing non-linearity of catchment response for very large events
            <citation>b8_c_r59,b8_c_r85</citation>, indicating relatively more catchment storage for
          increasing discharge and thus greater attenuation of flood peaks. However, this tendency
          may not continue to the range of Extreme events, if flow efficiency also increases
          substantially for these events. The conclusion from these studies might also be affected
          by the high degree of uncertainty in estimated flow rates for Very Rare to Extreme events:
          the apparent tendency towards linearity could alternatively be explained by
          underestimation of the true peak flow rate.</para>
        <para>The available studies cover only a limited range of catchment conditions, and care
          should thus be taken in applying the study results to other catchments. Detailed analysis
          of other large flood events and publication of results is highly desirable.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_pb3t4">
      <title>Design Parameter Values for Ungauged Catchments</title>
      <para>General guidance on the selection of parameter values for the estimation of design
        floods in ungauged catchments may be found in <xref linkend="book7"/>. In transferring
        parameter values from gauged to ungauged catchments for modelling of Very Rare to Extreme
        events, particular emphasis should be placed on assessing the similarity of catchment
        characteristics relevant to this flood range.</para>
      <para>Before applying any regional parameter values to modelling of more extreme events, they
        should be checked for consistency with the recommendations provided in the following
        section.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_wh2h5">
      <title>Physically-based Extrapolation of Model Parameter Values for Extreme Events</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_3m6si">
        <title>Background</title>
        <para>The most commonly applied runoff-routing models in Australia use conceptual storage
          elements to represent the hydrograph formation process in response to distributed inputs
          of rainfall excess. These conceptual storages represent the routing response of all
          catchment components, from hillslopes to river channels and floodplains. Each storage
          element is represented by a power-function relationship between Storage <emphasis
            role="italic">S</emphasis> and flow rate Q, with coefficient k and exponent m (<xref
            linkend="book5"/>). The exponent m expresses the degree of non-linearity in the
          catchment response; it typically varies between 0.6 and 1.0, where a value of 1.0
          corresponds to a linear response. Within a limited range of S and Q, different
          combinations of k and m can produce similar S-Q relationships, and the modelled flood
          outputs are not overly sensitive to the selection of a particular combination.</para>
        <para>While this simplified representation of the relationship between storage and discharge
          has been shown to produce satisfactory results over a limited range of flood magnitudes,
          it is well known that it fails to adequately represent the variations of flow conditions
          over a much wider range of flood magnitudes. As an example, it has been shown that the S-Q
          relationship for the transitional stages between in-bank and fully developed floodplain
          flow is much more complex <citation>b8_c_r82,b8_c_r4,b8_c_r59</citation>. The failure of
          the power-function relationship between S and Q to account for these complexities
          expresses itself in different calibrated pairs of k and m values for different flow
          ranges.</para>
        <para>The available flood data provide good evidence for the nature of non-linearity in
          stream-channel and floodplain flow for Rare floods and possibly even Very Rare events.
          However, relatively little evidence is available to assess the nature of the S-Q
          relationship for flows on hillslopes beyond the range of relatively frequent events, or
          for Extreme floods in stream-channel and floodplain systems.</para>
        <para>In this situation of limited reliable evidence from very large flood events, the
          extrapolation of model parameter values for application to extreme events must be guided
          by the consideration of specific catchment topography and hydraulic factors. These factors
          are further discussed in <xref linkend="b8_s_jzxuf"/>.</para>
        <para>Hydraulic models may be used to better define the representation of flow behaviour in
          complex environments, and their use for this purposes is discussed in <xref
            linkend="b8_s_fxgci"/> .</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_jzxuf">
        <title>Consideration of Catchment Topography and Hydraulic Factors</title>
        <para>It is evident that the relationship between catchment storage and flood flow rate for
          Extreme events is determined by catchment topographic and hydraulic factors. An analysis
          of these factors for the different parts of the catchment may thus provide valuable
          information on the general form of the S-Q relationship. As an example, the hydraulic
          analysis of channel and floodplain flow characteristics may shed some light on the nature
          of non-linearity in the streamflow routing elements in the extreme flood range. Similar
          analyses may be undertaken for hillslope segments but the results will necessarily be
          associated with a greater degree of uncertainty.</para>
        <para>The interpretation of calibration results can be guided by consideration of special
          cases of the relationships between storage and discharge. For the case of steady, uniform
          flow in a prismatic channel, the analysis using Manning’s equation produces a power law
          relationship between S and Q with m-values ranging from 0.6, for a wide rectangular
          channel, to 0.75 for a triangular channel <citation>b8_c_r40</citation>. This assumes that
          the cross-sectional areas contributing to flow and to storage are identical, and that a
            <emphasis role="italic">constant Manning’s n</emphasis> applies to all magnitudes of
          flow. It implies that the average flow velocity is increasing with increasing event
          magnitude. Another special case applies when a <emphasis role="italic">constant average
            flow velocity</emphasis> can be assumed over the range of flood magnitudes, and flow and
          storage areas are again identical. This case corresponds to a power law relationship
          between S and Q with an m-value of 1.0, i.e. a linear relationship.</para>
        <para>The following factors are considered to be responsible for variations of actual S-Q
          relationships between the above special cases:<orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis role="italic">Factors increasing the relative efficiency of flow with
                  increasing event magnitude (and thus decreasing the effective value of m):
                </emphasis>With increasing event magnitude, there is a tendency in hill-flow
                segments for concentration of flow in relatively efficient flow paths. The
                increasing depth of flow may reduce the effective roughness of vegetation and other
                flow resistance elements. Similarly, the removal and stripping of vegetation during
                rare flood flows will tend to decrease the effective value of m. Some
                short-circuiting of the more sinuous flow path taken during more frequent flood
                events is also likely to occur. When compared to transitional stream channel and
                floodplain flow in Very Rare to Extreme flood events, fully developed floodplain
                flow during Very Rare to Extreme events can be expected to be more efficient.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis role="italic">Factors reducing the relative efficiency of flow with
                  increasing event magnitude (and thus increasing the effective value of
                  m):</emphasis> Extreme flood events can be expected to produce significant changes
                to the catchment, stream and floodplain morphology. The erosive surface changes and
                sediment transport processes require significant inputs of flow energy, resulting in
                an increase of effective flow resistance. In stream/floodplain systems, an increase
                in flood magnitude is generally associated with more complex flow patterns and
                increased turbulence, also resulting in an increase of effective flow resistance.
                The question to be resolved for extrapolation to Extreme events is to what extent
                the increasing resistance will be offset by more efficient flow paths.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis role="italic">Factors increasing or reducing the effects of catchment
                  storage (and thus increasing or reducing, respectively, the value of m compared to
                  calibration events): </emphasis>In catchments with extensive floodplains,
                increasingly larger flood events will mobilise additional storage areas that may not
                contribute significantly to flood flow conveyance. The question to be addressed in
                extrapolation of calibration results to Extreme events is, to what extent these
                areas will still contribute mainly to storage, and to what extent they will become
                effective conveyance areas. In heavily vegetated catchments, flood debris may create
                temporary pondage areas and thus additional catchment storage.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist></para>
        <para>In extrapolating model parameter calibration results to Very Rare and Extreme events,
          the above factors should be carefully balanced.</para>
        <para>It is recognised that in many cases the constraints on the study budget will limit the
          extent to which the above factors can be evaluated. It will thus be necessary to place a
          greater reliance on experience gained from earlier studies and to introduce a margin of
          conservatism into the selection of parameter values. <xref linkend="b8_s_3iboy"/> gives
          recommendations for parameter selection based on these considerations.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_3iboy">
      <title>Specific Recommendations for Modelling Extreme Events</title>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_nqnbr">
        <title>General</title>
        <para>The model parameter values for design flood estimates in the range of Extreme events
          should be selected on the basis of the available evidence for the catchment of interest,
          as described in <xref linkend="b8_s_20a81"/>. Where the available information for the
          catchment is limited essentially to the range of Rare events, it should be supplemented by
          information from other catchments, and/or by consideration of catchment topography and
          hydraulic factors (<xref linkend="b8_s_wh2h5"/>).</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_0hh8x">
        <title>Gauged Catchments</title>
        <para>As discussed by <citation>b8_c_r59+1</citation>, and on the balance of the factors in
            <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/>, a value of the exponent m in the power law
          storage-discharge relation (S = k Q<superscript>m</superscript>) of less than 0.8 is
          generally conservative, in that Extreme floods tend to be overestimated. The recommended
          procedure described below for parameters associated with Extreme events and the PMP Flood
          applies directly to this form of the storage-routing relation as most published
          information relates to this form of model.</para>
        <para><orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
            <listitem>
              <para>Where most of the valleys in the catchment are V-shaped with only small
                floodplains:</para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if the available model calibration results for the catchment of interest
                    include Very Rare events and the calibrated m is in the range from 0.8 to 0.9
                    inclusive, adopt the calibrated value;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if the available model calibration results for the catchment of interest
                    include Very Rare events and the calibrated m is outside the range from 0.8 to
                    0.9, select an appropriate value, guided by the additional information and
                    considerations in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/>;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if the range of available model calibration results for the catchment of
                    interest is limited to Rare events, select an appropriate value of m in the
                    range from 0.8 to 0.85, guided by the additional information and considerations
                    in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/>;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if neither Very Rare event calibration data nor the appropriate expertise
                    for the considerations in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/> are available, adopt a
                    conservatively low value of m = 0.8.</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Where many of the valleys in the catchment have appreciable floodplains:</para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if the available model calibration results for the catchment of interest
                    include Rare events and the calibrated m is in the range from 0.85 to 0.9
                    inclusive, adopt the calibrated value;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if the available model calibration results for the catchment of interest
                    include Very Rare events and the calibrated m is outside the range from 0.85 to
                    0.9, select an appropriate value, guided by the additional information and
                    considerations in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/>;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if the range of available model calibration results for the catchment of
                    interest is limited to Rare events, select an appropriate value of m in the
                    range from 0.85 to 0.9, guided by the additional information and considerations
                    in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/>;</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>if neither Very Rare event calibration data nor the appropriate expertise
                    for the considerations in <xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/> are available, adopt a
                    conservatively low value of m = 0.85.</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>It should be noted that in the context of the above recommendations the term
          “Very Rare event” should be interpreted as floods that are <emphasis role="italic">clearly
            beyond the transition between within-bank and floodplain flow</emphasis>, i.e. fully
          developed floodplain flows of appreciable depth.</para>
        <para>The recommendations for m relate to all floods beyond the credible limit of
          extrapolation. If the value of m selected for extreme floods differs from the value of m
          for floods of lesser magnitude, then the coefficient k in the power law storage-discharge
          relation
            <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>(<?oxy_custom_end?><xref
            linkend="book5"/>) should be adjusted to ensure that the magnitude of flow at the
          credible limit of extrapolation is unchanged when used with the new value of m. An initial
          estimate of the required value of k can be obtained by means of Equation (<xref
            linkend="book5"/>).</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b8_s_y3k4g">
        <title>Ungauged Catchments</title>
        <para>For ungauged catchments, the model parameter values must be estimated from calibration
          on nearby catchments or from regional relationships (refer to <xref linkend="book7"/>).
          The regional relationships for the catchment routing parameters (k) are generally given
          for an m of 0.8, and they will thus be directly applicable to catchments with small flood
          plains. For catchments with appreciable flood plains, it may be possible to increase m and
          adjust the value of k from a regional relationship by means of
          <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160606T072244+1000" comment="is this supposed to be pilgrim 1998? reference to a chapter of ARR 1987???"?>equation
          3.19, <?oxy_comment_end?><citation>b8_c_r60</citation>. An estimate would be necessary of
          the magnitude of the floods used in deriving the data on which the regional relationship
          was based (this estimate represents the credible limit of extrapolation associated with
          the derived regional relationship). If possible, the designer should check the magnitudes
          of the floods from which the regional relationship is derived as a guide to the likely
          conservatism of the estimate.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_fxgci">
    <title>Model Parameterisation for Urban Catchments</title>
    <para>Floods in urban catchments are the product of more complex interactions of
      hydrometeorological, hydrologic and hydraulic factors than in rural catchments. Severe floods
      can result from short duration intense rainfall over relatively small areas. The hydrologic
      response to heavy rainfalls is affected by changes to the natural runoff characteristics by
      reducing infiltration and increasing impervious surface areas. The drainage characteristics
      are changed by provision of more efficient flow paths in storm drain systems and channelised
      sections of streams. The hydraulic characteristics of drainage systems are also made more
      complex by the presence of bridges, culverts, floodways and detention basins.</para>
    <para>The degree of complexity required when modelling an urban system is largely dictated by
      the design context. If the main focus is on sizing trunk drainage capacities then it may be
      sufficient to use non-linear storage routing models, where appropriate attention is given to
      characterising the shorter relative delay times associated with urbanisation of the natural
      drainage paths. Many hydraulic controls that influence flood response in urban catchments
      become drowned out under extreme conditions, and the complexities required to model the
      performance of these systems under Very Frequent to Rare conditions may not be required for
      more extreme events.</para>
    <para>In complex systems it may not be possible to predict the changing nature of flow paths
      with event magnitude, or adequately characterise the influence of major floodplain features.
      In such cases it would be expected that flood behaviour is best assessed using hydraulic
      models, as described in <xref linkend="book6"/> and <xref linkend="book7"/>. However, while
      the use of such models better resolves the influence of hydraulic controls, they introduce
      additional complexity associated with the need to interface with the hydrologic models used to
      derive input hydrographs. The need for such an interface might be avoided by inputting
      rainfall directly onto the hydraulic model grid, but this is only possible for catchments
      where the model covers the whole contributing area. While this potentially provides a more
      realistic representation of catchment controls, the approach is not well validated at this
      point in time and is subject to additional uncertainties, as discussed in <xref
        linkend="book7"/>.</para>
    <para>The joint use of hydrologic and hydraulic routing models involves some explicit trade-offs
      in modelling complexity. On one hand hydrologic models are easily run within a joint
      probability framework and are thus able to explicitly solve the joint probabilities involved
      in the production of flood runoff to yield unbiased estimates of flood risk. On the other,
      they are ill-suited to representing the influence of complex hydraulic controls that might
      arise in an urban environment under Extreme conditions.</para>
    <para>One means of balancing this trade-off is to use a hydraulic model to define the
      characteristics of a storage-discharge relationship. With this approach, a selection of flood
      hydrographs spanning the range of conditions of interest are input into the hydraulic model,
      and the outputs are then used to derive a relationship between storage, discharge and/or
      level, as relevant to the design problem of interest. This relationship can then be
      incorporated into a joint probability framework and then used to derive the flood
      characteristics without further need for hydraulic modelling. The advantage of the approach is
      that it combines the benefits of hydraulic modelling with stochastic simulation of flood
      processes but without impractical computational burden. The limitations of the approach is
      that it assumes that the derived storage-discharge relationship is adequate for all
      combinations of inputs, a situation that is only likely to be valid when considering one or
      two dominant mechanisms of flood loading. An example of this approach is provided by
        <citation>b8_c_r66+1</citation>, who used the hydrologic model to resolve the joint
      probabilities involved in reservoir drawdown and the concurrence of flood inflows from two
      major tributaries, and a hydraulic model to relate tributary inflows and tide levels to peak
      water levels at locations within a complex urbanised floodplain.</para>
    <para>For more complex environments it will be necessary to rely directly on a hydraulic model
      to provide a realistic representation of flow behaviour. At present it is usually impractical
      to consider running complex hydraulic models in a stochastic simulation scheme, though it is
      expected that this approach will become increasingly feasible as parallel and distributed
      computing capabilities improve and become more easily implemented. The simplest way of trading
      off the potential for bias associated with rainfall-runoff modelling and the need for accurate
      representation of hydraulic behaviour is by careful selection of deterministic hydrologic
      inputs. For example, estimates of the concurrent peak design floods may be obtained through
      ensemble or Monte Carlo approaches, and these may be used to scale representative hydrographs
      for input to deterministic simulation in a hydraulic model. At its simplest, single runs of
      hydraulic models may be undertaken for each combination of storm duration and event severity,
      but this can be extended to ensemble hydraulic runs for a more representative range of flood
      inputs. The success of either approach rests on the selection of inputs that minimise bias in
      the transformation between rainfall exceedance probability and the flood level (or outflow) of
      interest, and sensitivity analyses will assist the identification of dominant influences and
      the selection of representative scenarios to be modelled.</para>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
  
</chapter>
