<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" version="5.0" xml:id="b5_ch1"
  xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
  xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
  xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
      <title>Introduction</title>
          <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>

  </info>
  <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20160704T103109+1000" content="ErwinWeinmann, JamesBall"?></para>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Advanced draft</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section>
    <title>Flood Hydrograph Modelling </title>
    <para>From the alternative flood estimation approaches introduced in <xref linkend="b1_ch3"/>,
      the methods and models covered in this book of Australian Rainfall and Runoff focus on the
      event-based simulation approach. This approach simulates only the time period covering a
      single storm event, given the initial conditions for the event, but the storm may consist of
      several separate rainfall bursts, resulting in a multi-peaked flood hydrograph. </para>
    <para>The more general aspects of catchment simulation for design flood estimation are covered
      in <xref linkend="book4"/>, and the chapters in this book deal specifically with the models
      and design inputs required to transform the event-based design rainfall inputs from <xref
        linkend="book2"/> into design flood hydrographs at catchment locations of interest.</para>
    <para>This book is an extension of the material covered in <xref linkend="book3"/>, which deals
      with the calculation of design flood peak discharges. While peak discharges (without flood
      hydrographs) are adequate for many applications, such as calculating bridge or culvert
      capacity, flood hydrographs are essential for many other applications. These applications
      include those where floodplain storage or artificial storage is an important issue or where
      the movement and modification of flood events through a catchment is of interest. With the
      increasing implementation of more advanced hydrological modelling systems and more complex
      analysis requirements, guidance on flood hydrograph modelling is becoming increasingly
      important.</para>
    <para>The flood hydrograph methods described here provide an alternative method to the flood
      peak discharge methods covered in <xref linkend="book3"/> and allow cross checking between the
      two methods. There is a place therefore for both peak flow and flood hydrograph estimation for
      different applications.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Overall Flood Hydrograph Estimation Process</title>
      <para><?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160702T230307+1000" comment="check consistency with book 7"?>The
        process of developing and applying an event-based flood hydrograph estimation model involves
        the following steps:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Definition of the flood estimation problem and the model requirements;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Assessment of data requirements and data availability, data collation and checking;
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Study of catchment data and flood information to develop an understanding of the
            catchment behaviour during floods and to identify important features that need to be
            represented in the model - <xref linkend="b5_ch2"/>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Conceptualised representation of the runoff generation phase of flood formation
            (loss model and baseflow model) - <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch4"
            />;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Conceptualised representation of the flood hydrograph formation phase (the routing
            elements of the catchment) - <xref linkend="b5_ch2"/>, <xref linkend="b5_ch3"/> and
              <xref linkend="b5_ch6"/>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Determination of model parameters by calibration to observed events, from experience
            values in regions with similar flood producing characteristics or from links with
            measured catchment characteristics - <xref linkend="b7_ch5"/>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Validation of the calibrated model to ensure that it is fit for the intended purpose
            – <xref linkend="b7_ch6"/>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Application of the model with design rainfalls (<xref linkend="book2"/>), design
            losses (<xref linkend="b5_ch5"/>) and design baseflows (<xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>) to
            estimate design flood hydrographs - <xref linkend="b7_ch7"/>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Interpretation and presentation of model results, including determination of
            uncertainty – <xref linkend="b7_ch8"/> and <xref linkend="b7_ch9"/>; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The modelled design flood hydrographs will generally form the inputs to a hydraulic
            model of the study area.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>The following chapters of <xref linkend="book5"/> introduce the important hydrologic
        modelling principles that are applied in Steps 3 to 5 of the overall process. <xref
          linkend="b5_ch5"/> (Losses) and <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/> (Baseflow Models) also provide
        guidance on the design values required in Step 7. Detailed application guidance
        relating<?oxy_comment_end?> to the other steps is provided in <xref linkend="book7"
        />.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Conceptual Representation of Flood Formation</title>
      <para>The complex hydrologic processes involved in the formation and modification of flood
        hydrographs are represented in flood
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142509+1000" content="hydrograph"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142513+1000"?>hydrograph<?oxy_insert_end?>
        estimation models in a highly conceptualised form. The processes involved in the <emphasis
          role="italic">runoff generation phase</emphasis>, described in more detail in <xref
          linkend="b4_ch2"/>, are represented in <emphasis role="italic"
          >conceptual</emphasis><emphasis role="italic">loss models</emphasis> (<xref
          linkend="b5_ch5_s_ncyi2"/>) in a simplified fashion. These conceptual loss models divide
        the rainfall inputs into rainfall excess and loss (without modelling what happens with the
        loss component). As the name implies, the rainfall excess reflects only the surface runoff
        component that is directly attributable to the event rainfall. The additional component of
        streamflow originating from recession flows from previous rainfall events or groundwater
        inflows is referred to as baseflow. This baseflow component is represented in <emphasis
          role="italic">conceptual</emphasis><emphasis role="italic">baseflow models</emphasis>
          (<xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>). Baseflow contributions to runoff are added to the rainfall
        excess component either at the sub-catchment scale or, more commonly, as a total baseflow
        hydrograph at the catchment outlet.</para>
      <para>In the <emphasis role="italic">hydrograph formation phase</emphasis>, the routing of
        flood contributions from subareas through the various stream reaches, floodplains and
        natural or artificial storages is modelled by hydrologic or hydraulic routing models of
        different complexity (<xref linkend="b5_ch3"/>).</para>
      <para>Some flood hydrograph modelling approaches represent the catchment only as a single unit
        (lumped models). However, the models now typically applied in the event-based simulation
        approach are semi-distributed in nature; they represent the catchment being modelled by a
        number of sub-catchments or subareas, where the degree of spatial resolution used typically
        varies between around 10 to 100 subareas. The processes involved in the <emphasis
          role="italic">runoff generation phase</emphasis> are modelled at the sub-catchment or
        subarea scale, and the resulting runoff hydrographs are then routed along the different
        stream reaches and storages in the catchment to the point of interest. Node-link type
        runoff-routing models are the most common form of these models, where the nodes represent
        the subareas and stream junctions, and the links the routing reaches (<xref linkend="b5_ch6"
        />). In addition to providing a more detailed and physically based approach to hydrological
        modelling, distributed models allow the assessment of flood hydrographs for points within
        the main catchment as well as at the outlet, whereas lumped models allow calculation of
        hydrographs only at the catchment outlet.</para>
      <para><xref linkend="b5_ch1_fhdrks"
        /><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142555+1000" content=" shows"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142555+1000"?>
        depicts<?oxy_insert_end?> a schematic representation of how the flood formation processes
        are conceptualised in event-based flood hydrograph estimation models.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b5_ch1_fhdrks">
        <title>Conceptual
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142612+1000"?>R<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142611+1000" content="r"?>epresentation
          of
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142616+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142615+1000" content="f"?>lood
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142619+1000"?>F<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142618+1000" content="f"?>ormation
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142621+1000"?>P<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142621+1000" content="p"?>rocesses
          in the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142629+1000"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142628+1000" content="m"?>ost
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142633+1000"?>C<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142632+1000" content="c"?>ommonly
          used
          <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142636+1000" content="e"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142636+1000"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?>vent-based
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142644+1000"?>Fl<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142642+1000" content="fl"?>ood
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142651+1000"?>H<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142651+1000" content="h"?>ydrograph
          <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142654+1000"?>E<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142653+1000" content="e"?>stimation
          <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142657+1000" content="m"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142657+1000"?>M<?oxy_insert_end?>odels
          (courtesy R<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142701+1000" content="J"?>
          Nathan) </title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/5074.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Scope</title>
    <para>This book of Australian Rainfall and Runoff provides background information on the basic
      elements that make up event-based flood hydrograph estimation models, and an overview of the
      modelling systems most commonly used in Australia. This introductory information is intended
      to equip
      <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142753+1000" content="model users"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142753+1000"?>practitioners<?oxy_insert_end?>
      with a clearer understanding of the simplifications and assumptions involved in different
      model components. <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/> and <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/> also give guidance on
      the design loss and baseflow inputs for use with event-based flood hydrograph
      <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142837+1000"?>estimation
      <?oxy_insert_end?>models. Detailed guidance on other aspects of applying these models to
      practical flood hydrograph estimation problems is provided in <xref linkend="book7"/>.</para>
    <para>As in other books, the guidance provided here should not be interpreted as being
      prescriptive, as unusual catchment conditions may require special considerations. Importantly,
      the application of the models and design data for flood hydrograph estimation should be
      informed by a good understanding of general hydrologic principles and concepts relevant to
      flood estimation as well as specific interpretation of local flood data. </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T173636+1000"?>Book
      Contents<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T173636+1000" content="&lt;emphasis role=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Book Contents&lt;/emphasis&gt;"?></title>
    <para>After this introductory chapter, <xref linkend="b5_ch2"/> introduces the basic concepts
      and approaches used in representing catchments for event-based modelling of floods. <xref
        linkend="b5_ch5"
      /><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142926+1000" content=" then"?> gives
      details of the loss models applied in generating surface runoff, and the models used to
      represent the contribution of baseflow are dealt with in <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>. Both
      chapters are based on research undertaken as part of the ARR Revision Projects funded by the
      <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142953+1000" content="Federal Department of Climate Change and Energy Efficiency"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T142953+1000"?>Commonwealth
      of Australia<?oxy_insert_end?>.
      The<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T143024+1000"?> chapters
      <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T143022+1000" content="y first "?>give
      the background to the selection of the adopted models, then describe the sources of
      information for the derivation of design values of losses and baseflow, and finally provide
      guidance for the practical application of loss models and baseflow models. <xref
        linkend="b5_ch3"/> introduces important flood routing principles applied in modelling the
      movement of flood hydrographs through the stream and floodplain system, linking them with the
      hydraulic principles covered in <xref linkend="book6"/>. Finally, <xref linkend="b5_ch6"/>
      describes the most important conceptualisations and approaches used in
      runoff<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T143047+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160703T143046+1000" content=" "?>routing
      modelling systems to derive complete flood hydrographs at points of interest.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>

