<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" version="5.0" xml:id="b5_ch1"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>
      <td>5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>
      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>In preparation</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>
      <td>In preparation</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>
      <td>In preparation</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Chapters 4 and 5 are included in the book</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch1_s_brgjq">
    <title>Hydrologic Simulation</title>

    <para>There are many alternative definitions of hydrologic simulation that
    have been used in the literature. For the purposes of this chapter of
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff, the definition used will be consistent
    with the conceptual components of a catchment modelling system outlined in
    <xref linkend="b4_ch2"/><emphasis role="bold">;</emphasis> this definition
    is that hydrologic modelling is concerned with prediction of the inflow
    hydrographs entering the catchment drainage system.</para>

    <para>It is not possible to define explicitly the point within a catchment
    where the interface between the hydrologic modelling and the hydraulic
    modelling occurs. This difficulty arises due to the differing problems for
    which a catchment modelling system may be employed. Furthermore, there is
    need for the catchment modelling system to be designed to suit the problem
    rather than the problem be modified to suit the catchment modelling
    system. The result is the hydrologic model component of the system will
    vary with alternative degrees of complexity required for different
    problems.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch1_s_mwjqz">
    <title>Scope</title>

    <para>This book of Australian Rainfall and Runoff has been prepared to
    provide guidance on the background theory and practice associated with the
    hydrologic component of catchment modelling systems. Since catchments and
    the problems involved are diverse, and the related technology is changing,
    the recommendations on appropriate usage presented herein should not be
    taken as binding. They should be considered together with other
    information and local experience when being implemented.</para>

    <para>The contents of this book within Australian Rainfall and Runoff are
    intended for a wide readership including engineers, students, technicians,
    surveyors and planners. Readers should be familiar with the basic concepts
    of catchment hydrology and hence have a basic knowledge of
    hydrology.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch1_s_s22vi">
    <title>Terminology</title>

    <para>Many terms associated with design flow estimation have been used in
    a loose manner, and sometimes quite incorrectly and in a misleading
    fashion. As outlined in Book 1, the National Committee on Water
    Engineering of Engineers Australia had three major concerns:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Clarity of meaning</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Technical correctness</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Practicality and acceptability</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>In view of the loose and frequently incorrect manner in which many
    terms often are used, it was considered that Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff should adopt terminology that is technically correct, as far as
    this is possible and in harmony with other objectives. Even if this
    terminology is not entirely popular with all users, it was considered that
    Engineers Australia has a responsibility to encourage and educate
    engineers regarding correct and consistent terminology. It was recognised
    also by the National Committee on Water Engineering that as well as being
    correct technically, the terms adopted should be relatively simple and
    suitable for use in practical design as this would facilitate acceptance
    by the profession.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch1_s_0wjaz">
    <title>Book Contents</title>

    <para>There are five chapters within this book of Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff with the first chapter being an introduction to hydrologic
    estimation necessary for design flood prediction. Provided in the next
    chapter is a discussion of the alternative types of direct runoff models
    and the need for models enabling prediction of baseflow and losses. Each
    of these topics is then discussed in detail in the following chapters. In
    particular, alternative models for prediction of direct runoff and the
    relevant background to those models is presented in Chapter 3 together
    with recommendations on the usage of these models. In a similar manner,
    models for prediction of the baseflow occurring at the time of the flood
    event are presented in Chapter 4 while models for prediction of catchment
    losses during the flood event for both rural and urban catchments are
    presented in the final chapter.</para>

    <para>Different to previous versions of Australian Rainfall and Runoff, in
    the development of this edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff there
    has been an assumption that users will have computing resources available.
    The techniques presented in the following sections therefore require
    computing resources for their implementation. Therefore, the discussion in
    the following sections focusses on both the theoretical basis of the
    techniques and their implementation.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b5_ch1_s_f7m2s">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>No references included in this section.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
