<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b2_ch3"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Design Rainfall</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/green_janice.xml"/>
  </info>

  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>

      <td>2</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>

      <td>3</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>

      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>General</td>

      <td>IFD subject to change</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s1_0">
    <title>INTRODUCTION</title>

    <para>Obtaining an estimated rainfall depth for a specified probability is
    an essential component of the design of infrastructure including gutters,
    roofs, culverts, storm water drains, flood mitigation levees, retarding
    basins and dams.</para>

    <para>If sufficient rainfall records are available, at-site frequency
    analysis can be undertaken to estimate the rainfall depth corresponding to
    the specified design probability in some cases. However, limitations
    associated with the spatial and temporal distribution of recorded rainfall
    data necessitates the estimation of design rainfalls for most
    projects.</para>

    <para>The purpose of this chapter is to outline the processes used to
    derive temporally and spatially consistent design rainfalls for Australia
    by the Bureau of Meteorology (BoM). The classes of design rainfall values
    for which estimates have been developed are described in <xref
    linkend="b2_ch3_s2_0"/>.</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch3_s3_0"/> summarises the current recommendations
    on how climate change should be incorporated into design rainfalls for
    those situations where the design life of the structure means that it
    could be affected by climate change.</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch3_s4_0"/> summarises the steps involved in
    deriving the frequent and infrequent design rainfalls (also known as the
    Intensity-Frequency-Duration (IFD) design rainfalls) for Australia. <xref
    linkend="b2_ch3_s5_0"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s6_0"/> describe how the
    very frequent and rare design rainfalls were estimated. The methods
    adopted are only briefly outlined in these sections, with additional
    references provided to facilitate access to further technical information
    for interested readers. More detail on each of the methods is provided in
    Bureau of Meteorology (2016).</para>

    <para>In <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s7_0"/> a summary of the methods adopted
    for the estimation of Probable Maximum Precipitation is provided. <xref
    linkend="b2_ch3_s8_0"/> provides information on the uncertainties
    associated with the design rainfalls and <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s9_0"/>
    explains how to access estimates of each of the design rainfall
    classes.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s2_0">
    <title>DESIGN RAINFALL CONCEPTS</title>

    <para>Design rainfalls are a probabilistic or statistically-based estimate
    of the likelihood of a specific rainfall depth being recorded at a
    particular location within a defined duration.This is generally classified
    by an annual exceedance probability (AEP) or Exceedances per Year (EY).
    Design rainfalls are therefore not real (or observed) rainfall events;
    they are values that are probabilistic in nature.</para>

    <para>There are five broad classes of design rainfalls that are currently
    used for design purposes, generally categorised by frequency of
    occurrence. These are summarised below and presented graphically in <xref
    linkend="b2_ch3_f0"/>. However, it should be noted that there is some
    overlap between the classes. Different methods and data sets are required
    to estimate design rainfalls for the different classes and these are
    discussed in the following sections.</para>

    <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t1">
        <caption>Classes of Design Rainfalls</caption>

        <col width="33%"/>

        <col width="33%"/>

        <col width="33%"/>

        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Design Rainfall Class</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Frequency of occurrence</emphasis></th>

            <th><emphasis role="bold">Probability Range</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Very frequent design rainfalls</td>

            <td>Very frequent</td>

            <td>12EY to 1 EY</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Intensity-Frequency-Duration (IFD)</td>

            <td>Frequent</td>

            <td>1 EY to 10% AEP</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Intensity-Frequency-Duration (IFD)</td>

            <td>Infrequent</td>

            <td>10% to 1% AEP</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Rare design rainfalls</td>

            <td>Rare</td>

            <td>1 in 100 AEP to 1 in 2000 AEP</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>Probable Maximum Precipitation (PMP)</td>

            <td>Extreme</td>

            <td>&lt; 1 in 2000 AEP</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table></para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f0">
      <title>Classes of Design Rainfalls</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2031.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s3_0">
    <title>CLIMATE CHANGE IMPACTS</title>

    <para>The new design rainfalls provided are based on observed rainfall
    data that represent, primarily, the climate of the 20th century. As part
    of the overall ARR revision, a climate change research strategy paper was
    prepared to summarise the scientific understanding of how projected
    changes in the climate may alter the behaviour of factors that influence
    the estimation of the design floods that are used in policy decisions
    involving infrastructure, town planning, floodplain management and flood
    warning and emergency management.</para>

    <para>Ongoing climate change research will provide more scientifically
    rigorous advice on the impacts of climate change on design rainfalls.
    However, in the interim practitioners need to assess the possible impacts
    of climate change on design rainfall estimates that are being used
    currently in design flood studies.</para>

    <para>To address this, an Interim Climate Change Guideline for Considering
    Climate Change in Rainfall and Runoff has been provided (Bates et al.,
    2015) to give guidance over coming years. Details of this guideline can be
    found in <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/>.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s4_0">
    <title>FREQUENT AND INFREQUENT DESIGN RAINFALLS (IFDs)</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s4_1">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>This section summarises the steps involved in deriving frequent
      and infrequent designs rainfalls for the probabilities from 1EY to 1%
      AEP. As shown above, these classes of design rainfalls constitute the
      traditional IFD design rainfalls. The main steps involved in the
      derivation of the frequent and infrequent design rainfalls include the
      collation of a quality controlled database, extraction of the extreme
      values series, frequency analysis, regionalisation and gridding
      processes. These steps are discussed in more detail in the following
      sections and summarised in the flow chart provided as <xref
      linkend="b2_ch3_f_1"/> and in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_t2"/>. The Sections
      in which each of the steps is discussed are shown in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch3_f_1"/>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f_1">
        <title>Flow Chart of Frequent and Infrequent (IFD) Design Rainfall
        Method</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2032.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t2">
          <caption>Summary of Frequent and Infrequent (IFD) Design Rainfall
          Method</caption>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th><emphasis role="bold">Step</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Method</emphasis></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Number of rainfall stations</td>

              <td>Daily read - 8074</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td>Continuous – 2280</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Period of record</td>

              <td>All available records up to 2012</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Length of record used in analyses</td>

              <td><para>Daily read &gt;= 30 years</para></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td>Continuous &gt; 8 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Source of data</td>

              <td>Organisations collecting rainfall data across Australia</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Extreme value series</td>

              <td>Annual Maximum Series (AMS)</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Frequency analysis</td>

              <td>Generalised Extreme Value (GEV) distribution fitted using
              L-moments</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Extension of sub-daily rainfall statistics to daily read
              stations</td>

              <td>Bayesian Generalised Least Squares Regression (BGLSR)</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Regionalisation</td>

              <td>Region of influence (ROI)</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Gridding</td>

              <td>Regionalised at-site distribution parameters gridded using
              ANUSPLIN</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s4_2">
      <title>Rainfall Database</title>

      <para>Integral to the estimation of design rainfalls was the creation of
      a database containing data from all available rainfall stations across
      Australia. These rainfall data were collected at rainfall stations
      operated by various organisations using a range of types of collecting
      methods and instrumentation. Further information on the collection and
      archiving of rainfall data can be found in <xref
      linkend="b1_ch4"/>.</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_ht95s">
        <title>Types of rainfall data</title>

        <para>Rainfall data are collected using a number of different types of
        instrumentation. These provide different temporal and spatial
        resolutions of rainfall data, depending on the instrument type and
        reporting method used. A brief summary of each of the main types of
        rainfall data are provided below. <xref linkend="b2_ch3_t3"/>
        summarises the types of rainfall reporting methods used and indicates
        their use in the estimation of the design rainfalls. As can be seen
        from <xref linkend="b2_ch3_t3"/>, most of the rainfall data used to
        derive the design rainfalls were recorded by a daily read, pluviograph
        or tipping bucket rain gauge (TBRG).</para>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_0pj8x">
          <title>Daily read rainfall gauges</title>

          <para>Daily read rainfall gauges are read at 9:00 am each day and a
          total rainfall depth for the previous 24 hours is reported.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_jjawv">
          <title>Continuous rainfall gauges</title>

          <para>Continuous rainfall stations measure rainfall depth at much
          finer time intervals. In Australia there have been two main types of
          continuous rainfall stations as discussed below.<orderedlist
              numeration="lowerroman">
              <listitem>
                <para>DINES</para>

                <para>Dines tilting syphon pluviographs (DINES) recorded
                rainfall on a paper chart which was then digitised manually.
                Because of the limitations in the digitisation process, the
                minimum interval at which rainfall data could be accurately
                provided was 5 or 6 minutes.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Tipping Bucket Raingauges (TBRG)</para>

                <para>Since the 1990s the majority of Dines pluviographs have
                been replaced by Tipping Bucket Raingauges (TBRG) which
                typically have a 0.2mm capacity bucket. Each time the bucket
                is filled the gauge tips creating an electrical impulse which
                is logged. Rainfall data from TBRGs can be accurately provided
                for intervals of less than one minute.</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist></para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_6lbmv">
          <title>Event-reporting Radio Telemetry Systems (ERTS)</title>

          <para>The Event-reporting Radio Telemetry Systems (ERTS) network
          consists of over 1000 stations across Australia, operated by BoM,
          local government and other water agencies. As the purpose of these
          gauges is to provide information for use in flood forecasting and
          warning, the location and calibration of these gauges is not
          necessarily in accordance with the procedures adopted for the main
          rainfall station networks. However, the data from the ERTS stations
          do provide an additional source of information on large rainfall
          events.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_ku7nn">
          <title>Radio Detection and Ranging (RADAR)</title>

          <para>BoM’s network of RAdio Detection and Ranging (RADAR) provides
          near-real time estimates of rainfall accumulations which can be used
          in weather forecasting, flood modelling and flash flood warning. It
          also provides information on the spatial extent of rainfall events
          and can be used in combination with rainfall station measurements to
          improve estimates of rainfall in areas between rainfall
          stations.</para>

          <para>However, because of the relatively sparse spatial distribution
          of the RADAR network across Australia and the short period of
          record, data from RADAR were not able to be used in the estimation
          of the design rainfalls.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_ftceq">
          <title>Metadata</title>

          <para>Metadata provides essential information about the rainfall
          station such as the location of the rainfall station, the type of
          instrumentation and data collection method. It therefore provides
          context for the rainfall data collected at a station and an
          indication of its quality. At a minimum, metadata relating to
          location in terms of latitude and longitude were collated for each
          rainfall station. However, any additional metadata that were
          available including elevation, details on siting and clearance and
          photographs were also collated.</para>

          <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t3">
              <caption>Rainfall reporting methods</caption>

              <col width="16%"/>

              <col width="16%"/>

              <col width="16%"/>

              <col width="16%"/>

              <col width="16%"/>

              <col width="16%"/>

              <thead>
                <tr>
                  <th><emphasis role="bold">Type</emphasis></th>

                  <th><emphasis role="bold">Reporting</emphasis></th>

                  <th><emphasis role="bold">Recording
                  Resolution</emphasis></th>

                  <th><emphasis role="bold">Reporting Interval</emphasis></th>

                  <th><emphasis role="bold">Reporting Method</emphasis></th>

                  <th><emphasis role="bold">Used for design
                  rainfalls</emphasis></th>
                </tr>
              </thead>

              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Daily</td>

                  <td>Daily</td>

                  <td>24 hour totals (9am – 9am)</td>

                  <td>Daily to monthly</td>

                  <td>Paper</td>

                  <td>Yes</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>DINES Pluviograph</td>

                  <td>Continuous</td>

                  <td>5-6 minutes</td>

                  <td>Daily to weekly</td>

                  <td>Digitised</td>

                  <td>Yes</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>TBRG</td>

                  <td>Continuous</td>

                  <td>On occurrence</td>

                  <td>Hourly to six monthly</td>

                  <td>Logger</td>

                  <td>Yes</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>ERTS</td>

                  <td>Event</td>

                  <td>On occurrence</td>

                  <td>On occurrence</td>

                  <td>Electronic</td>

                  <td>Some</td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                  <td>RADAR</td>

                  <td>Spatial</td>

                  <td>10 minutes</td>

                  <td>10 minutes</td>

                  <td>Digital</td>

                  <td>No</td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table></para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_fh8n4">
        <title>Sources of data</title>

        <para>The rainfall database used for the estimation of the design
        rainfalls included rainfall data collected at rainfall stations
        operated by organisations around Australia. There were two main
        sources of data:</para>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_wthy9">
          <title>Australian Data Archive for Meteorology (ADAM)</title>

          <para>Rainfall data collected by BoM are stored in ADAM which
          contains:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>approximately 20 000 daily read rainfall stations (both
              open and closed) starting in 1800</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>nearly 1500 continuous rainfall stations – using both
              DINES and TBRG instrumentation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_jsw2p">
          <title>Australian Water Resources Information System (AWRIS)</title>

          <para>Under the terms of the Water Regulations 2008, water
          information (including rainfall data) collected by organisations
          across Australia are required to be provided to BoM. The rainfall
          data collected by organisations including local and state government
          water agencies, hydropower generators and urban water utilities are
          stored in AWRIS together with other water information. At present,
          AWRIS contains:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>approximately 350 daily read rainfall stations</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>approximately 2500 continuous rainfall stations.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>Of particular importance to design rainfall estimation are the
          dense networks of continuous rainfall stations operated by urban
          water utilities which provide data in areas of steep rainfall
          gradients and urban areas.</para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_3xowd">
        <title>Spatial distribution of rainfall data</title>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_63q37">
          <title>Daily read rainfall stations</title>

          <para>The location and period of record of the daily read rainfall
          stations operated by the BoM are shown in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3_f2"/>.</para>

          <para>As can be seen from <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f2"/> the spatial
          coverage of the daily read rainfall stations across Australia is
          reasonably good, especially over the eastern states and around the
          coast. Gaps in the spatial coverage of the daily read rainfall
          station network occur in the eastern half of Western Australia; the
          western and north eastern parts of South Australia; and the parts of
          the Northern Territory that are removed from the road and rail
          networks.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f2">
            <title>Location of Daily Read Rainfall Stations with their Period
            of Record</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2033.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_3cnyv">
          <title>Continuous rainfall stations</title>

          <para>The location and period of record of the continuous rainfall
          stations operated by the BoM and other organisations are shown in
          <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f3"/>. The sparseness of the network of
          continuous rainfall stations across Australia can be seen from this
          figure, especially when compared to the spatial distribution of the
          daily read rainfall stations. In spite of the significant
          improvement in the spatial coverage of the continuous rainfall
          stations by the inclusion of rainfall stations operated by other
          organsiations, there are still large areas of Australia with either
          no or very few continuous rainfall stations.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f3">
            <title>Location of Continuous Rainfall Stations with their Period
            of Record</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2034.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_o4dbt">
          <title>Increase in spatial coverage</title>

          <para>The increase in the spatial coverage of the daily read and
          continuous rainfall stations used for the design rainfalls compared
          to the spatial coverage available for the IFDs provided in the 1987
          edition of Australian Rainfall and Runoff (ARR 1987) (Pilgrim, D.H.,
          1987) are shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f4"/> and <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3_f5"/>.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f4">
            <title>Daily Read Rainfall Stations Used for ARR 1987 IFDs (blue)
            and Those Used for the Frequent and Infrequent Design Rainfalls
            (red and blue)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2035.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>The increase in daily read rainfall stations is due to the
          increased number of stations that met the minimum period of record
          criterion.</para>

          <para>As can be seen in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f5"/>, the inclusion
          of data from continuous rainfall stations operated by other
          organisations has resulted in a significant increase in the spatial
          coverage of these data. In particular, the spatial coverage along
          the east coast of Australia; the west coast of Tasmania; and large
          areas in Western Australia has been improved.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f5">
            <title>Continuous Rainfall Stations Used for ARR 1987 IFDs (blue)
            and Those Used for the Frequent and Infrequent Design Rainfalls
            (red and blue)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2036.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_r06dg">
        <title>Temporal distribution of rainfall data</title>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_molgz">
          <title>Daily read rainfall stations</title>

          <para>Official daily read rainfall data are available as far back as
          the early 1800s with the longest rainfall records in Australia being
          approximately 170 years. Some of these early rainfall stations are
          still open. the BoM’s ADAM database contains approximately 3000
          daily read rainfall stations with more than 100 years of
          record.</para>

          <para>In <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f6"/> the distribution of record
          lengths for daily read rainfall stations is shown. It can be seen
          that, although there are a reasonable number of long term stations,
          approximately half of the daily read rainfall stations have less
          than 10 years of record.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f6">
            <title>Length of Available Daily Read Rainfall Data</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2037.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_066n5">
          <title>Continuous rainfall stations</title>

          <para>While there are a small number of continuous rainfall stations
          with more than 70 years of record, the majority of stations have
          less than 40 years of record and a high proportion have less than 10
          years of record. <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f7"/> shows the distribution
          of available length of record for the continuous stations.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f7">
            <title>Length of Available Continuous Rainfall Data</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2038.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_tut3a">
          <title>Increase in length of available record compared to ARR
          1987</title>

          <para>The inclusion of nearly 30 years additional daily read
          rainfall data since the estimation of the ARR 1987 IFDs has
          increased both the amount of data available for the frequent and
          infrequent design rainfalls as well as the number of daily read
          rainfall stations which now met the minimum length of record
          criterion as shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f8"/>.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f8">
            <title>Number of Long-term Daily Read Stations Used for ARR 1987
            IFDs (red) and Those Used for the Frequent and Infrequent Design
            Rainfalls (blue)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2039.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>For the continuous rainfall data, the inclusion of stations
          operated by other organisations and the nearly 30 years of
          additional data resulted in a significant increase in both the
          length of record available and the number of rainfall stations that
          met the minimum record length criterion as can be seen in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3_f9"/>.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f9">
            <title>Length of Record of Continuoud Rainfall Stations Used for
            ARR 1987 IFDs (red) and Those Used for the Frequent and Infrequent
            Design Rainfalls (blue and yellow)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2040.gif"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_hzojx">
        <title>Quality controlling data</title>

        <para>In addition to ensuring that as much data as possible was used
        in estimating the design rainfalls, it was also necessary that the
        rainfall data be quality controlled. In light of the volume of data
        that needed to be quality controlled, automated procedures were
        developed for the identification of suspect data and, as far as
        possible, the correction of these data. However, the quality
        controlling of the data could only be automated so far and a
        significant amount of data was required to be manually checked.</para>

        <para>The quality controlling undertaken of both the daily read and
        continuous rainfall data is summarised below; detailed descriptions of
        these procedures can be found in Green <emphasis role="italic">et
        al</emphasis> (2011; 2012a). The quality controlled data base prepared
        for the estimation of the design rainfalls will be archived in AWRIS
        and made available from the BoM’s website via the Water Data Online
        product.</para>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_v8lkf">
          <title>Daily read rainfall stations</title>

          <para>For the daily read rainfall data automated quality controlling
          procedures were developed in order to:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>infill missing data;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>disaggregate flagged accumulated daily rainfall
              totals;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>detect suspect data, identify and correct:</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>unflagged accumulated totals</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>time shifts</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>identify gross errors - data inconsistent with
              neighbouring records but not either of the above two
              categories.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>Manual correction of gross errors identified during the
          automated quality controlling procedures was facilitated through the
          use of the BoM’s Quality Monitoring System (QMS). QMS is a suite of
          programs that has functionalities to map the suspect value in
          relation to nearby stations and to link to Geographic Information
          System (GIS) data from other systems including RADAR, Satellite
          Imagery and Mean Sea Level Pressure Analysis.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_y004i">
          <title>Continuous rainfall stations</title>

          <para>The automated procedures that were developed for the quality
          controlling of the continuous rainfall data used comparisons with
          other data sources including the Australian Water Availability
          Project (AWAP) gridded data, daily read rainfall stations, automatic
          weather stations, and synoptic stations to identify spurious and
          missing data.</para>

          <para>In order to reduce the amount of continuous rainfall data that
          needed to be quality controlled to a manageable volume, only a
          subset of the largest rainfall events was quality controlled. The
          subset was created by extracting the number of highest rainfall
          records equal to three times the number of years of record at each
          site for each duration being considered.</para>

          <para>Each continuous rainfall value in the data subset that was
          flagged as being spurious by the automated quality controlling
          procedures was subjected to manual quality controlling. The manual
          quality controlling of the data was undertaken in order to determine
          whether the flagged value was correct or not. The manual quality
          controlling procedure adopted involved comparing 09:00 am to 09:00
          am continuous rainfalls with daily (also 09:00 am to 09:00 am)
          rainfalls at the co-located daily read rainfall station. For
          continuous rainfall sites with no co-located daily site, the
          continuous rainfall record was compared with the daily rainfall
          record of the nearest site. The continuous rainfall value was not
          modified in any way - the comparison with daily values was made in
          order to assess whether it was valid or not. Where it was assessed
          that the flagged value was definitely incorrect it was excluded from
          the analyses, otherwise values were retained in the continuous
          rainfall database.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_o8csr">
          <title>Metadata</title>

          <para>The metadata associated with each of the rainfall stations
          were also checked. For the BoM operated rainfall stations, the BoM’s
          metadata database, SitesDB, includes details of the station’s
          location in latitude and longitude, and elevation. For rainfall
          stations operated by other organisations, metadata were provided
          with the rainfall data and stored in AWRIS. Gross error checks on
          station locations and elevation were performed by comparing
          elevations derived using a Digital Elevation Model (DEM) to those
          recorded in the station’s metadata. Checks of latitude and location
          were also carried out by plotting the latitudes and longitudes in
          GIS. Revisions to station locations or elevations were carried out
          using Google Earth and information on the station provided in the
          BoM’s station metadata catalogue.</para>

          <para>For the limited number of closed stations for which an
          elevation was not included in the metadata, the station elevation
          was extracted from the Geoscience Australia 9 second DEM<footnote>
              <para><link
              xlink:href="http://www.ga.gov.au/metadata-gateway/metadata/record/gcat_66006">http://www.ga.gov.au/metadata-gateway/metadata/record/gcat_66006</link></para>
            </footnote> based on the latitude and longitude.</para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_72cm2">
        <title>Stationarity assessment</title>

        <para>The quality controlled data base that was established contained
        rainfall data for the period extending from the 1800s to the present.
        However if climate change has caused non-stationarity in the recorded
        rainfalls, then possibly only a portion of the observed record should
        have been used in deriving the design rainfalls. This is because a key
        assumption in the statistical methods adopted for the derivation of
        the design rainfalls is that the data are stationary. In order to
        determine whether the complete period of available rainfall records
        could be adopted in estimating the design rainfalls, it was necessary
        to assess the degree of non-stationarity present in the historic
        record at rainfall stations across Australia (Green and Johnson,
        2011).</para>

        <para>Two methods were used to establish if there are trends in the
        annual maximum series of rainfalls for Australia. The first examined
        the records at individual stations which were tested to assess trends
        in the time series of the annual maximum rainfalls and changes in the
        probability distributions fitted to the annual maxima to estimate
        design rainfall quantiles. The second method used an area averaged
        approach to check for regional trends in the number of exceedances of
        pre-determined thresholds. The approach was based on that carried out
        by Bonnin et al. (2010) to assess trends in large rainfall events in
        the USA as part of the revisions by the National Oceanic and
        Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to design rainfalls.</para>

        <para>It was concluded that although some stations showed strong
        trends in the annual maximum time series, particularly for short
        durations and more frequent events, the magnitude of these changes was
        within the expected accuracy of the fitted design rainfall
        relationships. It was therefore considered appropriate to assume
        stationarity and use the complete period of record at all stations in
        the estimation of the design rainfalls.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s4_3">
      <title>Extraction of extreme value series</title>

      <para>Rainfall frequency analysis was an integral part of the estimation
      of the design rainfalls as it enabled rainfall depths corresponding to a
      probability quantile to be ascertained. In estimating the frequent and
      infrequent design rainfalls it is large rainfalls that were being
      considered and therefore it was the extreme value series that was of
      interest.</para>

      <para>The extreme value series can be defined using the Annual Maximum
      Series (AMS) or the Partial Duraton Series (PDS) (also known as Peak
      over Threshold). Further details on the extreme values series can be
      found in <xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>. For the frequent and infrequent
      design rainfalls, the AMS was used to define the extreme value series
      because of its lack of ambiguity in defining the series; its relatively
      simple application and the problem of bias associated with the PDS for
      less frequent AEPs.</para>

      <para>It should be noted that in extracting the AMS, the focus was on
      obtaining the largest rainfall depth in each year for each of the
      durations considered. Therefore the extracted depths comprised both
      total storm depths and bursts within storm storms.</para>

      <para>In order to reduce the uncertainty in the design rainfall
      estimates, minimum station record lengths were adopted. The criteria
      were:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>30 or more years of record for daily read rainfall
          stations</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>More than 8 years of record for continuous rainfall
          stations</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>These criteria were selected on the basis of optimising the
      spatial coverage of the rainfall stations while ensuring that there were
      sufficient AMS values at each site to undertake frequency
      analysis.</para>

      <para>The daily read rainfall data are for the restricted period from
      9am to 9am rather than for the actual duration of the event. As this may
      not lead to the largest rainfall total, it was necessary to convert
      these ‘restricted’ daily read rainfall depths to unrestricted rainfall
      depths. In order to do this, ‘restricted’ to unrestricted conversions
      factors were estimated using co-located daily read and continuous
      rainfall gauges at a number of locations around Australia of differing
      climatic conditions. The resultant factors are shown in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch3_t4"/>.</para>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t4">
          <caption>Rainfall reporting methods</caption>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <col width="12%"/>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Duration</td>

              <td>1 day</td>

              <td>2 days</td>

              <td>3 days</td>

              <td>4 days</td>

              <td>5 days</td>

              <td>6 days</td>

              <td>7 days</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Factor</td>

              <td>1.15</td>

              <td>1.11</td>

              <td>1.07</td>

              <td>1.05</td>

              <td>1.04</td>

              <td>1.03</td>

              <td>1.02</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_98oww">
        <title>At-site frequency analysis</title>

        <para>In order to assess the most appropriate distribution to adopt
        across Australia for the AMS, a range of distributions was trialled
        using single site analysis. Five distributions – GEV, Generalised
        Logistic (GLO), Generalised Normal (GNO), Pearson Type III (PE3) and
        Generalised Pareto (GPA) – were fitted to the AMS extracted from the
        available long-terms continuous rainfall stations for a range of
        durations. The goodness of fit of each distribution was assessed using
        the approach recommended by Hosking and Wallis (1997). It was found
        that the Generalised Extreme Value (GEV) distribution produced the
        best fit to the AMS on an at-site analysis. The comparison of
        distributions was subsequently repeated for regional estimates with
        the same results (Green et al, 2012b).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_brsiv">
        <title>Estimation of L-moments</title>

        <para>The linear combinations of the data (L-moments) (Hosking and
        Wallis, 1997) of mean, variation (L-CV) and skewness (L-skewness) were
        used to summarise the statistical properties of the extreme value
        series data at each station location. L-moments are commonly used in
        rainfall and flood frequency analysis (Hosking and Wallis, 1997) due
        to their efficiency in fitting the data and lack of bias in the sample
        estimates, particularly in the higher order moments, when compared to
        ordinary moments.</para>

        <para>While for durations of one day and longer this was a fairly
        straightforward approach, for sub-daily durations the scarcity of long
        term continuous rainfall records meant that an alternative approach
        was needed to supplement the available data. For the IFD revision
        project, a Bayesian Generalised Least Squares Regression (BGLSR)
        approach was adopted, a summary of which is provided below; more
        details can be found in Johnson et al (2012a) and Haddad et al
        (2015).</para>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_xnyyw">
          <title>Daily durations</title>

          <para>At sites at which there was a daily read rainfall station with
          30 or more years of record, the mean, L-CV and L-skewness, were
          determined from the at-site extreme value series for each
          duration.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_nstwd">
          <title>Sub-daily durations – at continuous rainfall stations</title>

          <para>At sites at which there was a continuous rainfall station with
          more than eight years of record, the mean, L-CV and L-skewness, were
          determined from the at-site extreme value series for each duration
          considered.</para>

          <para>As can be seen from<xref linkend="b2_ch3_f3"/> and <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3_f4"/> the spatial coverage of sub-daily rainfall
          stations is considerably less than that of the daily read stations.
          Therefore, a method was needed to improve the spatial coverage of
          the sub-daily data. This is most commonly done using information
          from the daily read stations with statistics of sub-daily data being
          inferred from those of the daily data. Previously adopted techniques
          for predicting rainfall depths at durations below 24 hours from
          those for the 24, 48 and 72-hour durations have been factoring of
          the 24 hours IFDs; principal component analysis followed by
          regression; and Partial Least Squares Regression. However, a major
          weakness of these previously adopted approaches is their inability
          to account for variation in record lengths from site to site and
          inter-station correlation</para>

          <para>The approach that was adopted for the frequent and infrequent
          design rainfalls was Bayesian Generalised Least Squares Regression
          (BGLSR) because it accounts for possible cross-validation and
          unequal variance between stations by constructing an error
          covariance matrix and can explicitly account for sampling
          uncertainty and intersite dependence. Details of the BGLSR approach
          can be found in Reis et al. (2005) and Madsen et al. (2002; 2009).
          In Australia, Haddad et al. (2012a) used BGLSR to obtain regional
          relationships to estimate peak streamflow in ungauged catchments and
          for pilot studies for the design rainfall project (Haddad and
          Rahman, 2009; Haddad et al., 2011; 2015).</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_wvl74">
          <title>Bayesian Generalised Least Squares Regression (BGLSR) –
          Overview</title>

          <para>BGLSR is an extension of ordinary least squares (OLS)
          regression such that the predictand (dependent variable) is
          calculated from a linear combination of a number of predictor
          variables (independent variables) with a suitable error model. In
          general the predictions for the rainfall statistic, <emphasis
          role="italic">y</emphasis>, of interest for site <emphasis
          role="italic">i</emphasis>, are made according to <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3_e1"/>.</para>

          <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e1">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>y</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>0</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:munderover>
                      <m:mo>∑</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>j-1</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>k</m:mi>
                    </m:munderover>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>β</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>X</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>ij</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:math>
          </equation>

          <para>Where <emphasis
          role="italic">X<subscript>ij</subscript></emphasis> (<emphasis
          role="italic">j</emphasis> = 1,…,<emphasis
          role="italic">k</emphasis>) are the <emphasis
          role="italic">k</emphasis> predictor variables, <emphasis
          role="italic">β<subscript>j</subscript></emphasis>­ are the
          parameters of the model that must be estimated, <emphasis
          role="italic">ε</emphasis> is the sampling error and <emphasis
          role="italic">δ</emphasis> is the model error.</para>

          <para>A further advantage of the BGLSR is that the Bayesian
          formulation allows for the separation of sampling and statistical
          modelling errors. This is important because it was found that the
          sampling errors dominate the total error in the statistical model.
          The BGLSR produces estimates of the standard error in:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>the regression coefficients</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>the predicted values at-site used in establishing the
              regression equations</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>the predicted values at new sites (that is, sites not used
              in deriving the regression). In the application of the BGLSR
              these are the daily rainfall stations where the predictions of
              sub-daily rainfalls statistics are required.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>The error variances for the predictions are comprised of the
          regional model error and the sampling variance.</para>

          <para>The errors in the BGLSR model are assumed to have zero mean
          and the covariance structure described in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3_e2"/>.</para>

          <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e2">
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>C</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>v</m:mi>

                  <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>

                  <m:mo>}</m:mo>

                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtable>
                        <m:mtr>
                          <m:mtd>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msubsup>
                                <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                  </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>

                                <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                              </m:msubsup>

                              <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mtd>
                        </m:mtr>

                        <m:mtr>
                          <m:mtd>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                                    <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                                  </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                                    <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                                  </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:msub>
                                <m:mi>ρ</m:mi>

                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:msub>
                                    <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                                    <m:mrow>
                                      <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                                      <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                                    </m:mrow>
                                  </m:msub>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:msub>

                              <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mtd>
                        </m:mtr>
                      </m:mtable>

                      <m:mtable>
                        <m:mtr>
                          <m:mtd>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                              <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                              <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mtd>
                        </m:mtr>

                        <m:mtr>
                          <m:mtd>
                            <m:mrow>
                              <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                              <m:mo>≠</m:mo>

                              <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                            </m:mrow>
                          </m:mtd>
                        </m:mtr>
                      </m:mtable>

                      <m:mo>;</m:mo>

                      <m:mi>C</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>o</m:mi>

                      <m:mi>v</m:mi>

                      <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mo>,</m:mo>

                      <m:msub>
                        <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                      </m:msub>

                      <m:mo>}</m:mo>

                      <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mtable>
                            <m:mtr>
                              <m:mtd>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:msubsup>
                                    <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                                    <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                                    <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                                  </m:msubsup>

                                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:mtd>
                            </m:mtr>

                            <m:mtr>
                              <m:mtd>
                                <m:mrow>
                                  <m:mn>0</m:mn>

                                  <m:mo>,</m:mo>
                                </m:mrow>
                              </m:mtd>
                            </m:mtr>
                          </m:mtable>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mtext> </m:mtext>

                  <m:mtable>
                    <m:mtr>
                      <m:mtd>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mtd>
                    </m:mtr>

                    <m:mtr>
                      <m:mtd>
                        <m:mrow>
                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                          <m:mo>≠</m:mo>

                          <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                        </m:mrow>
                      </m:mtd>
                    </m:mtr>
                  </m:mtable>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </equation>

          <para>Where <inlineequation>
              <m:math display="inline">
                <m:semantics>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msubsup>
                      <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                        </m:msub>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                    </m:msubsup>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:annotation encoding="MathType-MTEF">MathType@MTEF@5@5@+=
                  feaagKart1ev2aaatCvAUfeBSjuyZL2yd9gzLbvyNv2CaerbuLwBLn
                  hiov2DGi1BTfMBaeXatLxBI9gBaerbd9wDYLwzYbItLDharqqtubsr
                  4rNCHbGeaGqiVu0Je9sqqrpepC0xbbL8F4rqqrFfpeea0xe9Lq=Jc9
                  vqaqpepm0xbba9pwe9Q8fs0=yqaqpepae9pg0FirpepeKkFr0xfr=x
                  fr=xb9adbaqaaeGaciGaaiaabeqaamaabaabaaGcbaGaeq4Wdm3aa0
                  baaSqaaiabew7aLnaaBaaameaacaWGPbaabeaaaSqaaiaaikdaaaaa
                  aa@3B6F@</m:annotation>
                </m:semantics>
              </m:math>
            </inlineequation> is the sampling error variance at site <emphasis
          role="italic">i,</emphasis> <inlineequation>
              <m:math display="inline">
                <m:semantics>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msub>
                      <m:mi>ρ</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:msub>
                          <m:mi>ε</m:mi>

                          <m:mrow>
                            <m:mi>i</m:mi>

                            <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                          </m:mrow>
                        </m:msub>
                      </m:mrow>
                    </m:msub>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:semantics>
              </m:math>
            </inlineequation> is the correlation coefficient between sites
          <emphasis role="italic">i</emphasis> and <emphasis
          role="italic">j</emphasis>, <inlineequation>
              <m:math display="inline">
                <m:semantics>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:msubsup>
                      <m:mi>σ</m:mi>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mi>δ</m:mi>

                        <m:mi>i</m:mi>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mn>2</m:mn>
                    </m:msubsup>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:semantics>
              </m:math>
            </inlineequation> is the model error variance. For the Bayesian
          framework introduced by Reis <emphasis role="italic">et</emphasis>
          al. (2005), the parameters of the model (<emphasis
          role="italic">β</emphasis>) are modelled with a multivariate normal
          distribution using a non informative prior. A quasi analytic
          approximation to the Bayesian formulation of the GLSR has been
          developed by Reis et al. (2005) to solve for the posterior
          distributions of the mean and variance for <emphasis
          role="italic">β.</emphasis></para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_1qarp">
          <title>BGLSR - Application</title>

          <para>The aim of the BGLSR is to predict sub-daily rainfall
          statistics at the location of daily rainfall stations. As discussed
          previously, L-moments have been used to summarise the statistical
          properties of the AMS data (Hosking and Wallis, 1997) because
          L-moments are relatively robust against outliers in the datasets.
          The statistics that are required for the project are:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Mean of the AMS (also called the index rainfall)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>L-coefficient of variation (L-CV)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>L-skewness</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>These three statistics can then be used to define the
          parameters of any appropriate probability distribution which in the
          case of the design rainfalls had been shown to be the GEV
          distribution.</para>

          <para>The initial work required to apply the BGLSR was to determine
          the appropriate predictors (ie X from <xref linkend="b2_ch3_e1"/>)
          to estimate the three rainfall statistics listed above. A review of
          literature and meteorological causative mechanisms selected a number
          of site and rainfall characteristics for use as possible predictors
          as reported in Johnson et al. (2012a). These predictors were:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Latitude and longitude</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Elevation</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Slope</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Aspect</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Distance from the coast</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Mean annual rainfall</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Rainfall statistics (mean, L-CV and L-skewness) for the
              24, 48 and 72 hour duration events</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>Haddad and Rahman (2012b) provide extensive details of the
          cross validated predictor selection process for each of the study
          areas. It was found that the most important predictor is the 24 hour
          rainfall statistic. However performance of the model was not changed
          significantly by including all predictors so this approach was
          adopted.</para>

          <para>As well as determining the optimum combination of predictor
          variables, the testing for the BGLSR needed to determine the number
          of stations to contribute to each regression equation. Ideally the
          number of stations in each analysis area would be maximised to
          improve the accuracy of the regression equations. However the number
          of stations is limited to approximately 100 by the requirement for
          the error covariance matrices to be invertible. The delineation of
          the analysis areas thus needed to balance these two competing
          requirements.</para>

          <para>It was also important that stations were grouped into analysis
          areas where the causative mechanisms for large rainfall events are
          similar. The rainfall stations were grouped primarily according to
          climatic zones by considering the seasonality of rainfall events and
          mean annual rainfalls. Australian drainage divisions were also used
          to guide the division of larger climatic zones into smaller areas
          over which the BGLSR calculations are tractable, such as in the
          northern tropics where three analysis areas have been adopted (NT,
          GULF and NORTH_QLD). The final analysis areas are shown in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch3_f10"/>. A 0.2 degree buffer has been used in
          assigning stations to each analysis area to provide a smooth
          transition between adjacent areas.</para>

          <para>For each analysis area, a regression relationship was
          developed which could be applied to all stations within the analysis
          area. Where the density of stations was high, a ROI approach (Burn,
          1990) was adopted such that each station has its own ROI. This
          allowed the regression equations to smoothly vary across the data
          dense analysis areas. For sparser analysis areas, a clustering, or
          fixed region, approach was adopted such that stations were grouped
          by spatial proximity into analysis areas with rigid boundaries. All
          stations in each analysis area were used to derive one regression
          equation that was then adopted for the predictions at those
          stations.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f10">
            <title>Analysis Areas Adopted for the BGLSR - Fixed Analysis Areas
            are Shown with Solid Fill, ROI Areas are Hatched. Locations of
            Continuous Rainfall Stations are also shown</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2041.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>To improve the predictions from the BGLSR it was desirable
          that the distribution of each predictor variable was relatively
          symmetric and preferably approximately normally distributed. For
          each analysis area the distribution of the predictor variables from
          all sites in the area was examined using histograms and
          quantile-quantile plots. For predictors that appeared to be strongly
          skewed, a range of transformations were trialled to attempt to
          reduce the skewness of the variable. The transformations included a
          natural logarithm, square root transformation and Box-Cox (ie power)
          transformation. In general the log transformation and the Box-Cox
          transformation were successful in reducing the skewness of the
          predictors.</para>

          <para>After determining the regression coefficients for the analysis
          areas, these coefficients were combined with the set of predictors
          for the daily station locations to produce the estimates of the
          sub-daily rainfall statistics. There are no observations of the
          sub-daily rainfall statistics to which these predictions at daily
          sites can be compared. However “sanity” checks on the values were
          carried out by comparing the estimates to the 24 hour rainfall
          statistics and to the possible range of values for L-CV and
          L‑skewness (both limited to -1 to 1).</para>

          <para>The result of using estimated sub-daily rainfall statistics
          was that the number of locations with sub-daily information was
          increased from approximately 2300 to approximately 9700 when both
          the daily and continuous rainfall stations locations are used. This
          substantially increased density of sub-daily rainfall data assisted
          in the subsequent gridding of the rainfall quantiles across
          Australia described in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s4_5"/>.</para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s4_4">
      <title>Regionalisation</title>

      <para>Regionalisation recognises that for stations with short records,
      there is considerable uncertainty when estimating the parameters of
      probability distributions and short records can bias estimates of
      rainfall statistics. To overcome this, it is assumed that information
      can be combined from multiple stations to give more accurate estimates
      of the parameters of the extreme value probability distributions. One
      approach that is widely used to reduce the uncertainty and overcome bias
      in estimating rainfall quantiles is regional frequency analysis, also
      known as regionalisation.</para>

      <para>For the design rainfalls, regionalisation was used to estimate the
      L-CV and L-Skewness with more confidence. The regionalisation approach
      adopted is generally called the “index flood procedure” (Hosking and
      Wallis, 1997). This approach assumes that sites can be grouped into
      homogenous regions, such that all sites in the region have the same
      probability distribution, other than a scaling factor. The scaling
      factor is termed the index flood or in this case, since the
      regionalisation is of rainfall data, the “index rainfall”. The index
      rainfall is the mean (that is, first L-moment) of the extreme value
      series data at the station location.</para>

      <para>The homogenous regions for the frequency analysis can be defined
      in a number of ways. Cluster and partitioning methods divide the set of
      all stations into a fixed number of homogenous groups (Hosking and
      Wallis, 1997) where generally every site is assigned to one group.
      Alternatively, a ROI approach (Burn, 1990) can be adopted, such that for
      each station an individual homogenous region is defined. Each ROI will
      contain a potentially unique set of sites, with each site possibly
      contributing to multiple ROIs.</para>

      <para>For the design rainfalls, the station point estimates were
      regionalised using a ROI as the advantage of this approach is that the
      region sizes can be easily varied according to station density and the
      available record lengths. The assumptions of the approach are, firstly,
      that the specified probability distribution (GEV in the case of the AMS)
      is appropriate; that the region is truly homogenous; and, finally, that
      sites are independent or that their dependence is quantified.</para>

      <para>In the application of the ROI method, it was first necessary to
      establish how big the ROIs should be. The size of the ROI can be defined
      in two ways; either using the number of stations included in the region
      or alternatively by calculating the total number of station-years in the
      region as the sum of the record lengths of the individual stations
      included in the ROI.</para>

      <para>Region sizes from 1 to 50 stations and from 50 to 5000
      station-years were investigated to establish the optimum ROIs for
      estimating rainfall quantiles across Australia using a simple circular
      ROI and the Pooled Uncertainty Measure (PUM) (Kjeldsen and Jones, 2009).
      The minimum PUM values occur where there is an optimum size in the trade
      off between bias and variance of generally lead to the minimum PUM
      value. When considering the region defined using the number of stations
      it was found that a region of 8 stations performed best. Given that the
      average record length for stations used in the analysis was 66 years, a
      region of 8 stations will have on average 528 years of data which is
      consistent with the region size using the station-year criteria. The
      findings were generally independent of rainfall event duration and
      frequency.</para>

      <para>Defining regions in terms of station-years is attractive as this
      approach can adapt to different station densities and station record
      lengths. Given the similar results from both methods, the station-years
      definition for the region size was adopted.</para>

      <para>After finalising the optimum region size, a number of geographic
      and non-geographic similarity measures were investigated as methods to
      define membership of each ROI. Three different alternatives for defining
      the ROIs using geographical similarity were investigated:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Distance between sites (in kms) defined using latitude and
          longitude</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Euclidean distance between sites where distance was defined
          using latitude, longitude and scaled elevation (Hutchinson,
          1995)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Nearest neighbours defined using distance in kilometres inside
          an elliptical ROI.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Non-geographic characteristics were selected based on their
      potential influence on the properties of large rainfall events at a site
      (Johnson et al, 2012a). The site characteristics that were trialled
      were:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Location (latitude and longitude)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Elevation</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Mean Annual Rainfall</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Aspect</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Slope</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Distance from the coast</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Mean date of AMS (seasonality)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Variability of AMS occurrence (seasonality)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The results of the trialling showed that the best results were
      provided using</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>a circular ROI</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>distances defined in three dimensions using latitude;
          longitude and elevation.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_08y9d">
        <title>Regionalisation - application</title>

        <para>To undertake the regionalisation the following procedure was
        followed initially using the 24 hour rainfall data:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>For each station location, a circular ROI was expanded until
            500 stations years of record was achieved. The resultant region
            was tested for homogeneity using the H measure of Hosking and
            Wallis (1997)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>If the region was not homogenous the stations in the regions
            were checked according to the discordancy measures of Hosking and
            Wallis (1997) and the region membership revised where
            appropriate.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The average L-CV for each region was calculated using a
            weighted average of the L-CV at all stations in the region, with
            the weights proportional to the station lengths. This was repeated
            for the L-Skewness.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The regionalised L-CV and L-Skewness were used to estimate
            the scale (α) and shape (κ) parameters of the growth curve (scaled
            GEV distribution) at each location.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The regions defined for the 24 hour duration rainfall data were
        used for all daily and sub-daily durations. More details on the
        regionalisation can be found in Johnson et al (2012b).</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s4_5">
      <title>Gridding</title>

      <para>The regionalisation process resulted in estimates of the GEV
      parameters at all station locations, which were combined with the mean
      of the extreme value series at that site to estimate rainfall quantiles
      for any required exceedance probability. However frequent and infrequent
      design rainfall estimates are required across Australia, not just at
      station locations and therefore the results of the analyses needed to be
      extended in some way to ungauged locations.</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_d8spf">
        <title>Selection of approach to be adopted for gridding</title>

        <para>For the design rainfalls, the software package ANUSPLIN
        (Hutchinson 2007) was chosen to grid the GEV parameters so that
        frequent and infrequent design rainfall estimates are available for
        any point in Australia. ANUSPLIN applies thin plate smoothing splines
        to interpolate and smooth multi-variate data. The degree of smoothing
        of the fitted functions was determined through generalised cross
        validation. The splines are fitted using three independent variables;
        latitude, longitude and elevation. The elevation scale was exaggerated
        by a factor of 100 to represent the importance that elevation has on
        precipitation patterns (Hutchinson 1995).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_lxz5r">
        <title>Selection of parameters to be gridded</title>

        <para>The GEV parameters were gridded in ANUSPLIN rather than the
        rainfall depths, as earlier testing showed little difference in the
        resulting quantile estimates irrespective of whether point GEV
        parameters or point rainfall depths were gridded. Gridding the GEV
        parameters provided more flexibility in the choice of exceedance
        probabilities that could be extracted and enables the provision of a
        greater number of AEPs.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_g7u89">
        <title>Optimisation of gridding</title>

        <para>In undertaking the gridding, a considerable number of iterations
        was required to achieve an optimum outcome that represented the
        observed rainfalls but which did not place too much significance on
        short rainfall records or from poorly located rainfall stations. The
        appropriate degree of smoothing of the fitted functions was determined
        through generalised cross validation with the number of knots and
        transformation adopted varied to achieve optimal results. In addition
        to the statistical tests to determine the appropriate degree of
        smoothing, qualitative assessments were also conducted by preparing
        maps which compared the index rainfall derived from at-site frequency
        analysis of rainfall records, the length of record available at each
        station, and the spatial density of the raingauge network to the
        gridded index rainfalls produced by ANUSPLIN for daily
        durations.</para>

        <para>The final IFD grids were produced by the application of ANUSPLIN
        using a 0.025 degree DEM resolution and adopting 3570 knots with no
        transformation of the data. More details on the gridding approach
        adopted can be found in The et al (2012; 2014) and Johnson et al
        (2015).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_xyl6m">
        <title>Calculation of growth factors and rainfall depths</title>

        <para>The outputs of the ANUSPLIN analysis were grids across Australia
        of index rainfall and the GEV scale (alpha) and shape (kappa)
        parameters for each duration. These were then processed to firstly
        estimate the growth factors for each grid location and then the
        rainfall depths for each exceedance probability, according to the
        following equations:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e3">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>ξ</m:mi>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                <m:mi>α</m:mi>

                <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                <m:mi>Γ</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>κ</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>

                <m:mo>}</m:mo>

                <m:mo>/</m:mo>

                <m:mi>κ</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mi>ξ</m:mi>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the location parameter for the regionalised
        growth curve and <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mi>Γ</m:mi>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> represents the Gamma function.</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e4">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>q</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mi>ξ</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mi>α</m:mi>

                <m:mo>{</m:mo>

                <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                <m:msup>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                    <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>log</m:mi>

                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>

                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>κ</m:mi>
                </m:msup>

                <m:mo>}</m:mo>

                <m:mo>/</m:mo>

                <m:mi>κ</m:mi>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>q</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the quantile function of the growth curve for
        the cumulative probability <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mi>F</m:mi>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> .</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e5">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mi>μ</m:mi>

                <m:mi>q</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>Q</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the quantile function of the scaled growth
        curve, which is multiplied by the index rainfall <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mi>μ</m:mi>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> .</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_sguqy">
        <title>Derivation of sub-hourly rainfall depths</title>

        <para>To derive frequent and infrequent design rainfalls for durations
        of less than one hour to one minute the ‘simple scaling’ model
        developed by Menabde et al (1999) was adopted. The model was
        calibrated using the AMS from the BoM’s continuous rainfall stations
        with more than eight years of data. For each continuous rainfall
        station the scaling factor, η, was determined and the at-site η values
        gridded to provide estimates for all grid locations. The model was
        then applied to the 1 hour duration rainfall depth grids to estimate
        the rainfall depths for the 1 minute to 30 minute rainfall events
        according to the following equation:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e6">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:msup>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mo>(</m:mo>

                      <m:mrow>
                        <m:mfrac>
                          <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                          <m:mi>D</m:mi>
                        </m:mfrac>
                      </m:mrow>

                      <m:mo>)</m:mo>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mi>n</m:mi>
                </m:msup>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                  <m:mi>D</m:mi>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>d</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the sub-hourly rainfall intensity for duration
        <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mi>d</m:mi>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> , <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mi>I</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>D</m:mi>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the 60 minute rainfall intensity (i.e. duration
        <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mi>D</m:mi>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is 60 minutes).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_fzvel">
        <title>Consistency checking and smoothing</title>

        <para>In order to reduce inconsistencies across durations and smooth
        over discontinuities in the gridded data (unevenly spaced differences
        in design rainfall estimates at neighbouring durations) arising from
        application of the method, a smoothing process was undertaken. This
        was done by applying a 6th order polynomial to each grid point to all
        the standard durations from one minute up to seven days.</para>

        <para>Although polynomials up to order 12 were investigated, a 6 order
        polynomial was adopted as investigations showed that this order
        polynomial gives adequate results.</para>

        <para>Inconsistencies with respect to duration (rainfall depths at
        lower durations exceeding those at higher durations) were also found
        and were addressed in the manner described below.</para>

        <para>Inconsistencies were detected by subtracting each grid from a
        longer duration grid at the same probability and checking for negative
        values. Inconsistencies were addressed by adjusting by adjusting the
        longer duration rainfall upwards so that the ratio of shorter duration
        rainfall to the longer duration rainfall equals 0.99, or</para>

        <para><inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mfrac>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtext>Rainfall depth at the shorter duration</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtext>Rainfall depth at the longer duration</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:mfrac>

                  <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                  <m:mn>0.99</m:mn>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation></para>

        <para>The smoothing procedure was applied first to the original grids
        and the smoothed grids adjusted for inconsistencies. The grids were
        smoothed once again and a final adjustment for inconsistencies across
        durations was performed. The final grids were also checked for
        inconsistencies across AEP.</para>

        <para>Grids of the polynomial coefficients were prepared in order to
        enable IFDs for any duration to be determined.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s4_6">
      <title>Outputs</title>

      <para>The method described above produced frequent and infrequent design
      rainfall estimates across Australia. The design rainfall estimates are
      provided both as rainfall depths in millimetres (mm) and rainfall
      intensities in millimetres per hour (mm/hr) for the following standard
      durations and standard probabilities:</para>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t5">
          <caption>IFD Outputs</caption>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th><emphasis role="bold">Output</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Values</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Units</emphasis></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Standard durations</td>

              <td><para>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 10, 15, 30</para></td>

              <td><para>Minutes</para></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td><para>1, 2, 3, 6, 12</para></td>

              <td><para>Hours</para></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 7</td>

              <td>Days</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Standard probabilities</td>

              <td>1</td>

              <td><para>EY</para></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td>50%, 20%, 10%, 5%, 2%, 1%</td>

              <td>AEP</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s5_0">
    <title>Very Frequent Design Rainfalls</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s5_1">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>The previous section summarised the steps involved in deriving the
      frequent and infrequent design rainfall values (IFDs) for probabilities
      from 1EY to 1% AEP. This range of probabilities is suitable for most
      design situations, however, many stormwater quality or Water Sensitive
      Urban Design guidelines recommend a flow threshold of
      Q<subscript>3month</subscript> for the design of stormwater quality
      treatment devices.</para>

      <para>Design rainfalls for the 3 month average recurrence interval (4
      EY) have not been previously available, with agencies giving their own
      advice on the approach for estimating very frequent design rainfalls. To
      address this need, estimates for probabilities more frequent than 1 EY
      have been derived. In the following sections, the approach adopted for
      deriving these very frequent design rainfalls is presented.</para>

      <para>To ensure consistency between the very frequent design rainfalls
      and the frequent and infrequent design rainfall, the overall approach
      adopted for the very frequent design rainfalls was very similar to that
      adopted for the frequent and infrequent design rainfall. However, some
      modifications to the approach were necessary because of the increased
      frequency of occurrence that was being considered. A summary of the
      method is presented in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_t6"/> and in the following
      sections. Further details can be found in The et al (2015).</para>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t6">
          <caption>Summary of very frequent design rainfall method</caption>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th><emphasis role="bold">Step</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Method</emphasis></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Number of rainfall stations</td>

              <td><para>Daily read – 15 364</para></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td>Continuous – 2722</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Period of record</td>

              <td>All available records up to 2012</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Length of record used in analyses</td>

              <td><para>Daily read &gt; 5 years</para></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td>Continuous &gt; 5 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Source of data</td>

              <td>Organisations collecting rainfall data across Australia</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Extreme value series</td>

              <td>Partial Duration Series (PDS)</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Frequency analysis</td>

              <td>Generalised Pareto (GPA) distribution fitted using
              L-moments</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Ratios</td>

              <td>Ratio XEY to 50% AEP</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Gridding</td>

              <td>Regionalised at-site distribution parameters gridded using
              ANUSPLIN</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_h3_s5_2">
      <title>Rainfall Database</title>

      <para>The data adopted consisted of the stations used for the frequent
      and infrequent design rainfalls (Green et al 2011) and an additional
      7290 stations with shorter periods of record, which have undergone the
      same rigorous quality controlling as the frequent and infrequent design
      rainfall database.(Green et al 2011; 2012a). The locations of the
      stations used for the estimation of the very frequent design rainfalls
      are shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f11"/>.</para>

      <para>These additional stations could be used as the minimum number of
      years of record was reduced from 30 (for the frequent and infrequent
      design rainfalIs) to five years for the very frequent design rainfalls.
      A threshold of five effective years was selected for daily and sub-daily
      sites as this was deemed to be statistically acceptable given the high
      frequency of the estimated exceedances compared to the previous 1 EY.
      The shorter record length ensures greater use of available sites but
      also ensures that there is sufficient information available to derive
      the more frequent probabilities from 12EY to 2 EY.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f11">
        <title>Daily Read Rainfall Stations (light blue) and Continuous
        Rainfall Stations (dark blue) Used for Very Frequent Design Rainfalls
        (light blue)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2042.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s5_3">
      <title>Extraction of extreme value series</title>

      <para>A partial duration series (PDS) approach was adopted to estimate
      probabilities for events occurring more frequently than once a year. The
      advantage of using the PDS is that it extracts as much information as
      possible about large events and produces more accurate estimates for
      very frequent probabilities. As a PDS was used for the at-site series
      the selection of independent events was based on rank rather than
      temporal periods, thus completeness of record was not a
      consideration.</para>

      <para>As a PDS approach was being adopted it was necessary to define the
      threshold above which all events will be included. It was important to
      identify the number of values per year that are required to accurately
      estimate the more frequent IFD's. Given that the most frequent
      probability is 12 EY, a minimum of 12 events per year was used to
      adequately represent the at-site distribution for these higher frequency
      events.</para>

      <para>An assumption of the method, is that the events in the PDS are
      independent. In order to ensure that the events in the PDS were
      independent, an method that provided a consistent and meteorologically
      rigorous approach to defining independence of rainfall events across
      Australia was developed. The event independence testing criteria used
      were based on the minimum inter-event time (MIT), approach (Xuereb and
      Green, 2012). The analyses suggested that a MIT that varied from two to
      six days with latitude across Australia was appropriate for event
      durations up to three days while for durations longer than three days
      the MIT adopted was zero. For durations of less than one day, the MIT
      for the 1 day duration was adopted (Green et al 2014).</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_66ri1">
        <title>At-site frequency analysis</title>

        <para>The approach adopted effectively treated the PDS as a Monthly
        Partial Duration Series or - more correctly for the current dataset -
        a Monthly Exceedance Series (MES) (PDS where number of values = number
        of effective months: 12 nE). While the extracted PDS is the same, the
        averaging duration is changed, representing the time in months rather
        than years. The selection of an MES rather than an annual series
        allowed significantly more records to be included from each site to
        establish the at-site rainfall distribution, capturing the more
        frequent rainfall patterns.</para>

        <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s4_3"/> and Green et al.
        (2012b), testing of the most appropriate distribution to adopt for
        both the AMS and the PDS was undertaken as part of the derivation of
        the IFDs with results identifying the GEV distribution as the most
        appropriate for the AMS and the GPA distribution for the PDS. However,
        as a monthly exceedance data series was adopted for the very frequent
        design rainfalls there is some added uncertainty; to address this, a
        comparison was conducted of the GEV and GPA distributions. Twenty-four
        geographically distributed test sites with medium to long record
        lengths were selected for assessing the relative fit of the
        distributions to the at-site data. The test sites indicated that the
        GPA provides a closer fit to the site data in the majority of cases.
        On the basis of this, the very frequent design rainfalls used the GPA
        distribution fitted to the PDS for all stations which met the required
        record length.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_drzv8">
        <title>Estimation of L-moments</title>

        <para>Regional frequency analysis was undertaken using L-moments
        extracted from each of the at-site frequency distributions for
        sub-daily and daily data. The L-moments were used to estimate the
        parameters of the selected GPA distribution.</para>

        <para>Extracting 12 independent events per year of record for the MES
        introduced the issue of zero values included in the PDS at some sites.
        This particularly occurred through the arid areas of central Australia
        to the west coast, where annual rainfall is highly variable and strong
        seasonality can occur. These areas have short wet seasons and can fail
        to have 12 rain events on average that are independent of one another
        for every year. However, given the previously defined minimum number
        of events being 12, these zero values events are considered as part of
        the distribution. To manage the occurrence of the zero values in the
        extreme value series, Hosking and Wallis (1997) suggest using a ‘mixed
        distribution’ or more correctly a conditional probability adjustment
        that gives a probability of a zero value, and cumulative distribution
        for the non-zero values as seen in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_e8"/>
        (Guttman et al., 1993).</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e8">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>F</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                <m:mo>+</m:mo>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>

                <m:mi>G</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>Where <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mi>p</m:mi>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the probability of a zero rainfall value which
        is estimated by dividing the numbers of zeros by the total number of
        events and <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>G</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the cumulative distribution function of the
        non-zero rainfall events. Using this approach, if the non-exceedance
        probability (NEP) of interest is less than <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mi>p</m:mi>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> , then the quantile estimate is zero and if the
        NEP is greater than <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:mi>p</m:mi>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> , the quantile is estimated from <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mi>G</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                  <m:mi>x</m:mi>

                  <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> using the adjusted NEP shown in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch3_e9"/>.</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e9">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:mi>N</m:mi>

                <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mi>a</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>d</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>j</m:mi>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>

                <m:mo>=</m:mo>

                <m:mrow>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>N</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>E</m:mi>

                    <m:mi>P</m:mi>

                    <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mo>/</m:mo>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mo stretchy="false">(</m:mo>

                    <m:mn>1</m:mn>

                    <m:mo>−</m:mo>

                    <m:mi>p</m:mi>

                    <m:mo stretchy="false">)</m:mo>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>For series with small proportions of zeros, the impact on the
        distribution and resulting quantiles was negligible. For records with
        less than 10% zeros, there is very little difference and up to nearly
        20% zeros there is less than 10% average difference in the quantile
        depths. However the differences become much more significant when the
        proportion of zeros increases.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s5_4">
      <title>Ratio method</title>

      <para>The parameters of the GPA distribution derived from the L-moments
      were used to calculate at-site quantiles. The parameters or quantiles
      could be gridded in a similar method to the frequent and infrequent
      design rainfalls and smoothed or rescaled to intergrate them with the
      design rainfalls less frequent than 1EY. Alternatively, as adopted, a
      ratio method could be applied to derive the very frequent design
      rainfall estimates. A general ratio approach is currently used by
      various councils and authorities in Australia and internationally (Huff
      and Angel, 1992). It involves using the at-site data to determine the
      ratio of the various very frequent design rainfall values to either the
      1 EY or 50% AEP gridded design rainfalls.</para>

      <para>The ratio method adopted involves estimating at-site quantiles,
      using the at-site 50% AEP as the reference values for the ratios, and
      gridding the calculated ratios. The advantage of this approach and using
      the at-site 50% AEP, was that it allows for the spatial variability in
      the ratios. In addition, the ratio was generally a more accurate
      representation of the <emphasis role="italic">X</emphasis> EY to 50% AEP
      ratio since it was calculated from the same dataset and resulted in a
      smooth spatial pattern. Consistency was also inherent since the ratios
      would always decrease with increasing probability. Since the ratios were
      spatially consistent, the final very frequent design rainfall depths
      follow the frequent and infrequent 50% AEP depths closely. These depth
      estimates were calculated using the gridded ratios, and multiplying by
      the 50% AEP design rainfall.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s5_5">
      <title>Gridding</title>

      <para>The ratios for all durations and EYs were gridded using the
      splining software ANUSPLIN (Hutchinson and Xu, 2013) that was adopted
      for the frequent and infrequent design rainfalls. To determine the most
      appropriate method to adopt for the gridding of the ratios a range of
      tests was undertaken of combinations of variates and different knot
      sets. The final case adopted was a spline that incorporated latitude,
      longitude and elevation using 4000 knots for the daily dataset and 1000
      knots for the sub-daily dataset. The 0.025 degree Digital Elevation
      Model (DEM) of Australia was used to provide the elevation data which
      were the same as that used in the derivation of the frequent and
      infrequest grids (The et al, 2014).</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_yd8tt">
        <title>Depth estimates</title>

        <para>Very frequent design rainfall depth estimates for each duration
        and EY were calculated by multiplying the ratio grids with the
        corresponding 50% AEP design rainfall grids (<xref
        linkend="b2_ch3_f12"/>). As the frequent and infrequent design
        rainfall grids were based on AMS estimates, an AMS/PDS conversion
        factor was applied to account for the lower estimates (Green et al.,
        2012b).</para>

        <para>The grids were smoothed across duration to reduce any
        inconsistencies across durations and to smooth over discontinuities in
        the gridded data. A 6th order polynomial was applied to each grid
        point for all the standard durations from 1 minute up to 10080 minutes
        (7 days). Grids were also checked for inconsistencies across
        EY.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f12">
          <title>Procedure to derive very frequent design rainfall depth grids
          from ratios</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2043.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s5_6">
      <title>Outputs</title>

      <para>The method described above produced very frequent design rainfall
      estimates across Australia. The very frequent design rainfall estimates
      are provided both as rainfall depths in millimetres (mm) and rainfall
      intensities in millimetres per hour (mm/hr) for the following standard
      durations and standard probabilities:</para>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t7">
          <caption>Very frequent design rainfall outputs</caption>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th><emphasis role="bold">Output</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Values</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Units</emphasis></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Standard durations</td>

              <td><para>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 10, 15, 30</para></td>

              <td><para>Minutes</para></td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td><para>1, 2, 3, 6, 12</para></td>

              <td>Hours</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td/>

              <td>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 7</td>

              <td>Days</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Standard probabilities</td>

              <td>12EY, 6EY, 4EY, 3EY, 2EY</td>

              <td>EY</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s6_0">
    <title>Rare Design Rainfalls</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s6_1">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>In the previous section, the method adopted for the estimation of
      very frequent design rainfalls for probabilities from 12EY to 2EY has
      been summarised. These very frequent design rainfalls, together with the
      frequent and infrequent design rainfalls discussed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch3_s4_0"/> provide design rainfall estimates for
      probabilities from 12EY to 1% AEP. However, there are some situations
      where design rainfalls less frequent than 1% AEP are required. Rare
      design rainfalls (for AEPs from 1 in 100 to 1 in 2000) are used by
      engineers; hydrologists; planners etc for a range of purposes
      including:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the design of dams that fall into the Significant and Low
          Flood Capacity Category where the Acceptable Flood Capacity is the
          0.1% or 1 in 1000 AEP design flood (ANCOLD, 2000).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the design of bridges, where the ultimate limit state adopted
          in the Australian bridge design code is defined as ‘the capability
          of a bridge to withstand, without collapse, the design flood
          associated with a 2000 year return interval’(AUSTROADS, 1992)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the incorporation of climate change into IFDs in accordance
          with the Interim Climate Change Guideline for Australian Rainfall
          and Runoff which recommends that if the design probability for a
          structure is 1% AEP, then the possible impacts of climate change
          should be assessed using 0.5% and 0.2% AEP (Bates et al,
          2015).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>the undertaking of spillway adequacy assessments of existing
          dams as the Dam Crest Flood (DCF) of many dams lies between the 1%
          AEP flood and the Probable Maximum Flood (as defined by the Probable
          Maximum Precipitation, PMP). Rare design rainfalls enable more
          accurate definition of the design rainfall and flood frequency
          curves between the 1% AEP and Probable Maximum Events.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Unlike the derivation of very frequent, frequent and infrequent
      design rainfalls which are based on observed rainfall events that lie
      within the range of probabilities being estimated, rare design rainfalls
      are an extrapolation beyond observed events. As can be seen from <xref
      linkend="b2_ch3_f2"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f6"/>, the longest
      period for which daily read rainfall records are available is around 170
      years however rare design rainfalls are required for probabilities much
      rarer than this As a consequence it is difficult to validate the
      resultant rare design rainfalls and therefore the method adopted needs
      to be based on a qualitative assessment that the assumptions made in the
      method are reasonable and that the adopted approach is consistent with
      methods used to derive more frequent design rainfalls where the results
      can be validated.</para>

      <para>The method adopted for deriving the rare design rainfalls was
      based on the data and method adopted for the more frequent design
      rainfalls but places more weight on the largest observed rainfall events
      which are of most relevance to rare design rainfalls. The adopted
      regional LH-moments approach is summarised in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch3_t8"/> and the following sections. More detail can be
      found in Green et al (2015) and Bureau of Meteorology (2015).</para>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t8">
          <caption>Summary of rare design rainfall method</caption>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <col width="50%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Step</th>

              <th>Method</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Number of rainfall stations</td>

              <td>Daily read – 3955</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Period of record</td>

              <td>All available records up to 2012</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Length of record used in analyses</td>

              <td>Daily read &gt;= 60 years</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Source of data</td>

              <td>Bureau of Meteorology</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Extreme value series</td>

              <td>Annual Maximum Series (AMS)</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Frequency analysis</td>

              <td>Generalised Extreme Value (GEV) distribution fitted using
              LH(2)-moments</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Regionalisation</td>

              <td>Region of influence</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Extension to ungauged locations</td>

              <td>Regression of LH-CV and LH-Skew against hydro-climatic
              predictors</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s6_2">
      <title>Rainfall Database</title>

      <para>The quality controlled rainfall database established for the
      derivation of the more frequent design rainfalls was used as the basis
      for the database used for the rare design rainfalls. However, as the
      estimation of rare design rainfalls relies on long term records, only
      those stations with more than 60 years of record were selected. This
      reduced to data set to approximately 4000 stations, the locations of
      which are shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f13"/>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f13">
        <title><emphasis role="bold">Location of Daily Read Rainfall Stations
        with 60 or More Years of Record</emphasis></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2044.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s6_3">
      <title>Extraction of extreme value series</title>

      <para>The AMS was extracted from all daily read rainfall stations with
      60 or more years of record. The AMS was used to define the extreme value
      series for the rare design rainfalls as the focus here is on the largest
      recorded events.</para>

      <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch3_s4_3"/>, the GEV
      distribution was adopted for AMS for the frequent and infrequent design
      rainfalls following extensive testing of a range of candidate
      distributions. On the basis of these trials and similar results found by
      Nandakumar et al (1997) and Schaefer (1990), the GEV distribution was
      adopted for the rare design rainfall analyses.</para>

      <para>In keeping with the approach adopted for the more frequent design
      rainfalls, the statistical properties of the at-site data were estimated
      and then translated into the relevant GEV distribution parameters.
      However, whereas L-moments were used for the more frequent design
      rainfalls, for the rare design rainfalls LH-moments were adopted (Wang,
      1997). LH-moments were adopted as they more accurately fit the upper
      tail (rarer probabilities) of the distribution.</para>

      <para>LH-moments are a generalisation of L-moments and allow the
      distribution to be increasingly focused on the larger data values
      depending on the value of <emphasis role="italic">ƞ, </emphasis>where
      <emphasis role="italic">ƞ</emphasis>=0 is <emphasis
      role="italic">e</emphasis>quivalent to L-moments. The equations for
      deriving LH-moments and the associated GEV parameters are given in Wang
      (1998). LH-moments with a <emphasis role="italic">ƞ</emphasis>=2 were
      selected as a compromise between providing a better fit to the tail of
      the at-site distribution without giving too much influence to the high
      outliers. LH-moments (<emphasis role="italic">ƞ</emphasis>=2) were
      derived for all stations with greater than 60 years AMS.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s6_4">
      <title>Regionalisation</title>

      <para>For the rare design rainfalls, the ROI approach adopted for the
      IFDs was used to reduce the uncertainty in the estimated LH-moments by
      regionalising the station point estimates. However, where for the IFDs
      500 station years was found to be an optimum pool size, as the rare
      design rainfalls are provided for probabilities out to 1 in 2000 AEP,
      the ROI needed to be increased. The tradeoff between gaining improved
      accuracy from a larger pool of data was that the assumption of
      homogeneity may not be satisfied. Based on testing for the pool size
      that reduced uncertainty without introducing significant homogeneity, a
      minimum of 2000 station years was adopted. However, where necessary, the
      number of pooled station years was increased above this number to
      maximize the available record used, while ensuring homogeneity.</para>

      <para>The average LH-CV for each region was calculated using a weighted
      average of the LH-CV at all stations in the region, with the weights
      proportional to the station lengths. This was repeated for the
      LH-Skewness.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s6_5">
      <title>Regression</title>

      <para>In light of the rarer probabilities being estimated; the smaller
      number of rainfalls stations being used; and the resultant decrease in
      station density, a regression based approached was adopted for deriving
      GEV parameters at ungauged locations, rather than the gridding
      undertaken for the very frequent, frequent and infrequent design
      rainfalls.</para>

      <para>The regression was based on the BGLSR approach used with the
      frequent and infrequent design rainfalls to derive sub-daily rainfall
      statistics from daily rainfall statistics. However, for the rare design
      rainfalls the BGLSR was used to define the relationship between
      regionalised LH-CV and LH-skew and hydro-climatic predictors. To provide
      spatial continuity, regression relationships were defined using a ROI
      approach such that each station had its own ROI. Regression coefficients
      were interpolated for predictands at ungauged sites to provide values
      for each 2.5km grid point.</para>

      <para>Quantiles were estimated for each grid using the GEV parameters.
      These were then scaled to ensure consistency between the infrequent and
      the rare design rainfalls. The depths were smoothed across durations and
      AEPs to ensure consistency.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s6_6">
      <title>Outputs</title>

      <para>The method described above produced rare design rainfall estimates
      across Australia for the following standard durations and standard
      probabilities:</para>

      <para><table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch3_t9">
          <caption>Rare design rainfall outputs</caption>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <col width="33%"/>

          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th><emphasis role="bold">Output</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Values</emphasis></th>

              <th><emphasis role="bold">Units</emphasis></th>
            </tr>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Standard durations</td>

              <td>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 7</td>

              <td>Days</td>
            </tr>

            <tr>
              <td>Standard probabilities</td>

              <td><para>1 in 100; 1 in 200; 1 in 500; 1 in 1000; 1 in
              2000</para></td>

              <td>AEP</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s7_0">
    <title>Probable Maximum Precipitation Estimates</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s7_1">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>The very frequent, frequent and infrequent design rainfalls
      described in the previous sections were derived using frequency
      analysis. However, extreme rainfalls events such as the Probable Maximum
      Precipitation (PMP), lie beyond both any directly observed events and
      the limit to which observed data can be extrapolated. As a result,
      estimation of extreme rainfall events is based on the broadest
      understanding of extreme events and the meteorological processes that
      produce them.</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_vsqz4">
        <title>Definition</title>

        <para>The Probable Maximum Precipitation (PMP) is defined as ‘the
        theoretical greatest depth of precipitation that is physically
        possible over a particular catchment’ (World Meteorological
        Organisation, 1986). The PMP assumes the simultaneous occurrence in
        one storm of maximum amount of moisture and the maximum conversion
        rate of moisture to precipitation (maximum efficiency).</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s7_2">
      <title>Estimation of PMPs</title>

      <para>the BoM has been providing PMP estimates for over 70 years,
      however, the methods adopted have changed with time, as the
      understanding of extreme storms and the mechanisms which produce them
      have developed, and the data bases of observed extreme storms have
      expanded. These methods include:</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_sr0qg">
        <title><emphasis role="italic">In Situ</emphasis> Maximisation
        Method</title>

        <para>During the 1950’s to 1970’s PMP estimates were based on the
        maximisation of the moisture content of storms which had been observed
        over the catchment of interest. The limitation of this method was that
        the differing lengths of rainfall records and occurrence or
        non-occurrence of an extreme storm led to inconsistent PMP estimates
        for catchments within the same region.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_mgbab">
        <title>Storm Transposition Method</title>

        <para>During the late 1960’s and early 1970’s the size of the extreme
        storm sample for a specific catchment was increased by the
        transposition to the catchment of interest of extreme storms which had
        been observed over nearby catchments which had similar
        hydrometeorological and topographic features. Although this improved
        the within-region consistency of PMP estimates, the method was
        limited, as only storms from a similar topographic region could be
        transposed, and the selection of storms introduced a significant level
        of subjectivity.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_eywdg">
        <title>Generalised Methods</title>

        <para>From the mid-1970’s generalised methods were introduced into
        Australia. Generalised methods make use of all available storm data
        for a large region by making adjustments for moisture availability and
        differing topographic effects. The generalised methods currently
        adopted in Australia are described below.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s7_3">
      <title>Generalised Methods for PMP estimation</title>

      <para>There are three main generalised methods used for PMP estimation
      in Australia. These methods and their area of applicability are shown in
      <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f14"/> and described below:</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_jl11a">
        <title>Generalised Short-Duration Method (GSDM)</title>

        <para>The Generalised Short-Duration Method (GSDM) is applicable
        across Australia for catchment areas less than 1000 km2 and for
        durations up to three hours or six hours depending on the part of
        Australia (Bureau of Meteorology, 2003).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_2k6wm">
        <title>Generalised Southeast Australia Method (GSAM)</title>

        <para>The Generalised Southeast Australia Method is applicable to the
        southern third of Australia where it is assumed that the causative
        mechanism of the PMP would not be tropical. The GSAM method is
        applicable for durations from 12 hours to 120 hours. (Bureau of
        Meteorology, 2006; Minty et al, 1996).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_njktq">
        <title>Revised General Tropical Storm Method (GTSMR)</title>

        <para>The Revised Generalised Tropical Storm Method (GTSMR) is
        applicable to the northern two-thirds of Australia where it is assumed
        that the causative mechanism of the PMP would be a tropical storm. The
        GTSMR method is applicable for durations from 12 hours to 120 hours.
        (Bureau of Meteorology, 2005; Walland et al, 2003).</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f14">
          <title>Generalised PMP Method Zones</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2045.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>There are two other generalised methods:</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_hr3z0">
        <title>West Coast Tasmania Method Zone</title>

        <para>The West Coast Tasmania Method Zone method applies to the west
        coast region of Tasmania which is outside the region of applicability
        of the Tasmanian GSAM coastal zone. It is applicable for durations
        between 24 and 72 hours (Xuereb et al, 2001).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_sdfvm">
        <title>GSAM-GTSMR Coastal Transition Zone</title>

        <para>The GSAM-GTSMR Coastal Transition Zone method to the coastal
        area In NSW where is it considered that PMPs could be caused by either
        tropical or non-tropical storms.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s7_4">
      <title>Generalised Method of PMP estimation</title>

      <para>Although each of the three generalised methods has specific
      features, the generalised method approach can be summarised as
      follows:</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_r6zes">
        <title>Development of storm data base</title>

        <para>The ten highest one to seven day rainfalls which were common to
        a number of stations were selected and the storms prioritised
        according to the rarity of the event in order to identify the 100 or
        more largest storms. For each storm the following analyses were
        undertaken.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>To determine the spatial distribution of each storm, the
            rainfall totals for the total storm duration were plotted on a
            topographic map and isohyets drawn to determine the spatial extent
            and distribution of each storm.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>To determine the storm temporal distribution, parallelograms
            were drawn around the storm centre for standard areas of 100; 500;
            1 000; 2 500; 10 000; 40 000 and 60 000 km^2. The average daily
            rainfall depths within a parallelogram were determined using
            Thiessen weights. For each standard area, the percentage of the
            total storm that fell during each 24-hour period was determined.
            These daily data were supplemented by pluviograph and 3-hourly
            synoptic charts.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The representative dewpoint temperature for each storm was
            determined using a number of sources including the Australian
            Region Mean Sea Level charts; National Climate Centre Archives;
            and Observers’ Logbooks.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_xn74t">
        <title>Generalisation of storm database</title>

        <para>The ‘site specific’ attributes of each storm were removed in
        order to attain a homogenous data set.</para>

        <para>The effects of storm type were removed from the data set by the
        dividing of Australia into the GSAM and GTSMR regions on the basis of
        the type of that produces the largest observed rainfall depths. The
        two regions were further divided into Coastal and Inland Zones on the
        basis that different mechanisms produce the largest rainfall depths in
        each of the zones (refer <xref linkend="b2_ch3_f14"/>).</para>

        <para>The specification of each storm in terms of depth-area-duration
        curves as done previously effectively removed the storm specific
        spatial distribution.</para>

        <para>The removal of the site specific topographic effects was
        undertaken using 72-hour, 50-year ‘flat land’ rainfall intensity field
        in order to produce the convergence component of each storm.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_8uaqe">
        <title>Removal of the site-specific and storm-specific moisture
        content</title>

        <para>To remove the storm-specific moisture content from each storm
        and simultaneously to maximise the moisture content, the convergence
        depths were multiplied by a moisture maximisation factor. The moisture
        maximisation factor is defined as the ratio of extreme precipitable
        water associated with the extreme dewpoint temperature at the storm
        location.</para>

        <para>The site-specific moisture content of each storm was removed by
        transposition to a single location which for the GSAM was chosen as
        Brisbane and for GTSMR as Broome. For each location, representative
        seasonal extreme 24-hour persisting dewpoint temperatures were
        selected and the moisture content for each storm standardised.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_gknqj">
        <title>Determination of ‘Storm’ of Maximum Moisture Content</title>

        <para>The moisture maximisation factor and the standardised
        convergence depths were combined to estimate the maximised
        standardised convergence depths. To determine a single hypothetical
        storm of maximum moisture content, an envelope curve was drawn to the
        set of maximised, standardised convergence depth-area curves.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_xp9qt">
        <title>Determination of Catchment Specific PMP</title>

        <para>The envelope curves represent the maximised convergence
        component of the PMP at the standardising locations (Brisbane for the
        GSAM and Broome for GTSMR). To obtain an estimate of the PMP for a
        specific catchment it is necessary to build in the moisture content
        and topographic influences specific to the catchment of interest. The
        moisture content of the standard PMP convergence depth is adjustment
        using a moisture adjustment factor such that:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e10">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>MAF=EPW</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>catchment</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>/EPW</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>std</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>

        <para>where MAF = moisture adjustment factor; <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="inline">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtext>EPW</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtext>catchment</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the extreme precipitable water associated with
        the catchment extreme dewpoint temperature; <inlineequation>
            <m:math display="block">
              <m:semantics>
                <m:mrow>
                  <m:msub>
                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtext>EPW</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>

                    <m:mrow>
                      <m:mtext>std</m:mtext>
                    </m:mrow>
                  </m:msub>
                </m:mrow>
              </m:semantics>
            </m:math>
          </inlineequation> is the extreme precipitable water associated with
        the standard extreme dewpoint temperature for appropriate
        season</para>

        <para>The topographic enhancement factor (TEF) for the catchment PMP
        is estimated in the same manner as the topographic component of the
        storms in the database using the 72-hour 50 year rainfall
        intensities.</para>

        <para>The total PMP for a specific catchment for each of the standard
        durations is estimated as:</para>

        <equation xml:id="b2_ch3_e11">
          <m:math display="block">
            <m:semantics>
              <m:mrow>
                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>PMP</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>catchment</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>=MCD</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>std</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>*MAF</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>catchment</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>

                <m:msub>
                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>*TEF</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>

                  <m:mrow>
                    <m:mtext>catchment</m:mtext>
                  </m:mrow>
                </m:msub>
              </m:mrow>
            </m:semantics>
          </m:math>
        </equation>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s8_0">
    <title>Uncertainty in Design Rainfalls</title>

    <para>The design rainfalls described in this Chapter are the best
    estimates currently available and have been derived using an extensive
    rainfall database which has been analysed using the most appropriate
    techniques.</para>

    <para>However, there are uncertainties associated with the design
    rainfalls which arise from various sources including:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>errors in the data due to short record length; instrumentation
        errors; gaps in the data; unidentified errors in the data</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>sampling errors including network sparsity; poorly placed
        gauges; non-representativeness of gauging networks</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>limitations in the adopted methods including delineation of
        regions; lack of homogeneity in regions; selection of distribution;
        parameter and quantile estimation; and extrapolation of data to
        ungauged locations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>These uncertainties need to be taken into consideration when the
    design rainfalls are being used in conjunction with other design flood
    inputs. Quantification of the uncertainties associated with the design
    rainfalls is described in Bureau of Meteorology (2016) as well as advice
    on how to incorporate uncertainty when using the design rainfalls.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s9_0">
    <title>Application</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s9_1">
      <title>Design rainfalls</title>

      <para>The very frequent, frequent, infrequent and rare design rainfalls
      are available via the BoM’s website<footnote>
          <para><link
          xlink:href="http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/ifd/index.shtml">http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/ifd/index.shtml</link></para>
        </footnote> and can be estimated using the steps outlined
      below.</para>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_e7gwf">
        <title>Input data requirements and options</title>

        <para>To estimate a design rainfall for a point location it is
        necessary to enter the co-ordinate of the location in one of three
        co-ordinate format options:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Decimal degrees</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Degrees, Minutes, Seconds</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Easting, Northing, Zone</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The location of the entered co-ordinate can be seen by using the
        map preview option and a location label can also be entered (see <xref
        linkend="b2_ch3_15"/>).</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_15">
          <title><emphasis role="bold">Design Rainfall Point Location Map
          Preview</emphasis></title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2046.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>Determine the design rainfall class for which design rainfalls
        are required:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Very frequent</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Frequent and infrequent (IFDs)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Rare</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Determine the durations for which design rainfalls are
        required:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Standard</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Non-standard</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Determine the units in which the design rainfalls will be
        provided:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Depths as millimetres (mm)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Intensities as millimetres per hour (mm/hr)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s9_2">
      <title>Frequent and Infrequent Design Rainfalls (IFDs)</title>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f16">
        <title>IFD Outputs</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2047.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s9_3">
      <title>Very frequent design rainfalls</title>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f17">
        <title>Very frequent design rainfall outputs</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2048.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s9_4">
      <title>Rare design rainfalls</title>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f18">
        <title>Rare design rainfall outputs</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2049.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_awaua">
        <title>Output options</title>

        <para>The design rainfall information for the selected location can be
        seen in either tabular form (<xref linkend="b2_ch3_f19"/>) or
        graphical form (<xref linkend="b2_ch3_f20"/>).</para>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f19">
          <title><emphasis role="bold">Design rainfall output shown as
          table</emphasis></title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2050.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <figure xml:id="b2_ch3_f20">
          <title><emphasis role="bold">Design rainfall output shown as
          chart</emphasis></title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2051.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s_uj2rm">
        <title>Export options</title>

        <para>The table can be exported as a .csv file for ease of
        incorporation into software and the chart as a .png to facilitate
        integration into reports.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s9_5">
      <title>Probable Maximum Precipitation estimates</title>

      <para>Probable Maximum Precipitation estimates for the GSDM can be
      estimated using the method contained in Bureau of Meteorology (2003)
      which can be downloaded from the BoM’s website.</para>

      <para>Guides for the application of the GSAM and GTSMR methods are
      available from the BoM (Bureau of Meteorology, 2005; Bureau of
      Meteorology, 2006).</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch3_s10_0">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>ANCOLD (2000), Guidelines on Selection of Acceptable Flood Capacity
    for Dams. Australian National Committee on Large Dams, 2000.</para>

    <para>AUSTROADS (1992) AUSTROADS. ’92 AUSTROADS Bridge Design Code.</para>

    <para>Bates,B.C., McLuckie, D., Westra, S., Johnson, F., Green, J.,
    Mummery, J. and Abbs, D. (2015). Revision of Australian Rainfall and
    Runoff – The Interim Climate Change Guideline. Presented at National
    Floodplain Management Authorities Conference, Brisbane, Qld, May
    2015.</para>

    <para>Bell, F.C., (1976), <emphasis role="italic">The areal reduction
    factors in rainfall frequency estimation</emphasis>. Natural Environmental
    Research Council (NERC), Report No. 35, Institute of Hydrology,
    Wallingford, U.K.</para>

    <para>Bonnin, G., Maitaria, K. &amp; Yekta, M. (2010) Trends in Heavy
    Rainfalls in the Observed Record in Selected Areas of the U.S. IN PALMER,
    R. N. (Ed.) <emphasis role="italic">World Environmental and Water
    Resources Congress 2010: Challenges of Change.</emphasis> Providence,
    Rhode Island, American Society of Civil Engineers.</para>

    <para>Bureau of Meteorology (2003) <emphasis role="italic">The Estimation
    of Probable Maximum Precipitation in Australia: Generalised Short-Duration
    Method</emphasis>, [Online] Bureau of Meteorology, Melbourne, Australia,
    June 2003, (39pp). Available at: <link
    xlink:href="http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/pmp/gsdm_document.shtml">http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/pmp/gsdm_document.shtml</link></para>

    <para>Bureau of Meteorology. (2005) <emphasis role="italic">Guidebook of
    the Estimation of Probable Maximum Precipitation: Generalised Tropical
    Storm Method</emphasis>, Included on compact disc 'Guide to the Estimation
    of Probable Maximum Precipitation: Generalised Tropical Storm Method',
    Hydrometeorological Advisory Service, Bureau of Meteorology, September
    2005</para>

    <para>Bureau of Meteorology. (2006) <emphasis role="italic">Guidebook of
    the Estimation of Probable Maximum Precipitation: Generalised Southeast
    Australia Method</emphasis>, included on the compact disc 'Guide to the
    Estimation of Probable Maximum Precipitation: Generalised Southeast
    Australia Method', Hydrometeorological Advisory Service, Bureau of
    Meteorology, October 2006</para>

    <para>Bureau of Meteorology. (2016) <emphasis role="italic">Design
    rainfalls for Australia: data, methods and analyses.</emphasis> Bureau of
    Meteorology, Melbourne VIC, 2016</para>

    <para>Burn, D. H. (1990), <emphasis role="italic">An appraisal of the
    "region of influence" approach to flood frequency analysis,</emphasis>
    Hydrological Sciences - Journal-des Sciences Hydrologiques 35(2):
    149-165.</para>

    <para>Green, J. and Johnson, F.J., (2011). Stationarity Assessment of
    Australian Rainfall. Internal Bureau of Meteorology Report. 2011</para>

    <para>Green, J.H., Xuereb, X. and Siriwardena, L. (2011). "Establishment
    of a Quality Controlled Rainfall Database for the Revision of the
    Intensity-Frequency Duration (IFD) Estimates for Australia”. Presented at
    34th IAHR Congress, Brisbane, Qld, June 2011.</para>

    <para>Green, J.H., Johnson, J., McKay, D., Podger, P., Sugiyanto, M., and
    Siriwardena, L. (2012a). Quality Controlling Daily Read Rainfall Data for
    the Intensity-Frequency Duration (IFD) Revision Rainfall Project.
    Presented at Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Sydney, NSW,
    November 2012.</para>

    <para>Green, J.H., Xuereb, K. Johnson, J., Moore, G. and The, C. (2012b).
    The Revised Intensity-Frequency Duration (IFD) Design Rainfall Estimates
    for Australia – An Overview. Presented at Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium, Sydney, NSW, November 2012.</para>

    <para>Green, J.H., Beesley, C., Frost, A., Podger, S. and The, C. (2015)
    National Estimates of Rare Design Rainfall. Presented at Hydrology and
    Water Resources Symposium, Hobart, Tas, December 2015.</para>

    <para>Guttman, N. B., Hosking, J. R. M. and Wallis, J. R. (1993),
    <emphasis role="italic">Regional precipitation quantile values for the
    continental U. S. computed from L-moments</emphasis>. Journal of Climate,
    6, 2326-2340.</para>

    <para>Haddad, K., Rahman, A. and Green, J. (2011), <emphasis
    role="italic">Design Rainfall Estimation in Australia: A Case Study using
    L moments and Generalized Least Squares Regression,</emphasis> Stochastic
    Environmental Research &amp; Risk Assessment, 25, 6, 815-825.</para>

    <para>Haddad, K. and Rahman, A. (2012a), <emphasis role="italic">Regional
    flood frequency analysis in eastern Australia: Bayesian GLS
    regression-based methods within fixed region and ROI framework: quantile
    regression vs parameter regression technique.</emphasis> Journal of
    Hydrology, Volume 430, 2012, Pages 142-161.</para>

    <para>Haddad, K. and Rahman, A. (2012b), <emphasis role="italic">A Pilot
    Study on Design Rainfall Estimation in Australia using L-moments and
    Bayesian Generalised Least Squares Regression: Comparison of Fixed Region,
    Facets and Region of Influence Approach,</emphasis> EnviroWater
    Sydney.</para>

    <para>Haddad, K., Johnson, F., Rahman, A., Green, J., and Kuczera, G.
    (2015), <emphasis role="italic">Comparing three methods to form regions
    for design rainfall statistics: Two case studies in Australia.</emphasis>
    Journal of Hydrology, Volume 527, August 2015, Pages 62-76</para>

    <para>Hosking, J.R.M. and Wallis, J.R., (1997). Regional Frequency
    Analysis: An Approach Based on L-Moments. CambridgeUniversity Press,
    Cambridge, UK. 224 pp.</para>

    <para>Huff, F. A., and Angel, J. R. (1992), <emphasis
    role="italic">Rainfall Frequency Atlas of the Midwest. Illinois State
    Water Survey</emphasis>, Champaign, Bulletin 71, 1992.</para>

    <para>Hutchinson, M.F. (1998), <emphasis role="italic">Interpolation of
    rainfall data with thin plate smoothing splines – part 2: Analysis of
    topographic dependence</emphasis>, Journal of Geographic Information and
    Decision Analysis 2(2): 152-167.</para>

    <para>Hutchinson, M. F. (2007), ANUSPLIN version 4.37 User Guide, The
    Australian National University, Centre for Resources and Environmental
    Studies, Canberra</para>

    <para>Hutchinson, M.F and Xu, T (2013), <emphasis role="italic">ANUSPLIN
    Version 4.4 User Guide</emphasis>, The AustralianNationalUniversity.
    FennerSchool of Environment and Society, Canberra, Australia</para>

    <para>Johnson, F., Xuereb, K., Jeremiah, E., and Green, J. (2012a).
    Regionalisation of Rainfall Statistics for the IFD Revision Project.
    Presented at Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Sydney, NSW,
    November 2012.</para>

    <para>Johnson, F., Haddad, K., Rahman, A., and Green, J. (2012b).
    Application of Bayesian GLSR to Estimate Sub Daily Rainfall Parameters for
    the IFD Revision Project. Presented at Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium, Sydney, NSW, November 2012.</para>

    <para>Johnson, F., Hutchinson, M.F.; The, C.; Beesley, C., and Green, J.
    (2015). Topographic relationships for design rainfalls over Australia.
    Accepted for publication Journal of Hydrology.</para>

    <para>Kjeldsen, T. R. and Jones, D. A. (2009), <emphasis role="italic">A
    formal statistical model for pooled analysis of extreme floods,
    </emphasis>Hydrology Research 40(5): 465-480.</para>

    <para>Madsen, H., Mikkelsen, P.S., Rosbjerg, D. and Harremoes, P. (2002),
    Regional estimation of rainfall intensity duration curves using
    generalised least squares regression of partial duration series
    statistics. Water Resources Research, 38 (11), 1239</para>

    <para>Madsen, H., Arnbjerg-Neilsen, K. and Mikkelsen, P.S. (2009), Update
    of regional intensity-duration-frequency curves in Denmark: Tendency
    towards increased storm intensities. Atmospheric Research, 92,
    343-349</para>

    <para>Menabde, M, A Seed, G Pegram. (1999). <emphasis role="italic">A
    simple scaling model for extreme rainfall</emphasis>. Water Resources
    Research, 35, pages 335 – 339.</para>

    <para>Minty, L.J., Meighen, J. and M.R. Kennedy (1996) <emphasis
    role="italic">Development of the Generalised Southeast Australia Method
    for Estimating Probable Maximum Precipitation</emphasis>, [Online] HRS
    Report No. 4, Hydrology Report Series, Bureau of Meteorology, Melbourne,
    Australia, August 1996, (48pp). Available at: <link
    xlink:href="http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/pmp/gsam.shtml">http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/pmp/gsam.shtml</link></para>

    <para>Nandakumar, N., Weinmann, P. E., Mein, R. G., Nathan, R. J. (1997),
    Estimation of Extreme Rainfalls for Victoria using the CRCFORGE Method,
    CRC for Catchment Hydrology.</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, DH (ed) (1987) Australian Rainfall and Runoff – A Guide to
    Flood Estimation, Institution of Engineers, Australia, Barton, ACT,
    1987.</para>

    <para>Reis Jr., D.S., Stedinger, J.R. and Martins, E.S. (2005), Bayesian
    GLS regression with application to LP3 regional skew estimation. Water
    Resour Res. 41, W10419, (1) 1029.</para>

    <para>Schaefer, M.G. (1990), <emphasis role="italic">Regional analysis of
    precipitation annual maxima in Washington State</emphasis>, Water Resoures
    Research., 26(1), pp119-131.</para>

    <para>The, C., Johnson, F., Hutchinson, M., and Green, J. (2012). Gridding
    of Design Rainfall Parameters for the IFD Revision Project for Australia.
    Presented at Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Sydney, NSW,
    November 2012.</para>

    <para>The, C., Hutchinson, M., Johnson, F., Beesley, C. and Green, J.
    (2014). Application of ANUSPLIN to produce new
    Intensity-Frequency-Duration (IFD) design rainfalls across Australia.
    Presentated at Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium, Perth, WA,
    February 2014.</para>

    <para>The, C., Beesley, C., Podger, S., Green, J., Hutchinson, M. and
    Jolly, C.(2015). Very frequent design rainfalls – an enhancement to the
    new IFDs. Accepted for presentation at Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium, Hobart, TAS, December 2015.</para>

    <para>Walland DJ, Meighen J, Xuereb KC, Beesley CA and Hoang TMT, 2003,
    <emphasis role="italic">Revision of the Generalised Tropical Storm Method
    for Estimating Probable Maximum Precipitation </emphasis>[Online], HRS
    Report No. 8, Hydrology Report Series, Bureau of Meteorology Melbourne,
    Australia, available at: <link
    xlink:href="http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/hrs8.shtml">http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/hrs8.shtml</link></para>

    <para>Wang, QJ. (1997) <emphasis role="italic">LH moments for statistical
    analysis of extreme events</emphasis>. Water Resources Research, 33(12)
    2841-2848.</para>

    <para>Wang, QJ. (1998) <emphasis role="italic">Approximate goodness-of-fit
    tests of fitted generalised extreme value distributions using LH
    moments.</emphasis> Water Resources Research, 34(12) 3497-3502.</para>

    <para>World Meteorological Organisation (1986). ‘Manual for Estimation of
    Probable Maximum Precipitation’. Second Edition. Operational Hydrology
    Report No. 1, WMO - No. 332, Geneva.</para>

    <para>Xuereb, K.C., Moore, G.J., and Taylor, B.F. (2001) <emphasis
    role="italic">Development of the Method of Storm Transposition and
    Maximisation for the West Coast of Tasmania.</emphasis> HRS Report No. 7,
    Hydrology Report Series, Bureau of Meteorology, Melbourne, Australia,
    January 2001.</para>

    <para>Xuereb, K. and Green, J. (2012). <emphasis role="italic">Defining
    Independence of Rainfall Events with a Partial Duration Series
    Approach</emphasis>. Presented at Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium,
    Sydney, NSW, November 2012.</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold">Acknowledgements:</emphasis></para>

    <para>The authors would like to acknowledge the contributions made by the
    following people during the IFD Revision Project:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Dr Louise Minty and Dr Ian Prosser for their direction of the
        project</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Andrew Frost, Khaled Haddad, Catherine Jolly, Garry Moore, Scott
        Podger, Ataur Rahman, Lionel Siriwardena and Karin Xuereb for their
        contribution during various stages of the project</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Professor Mike Hutchinson for his ongoing advice on the
        application of ANUSPLIN</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Erwin Jeremiah, Deacon McKay, Scott Podger and Michael Sugiyanto
        for their cheerful quality controlling of the data</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Dr George Kuczera, Dr Nanda Nandakumar; Dr Rory Nathan and Erwin
        Weinmann for their sage advice on the rare design rainfalls</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Damian Chong, Ceredwyn Ealanta Murray Henderson, Chris Lee,
        Quentin Leseney, Maria Levtova, Max Monahon, Julian Noye, and William
        Tall for the webpages.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
