<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b1_ch6" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Climate Change Considerations</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/wasko_conrad.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/westra_seth.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/jakob_dorte.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nielsen_chris.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/evans_jason.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/rodgers_simon.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ho_michelle.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/dowdy_andrew.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/sharples_wendy.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td>Chapter Status</td>
      <td>Final</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>27/08/2024</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_s1">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Key messages</emphasis></para>
          <para>Because our climate is changing, unadjusted historical observations are no longer a
            suitable basis for design flood estimation: they must be adjusted to reflect the impacts
            of rising global temperatures. This chapter provides guidance on how to do this. It is
            based on a systematic review and meta-analysis of recent peer-reviewed science. </para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
    <para>There is unequivocal evidence that greenhouse gas emissions have caused global warming.
      The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change’s sixth assessment report concluded that global
      surface temperatures have significantly increased above pre-industrial levels, with
      significant further warming expected <citation>b1_c6_r16</citation>. This warming is causing
      an increase in many drivers of flood risk, including an intensification of extreme rainfall
      events and the elevation of average and extreme sea levels
      <citation>b1_c6_r16</citation>.</para>
    <para>Traditionally, design flood estimation has assumed that historical observations are
      representative of current and future conditions. This is no longer the case. Records on
      historical flooding or flood drivers (such as extreme rainfall or sea level) can no longer be
      assumed to provide a direct analogue of current or future flood risk. To account for
      significant observed and projected changes to the drivers of flooding, it is necessary to
      account for the non-stationarity of flooding in the assessment of current and future flood
      risks. </para>
    <para>This chapter provides practitioners, designers, and decision makers with guidance on how
      to assess the impact of climate change on design flood characteristics. As with the rest
        of<emphasis> Australian Rainfall and Runoff </emphasis> (ARR) the content is advisory, so
      additional guidance or requirements may need to be sought from relevant government regulation
      in the jurisdiction of interest. </para>
    <para>This chapter replaces the 2019 Climate Change Considerations chapter
        <citation>b1_c6_r23</citation> in Book 1, Chapter 6 of ARR Version 4.1. This chapter
      provides guidance that reflects the contemporary science, is applicable across the range of
      design flood approaches, and facilitates consistent application of climate change in design
      flood estimation. This guidance is based on an extensive and rigorous systematic review and
      meta-analysis of over 300 distinct peer-reviewed scientific studies published largely from
      2011 onwards. For further information on the scientific basis for this guidance, readers are
      referred to <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation>. </para>
    <para>Key differences from the 2019 Climate Change Considerations chapter (Version 4.1) include: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>recognition that global temperatures have increased over the historical period used
            to derive design rainfall information </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a recommendation to adjust 2016 Intensity-Frequency-Duration (IFD) curves to present
            (i.e. current climate) conditions </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>provision of information to support a range of approaches to decision-making</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>provision of guidance across the range of Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP)
            considered in ARR up to and including the Probable Maximum Precipitation (PMP) </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>provision of uncertainty estimates</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>consideration of additional factors that influence design flood estimates; that is,
            changes in rainfall losses, temporal patterns, and sea level rise.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>This chapter is structured as follows: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s2"/> discusses the 2 primary types of uncertainty
            exacerbated by climate change that are relevant to flood design.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s3"/> covers how climate change affects design flood
            estimation methods more broadly.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s4"/> describes how to account for climate change in the key
            aspects of event-based design flood estimation, with the recommendations linked to the
            worked examples in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s6"/>. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s5"/> recommends an approach for future updates to the
            climate change considerations chapter.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s6"/> provides worked examples of the guidance presented in
              <xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s4"/>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_s2">
    <title>Decison Contexts for Flood Guidance</title>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Key messages</emphasis></para>
          <para>Climate variability heavily influences the risks of flooding from one time period to
            the next (‘aleatory uncertainty’) and these risks will shift under climate change. There
            is considerable uncertainty associated with future global emissions and the physical
            effects of these emissions on flood drivers increases the uncertainty of design flood
            estimates (‘epistemic uncertainty’). A user needs to choose their approach to design
            flood estimation in the context of these two sources of uncertainty. </para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
    <para>ARR provides guidance to support the estimation of design floods that inform either
      standards-based design criteria (such as designing to the 1% AEP standard) or risk-based
      approaches that seek to understand flood behaviour across a range of flood magnitudes up to
      and including the Probable Maximum Flood (PMF) (see <xref linkend="b1_ch5"/> for more detail).
      Guidance in ARR is largely focused on dealing with the inherent randomness of factors (the
      aleatory uncertainties) that influence the exceedance probability of a given event (<xref
        linkend="b4_ch3"/>). In rainfall-based estimates this most often involves consideration of
      Intensity-Frequency-Duration (IFD) rainfall bursts (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>), variability in
      rainfall temporal patterns (<xref linkend="b2_ch5"/>), and the influence of antecedent and
      event losses (<xref linkend="b5_ch5"/>). In techniques based on the direct analysis of flood
      data (<xref linkend="book3"/>), the aleatory uncertainty of these factors is implicitly
      accounted for in the sampling variability represented in the available flood observations.
      Climate change is now impacting the frequency and behaviour of many of the factors that
      influence flood behaviour resulting in non-stationarity in design flood estimates, shifting
      estimates of the aleatory uncertainty (<xref linkend="b1_ch6_f_f1"/>). </para>
    <para>While much of the emphasis of climate science is to understand the likely historical and
      future changes to key flood risk drivers, another important consequence of climate change is
      an increase in the epistemic uncertainty of design flood estimates (<xref linkend="b1_ch6_f_f1"/>). This additional uncertainty arises from limitations in data and
      knowledge, where in the context of climate change this includes the uncertainty associated
      with future global emissions and mitigation strategies, resultant uncertainty in future global
      and regional temperature changes, and uncertainties on the implication of changing
      temperatures and associated processes on flood risk drivers. Within risk-based decision-making
      frameworks (where risk is commonly defined as ‘the effect of uncertainty on objectives’, ISO
      31000), considerations of the projected changes in flood risk drivers as well as the
      increasing level of uncertainty associated with those drivers are both relevant in assessment
      of overall risk. </para>
    <figure xml:id="b1_ch6_f_f1">
      <title>Climate change is shifting our best estimate of the relationship between event
        magnitude and frequency and increasing the inherent uncertainty in such estimates</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/b1_c6_f1.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>In addition to standards-based and risk-based decision-making approaches, there has
      recently been interest in decision-making frameworks that are less reliant on annualised
      probability-based estimates of flood magnitude. Examples include robust design approaches that
      can adapt to changes in design flood estimates over time (adaptive management), sensitivity
      and stress-testing approaches that explore the effect of alternative assumptions on
      decision-making (‘bottom-up’ and ‘decision-scaling’ approaches), and ‘storyline’ methods that
      often draw on historical flood events, but which are modified to account for potential impacts
      of climate change. </para>
    <para>This chapter provides guidance for future changes to design floods recognising the
      requirements of current design procedures (and the need to capture the shifts in the
      magnitude-frequency relationships relevant to both standards-based and risk-based
      decision-making approaches), while also providing information to assist in estimating the
      uncertainty associated with those best estimates. This allows for consistency in the guidance
      here and the above decision-making frameworks. For example, a standards-based approach may
      adopt the median values presented in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s4"/> and incorporate the
      uncertainty in a Monte Carlo framework. A bottom-up approach may use the uncertainty as a
      guide for sensitivity testing to develop system response surfaces for the hazard of interest.
      A risk-based approach may consider the probabilities and consequences of flooding across a
      range of exceedance probabilities, accounting for both aleatory and epistemic uncertainties. </para>
    <para>The reader is referred to <xref linkend="b1_ch5"/> for further information on risk-based
      decision making, with <xref linkend="b1_ch5_s_6kvuz"/> detailing a possible process of
      undertaking a non-stationary risk assessment. Further information on approaches for
      representing epistemic uncertainty as part of the design flood estimation process are
      presented in <xref linkend="b7_ch8"/>, with the different approaches to address aleatory
      uncertainty described in <xref linkend="b1_ch3"/>. </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_s3">
    <title>Selection of a Design Flood Estimation Method Under Climate Change</title>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Key messages</emphasis></para>
          <para>There are two broad classes of design flood estimation methods: direct flood-based
            procedures and rainfall-based procedures. Rainfall-based procedures can be further
            divided into continuous and event-based approaches. The impacts of climate change are
            most readily incorporated into event-based methods, and hence this guidance focusses on
            generic advice that is relevant to these methods. Direct flood-based procedures (e.g.
            flood frequency) and continuous simulation approaches remain important tools for the
            assessment of flood risk, though there is no clear consensus on how such methods should
            be adjusted to account for climate change. </para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
    <para>Although frequency analysis will continue to be used for design flood estimation and the
      calibration of models to historic data, climate change influences a range of flood drivers
      which impact on flood magnitude in a highly non-linear fashion. It is thus difficult to
      directly adjust flood information without reference to the causal processes by which climate
      change influences flood magnitude <citation>b1_c6_r22</citation>. This means that
      extrapolating historical trends into the future or scaling historical flood magnitudes by a
      fixed amount may not adequately capture how changes in the causal drivers propagate through a
      catchment to influence changes in flood behaviour. Accordingly, it is recommended that any
      adjustment of historical flood frequency estimates to account for climate change be undertaken
      in a manner that it is consistent with the impact of changes in the flood drivers (e.g.
      extreme rainfall, antecedent conditions, sea level, etc) as described in this chapter. </para>
    <para>In contrast to flood-based procedures, rainfall-based procedures provide a mechanism to
      relate information on climate projections to design flood estimates using either event-based
      or continuous simulation approaches. For continuous simulation to be suitable for flood
      estimation under a non-stationary climate, the timeseries need to reflect the complexities of
      future changes that are relevant to the design flood estimation problem. As highlighted in
        <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation>, extreme rainfall is likely to change at a different rate
      to annual average rainfall. Similarly short-duration extremes (sub-daily rainfall) and
      longer-duration extremes (multi-day accumulations) are likely to be experiencing differing
      rates of change in both frequency and intensity, leading to complex changes in the temporal
      patterns of rainfall. There may also be changes to the seasonality of heavy rainfall events,
      and to the sequencing of wet and dry periods. </para>
    <para>Although continuous simulation approaches can be adapted to use climate-adjusted input
      timeseries (rainfall and potential evapotranspiration), further research is required to
      develop robust and practical methods to generate these climate-adjusted inputs into continuous
      simulation models, and applications will generally require the development of individualised
      solutions. As a pragmatic minimum, it is recommended that extreme rainfalls in the timeseries
      used for continuous simulation be scaled to reflect the recommendations for incorporating
      climate change into Intensity-Frequency-Duration curves (<xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_ss1"/>), with
      the remaining rainfalls adjusted to reflect projections of the mean seasonal or annual
      rainfall for the location of interest. Suitable account will also need to be given to
      adjusting evaporative demand inputs. </para>
    <para>Due to the above considerations, and because event-based procedures are commonly applied
      in design flood estimation, event-based procedures are recommended as the primary class of
      procedures for incorporating climate change into design flood estimates. In the context of
      climate change assessments, the advantages of this class of procedures are the ability to
      clearly map climate projections (including those related to extreme rainfall and/or sea
      levels) to the inputs of event-based rainfall-runoff and hydraulic models, together with their
      general applicability across both gauged and ungauged catchments and for a wide range of
      annual exceedance probabilities from the 1 exceedance per year (EY) event through to the
      Probable Maximum Precipitation (PMP) (<xref linkend="b1_ch3_f_9qc3y"/> of Book 1, Chapter 3). </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_s4">
    <title>Incorporating Climate Change into Event-Based Design Flood Estimates</title>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Key messages</emphasis></para>
          <para>Changes in extreme rainfall are likely to represent the primary mechanism for
            increases in flood risk across most Australian catchments. This section provides
            information on how to adjust design rainfall estimates as well as temporal patterns,
            loss parameters, and sea level rise. Uncertainties are presented for each of the aspects
            of the design flood estimate for which climate change guidance is provided. The reader
            is referred to supporting guidance for sea level rise. Examples are presented in <xref
              linkend="b1_ch6_s_s6"/>. </para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
    <para>Event-based procedures are summarised in <xref linkend="b4_ch3"/>, and as highlighted in
      that chapter, they generally take into consideration the following climate-related factors: <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A design storm of a given AEP and duration, usually derived from published IFD data
              (<xref linkend="b2_ch2"/>).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Temporal patterns to distribute the design rainfall over the duration of the event
              (<xref linkend="b2_ch5"/>).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Spatial patterns to represent rainfall variation over a catchment (<xref
              linkend="b2_ch4"/>).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Loss parameters that represent soil moisture conditions in the catchment antecedent
            to the event and the capacity of the soil to absorb rainfall during the event (<xref
              linkend="b5_ch3"/>). </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>This list of climate-related factors is not necessarily exhaustive. For example,
      in low-lying (such as estuarine) catchments, the above is combined with information on sea
      levels that are influenced by both astronomical tides and storm surges (<xref linkend="b6_ch5"
      />). In the following sections, guidance is provided on accounting for climate change
      associated with each of the 4 aspects of event-based design flood modelling described above.
      The section closes with a discussion of the approach to estimating the epistemic uncertainty.
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?></para>
    <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_ss1">
      <title><?oxy_insert_end?>Intensity-Frequency-Duration
        Curves<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?></title>
      <para><?oxy_insert_end?>For most Australian catchments, changes in extreme rainfall are likely
        to represent the primary mechanism for increases in flood risk with
          <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation> identifying over 40 studies that quantify changes of
        extreme rainfall over Australia. For consistency with the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate
        Change (IPCC) projections, and to be representative of the climatic drivers of changes in
        moisture sources, a scaling approach is recommended whereby design rainfalls are factored at
        a rate proportional to global surface (land and sea) temperature increase. </para>
      <para>The current IFD curves that are included in the 2016 IFD portal<footnote>
          <para><link xlink:href="http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/ifd/"
              >http://www.bom.gov.au/water/designRainfalls/ifd/</link></para>
        </footnote> were derived using historical data (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>). The data from
        individual gauges varies, but a good estimate for the midpoint of the data period used in
        estimating the 2016 IFDs is 1961-1990. <xref linkend="b1_ch6_f_f2"/> presents the latest
        Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) temperature projections based on Shared
        Socioeconomic Pathways (SSPs) that cover a broad range of potential future development
        options often referred to as very low (SSP1-1.9), low (SSP1-2.6), medium (SSP2-4.5), high
        (SSP3-7.0) and very high (SSP5-8.5) emissions pathways. The best estimate for the mid-point
        of the data used for the generation of the 2016 IFDs is shaded. As global temperatures have
        risen since this period, design rainfall estimates require factoring to account for this
        temperature increase.
          <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?><figure
          xml:id="b1_ch6_f_f2">
          <title><?oxy_insert_end?>Projected temperature increases associated with AR6 socioeconomic
            pathways relative to 1961-1990 and their associated uncertainty<footnote>
              <para>Figure based on Figure SPM.8 from the Summary for Policymakers (SPM) of the
                Working Group I (WGI) Contribution to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change
                (IPCC) Sixth Assessment Report (AR6) <citation>b1_c6_r15,b1_c6_r11</citation>. Data
                can be obtained from the associated references.</para>
            </footnote><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?></title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/b1_c6_f2.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?></para>
      <?oxy_insert_end?>
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?>
      <para><?oxy_insert_end?>To account for changes since the period represented by the IFD curves
        in the 2016 IFD portal, it is recommended that IFD information as well as estimates of the
        PMP should be adjusted using <xref linkend="b1_ch6_e_e1"/> and the relevant rate of change
        in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/>: </para>
        <equation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e1">
          <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>I</mi>
                <mi>p</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>I</mi>
              <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mfenced>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <mfrac>
                      <mi>&#x3B1;</mi>
                      <mn>100</mn>
                    </mfrac>
                  </mrow>
                </mfenced>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>&#x394;</mo>
                  <mi>T</mi>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
          </math>
        </equation>
      <para>where <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>I<subscript>p</subscript> the projected (current or future) design rainfall depth
              or intensity </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>α is the rate of change from <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>I is the historical design rainfall depth or intensity (e.g. from the 2016 IFD
              portal or historical PMP estimates)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>∆T is the most up-to-date estimate of global (land and ocean) temperature
              projection for the design period of interest and selected climate scenario relative to
              a baseline time period. When used in conjunction with the 2016 IFD curves the baseline
              is recommended to be the 1961-1990 period (see <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/> and text
              below).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>The rates of change in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/> apply to exceedance
        probabilities from the 1EY event through to the PMP and have been developed for application
        across mainland Australia and Tasmania. There is some evidence for heterogeneity in the rate
        of change across space as well as by event severity. However, there is insufficient
        information to quantitatively describe these differences, and/or the magnitude of difference
        was deemed to be small relative to the associated uncertainty. The information provided in
          <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/> relates to storm durations for which most published evidence
        is available. Guidance on factors for use with burst durations between 1 and 24 hours is
        given in Appendix A. As pre-burst rainfalls are defined as a fixed proportion of the burst
        rainfall depth (<xref linkend="b2_ch5"/>), these rates of change also apply to pre-burst
        rainfalls. </para>
      <para>The differing rates of change with storm duration reflect the fact that the mechanisms
        that cause extreme rainfall at these 2 durations are often distinct. Note that short
        duration extremes are often embedded in longer duration extremes. It is possible that
        application of the scaling factors provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/> and <xref
          linkend="b1_ch6_t_tA1"/> may yield inconsistencies in the resulting design rainfall
        frequency curves. Such inconsistencies are not unexpected given the uncertainties involved
        in their derivation. Accordingly, the IFD curves should be adjusted as minimally as possible
        to ensure the curve of one duration does not cross the curve of another. </para>
      <para>
        <table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch6_t_t1">
          <caption>Recommended rates of change (α) and associated uncertainty derived in
              <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation>, presented per degree global temperature change
            (%/°C). The factors in this table are applicable for exceedance probabilities from 1EY
            up to and including the PMP and are designed for application across mainland Australia
            and Tasmania.</caption>
          <col width="35%"/>
          <col width="15%"/>
          <col width="30%"/>
          <col width="15%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th/>
              <th>≤ 1 hr</th>
              <th>> 1 hr and &lt; 24 hr</th>
              <th>≥ 24 hr</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Central (median) estimate (%/°C)</td>
              <td>15</td>
              <td rowspan="2">Interpolation zone (see <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_tA1"/>)</td>
              <td>8</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>‘Likely’ range (corresponding to ~66%<footnote>
                  <para>Consistent with terminology used by the IPCC the 66% range corresponds to an
                    uncertainty range of +/- 33%.</para>
                </footnote> range) (%/°C)</td>
              <td>7-28</td>
              <td>2-15</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </para>
      <para>To ensure consistency with IPCC projections and be representative of the climatic
        drivers of change in extreme rainfall, the rates of change in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/>
        are presented relative to global temperature changes. Hence, to adjust IFDs for climate
        change, global temperature projections ∆T are required. The current global temperature
        projections are provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/> are derived from the IPCC Sixth
        Assessment Report (AR6). An example application of <xref linkend="b1_ch6_e_e1"/> is provided
        in Example 1a in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s6"/>. </para>
      <para>A range of factors are likely to influence selection of SSP(s) that are specific to the
        design problem of interest. For more information on how to include SSP uncertainty as part
        of a holistic assessment of flood risk uncertainty, refer to <xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s6"/>.
        Users should seek the most up to date relevant guidance or information in relation to the
        selection of timeframes and climate scenarios. </para>
      <para>
        <table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch6_t_t2">
          <caption>Global mean surface temperature projections (∆T) for four socio-economic pathways
            relative to 1961-1990. The 90% uncertainty interval is provided in parentheses<footnote>
              <para>Projections adapted from the Summary for Policymakers (SPM) of the Working Group
                I (WGI) Contribution to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) Sixth
                Assessment Report (AR6)<footnote>
                  <para> Refer to Table SPM.1 from the Summary for Policymakers (SPM) of the Working
                    Group I (WGI) Contribution to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change
                    (IPCC) Sixth Assessment Report <citation>b1_c6_r15</citation></para>
                </footnote>. The projected temperature increases in the table above use a different
                baseline to the global warming levels referenced in relation to the Paris Agreement
                which uses a pre-industrial period (represented by the 1850-1900 period). There are
                approximately 0.3 degrees of global warming between the pre-industrial reference and
                1961-1990, and this amount needs to be added to the temperatures in the above if
                comparing to the 1850-1900 period. The IPCC offers a range of summary projections
                information including in the assessment reports and the interactive atlas. We have
                selected the global climate projections from AR6 as they represent a balanced
                assessment of future global climate based on multiple lines of evidence, rather than
                a simple average of the global climate model output. This data is only available at
                the global level, not the regional level.</para>
            </footnote></caption>
          <col width="28%"/>
          <col width="18%"/>
          <col width="18%"/>
          <col width="18%"/>
          <col width="18%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Climate Scenario</th>
              <th>SSP1-2.6</th>
              <th>SSP2-4.5</th>
              <th>SSP3-7.0</th>
              <th>SSP5-8.5</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Current and near-term (2021-2040) (°C)</td>
              <td>1.2 (0.9-1.5) </td>
              <td>1.2 (0.9-1.5) </td>
              <td>1.2 (0.9-1.5) </td>
              <td>1.3 (1.0-1.6) </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Medium-term (2041-2060) (°C)</td>
              <td>1.4 (1.0-1.9) </td>
              <td>1.7 (1.3-2.2) </td>
              <td>1.8 (1.4-2.3) </td>
              <td>2.1 (1.6-2.7) </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Long-term (2081-2100) (°C)</td>
              <td>1.5 (1.0-2.1) </td>
              <td>2.4 (1.8-3.2) </td>
              <td>3.3 (2.5-4.3) </td>
              <td>4.1 (3.0-5.4) </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </para>
      <para>The IPCC AR6 projections use climate model simulations from the Coupled Model
        Intercomparison Project Phase 6 (CMIP6) based on a range of assumptions including physical
        climate science, socio-economic factors and mitigation efforts. These projections are
        neither predictions nor forecasts but instead describe plausible scenarios that represent
        future climate uncertainty. It is noted that future Assessment Reports by the IPCC may
        potentially move away from the current SSPs. If a user wishes to design based on Global
        Warming Levels – the global temperature change relative to the pre-industrial period of
        1850-1900 – then an adjustment for the additional warming of 0.3°C between 1850-1900 and
        1961-1990 is required (see Example 1b). Further, it may be that IFD curves will be updated
        in the future. If a user has reason to believe a different baseline (refer <xref
          linkend="b1_ch6_f_f2"/>) is applicable to the adjustment of design rainfalls, then the
        warming since the baseline needs to be calculated by the user (see Example 1c). Readers
        should always refer to the latest global climate projections and Global Warming Levels. </para>
      <para>The projections in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/> are provided up to 2081-2100. For
        projections up to the year 2300, the reader is referred to Section 4.7.1.2 in Chapter 4 of
        the IPCC AR6 Report<footnote>
          <para><link xlink:href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/"
              >https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/</link>
            <citation>b1_c6_r18</citation></para>
        </footnote>, noting that for SSP2-4.5, SSP3-7.0 and SSP5-8.5, temperatures are projected to
        continue increasing beyond 2100. Although there may be interest in using projections beyond
        2100 for flood designs with a long effective service and/or design life, the available
        evidence to support such projections is more speculative than that used to develop
        projections out to 2100. The defensibility of designing for specific climate change
        projections beyond 2100 is therefore questionable, and a more flexible and adaptive approach
        may be advisable. No formal guidance on adaptive approaches has yet been developed for flood
        design in Australia, but adaptive design generally involves building in flexibility to adapt
        to changing conditions. That is, rather than build a structure to withstand loading
        conditions as they might exist beyond 2100, structures with long service lives might be
        designed to cater for conditions over the time horizons described in <xref
          linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/>, while also ensuring that the structure can be augmented in the
        future to cater for more severe conditions as necessary. A simple illustration of this
        concept is provided in Example 2 (<xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s6"/>).
        <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?></para>
      <?oxy_insert_end?>
      <?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_ss2">
      <title><?oxy_insert_end?>Temporal
        Patterns<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190507T091251+1000"?></title>
      <para><?oxy_insert_end?>Evidence presented in <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation> found that due
        to climate change, temporal patterns may become slightly more front-loaded with a greater
        proportion of the storm volume falling towards the start of the storm. While the shift
        towards more front-loaded storms based on the analysis of historical data is statistically
        significant, the magnitude of these changes is small and the impact of temporal pattern
        changes on design flood estimates may be of little practical significance, particularly for
        those systems where flood levels are largely dependent on flood volume. </para>
      <para>Currently there is no published methodology for quantifying the effect of changing
        temporal patterns on design flood estimates, nor published literature on the implications on
        their impacts on design flood estimates. If a user believes their design flood estimate may
        be sensitive to small changes in the temporal pattern, a sensitivity analysis can be
        undertaken (<xref linkend="b7_ch8"/>). This can be performed using a non-uniform sampling
        (or weighting) approach in either an Ensemble Event averaging (<xref
          linkend="b4_ch3_s_0xgbz"/>) or Monte Carlo scheme (<xref linkend="b4_ch3_s_u6s3a"/>)
        whereby temporal patterns are preferentially selected based on projected future changes. If
        Ensemble Event averaging is used, then it may also be possible to directly alter the shape
        of the temporal patterns. </para>
      <para>The projected change can be assessed by applying a reduction in the percentage of the
        event duration at which 50% of the cumulative event precipitation total is reached. This
        reduction is to be applied relative to the global temperature change ∆T (<xref
          linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/>) as per <xref linkend="b1_ch6_e_e1"/>. For storm durations less
        than or equal to 6 hours, this change is no greater than a 2.5% per degree global
        temperature change. For events between 6 and 24 hours in duration the reduction is no
        greater than 1% per degree global temperature change. For longer durations, the shift may be
        assumed to be zero. More detailed information on the variation and uncertainty in these
        factors can be found in Figure 9 in <citation>b1_c6_r21+1</citation>. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_ss3">
      <title><?oxy_insert_end?>Spatial Patterns </title>
      <para>Although there is some evidence that climate change will influence spatial patterns of
        extreme rainfall, there are considerable uncertainties around such changes for localised
        regions. As such, there is insufficient justification for amending spatial patterns or areal
        reduction factors. </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_ss4">
      <title><?oxy_insert_end?>Loss Parameters </title>
      <para>There is evidence that historical changes in antecedent moisture conditions – the
        expected conditions prior to an extreme rainfall event – have impacted on frequent flood
        peaks, with smaller proportional impacts for rarer events. The review of
          <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation> found multiple studies that presented evidence of drying
        antecedent moisture conditions across Australia, particularly in regions that are
        experiencing decreases in annual and/or seasonal rainfall. <citation>b1_c6_r14+1</citation>
        linked projected changes in soil moisture to loss model parameters, allowing for the
        projection of loss parameters in design flood estimation under climate change. Respecting
        that regional differences will exist due to the differential wetting/drying of the continent
        with climate change, particularly with greater drying projected in southern Australia, <xref
          linkend="b1_ch6_t_t3"/> presents rates of change per degree Celsius for the National
        Resource Management Regions clusters (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_001"/>)
          <citation>b1_c6_r2</citation>. These clusters are the same as those used for temporal
        patterns (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_09"/>) and can be obtained from the ARR datahub
          <citation>b1_c6_r24</citation>. As there is limited data for the Rangelands, a pragmatic
        solution is to apply the changes recommended for the East Flatlands and West Flatlands. </para>
      <para>The rates of change for initial loss (IL) and continuing loss (CL) are generally
        positive (losses will generally increase with higher temperatures), which reduces the impact
        of increased rainfall intensities, particularly for frequent floods or for systems whose
        performance is dependent on the volume of a flood as well as its peak. While it is perhaps
        surprising that adjustment factors are applied to continuing loss, it needs to be recognised
        that the IL/CL model is a gross simplification of the governing catchment processes. For
        example, it ignores differences in the travel times of runoff response across the catchment,
        differences in partially saturated areas due to antecedent conditions, and spatial
        heterogeneity of soil properties. As such, it is to be expected that the tendency for soils
        to be drier in warmer conditions will impact on estimates of both initial and continuing
        loss.</para>
      <para> To adjust the loss parameters for climate change, the rates of change can be applied as
        per <xref linkend="b1_ch6_e_e1"/> relative to the 1961-1990 baseline, as this represents a
        similar data baseline for the derivation of loss parameters in <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/> (see
        Example 2). As these represent storm losses, if applied to bursts they can be applied with
        reference to <xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_s9s9"/>. The uncertainty range represents pooling
        across individual sites, climate change projections, different climate models and bias
        corrections methods. Given this pooling, and the non-linear response of soil moisture to
        changes in rainfall and temperature, the uncertainty presented here is likely to
        underestimate the true uncertainty. A sensitivity analysis to these uncertainties can be
        undertaken following the methodology in <xref linkend="b7_ch8"/>.</para>
      <para>
        <table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch6_t_t3">
          <caption>Rates of change for initial loss (IL) and continuous loss (CL) parameters per
            degree global temperature change (%/°C) for Natural Resource Management Regions clusters
              <citation>b1_c6_r2</citation>, adapted from <citation>b1_c6_r14+1</citation>. The
            ‘likely’ range (corresponding to ~66% range) is presented in parenthesis. These rates of
            change should be applied relative to a 1961-1990 baseline global temperature date unless
            a reasonable alternative is justified</caption>
          <col width="33%"/>
          <col width="33%"/>
          <col width="33%"/>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Natural Resource Management Cluster</th>
              <th>IL (%/°C)</th>
              <th>CL (%/°C)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">East Flatlands, and West Flatlands, Rangelands, and
                  Rangelands West</emphasis></td>
              <td>4.5 (2.0-7.1)</td>
              <td>5.6 (2.5-8.7)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Murray Basin</emphasis></td>
              <td>3.1 (1.0-5.7)</td>
              <td>6.7 (1.5-12.1)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Southern Slopes Mainland, and Southern Slopes
                  Tasmania</emphasis></td>
              <td>3.9 (1.5-7.2)</td>
              <td>8.5 (2.9-15.7)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">East Coast North, and East Coast South</emphasis></td>
              <td>2.0 (0.6-4.3)</td>
              <td>3.8 (1.1-8.0)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Central Slopes</emphasis></td>
              <td>1.1 (0.4-2.2)</td>
              <td>2.0 (-0.5-7.5) </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Wet Tropics</emphasis></td>
              <td>0.8 (-0.4-2.0)</td>
              <td>1.4 (-0.1-4.8)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><emphasis role="bold">Monsoonal North</emphasis></td>
              <td>2.4 (1.0-5.4)</td>
              <td>4.4&#xD;(3.1-9.5)</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_ss5">
      <title><?oxy_insert_end?>Sea Levels and Sea Level Interaction </title>
      <para>There is significant evidence that sea levels are increasing and will continue to
        increase due to climate change. Acknowledging that sea level rise and changes in storm
        surges vary regionally, the reader is referred to the 4th Edition of the Guidelines for
        Responding to the Effects of Climate Change in Coastal and Ocean Engineering
          <citation>b1_c6_r13</citation> (and future updates) as well as their own jurisdictional
        guidance on changes in the sea level. The change in the sea level, jointly with a change in
        the extreme rainfall, can then be considered using the steps outlined in <xref
          linkend="b6_c5_s_expsz"/>. </para>
      <para>Changes to the interaction (or ‘joint probability’) between high sea levels (due to the
        combination of high astronomic tides and storm surges) and heavy rainfall events, remain
        poorly understood. The approach to calculating the joint probability of extreme rainfall and
        elevated sea levels described in <xref linkend="b6_ch5"/> does not account for possible
        changes in the interaction between those drivers. One approach to evaluate the importance of
        changes to the interaction between extreme rainfall and storm surge would be to conduct a
        sensitivity analysis on the dependence parameter recommended in <xref linkend="b6_ch5"/>.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_ss6">
      <title><?oxy_insert_end?>Increased Uncertainty Due to Climate Change</title>
      <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_s_s1"/>, design flood estimates need to account
        for climate change and the associated increase in uncertainty. Epistemic uncertainties (due
        to lack of knowledge) affect: <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>temperature projections, due to future emission pathways and feedbacks within the
              earth system, as described in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>future precipitation extremes for a given temperature change, as described in
                <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>loss parameters, as described in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t3"/>.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>Although not provided here, epistemic uncertainties also impact: <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>sea level rise </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>other inputs to the rainfall-runoff model, including temporal and spatial
              patterns</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>rainfall-runoff transformation, recognising that potential changes to catchment
              properties (such as vegetation changes and/or bushfire) may mean that calibration of
              rainfall-runoff models to historic information may not reflect future
              conditions.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>Each of these epistemic uncertainties affect the overall confidence in the
        design flood estimate. Epistemic uncertainties are not unique to the consideration of
        climate change. For example, IFD curves have inherent uncertainties associated with finite
        sample sizes. There are also other knowledge-based uncertainties associated with translating
        rainfall to estimates of runoff, flood level and velocity. When applied in the context of
        risk assessments, there are also uncertainties in estimating consequences (such as damages
        and/or loss of life) that reflect current and future exposure and vulnerability of assets
        and populations. It is recommended that approaches to characterising uncertainty associated
        with design floods should recognise that both climate change factors and non-climate change
        factors influence the design flood uncertainty. Various approaches for representing
        uncertainty within design flood estimation methods are provided in <xref linkend="b7_ch8"/>.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_s5">
    <title>Future Updates to the Climate Change Considerations</title>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Key messages</emphasis></para>
          <para> While information in this update is the best available at the time of publication,
            more and better information will become available over the coming years. Future updates
            should consider the same approach of drawing on peer-reviewed science, considering
            multiple lines of evidence, synthesising these lines of evidence and publishing the
            results in a reputable peer-reviewed journal.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
    <para>Climate change projections provided in this guidance are based on the review of the
      science by <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation> and represent best-available information at the
      time of publication. The science review adopted a rigorous systematic review process, together
      with a meta-analysis to quantify the scaling relationships presented in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch6_s_ss1"/>. Information from multiple lines of evidence was sought, including
      the instrumental records (such as daily and sub-daily rainfall datasets and radar rainfall
      records) and modelling studies (including general circulation models and several classes of
      regional climate models together with statistical downscaling approaches). </para>
    <para>It is recommended that future best practice updates of this chapter should consider: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>drawing on peer-reviewed studies in reputable scientific journals</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>adopting a multiple-lines-of-evidence approach that recognises potential limitations
            with any single line of evidence</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>synthesising available evidence using protocols that ensure rigour and avoid
            potential for biases</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>ensuring that any synthesis is peer-reviewed and published in a reputable scientific
            journal.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_s6">
    <title>Worked Examples</title>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Key messages</emphasis></para>
          <para> This section comprises 4 worked examples. Examples 1a, 1b and 1c present a simple
            end-of-life design. They aim to familiarise the practitioner with the use of temperature
            projections in the context of design rainfall adjustment. The choice of climate scenario
            in these first examples is solely adopted for the purposes of demonstrating design
            rainfall adjustment.</para>
          <para>Example 2 focuses on design flood estimation using adaptive management, presenting a
            use case that demonstrates how a practitioner could adopt climate scenarios in their
            design. </para>
          <para>The user should also consider the decisions their modelling is informing and seek
            relevant jurisdictional guidance or information in relation to the consideration of
            climate change, including the selection of timeframes and climate scenarios. </para>
          <para>The examples are: </para>
          <para>1a - Design rainfall adjustment for a given emissions scenario. </para>
          <para>1b - Design rainfall adjustment for a given global warming level. </para>
          <para>1c - Design rainfall adjustment using a non-standard baseline. </para>
          <para>2 - Adaptive management under uncertainty in the future climate. </para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
    
    <para xml:id="b1_c6_p_ex1a"><emphasis role="bold">Example 1a - Design rainfall adjustment for a
        given emissions scenario</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>This example presents a common use case where a practitioner wishes to estimate the impact
      of climate change on the existing 2016 IFDs for a time horizon corresponding to the end of the
      century (2081 to 2100 time horizon, <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/>). For this example, the
      practitioner requires an estimate of the 1% AEP 24-hour rainfall depth. </para>
    <para>Using the 2016 IFD portal (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>) the rainfall depth for the 24 hour,
      1% AEP is 300 mm. </para>
    <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/> provides an 8%/°C rate of change for a duration of 24 hours.
      The practitioner is testing the impact of the SSP2-4.5, which corresponds to a 2.4°C increase
      by the end of the century (<xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/>) relative to the baseline adopted for
      the 2016 IFDs. </para>
    <para>Using <xref linkend="b1_ch6_e_e1"/> the factored design rainfall is: </para>
 
    <para><inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e2">
      <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
        <mrow>
          <mn>300</mn>
          <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mfenced>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mn>8</mn>
                  <mn>100</mn>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
            </mfenced>
            <mn>2.4</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mn>361</mn>
          <mo>&#xA0;</mo>
          <mtext>mm</mtext>
        </mrow>
      </math>
    </inlineequation></para>
    
    <para xml:id="b1_c6_p_ex1b"><emphasis role="bold">Example 1b - Design rainfall adjustment for a
        given global warming level</emphasis></para>
    <para>The Shared Socioeconomic Pathways (SSPs) used in the sixth Assessment Report by the IPCC
      are likely to be superseded. Global Warming Levels (GWLs), which are derived from climate
      models run using SSPs, may be used more widely in the future to describe temperature
      projections. GWLs are reported relative to the pre-industrial period which has a different
      baseline to that used in the derivation of the 2016 IFDs. This example presents an approach to
      estimating the impact of climate change on design rainfall using global warming levels. </para>
    <para>For comparison, we follow Example 1a. A practitioner wishes to estimate the 1% AEP 24 hour
      rainfall depth for the end of the century (2081 to 2100 time horizon, <xref
        linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/>). Here, the practitioner is testing a scenario under which the world
      will warm by 3.0°C<footnote>
        <para>This value corresponds closely to the projected warming for SSP2-4.5 by the end of the
          century.</para>
      </footnote> by the end of the century relative to pre-industrial levels. </para>
    <para>Using the 2016 IFD portal (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>) the rainfall depth for the 24 hour,
      1% AEP is 300 mm. </para>
    <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/> provides an 8%/°C rate of change for a duration of 24 hours.
      The data used to derive the IFD curves can be approximated to correspond to the baseline of
      1961-1990, but Global Warming Levels are calculated from pre-industrial periods. Hence the
      additional warming is 3.0°C-0.3°C = 2.7°C where 0.3°C is the difference between the
      pre-industrial period and the period used for derivation of the 2016 IFD curves. </para>
    <para>Using <xref linkend="b1_ch6_e_e1"/> the factored design rainfall is: </para>
    
    <para><inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e3">
      <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
        <mrow>
          <mn>300</mn>
          <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mfenced>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mn>8</mn>
                  <mn>100</mn>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
            </mfenced>
            <mn>2.7</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mn>369</mn>
          <mo>&#xA0;</mo>
          <mtext>mm</mtext>
        </mrow>
      </math>
    </inlineequation></para>
    
    <para xml:id="b1_c6_p_ex1c"><emphasis role="bold">Example 1c - Design rainfall adjustment using
        a non-standard baseline</emphasis></para>
    <para>It is likely that IFD curves may be updated from time to time and hence a different
      baseline will be relevant. Furthermore, a practitioner may have reason to believe that a
      different baseline applies to the data for a particular region or location. This example
      presents how temperature projections can be adjusted to a non-standard baseline. </para>
    <para>Following Example 1a, a practitioner wishes to estimate the 1% AEP 24-hour rainfall depth
      for the end of the century (2081 to 2100 time horizon, <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/>). Here
      however, the practitioner has estimated the 24-hour 1% AEP design rainfall using a record
      length from 1951 to 2020. </para>
    <para><xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t1"/> provides an 8%/°C rate of change for a duration of 24 hours.
      The practitioner needs to choose an emissions scenario and chooses to test the impact of
      SSP2-4.5 which corresponds to a 2.4°C increase by the end of the century (<xref
        linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/>) relative to the baseline adopted for the 2016 IFDs. But the
      temperature projections in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/> are estimated relative to 1961-1990.
      Hence the practitioner needs to check if there was additional warming between these 2
      baselines. </para>
    <para>There are several reputable sources of global temperature anomalies<footnote>
        <para>A summary is provided at <link
            xlink:href="https://www.metoffice.gov.uk/weather/climate/science/global-temperature-records"
            >https://www.metoffice.gov.uk/weather/climate/science/global-temperature-records</link>
          ; with links provided at <link
            xlink:href="https://climate.metoffice.cloud/temperature.html"
            >https://climate.metoffice.cloud/temperature.html</link>.</para>
      </footnote>. Examples include: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Met Office, in collaboration with the Climatic Research Unit (CRU) at the University
            of East Anglia (UK).<footnote>
              <para>See also <link xlink:href="https://crudata.uea.ac.uk/cru/data/temperature/"
                  >https://crudata.uea.ac.uk/cru/data/temperature/</link></para>
            </footnote></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Goddard Institute for Space Studies (GISS), which is part of the National
            Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) (USA).<footnote>
              <para>See also <link xlink:href="https://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/"
                  >https://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/</link></para>
            </footnote></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>National Climatic Data Center (NCDC), which is part of the National Oceanic and
            Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) (USA).<footnote>
              <para>See also <link
                  xlink:href="https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/access/monitoring/global-temperature-anomalies"
                  >https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/access/monitoring/global-temperature-anomalies</link>
              </para>
            </footnote></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>Using the data from NOAA, the difference between the mean global temperature
      for the 1951-2020 period is approximately 0.2°C warmer than the 1961-1990 baseline baseline
      (i.e. 0.5°C above the pre-industrial baseline 1850-1900). The practitioner can proceed using
      the temperatures provided in <xref linkend="b1_ch6_t_t2"/> by adjusting for this increase. The
      long-term climate projected temperature increase is 2.4°C-0.2°C = 2.2°C above the new
      1951-2020 baseline. </para>
    <para>Using <xref linkend="b1_ch6_e_e1"/>, the factored design rainfall is: </para>
    <para><inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e4">
      <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
        <mrow>
          <mn>300</mn>
          <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mfenced>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mn>8</mn>
                  <mn>100</mn>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
            </mfenced>
            <mn>2.2</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mn>355</mn>
          <mo>&#xA0;</mo>
          <mtext>mm</mtext>
        </mrow>
      </math>
    </inlineequation></para>  
    
    <para xml:id="b1_c6_p_ex2"><emphasis role="bold">Example 2 - Adaptive management under
        uncertainty around future climate</emphasis></para>
    <para>A local council is considering construction of a levee to protect an adjacent community
      from flooding. A range of options were considered to find a solution that best balances the
      trade-offs between construction costs and ongoing savings in avoided damages and flood
      hazards. It was decided that the levee should provide protection from 1% AEP flooding impacts. </para>
    <para>In this example, SSP2-4.5 and SSP3-7.0 are adopted as the moderate and high-warming
      scenarios, respectively, and the SSP5-8.5 scenario is adopted to aid the stress testing of
      decisions under a lower risk tolerance. Although SSP5-8.5 is not consistent with expected
      emission trends <citation>b1_c6_r19</citation>, using this scenario in a suite is one method
      of considering the uncertainty in each of the relationships between emissions, temperatures
      and resulting climate impacts. That is, use of the SSP5-8.5 scenario is used here to
      notionally represent a plausible upper bound on the projected climate impacts. </para>
    <para>In practice, given the deep uncertainties involved, it was decided to take an adaptive
      approach whereby the levee was initially designed to provide protection from 1% AEP flooding
      out to the mid-term (2041-2060) under the mid-range emission scenario (SSP2-4.5). The design
      incorporated additional capacity in the levee foundations, and an extended riverbank corridor
      width to allow for a wider and taller embankment. This feature could be added at a time in the
      future associated with a high-range emission scenario (SSP3-7.0) with consideration given to
      the very-high (SSP5-8.5) emission scenario. </para>
    <para>Accordingly, designs were prepared to provide for 2 combinations of emissions scenarios
      and time horizons (SSP2-4.5 in the mid-term, 2041-2060, and SSP3-7.0 in the long-term,
      2081-2100), with consideration given to SSP5-8.5). </para>
    <para>A summary of the design inputs used to develop the adaptive approach is provided in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch6_t_t4"/> for an event with a critical duration of 24 hours and historical
      design rainfall from the 2016 IFD portal of 125 mm, with initial loss of 15.0 mm and
      continuing loss of 2.5 mm/hr. </para>
    
    <para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch6_t_t4">
        <caption>Design inputs factor for climate change for Example 2. Design inputs assume an
          event critical duration of 24 hours duration and historical design rainfall of 125 mm,
          with initial loss of 15.0 mm and continuing loss of 2.5 mm/hr</caption>
        <col width="16%"/>
        <col width="28%"/>
        <col width="28%"/>
        <col width="28%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Design consideration</th>
            <th>SSP2-4.5 (2041-2060)</th>
            <th>SSP3-7.0 (2081-2100)</th>
            <th>SSP5-8.5 (2081-2100)</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Temperature increase (°C)</td>
            <td>1.7</td>
            <td>3.3</td>
            <td>4.1</td>
            </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>24 hr rainfall (mm)</td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e5">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>125</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>8</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>1.7</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>142</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e6">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>125</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>8</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>3.3</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>161</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e7">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>125</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>8</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>4.1</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>171</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Initial loss (mm)</td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e8">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>15.0</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>3.9</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>1.7</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>16.0</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e9">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>15.0</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>3.9</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>3.3</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>17.0</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e10">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>15.0</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>3.9</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>4.1</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>17.6</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Continuing loss (mm/hr)</td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e11">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>2.5</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>8.5</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>1.7</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>2.9</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e12">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>2.5</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>8.5</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>3.3</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>3.3</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
            <td>
              <inlineequation xml:id="b1_ch6_e_e13">
                <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>2.5</mn>
                    <mo>&#xD7;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mfenced>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>8.5</mn>
                            <mn>100</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                        </mrow>
                      </mfenced>
                      <mn>4.1</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>3.5</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </math>
              </inlineequation>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="b1_ch6_s_s7">
    <title>Appendix</title>
    <para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch6_t_tA1">
        <caption>Interpolated rate of change for rainfall depth with associated uncertainty range.
          Values have been interpolated from the values provided in Table 1 which was derived in
            <citation>b1_c6_r22+1</citation>. Rates of change are presented per degree global
          temperature change (%/°C). The factors in this table are applicable for exceedance
          probabilities from 1EY up to and including the PMP and are designed for application across
          mainland Australia and Tasmania. If applied to the 2016 IFD curves these rates of change
          should be applied relative to a 1961-1990 baseline global temperature date unless a
          reasonable alternative is justified. Less information is available for rates of change for
          storm bursts between 1 and 24 hours, and hence estimates for these durations are obtained
          by a simple non-linear interpolation that represents the pragmatic interpretation of
          results obtained from <citation>b1_c6_r20+1</citation></caption>
        <col width="25%"/>
        <col width="75%"/>
        
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Duration</th>
            <th>Rate of change (%/°C) and estimates of ‘likely’ range (corresponding to ~66% range)
              in parentheses.</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>1.5 hour </td>
            <td>13.7 (6.1-25.6)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2 hour </td>
            <td>12.8 (5.5-24.0)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>3 hour </td>
            <td>11.8 (4.7-22.0)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>4.5 hour </td>
            <td>10.8 (4.0-20.3)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>6 hour </td>
            <td>10.2 (3.6-19.2)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>9 hour </td>
            <td>9.5 (3.1-17.8)</td>
            </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>12 hour </td>
            <td>9.0 (2.7-16.9)</td>
           </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>18 hour </td>
            <td>8.4 (2.3-15.7)</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </para>
    <para> </para>
  </section>
  
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
</chapter>
