<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b8_ch2" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <info>
    <title>Procedures for Estimating Very Rare to Extreme Floods</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20160710T220244+1000" content="20/11/2018"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20160710T220244+1000"?>13/5/2019<?oxy_insert_end?>
      </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_2vj4c">
    <title>Overall Design Approach</title>
    <para>The overall emphasis of this Book is on the estimation of a flood frequency curve for Very
      Rare to Extreme floods rather than on the estimation of a design flood of specific magnitude.
      The procedures employed are generally based on Flood Frequency Analysis and rainfall-based
      simulation techniques. While general guidance on these techniques should be sought elsewhere
      in ARR (<xref linkend="b3_ch2"/>), this Book gives consideration to a number of issues
      specific to the estimation of Very Rare to Extreme design floods.</para>
    <para>The procedures are generally based on the assumption that final design estimates should
      incorporate the best and most relevant information available. As emphasised in <xref
        linkend="book1"/> the use of new procedures and design information is encouraged, especially
      where these can be shown to be more appropriate than the guidance provided here.</para>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_81v7f">
      <title>Flood Frequency Analysis</title>
      <para>The procedures recommended in <xref linkend="book3"/> are directly relevant to the
        estimation of Rare floods, and with the incorporation of regional information at-site Flood
        Frequency Analysis can also be used to estimate Very Rare floods. Special consideration is
        provided here on the benefits of incorporating paleo-hydrological information, (<xref
          linkend="b3_ch2_s_22h0g"/>) as this type of information has the potential to considerably
        extend the credible limit of extrapolation.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b8_s_fr02f">
      <title>Rainfall-Based Procedures</title>
      <para>The procedures provided in <xref linkend="book5"/> provide general guidance on the use
        of rainfall-based simulation methods. For risk-based design it is necessary to transform
        design rainfalls into floods in a fashion that minimises bias in the resulting exceedance
        probabilities; that is, we wish to ensure that the 1 in Y AEP design rainfalls are converted
        to the corresponding 1 in Y AEP floods (i.e. Probability neutrality). For those inputs and
        model parameters with a small impact on flood discharge it is usually sufficient to adopt a
        single representative value from the central range of observations; often either the mean or
        median is adopted. However, the most appropriate value depends on the degree of
        non-linearity in the transformation between rainfall and runoff and in the cumulative
        probability distribution. If one or both of these forms of non-linearity is great, it is
        desirable to adopt a joint probability approach in which the inputs and model parameters are
        characterised by their probability distributions rather than by a single value. This is
        particularly so for those inputs and model parameters with a large impact on flood
        magnitude.</para>
      <para>The adoption of a simplified probability neutral approach is accepted practice for
        Frequent to Rare floods, where it is usually possible to derive independent estimates of the
        design floods to check that no bias has been introduced into the transformation between
        rainfall and runoff. Where such independent information is available, simple event based
        approaches, i.e. those involving the deterministic application of models based on linear and
        non-linear routing with representative values of inputs and model parameters, should be
        adequate for many practical purposes. However, it becomes increasingly difficult to obtain
        independent estimates of floods in the Very Rare to Extreme range, and thus there is an
        increased need to explicitly consider the joint probabilities involved. This is particularly
        so when considering the impacts of changing factors (such as revised operating conditions on
        reservoir levels) whose variability may be characterised with reasonable confidence but
        whose influences may not be reflected in the observed record. Ensemble event approaches have
        the potential to mitigate this bias, but these are only likely to be defensible for those
        problems (linearly) influenced by a single dominant factor in addition to rainfall. Monte
        Carlo simulation methods provide a more flexible and rigorous means of resolving these
        difficulties, but the defensibility of these estimates rests upon the representativeness of
        the inputs and the correct treatment of correlations which may be present.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_dkdq3">
    <title>Procedures for Different Categories of Design Floods</title>
    <para>The procedures for deriving design estimates for flood classes of most relevance to
      extreme floods can be summarised in the following three main categories depending on the
      probability of the flood to be estimated:</para>
    <para>
      <orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
        <listitem>
          <para>Floods with AEPs approaching 1 in 100 (Rare floods):</para>
          <para>Estimates should be based on a combination of approaches that consider (where
            possible) at-site flood frequency analyses (<xref linkend="b2_ch2"/>), regional flood
            methods (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>), and rainfall-based event modelling (<xref
              linkend="b3_ch3_s_ynzmg"/>). The comparison of results obtained using different
            methods yields insights about errors or assumptions that might otherwise be missed, and
            the process of reconciling the different assessments provides valuable information that
            aids adoption of a final “best estimate”. As discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch3"/>, the
            adoption of a single best estimate is ideally achieved by weighting estimates obtained
            from different methods by their uncertainty, or through the process of reconciliation in
            which selected factors are varied within their expected range to achieve the desired
            level of consistency.</para>
          <para>While there is scope for considering the use of continuous simulation approaches,
            their use for estimation of Vary Rare to Extreme events should only be considered for
            systems which are strongly dependent on flood volume in a manner not easily handled by
            event-based procedures; this might be the case for the design of tailings dams with
            small catchment areas, or cascade systems of storages involving complex interaction of
            joint probabilities. The advantages and limitations of continuous simulation approaches
            are broadly discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch3"/>, but in the context of the estimation
            of extreme floods, it is worth noting that their use will require careful generation of
            stochastic rainfall inputs that are consistent with design rainfall information provided
            in <xref linkend="book2"/>. If the exceedance probabilities of interest lie in the Very
            Rare to Extreme event range then there is little point using a different approach for
            estimation of Rare floods.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20160710T153050+1000" content="(ii) "?>Floods
            with AEPs beyond 1 in 100 AEP to the credible limit of extrapolation (Very Rare
            floods):</para>
          <para>Estimates should be primarily based on rainfall-based simulation methods, with
            rainfalls derived using methods described in <xref linkend="b8_s_vgrwa"/>, or else on
            flood frequency estimates derived using historical and paleo flood information (<xref
              linkend="b8_s_e0h7b"/>). Such estimates necessarily involve significant extrapolation,
            and their defensibility will partly depend on the ease with which different estimates of
            Rare floods can be reconciled.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Floods with AEPs beyond the credible limit of extrapolation (Extreme floods,
            including the Probable Maximum Precipitation Flood):</para>
          <para>These flood estimates may be required for direct use in design situations of high
            risk, either in terms of risk to human life or economic losses, or where social or
            political considerations require a very high level of safety. Estimates should be based
            on the use of a flood event model with design rainfalls obtained by interpolation
            between the credible limit of extrapolated rainfalls and the Probable Maximum
            Precipitation (PMP). To avoid confusion with the Probable Maximum Flood (refer to iv),
            the flood derived from the PMP using probability neutral assumptions is here termed the
            “PMP Flood”.</para>
          <para>An additional category of procedures differs from the above in its design
            objective:</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Probable Maximum Flood (the limiting value of flood that could reasonably be
            expected to occur):</para>
          <para>This may be required for comparison with estimates derived from previous studies or
            for some other design objective that usually requires a notional upper limiting value of
            flood without an associated AEP. In practice, the magnitude of the PMF will generally be
            greater than the magnitude of the flood derived from the PMP using probability neutral
            assumptions (the PMP Flood).</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>A brief summary of the recommended procedures and references to the relevant sections are
      presented in <xref linkend="b8_t_bkw7k"/> and <xref linkend="b8_t_vxhjn"/>. It should be
      recognised that these tables represent a summary of procedures that are described in detail in
      later sections; they are not intended to be self-explanatory.</para>
    <para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b8_t_bkw7k">
        <caption>Summary of Procedures to Derive Design Rainfalls</caption>
        <col align="left" width="20%"/>
        <col align="center" width="18%"/>
        <col align="center" width="15%"/>
        <col align="center" width="21%"/>
        <col align="left" width="26%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Design Consideration</th>
            <th colspan="3">Design Category</th>
            <th>Comments</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <th/>
            <td>
              <para>Rare</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Very Rare</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Extreme</para>
            </td>
            <td rowspan="2"><emphasis>The credible limit of extrapolation generally ranges from 1 in
                100 to 1 in 5000 AEP</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <th/>
            <td>Towards 1 in 100 AEP</td>
            <td>
              <para>Beyond 1 in 100 AEP to 1 in 2000 AEP</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Rarer than 1 in 2000 AEP</para>
            </td>
          </tr>
         </thead>
         <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Point Design Rainfall Depths up to the PMP</emphasis></td>
            <td colspan="2">Generalised information on design rainfall bursts, as described in <xref
                linkend="b2_ch3"/>.</td>
            <td>
              <para>Not applicable</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>Point design rainfall depths for non-standard durations from
                        procedures in </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_i77bn"/></para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>For information on seasonal estimates see </emphasis><xref
                        linkend="b8_s_9piio"/></para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Areal Design Rainfall Depths up to the PMP</emphasis></td>
            <td colspan="2">Derived from point design rainfalls by application of Areal Reduction
              Factors (ARFs), selected as a function of storm area, duration, and AEP (<xref
                linkend="b2_ch4"/>).</td>
            <td>Interpolation to areal PMP estimate based on two parameter parabolic function (<xref
                linkend="b8_s_ysol4"/>)</td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b2_ch4"/><emphasis> for discussion
                      on Areal Reduction Factors</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Probable Maximum Precipitation (PMP)</emphasis></para>
            </td>
            <td colspan="2">Not applicable</td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>GSDM for short durations and small areas</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>GSAM for South-East Australia region</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>GTSM for tropical region</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_1a1fg"/><emphasis> for areas
                        covered by different generalised methods</emphasis></para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>PMP estimates are areal depths</emphasis></para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>AEP of PMP based solely on catchment area, </emphasis><xref
                        linkend="b8_s_bb68z"/></para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Temporal Patterns</emphasis></para>
            </td>
            <td rowspan="2">Areal patterns (for bursts and complete storms) as described in <xref
                linkend="b2_ch5"/>.</td>
            <td colspan="2">
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>GSAM &amp; GTSM-R areal patterns for all long durations</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>GSDM point patterns for short durations</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Both GSDM and GSAM/GTSM-R patterns for intermediate durations</para>
                  <para/>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
            <td rowspan="2">
              <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_t_vskyx"/><emphasis> for
                        summary of temporal pattern selection</emphasis></para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>Pre-burst temporal patterns may be used in conjunction with
                        storm losses (</emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_isy73"
                      /><emphasis>)</emphasis></para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td colspan="2">Use of a mix of selected at-site and generalised PMP patterns in an
              ensemble for Rare and Very Rare events may be required to provide a smooth transition
              across different sources of data</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Spatial Patterns</emphasis></td>
            <td>Regional information on design rainfall spatial patterns as described in <xref
                linkend="b2_ch4"/></td>
            <td colspan="2">Use either GSDM, GSAM, or GTSMR spatial patterns as appropriate for the
              location and duration</td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_sborg"/><emphasis> for
                      discussion on need for incorporation of spatial trend</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_t_hk25s"/><emphasis> for summary
                      of spatial pattern selection</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </para>
    <para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b8_t_vxhjn">
        <caption>Summary of Procedures to Derive Design Floods</caption>
        <col align="left" width="20%"/>
        <col align="center" width="18%"/>
        <col align="center" width="15%"/>
        <col align="center" width="21%"/>
        <col align="left" width="26%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Design Consideration</th>
            <th colspan="3">Design Category</th>
            <th>Comments</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <th/>
            <td>
              <para>Rare</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Very Rare</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>Extreme</para>
            </td>
            <td rowspan="2"><emphasis>The credible limit of extrapolation generally ranges from 1 in
                100 to 1 in 5000 AEP</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <th/>
            <td>Towards 1 in 100 AEP</td>
            <td>Beyond 1 in 100 AEP to the credible limit of extrapolation</td>
            <td>Beyond the credible limit of extrapolation</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Losses</emphasis></para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>For complete design storms</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
            <td colspan="3">Use “complete storm” initial and continuing losses for all durations and
              all AEPs (a probability distributed model may be warranted for south-west Australia)
              consistent with <xref linkend="b5_ch5"/></td>
            <td>
              <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_wzey8"/><emphasis> for
                        general recommendations</emphasis></para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Hydrograph model</emphasis></para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Selection and configuration</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Calibration</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
            <td colspan="3">
              <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Non-linear storage-routing models (or equivalent)</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Calibration to range of flood magnitudes, including reconciliation with
                      design flood estimates derived from at-site/regional flood frequency and
                      paleohydrological procedures</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>For Rare to Extreme events non-linearity in S =
                        kQ<superscript>m</superscript> relation generally assumed to be in range 0.8
                      to 0.9 (depending on catchment characteristics)</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_zvvef"/><emphasis> and
                        </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_cd813"/></para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_20a81"/><emphasis> and
                        </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_pb3t4"/></para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_wh2h5"/></para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </para>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Baseflow</emphasis></td>
            <td>Adopt baseflow recommendations as discussed in <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/></td>
            <td>Baseflow to be varied gradually between that adopted for the 1 in 100 AEP and the
              PMP Flood</td>
            <td>Adopt constant value 20% to 50% higher than maximum observed</td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_fzd4a"/></para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Design flood frequency curve</emphasis></td>
            <td colspan="3">Derive rainfall-based estimates for range of design rainfall durations
              and AEPs, and adopt highest peak discharge from the range of durations for each
              AEP</td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_3o5gi"/><emphasis> for general
                      guidance and </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_whun4"/><emphasis> for guidance on
                      seasonal floods</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><emphasis role="bold">Probable Maximum Flood (PMF)</emphasis></td>
            <td colspan="2">
              <para>Not applicable</para>
            </td>
            <td>Defined as the limiting value of flood that could reasonably be expected to occur
                (<xref linkend="b8_s_gbk9t"/>)</td>
            <td><emphasis>There are no established procedures to assign an AEP to the
              PMF</emphasis></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Additional design considerations</emphasis></para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Reservoir outflows</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Concurrent flooding</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Seasonal floods</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Snowmelt floods</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Long duration events</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
            <td colspan="3">
              <para>Probability neutral procedures are recommended to ensure that any bias in the
                AEP of the transformation between rainfall and runoff is minimised. A range of
                procedures from the simple to the rigorous are provided</para>
            </td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_ch7"/><emphasis> for general
                      guidance</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Preliminary design flood estimates</emphasis></para>
            </td>
            <td>Regional procedures and Flood Frequency Analysis (<xref linkend="book4"/></td>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160529T182750+1000" comment="check wording"?>
            <td>Simple log Normal interpolation may be used to determine Very Rare preliminary</td>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
            <td>Regional information may be used to estimate the PMP Flood (conservatively assumed
              to equal the PMF)</td>
            <td>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>See </emphasis><xref linkend="b8_s_laqj1"/></para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b8_s_v4uey">
    <title>Relevance of Procedures to Specific Applications</title>
    <para>The procedures outlined in this Book are intended to cover the broad spectrum of
      applications listed in <xref linkend="b8_s_h5bgs"/> and the flood classes described in <xref
        linkend="b8_s_ji1cq"/>. However, when deriving flood estimates for a specific application,
      the practitioner’s interest may be focused on a more limited range of procedures. This section
      provides some guidance on the applicability of different parts of the guidelines to specific
      investigations or design tasks.</para>
    <para><xref linkend="b8_f_77nq1"/> gives a qualitative indication of the range of flood
      magnitudes and the relative degree of reliability required for different applications. An
      extension of the flood range of interest is associated with a greater degree of extrapolation
      and thus larger uncertainty (lower reliability). The level of expertise and effort required
      for deriving design floods increases with increasing level of reliability required.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b8_f_77nq1">
      <title>Qualitative Indication of the Range of Flood Magnitudes and the Relative
        Degree of Reliability Required for Different Applications</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/8002.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>As shown in <xref linkend="b8_f_77nq1"/>, the qualitative indication of the range of flood
      magnitudes and associated relative degree of reliability can be divided into four groups of
      applications. For the first three groups of applications, approximate or simplified flood
      estimation procedures may be applicable; however, the practitioner has to apply  engineering
      judgement in deciding on the degree of detail and accuracy required for a specific
      application. The fourth group of applications demands the most accurate estimates and hence
      the greatest level of effort.</para>
    <para>(i) <emphasis role="italic">Planning and feasibility studies, initial screening of
        options, preliminary designs:</emphasis></para>
    <para>For these types of applications, where decisions based on the flood estimates are only
      moderately sensitive to estimation uncertainties, approximate design flood estimates can be
      derived by preliminary methods
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20160710T153202+1000" content="(see"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20160710T153202+1000"?>(refer to<?oxy_insert_end?>
      <xref linkend="b8_s_laqj1"/>).</para>
    <para>(ii) <emphasis role="italic">Performance checks or preliminary designs of
        structures:</emphasis></para>
    <para>Many design codes require safety checks for conditions exceeding the design objective.
      Approximate estimates of floods  from 1 in 100 AEP to an absolute limit of 1 in 2000 AEP can
      be obtained by use of design rainfalls (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>) in combination with a flood
      event model configured using regional estimates of losses and routing parameters. The rainfall
      frequency curve may be extended to the AEP of the PMP by deriving site-specific estimates of
      the PMP. Flood estimates based on use of regional parameters without calibration or additional
      confirmatory estimates are subject to considerable uncertainty, and correspondingly greater
      responsibility then rests with the practitioner to ensure that the estimates are consistent
      with any relevant flood estimates for the region.</para>
    <para>(iii) <emphasis role="italic">Design of floodplain management or flood protection schemes
        based on risk management principles:</emphasis></para>
    <para>While risk-based design requires the assessment of the contribution of Rare to Extreme
      floods to the total expected flood damage figure, the low probability of floods in this range
      means that the contribution from this range of floods to the total expected flood damage is
      relatively low in most situations. A lower degree of reliability of flood estimates in the
      Rare to Extreme range is therefore acceptable for these applications.</para>
    <para>(iv)<emphasis role="italic"> Final design of major works and assessment of the adequacy of
        existing infrastructure, where failure would result in serious consequences or possible of
        life:</emphasis></para>
    <para>For this
      <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160529T202902+1000" comment="consistent language with earlier in section
"?>group<?oxy_comment_end?>
      of applications, efforts should be made to reduce uncertainties in design flood estimates to
      the minimum possible. The further the AEP range of interest extends beyond the Rare floods,
      the more important it is for the practitioner to consider in detail the guidelines in <xref
        linkend="b8_ch4"/> and <xref linkend="b8_ch5"/> on extrapolation of hydrograph model
      characteristics. For all applications where the range of interest extends to extreme floods,
      and where large uncertainty in flood estimates would impact significantly on design decisions,
      detailed flood studies are justified.</para>
  </section>
  
  
</chapter>


<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>