<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b1_ch4"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Data</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weeks_william.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/smith_grantley.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ling_fiona.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/green_janice.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>13/5/2019</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_yb78j">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Data, in a range of types, is essential for all water resources
    investigations, especially the topics involving design flood estimation
    covered by Australian Rainfall and Runoff. This data is needed to
    understand the processes and to ensure that models are accurate and
    reflect the real world issues being analysed.</para>

    <para>While standard hydrologic data includes rainfall, water levels and
    streamflow, a range of other data is also useful or even essential for
    flood investigations. This chapter provides some background on the types
    of data needed, and specific issues related to each of these.</para>

    <para>It also needs to be pointed out that most the procedures and guidelines presented in
      Australian Rainfall and Runoff could not have been developed without historical data, and
      often the reliability of the methods presented depends on the extent of data that has been
      used in its development.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Background</title>

    <para>Because of variability in water resources data (especially in
    Australia), long historical records are important to ensure that this
    variability is well sampled. Long records help to ensure that extremes of
    both wet and dry periods have been sampled.</para>

    <para>However, having long term records means that trends in the data may be important. Trends
      may be natural or human-induced and may be difficult to detect because of variability and the
      infrequent occurrence of rare events. Trends can result from human-induced climate change,
      land use changes, or poorly understood long term climate cycles (e.g. related to the
      Inter-decadal Pacific Oscillation and other large scale phenomena). Careful analysis is needed
      to ensure that the long historical records are considered in the context of long and short
      term natural variability and trends.</para>

    <para>There are many organisations that collect and maintain data that is useful for flood
      estimation. Some of these organisations are major authorities that can be clearly identified
      and have well organised data in accessible formats. However, there is also a considerable
      amount of data that is harder to find and often valuable information can be found in
      unexpected locations. This chapter provides information on the types of data that may be
      useful, sources where this data can be found and the accuracy that can be expected. A useful
      discussion on the value of hydrologic data, specifically streamflow data, is included in the
      paper by <citation>b1_c4_r32+1</citation>.</para>

    <para>Routine data collection programmes are important, but it is often
    valuable to expend some effort in finding and verifying other data for
    particular projects. It is also important to note that data useful for
    these projects may be anecdotal rather than formal and often valuable
    information can be gathered by simply holding discussions with local
    residents or other stakeholders. Many projects have a consultation
    programme which can uncover useful information.</para>

    <para>As well, specific formal data collection programmes are often needed
    for particularly large projects, where the scale of the project justifies
    expenditure on data collection. For example, this type of programme is
    often carried out as part of environmental impact studies for major
    projects during the approval process.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Risks From Inadequate Data</title>

    <para>The following comments are taken from the paper by
      <citation>b1_c4_r32+1</citation>.</para>

    <para>Australia is the driest inhabited continent and has a more variable
    climate than other continents. As a result water resources in Australia
    are often scarce and are therefore critical to the nation’s prosperity. At
    the other end of the scale, large floods often cause devastating damage to
    property and endanger lives. While present generations are benefiting from
    the data collection activities of our predecessors, it is our
    responsibility to ensure that future generations are not disadvantaged by
    the changes we are implementing now. Data collection is about reducing the
    risks and increasing the benefits the current and future generations
    receive from the expenditure of the limited funds available for water
    management.</para>

    <para>Water resources data are used for:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Flood warning (e.g. the Nyngan floods);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Groundwater and dry-land salinity assessment and management (e.g. throughout the
          Murray Darling Basin and much of WA, the Great Artesian Basin and inland sub-artesian
          aquifers);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Drinking water quality (e.g. coliform counts as health indicators);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Design of bridges, dams, stormwater and sewer systems;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>River water quality (e.g. blue-green algae outbreak in the Darling River, habitat
          protection);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Water supply for urban and rural communities (e.g. water restrictions and new
          dams);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Irrigation for agriculture (e.g. the cap on extractions from the Murray Darling
          Basin);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Assessing climate change and its effects on future availability
        of freshwater;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Extreme flood estimation (e.g. Warragamba Dam spillway upgrade);</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Water trading – agreed volumes and timing must be reconcilable,
        and be measured accurately, compliance with licence entitlements;
        and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Development of water plans and policies.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Considering the specific concerns for Australian Rainfall and Runoff, inadequate data or
      the lack of data leads to uncertainty in the results of the analysis and will tend to require
      additional freeboard allowance for example to compensate for the uncertainty. While there are
      available procedures that are regional specific and can be implemented on ungauged catchments,
      there will be more uncertainty in these applications and therefore an increase risk in the
      flood estimation application. Practitioners need to utilise as much local information, even if
      this is anecdotal and limited, as possible to reduce this risk.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Stationarity</title>

    <para>Detection of changes in river discharge and magnitude of flood peaks, whether it is abrupt
      or gradual change is of considerable importance, being fundamental for planning of future
      water resources and flood protection <citation>b1_c4_r37</citation>. Generally flood analysis
      and planning design rules, including data collection programmes, are based on the assumption
      of stationary hydrological data sets. If the stationarity assumption is proved to be invalid
      through global climate change then the existing procedures for designing water-related
      infrastructures will need revision. This has been recognized in the US with increased emphasis
      on maintaining stations with long data records <citation>b1_c4_r40</citation>. Long data sets
      and ongoing analysis are essential to promote accurate design of systems to perform adequately
      for their design probability and not be over designed resulting in higher costs or
      under-designed resulting in large damage bills, loss of life and perhaps ultimate failure of
      structures with resultant community destruction.</para>

    <para>A range of human activities including man-made structures such as
    dams, reservoirs and levees can change the natural flow regime. Land cover
    and land-use changes including deforestation and urbanization controls
    many facets of the rainfall–runoff process increasing the peak flows and
    increasing the amount of runoff. Water conveyance in rivers is altered by
    river regulation measures (such as channel straightening and shortening,
    construction of embankments, construction of weirs and locks) or the
    rehabilitation of rivers with increased stabilisation using trees and logs
    to provide a better environment for native species. Abstractions from
    river systems can cause them to run dry and further change the natural
    channel system and henceforth impinge on the magnitude of larger floods
    stage height by the considerable amount of debris in the rivers.</para>

    <para>Hydrologic data series have generally been considered to be stationary series i.e. there
      are no long-term shifts in the time series statistical parameters. However, it is recognised
      that with the “greenhouse effect” analyses might need to take into account the non-stationary
      effects when performing hydrologic designs. There is therefore a demonstrated need to continue
      data collection to avoid potential large errors in hydraulic structures design and water
      resources management due to inadequate streamflow data <citation>b1_c4_r43</citation>.</para>

    <para>All flood investigations need to consider the potential for
    non-stationarity in any data applied to the project, and make appropriate
    adjustments as required.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_on3ct">
    <title>Hydroinformatics</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_c8pza">
      <title>Introduction to Hydroinformatics</title>
      <para>An important component for prediction of design flood characteristics is the
        consideration of the data available for the purpose of predicting both, the magnitude and
        probability of a flood characteristic. Since the publication of the previous edition of
        Australian Rainfall and Runoff <citation>arr_1987</citation>, the increasing computational
        power available has seen changes in availability and perceptions of data. These changing
        perceptions resulted in development of hydroinformatics as a conceptual framework for
        various techniques and approaches to deal with information about water in an electronic
        format.</para>
      <para>Though <citation>b1_c4_r27+1</citation> first proposed the term "Hydroinformatics" as a
        generic term describing the utilisation of information and data about water, the most
        encompassing and concise definition was presented by <citation>b1_c4_r38+1</citation> who
        stated:</para>
      <blockquote>
        <para>... hydroinformatics deals with the electronic knowledge encapsulation of various
          sources of information related to the hydro sciences.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <para>With this definition, it is clear that the term 'hydroinformatics' covers a wide range
        of subject areas that are beyond the classical hydrological and hydraulic sciences involved
        in design flood prediction and management. This definition also includes data and
        information from the political, social, economic and legal spheres relevant to design flood
        events. As suggested, though the scope of hydroinformatics is extensive, however, only those
        aspects relevant to prediction of design flood characteristics will be discussed in this
        chapter.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_lu01g">
      <title>Components of a Hydroinformatics System</title>

      <para>Since the specifications of each hydroinformatics system are
      different and their components will also differ for each application, it
      is impossible to define all the components that together will constitute
      a system, however, the concept is that a hydroinformatics system deals
      with data processing in hydro-environmental sciences. Therefore, any
      software that assists in this regard can be considered to form part of a
      hydroinformatics system.</para>

      <para>Generally, for a system concerned with the prediction of design
      flood quantiles, the following components are expected :</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Databases for the storage, retrieval and display of spatial,
          temporal and statistical data;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Models for prediction of design flood quantiles using the
          information contained in the relevant databases;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Models for generation of data about catchment response to
          storm bursts or complete events; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Decision support systems for enhanced modelling and
          analysis.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>This guide does not discuss all the aspects of a hydroinformatics system, rather the
        purpose of this guide is to introduce the concept of a hydroinformatic system for design
        flood estimation in sufficient detail for design flood analysts. Further information on
        development in and application of hydroinformatics systems can be found in
          <citation>b1_c4_r23+1</citation>, <citation>b1_c4_r18+1</citation>,
          <citation>b1_c4_r10+1</citation>, <citation>b1_c4_r47+1</citation>, and
          <citation>b1_c4_r46+1</citation>.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Data Categories and Issues</title>

    <section>
      <title>General</title>

      <para>There are two broad groups in which hydrologic data can be categorised, as
        follows:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Routine</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Project specific</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Routine data collection includes the standard and widely available
      data, such as streamflow or rainfall data collected on a routine basis
      by major government agencies such as the Bureau of Meteorology. This
      data is collected to provide a long term understanding of Australia’s
      climatic conditions for a representative selection of sites throughout
      the country. These stations are the basis of many flood estimation
      procedures and for projects, though the data is appropriate for many
      other applications.</para>

      <para>Project specific data is collected especially for a particular
      project, and may include observations for major floods in the project
      area and other specific information to assist in a particular
      project.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Data Source Organisations</title>

      <para>Data can be obtained from a wide range of organisations and
      individuals, and effort expended in sourcing and checking all available
      flood data and information is worthwhile. Data can be sources from a
      number of immediately obvious organisations, but can also be found from
      others that may not be so obvious.</para>

      <para>Major water authorities, such as the Bureau of Meteorology and
      state water agencies are immediately obvious sources, and these
      organisations are expected to hold most of the data from formal data
      collection programmes. These agencies generally have well designed
      websites, where data can be reviewed and downloaded, and almost all data
      required for flood investigations can usually be downloaded from these
      agency websites for no charge.</para>

      <para>Other sources include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Local authorities. Councils are responsible for planning
          process and flooding is an important constraint to their planning.
          Councils therefore usually hold historical data on flood levels as
          well as other observations.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Transport agencies. The major state government road and rail
          agencies, as well as privatised road and rail organisations usually
          hold extensive data on flooding as it affects their
          infrastructure.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Other government agencies. Activities of other agencies such
          as those responsible for the primary industries, environment or
          mining are impacted by flooding and they will often hold flood or
          other meteorological data relevant to flooding.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Commercial organisations. Mining or agribusiness companies
          require flood data as it affects their activities and may hold
          relevant data.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Farmers and graziers. The weather is critical to agricultural
          industries and many farmers operate a raingauge and can at least
          provide data for major storm events, but they may also hold flood
          records as they affect their irrigation performance for
          example.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Individuals. Many individuals have an interest in flooding
          especially if it affects them so flood levels and other observations
          can often be obtained from individual property owners.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Others. There may be specific stakeholders who could supply
          flood data for a particular flood investigation, and these can vary
          depending on the actual project and location.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>In general therefore, it is important to search widely for flood
      data during projects. Even anecdotal information will usually be of
      value in setting model parameters and improving local understanding of
      flood conditions.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Data on Historical Events</title>

      <para>This information is particularly important for most projects, and
      can often provide a significant improvement in the quality of the
      analysis. While data on historical floods may be difficult to obtain at
      times, efforts expended in finding and analysing this data is extremely
      valuable.</para>

      <para>There are three types of data referred to here. These are:</para>

      <para><variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Significant events.</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If a major event occurs, it is important for the Bureau of
              Meteorology, Council or other appropriate agency to collect as
              much relevant information as possible soon after the event and
              publish this, even if only in an internal report. Because major
              events occur rarely and unexpectedly, it is often difficult to
              mobilise the resources in time and appropriately. As well it may
              not always be obvious that this data will be useful, so there
              may not be an immediate interest in the data collection. The
              Bureau of Meteorology produce reports following major events and
              these reports usually contain information that is very helpful
              in particular projects.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Historical events.</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Where especially significant events have occurred in past,
              there are often historical records of the event. These records
              may be in reports by relevant government agencies, but often
              there may be useful information in newspaper reports, historical
              societies or museums or information can be gathered from old
              long term residents. Particularly significant events such as the
              Clermont storm of 1916 and the Brisbane floods of 1893 have good
              published data, but other events may be more difficult to
              locate.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>"Routine" flood data.</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>As well as the major events noted above, data on more
              routine (though still large) events can be sourced from
              discussions with residents and other stakeholders. This data is
              usually descriptive, but often actual flood levels can be
              surveyed based on the data held by residents and flood marks on
              buildings and elsewhere. This data is especially useful if there
              has been a major flood in reasonably recent times, and local
              residents can recall details. Photos or videos can be obtained
              as part of these programmes.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist></para>

      <para>The accuracy of this type of data may be extremely variable and
      careful review and checking is essential. The requirements for checking
      are difficult to specify, but the checks should involve review of the
      consistency between individual data points and a general check of
      "reasonableness".</para>

      <para>Usually this type of data is of variable quality, but with careful
      collection and checking, is almost always very valuable in
      implementation of projects.</para>

      <para>As well as "numerical data", other less formal data can be
      collected for historical events. These can include photos or videos
      taken during the flood or eye witness descriptions and accounts. While
      this type of information may not be directly applicable for model
      calibration, it is invaluable in many applications to ensure that the
      model is representing the general flow conditions and
      distribution.</para>

      <para>This type of data is often sourced from local residents during
      consultation programmes, when the flood specialist specifically searches
      for it.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_kt4gt">
    <title>Discussion on Hydrologic Data Issues</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_ih4n7">
      <title>Data Types</title>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_iz4s6">
        <title>General</title>

        <para>Data is defined as the value of qualitative or quantitative
        variables. While this definition is simple, the interaction of data
        with knowledge and data warrants discussion, particularly because the
        concept of the terms data, information and knowledge frequently
        overlap each other.</para>

        <para>The main difference between these terms is in the level of abstraction being
          considered. Data is the lowest level of abstraction, while information is the next level,
          and knowledge is the highest level among all three however, data on its own carries no
          meaning. For data to become information, it must be interpreted and should take on a
          meaning. For example, the height of Mt. Everest is considered generally as 'data', but a
          book on the geological characteristics of Mt. Everest may be considered as 'information',
          while a report containing practical information on the best way to reach the peak of Mt.
          Everest may be considered as 'knowledge'. This distinction between the terms is consistent
          with <citation>b1_c4_r30+1</citation> who uses the concept of a sign to distinguish
          between data and information; data are symbols while information occurs when symbols are
          used to refer to something.</para>

        <para>In the following discussion of types of data, the lowest level
        of abstraction is used, namely data has a value but no meaning.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_thbdf">
        <title>Deterministic</title>

        <para>Deterministic data can be defined as data that has a unique
        value in spatial and temporal dimensions. There are many examples of
        deterministic data used in prediction of design flood quantiles; these
        examples include Digital Elevation Model (DEM) of the catchment, the
        surface roughness parameter, and the continuing loss rate
        parameter.</para>

        <section>
          <title>Probabilistic</title>

          <para>In contrast to deterministic data, probabilistic data does not
          have a unique value, rather it has a range of values described by a
          statistical relationship. Each time a data value is sought from
          probabilistic data, the data value will be different. An example of
          a probabilistic parameter would be the continuing loss rate for use
          in a Monte Carlo simulation; in this example, the continuing loss
          rate will be sampled from distribution of potential continuing loss
          rates, with each sample likely to differ from previous
          samples.</para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_mc30y">
        <title>Spatial</title>

        <para>Data can be unique to a point or cover a spatial extent.
        Additionally, the data may vary in the spatial dimensions but be
        invariant with time. There are many examples of spatial data types in
        design flood prediction, including:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Soil types;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Spatial patterns of rainfall; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Flood surface elevations.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Temporal</title>

        <para>Temporal data, in contrast to spatial data, consists of data
        that varies in the time dimension but, usually, has a fixed location .
        There are many examples of temporal data types in design flood
        prediction, including:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Temporal patterns of rainfall; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Historical flood hydrographs.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_v7t96">
        <title>Meta-data</title>

        <para>For optimal utility in use of data, it is imperative that
        potential users have the possibility of tracing the data passage
        stored in an electronic database to its initial source. Questions such
        as “How were the values obtained?”, “What is the reliability of the
        values?”, “What editing of the data has occurred?” are vital in
        assisting the user to interpret the data in a manner appropriate for
        resolution of the issue under consideration. The development of
        hydroinformatic systems offers the possibility of facilitating access
        to meta-data and enhancing the utility of data. The inclusion of
        meta-data, therefore, is an essential and necessary aspect for
        suitable use of data in a hydroinformatic system.</para>

        <para>A further example of the utility of meta-data for interpretation
        of data is obtained from consideration of the data necessary for
        floodplain management. It is possible that a review of the meta-data
        contained within the hydroinformatic system used for flood management
        of the catchment may result in the finding that all data within the
        hydroinformatic system was derived from application of catchment
        modelling systems and that complementary monitored data was not
        available. The interpretation of the stored data, therefore, will be
        different from what would have been the case if the meta-data were not
        available and it had been assumed that the data were from catchment
        monitoring.</para>

        <para>It is worth noting that prior to the widespread availability of computerised data
          (i.e. hydroinformatic systems), the analyst preparing the recommendation for freeboard
          probably would have been aware of the data sources (i.e. the meta-data) and, therefore,
          would have incorporated this knowledge into the interpretation and ultimate
          recommendation. Consequently, the inclusion of meta-data in the hydroinformatic system
          does not generate new knowledge in itself but merely incorporates knowledge currently
          available only in a non-electronic form.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_679o2">
      <title>The Data Cycle</title>

      <para>Fundamental to the concept of hydroinformatics is the management of data and its passage
        from the time it is generated to the time when it is used or presented to stakeholders and
        other interested parties. During this time, data can be considered to pass through a number
        of conceptual components. The passage of data through these components is not uniform and
        linear, rather will pass through the cycle in a random and nonuniform manner. The passage of
        the data and the components through which it passes, can be considered as the data cycle
          <citation>b1_c4_r29</citation>.</para>

      <para>Conceptually, the data cycle is analogous to the hydrologic cycle
      where the passage of data through the data cycle can be considered
      analogous to the passage of water through the hydrologic cycle. Also,
      similar to the hydrologic cycle, the data cycle can be considered in a
      systems format with the data flowing between different
      components.</para>

      <para>If the data necessary for prediction of design flood
      characteristics is considered in this manner, then it is apparent that
      the components of the data cycle are relevant to the design flood
      problem. Hence, the concepts associated with hydroinformatics and the
      data cycle are relevant to the prediction of design flood
      quantiles.</para>

      <para>One of the conceptual views of components forming the data cycle is shown in <xref
          linkend="b1_ch4_f_ec7nz"/>. The conceptual components shown in the figure are Generation,
        Editing, Storage, Analysis and Presentation. Also, as indicated , there is a circularity in
        the flow of information, which arises from analysis of data resulting in generation of new
        data that needs to be edited and stored in a manner similar to previous data. Considered in
        this manner, an individual component within a hydroinformatic system is both, a supplier and
        the data user.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_ec7nz">
        <title>The Data Cycle</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="30%" fileref="../../figures/1001.png"
              scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Within each of these conceptual components of the data cycle, the
      pertinent aspects are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Generation</emphasis> - In this component the data
          is <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151007T160603+1100" comment="from where?"?>sourced<?oxy_comment_end ?>;
          this can be restated as this is the component where the data is
          created or collected. Furthermore, it is the component where data is
          recognised relevant for prediction of the design flood
          characteristics.</para>

          <para>For example, in a catchment monitoring program aimed at collecting discharge data,
            the necessary steps, as discussed by <citation>b6_c2_r140+1</citation>, would be:</para>

          <para><itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>sensing the phenomenon;</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>recording the value of the phenomenon; and</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>transmission of these values to a storage repository.
                This storage depository may be centralised or distributed
                according to the needs of the stakeholders involved.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>

          <para>Further details on data creation through monitoring programs
          are presented <xref linkend="b1_ch4_s_brxk2"/>.</para>

          <para>In addition to the data generation through technical
          approaches, there are other methods of data generation, where data
          can be collected through social surveys, census surveys, and
          historical reviews for example. This data, similar to the technical
          data, will require management using the concepts of hydroinformatics
          and the data cycle.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Editing</emphasis> - An important aspect of data is
          knowledge of its accuracy (sometimes referred to as its uncertainty)
          and original source. Prior to insertion into a database, it is
          necessary to define these parameters; in other words, the relevant
          meta-data has to be attached to the data. The term meta-data is used
          here to describe the background material about the data which is
          referred to sometimes as the data about the data. Meta-data is
          discussed further in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_s_v7t96"/>.</para>

          <para>For monitored data, items of primary relevance include issues
          regrading how the data was observed, the reliability of monitoring
          (for example, the sensitivity of the sensing equipment, the
          robustness of the rating table for monitored discharges, the
          detection limit of contaminants for water quality constituents), and
          editing changes to the data and the philosophy behind these changes.
          These meta-data are of great importance for catchment monitoring
          since at least <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151007T161013+1100" comment="Do we have a percentage for this?"?>some
          <?oxy_comment_end ?>of the monitored data will be inaccurate; in
          other words, some of the monitored data will contain undiscovered
          errors.</para>

          <para>In a similar manner, data generated by catchment modelling systems needs to be
            defined by the software (and version) used, the input data inclusive of adopted
            parameter values or distribution of parameter values. It is should be noted that input
            data covers both the parameters necessary for operation of the software and the data
            necessary for implementation of the modelling system. Therefore, one can conveniently
            state that editing of data generated from catchment modelling systems, i.e. the
            attachment of meta-data, should be sufficient to define how the data was generated and
            enable replication.</para>

          <para>The step involving data editing is a vital part of the data
          cycle and should prioritised above data insertion into relevant
          database and its subsequent usage by others not involved in its
          generation. The inclusion of the meta-data and its availability to
          future users is becoming increasingly important as the availability
          of digital data increases and data users become more remote from the
          generation of the data.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Storage</emphasis> - The storage of the data is
          performed in this component of the data cycle. In general, the
          storage of data will comprise the insertion of the data into a
          digital database. It is important to note that the manner of data
          storage should ensure that its retrieval is both practical and
          feasible. If retrieval is not easy, there is no addition to the data
          available for design flood estimation.</para>

          <para>There are many different forms of data stored in a database
          which in turn influences the data storage design. Commonly, spatial
          databases are referred to as Geographic Information Systems (GIS)
          while databases used to store temporal data can be referred to as a
          Time-Series Managers (TSM). These computerised storage facilities
          have superseded, in general, the previous techniques based on data
          storage through maps and charts. There are a large number of
          alternative GISs and TSMs that can be used for data storage. It is
          not the purpose of Australian Rainfall and Runoff to recommend a
          particular GIS or TSM but rather to note their use for storing data
          relevant to design flood estimation.</para>

          <para>Since 2008, the Bureau of Meteorology (BoM) has been responsible for delivering
            water data throughout Australia. As part of this role, the Bureau of Meteorology has
            been collecting water data from more than 200 organisations across the nation and is
            using this data to report on water availability, condition and use in a nationally
            consistent way. To facilitate this role, the Bureau of Meteorology is building the
            Australian Water Resources Information System (AWRIS) as a secure repository for water
            data and as a means to deliver high quality water data to all Australians.</para>

          <para>The aim of AWRIS is to allow the Bureau of Meteorology to process and publish water
            data in new and powerful ways. The Bureau of Meteorology will be able to merge
            historical water data records with current observations to suit a variety of user needs.
            By spatially enabling this data we will be able to query and report the data in many
            different ways. Data stored in AWRIS will be delivered to the web, to mobile devices and
            various hydrologic forecasting systems to be operated by the Bureau of
            Meteorology.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Analysis</emphasis> - It is common that analysis of
          data will be required. The analysis techniques form this component
          of the data cycle. The steps involved in this component can be
          summarised as data retrieval, and data usage. It is worth noting
          that the data obtained from the analysis could be considered as part
          of the data generation component. Hence there is some similarity
          between the generation and analysis components.</para>

          <para>There are many alternative analysis techniques. For design flood estimation
            purposes, the most commonly used analysis techniques would be statistical modelling (for
            example, Flood Frequency Analysis) and catchment response modelling using a catchment
            modelling system. Both of these techniques result in the generation of additional data
            that, in turn, requires editing and storage.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Presentation</emphasis> - The final conceptual
          component is the presentation component. Within this step, the
          stored or analysed data is presented in a manner that is
          understandable to relevant stakeholders. The technical level of the
          presented data would not be constant for all presentations but,
          rather, would vary with the technical expertise of the audience. The
          important point about the presentation of data is that it is
          presented in a manner that is clear and precise for the
          audience.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Hydrologic Data</title>

    <para>This section has an outline of the types of data that is needed for
    hydrology and hydraulic analysis required for flood estimation and the
    issues associated with each type.</para>

    <para>The data types that are needed are as follows, with discussion or
    each in the following sections.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Rainfall;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Other precipitation types;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Water levels;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Streamflow;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Catchment data, including topography, survey, digital terrain, land use and planning
          data; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Other hydrologic data, including tidal information,
        meteorological, sediment movement and deposition and water
        quality.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>This data needs to be collected, reviewed for completeness and
    accuracy and then archived and disseminated to practitioners as required.
    Discussion on specific details is included below.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_kc69e">
    <title>Rainfall Data</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_n0qqu">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>Rainfall is a primary data input for almost all water resources
      projects, and rainfall data forms the basic input to the development of
      the rainfall chapters in "Australian Rainfall and Runoff" as well as a
      key input to other components.</para>

      <para>The Bureau of Meteorology is the primary agency responsible for
      collection of rainfall data in Australia, but there are many other
      agencies which have significant records of rainfall data. The other
      agencies include local authorities and water agencies, but some
      organisations have particular local data programmes that may be useful
      in specific projects. As well rainfall data can be collected from
      various sources for major historical floods as discussed further
      below.</para>

      <para>In many major flood events, it is often valuable to look for
      unofficial rain gauges where data has been collected by members of the
      public. In rural areas, most property owners have rain gauges and they
      are also not unusual in towns and cities.</para>

      <para>Data endorsed by the Bureau can be regarded as accurate, but some
      checks for consistency and the reasonableness of the data should also be
      carried out. In particular, tests for missing (accumulated) data need to
      be considered but it is also possible that gauge overflows mean that the
      larger events are not well measured. Data from other agencies may be
      also of a high standard, but these agencies sometimes have poorer
      quality data. More careful checks are needed on this data. Data
      collected at unofficial rain gauges operated by members of the public
      may be sometimes of very poor quality, with poor exposure for example,
      and records from these sources must be checked very carefully. However
      the value of this data means that it is often worth further analysis to
      ensure that useful data is not discarded. Data from unofficial gauges is
      especially important for major events where it can be used to supplement
      information from official gauges.</para>

      <para>Most publicly available rainfall data should be available through the Bureau of
        Meteorology’s AWRIS database.</para>

      <para>The types of rainfall data that may be useful include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Daily rainfall records; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Pluviometer records.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Normally data endorsed by the Bureau of Meteorology can be relied upon. However, users
        should check the data for consistency and logic, before application. In particular, tests
        for missing or accumulated data need to be considered, along with assessing the potential
        for gauge overflows.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_pq853">
      <title>Rainfall Observations</title>

      <para>The standard instrument for manual measurement of rainfall is the 203 mm rain gauge (see
          <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_vx3ga"/>). In essence, this instrument is a circular funnel, with
        a diameter of 203 mm and the top located 0.3 m above the ground surface,that collects the
        rain into a graduated and calibrated cylinder. Any excess precipitation is captured in the
        outer metal cylinder. Most manually read gauges are used for daily observations.</para>

      <para>Daily rainfall is nominally measured each day at 9:00 am local time. At most rainfall
        sites, observations are taken by volunteers who send in a monthly record of daily
        precipitation at the end of each month. A subset of observers at strategic locations, as
        well as automatic weather stations, send observations electronically to the Bureau of
        Meteorology each day. Very few stations have a complete unbroken record of climate
        information. Missed observations may be due to observer illness or equipment failure. If,
        for some reason, an observation is unable to be made, the next observation is recorded as an
        accumulation, since the rainfall has been accumulating in the rain gauge since the last
        reading.</para>

      <para><figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_vx3ga">
          <title>Standard Rain Gauge (Source: Bureau of Meteorology)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentdepth="200%" scalefit="1" width="100%"  fileref="../../figures/1009.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>An alternative to the manual measurement is to use a
      continuous recording rain gauge resulting in either an analogue chart
      record or a digital record. While some chart recorders remain in
      operation, the more common form of continuous rain gauges is the Tipping
      Bucket Rain Gauge (see <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_6l2nu"/>). Like the
      manual rain gauge, the aperture of the funnel for a TBRG is 203
      mm.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_6l2nu">
        <title>Tipping Bucket Rain Gauge (Source: Bureau of Meteorology)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="200%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="../../figures/1010.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Advantages of the TBRG are
        <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151007T171701+1100" comment="By whom?"?>claimed
        <?oxy_comment_end?>to include unattended, automatic operation, and the ability to record the
        rate at which the rain is falling. Operation of a TBRG is based on the generation of an
        electronic pulse when the water volume collected in the bucket results in bucket tipping.
        While the usual volume of water collected is equivalent to a depth of 0.2 mm, some early
        TBRGs required a depth of 0.5 mm before the bucket would tip. When analysing data from
        TBRGs, users should check the bucket size to ensure the validity of the analysis; this
        information should be available from the meta-data attached to the recorded data.</para>

      <para>Traditionally rainfall is measured to the nearest 0.2 mm (prior to 1974 records were in
        Imperial units and measurements were to the nearest 1 point, approximately 0.25 mm).
        However, in recent years some observations have been reported to 0.1 mm. Hence, users check
        the meta-data attached to the data records to note the measurement accuracy rather than the
        inferred accuracy from the database records.</para>

      <para>The Bureau of Meteorology undertake a number of quality control processes to detect
        errors in the rainfall data forwarded from the many volunteer and professional readers. This
        data checking includes:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Values that extend beyond what is considered realistic;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Inconsistent observations (for example, high rainfall combined
          with clear skies); and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Discontinuous or abrupt changes in values over a short period
          of time.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>While the Bureau of Meteorology undertakes these checks it is recommended that
        individual users ensure that their rainfall data is suitable for purpose. This may entail
        undertaking additional quality control processes.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Review of Rainfall Data</title>

      <para>While rainfall data is frequently regarded as reliable and
      accurate, there are some issues with the accuracy and consistency of
      rainfall data and these need to be considered while applying data to
      practical applications. Issues often encountered are.</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Accumulated records. Rainfall data, especially from daily read
          gauges may have missing days of record. In some cases, these missing
          days are simply not recorded while on other occasions, the total for
          a number of days is accumulated. This occurs since thee rainfall is
          collected in the raingauge and several days record are recorded on a
          single day at the end of the accumulated period. These records need
          to be reviewed in conjunction with records from neighbouring gauges
          and adjustments made as necessary. Accumulated records may give an
          excessively high daily record for the day where the records are
          accumulated.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Missing data. In some cases, for both daily read and
          continuous gauges, there may be missing periods of record. In this
          case, the record should be reviewed carefully in conjunction with
          records from neighbouring catchments and appropriate adjustments
          made.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Gauge quality. Rain gauges operated by the Bureau of Meteorology are expected to
            meet the Bureau of Meteorolgy’s standards, however other gauges, especially privately
            operated gauges which may be used to supplement rainfall records for major events, may
            not meet the Bureau of Meteorolgy’s stringent standards. Where privately operated gauges
            appear inconsistent with nearby stations, the siting of the gauge needs consideration
            and it may be necessary to remove the gauge from the analysis.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_6l32u">
      <title>Rainfall Databases</title>

      <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>

        <para>The Bureau of Meteorology has developed a number of databases for storage of rainfall
          data and its meta-data. These databases include:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Australian Data Archive for Meteorology (ADAM);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Site Meta-data (SitesDB); and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Australian Water Resources Information System
            (AWRIS).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Australian Data Archive for Meteorology</title>

        <para>The Australian Data Archive for Meteorology (ADAM) stores meteorological observations
          from observing systems over mainland Australia and from neighbouring islands, the
          Antarctic, ships and ocean buoys that are operated by the Bureau of Meteorology. It also
          stores a limited number of observations from other local and international sources to
          support research and improve Bureau of Meteorology services.</para>

        <para>The most common observation type stored in ADAM is daily rainfall. Dating back to the
          mid-1800s, these total more than 200 million records from a network of over 16 000
          locations. Other types of weather data that are stored in ADAM include air temperature,
          humidity, wind velocity, sunshine, cloud cover, soil temperatures, upper atmospheric wind
          and temperature, and observed weather phenomena (for example, thunder, frost and
          dust).</para>

        <para>To support this large database, the ADAM system contains
        supporting database tables and software tools required to enter,
        retrieve and quality control data efficiently. A set of detailed rules
        and procedures ensure consistent treatment of information.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Site Meta-data</title>

        <para>Meta-data about the Bureau of Meteorology’s rainfall stations is stored in 'SitesDB'.
          It contains meta-data for each of the Bureau of Meteorology operated rainfall stations and
          includes, as a minimum, the following information:</para>

        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Rainfall station name and number;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Rainfall station location in latitude and
              longitude;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Rainfall station elevation; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Details of the current instrumentation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>However, for many stations the following meta-data
        are available also:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Maps showing location of rainfall station;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Schematic of rainfall station layout;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Photos of rainfall station;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Photos for each of the four main compass points showing
            siting, clearance and proximity to trees, buildings and other
            factors likely to influence measurement of rainfall;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>History of instrumentation installed at site; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Record of dates of site visits, maintenance undertaken,
            problems identified and resolution adopted.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Australian Water Resources Information System</title>

        <para>The Bureau of Meteorology is building the AWRIS as a secure repository for water data
          and as a means to deliver high quality water information to all Australians. Under the
          Water Regulations 2008, the Bureau of Meteorology receives information about river
          discharges and groundwater levels, water volumes in storage, water quality in rivers and
          aquifers, water use and restrictions, water entitlements and water trades. The intention
          is that AWRIS will store and manage this data in a central database.</para>

        <para>To achieve this aim, AWRIS is a powerful hydroinformatic system capable of receiving,
          standardising, organising and interpreting water data from across the nation. The
          Australian Hydrological Geospatial Fabric (also known as the Geofabric refer to <xref
            linkend="b1_ch4_s_2cgbg"/>) is a vital component of AWRIS. It is a specialised
          Geographic Information System that enables a spatial context to the data stored within
          AWRIS. With this spatial context, the utility of water data of the data will be enhanced
          through ease of access. Additionally, the Geofabric encodes the spatial connections and
          relationships between most of Australia’s hydrological features including rivers, dams,
          lakes, aquifers, diversions, supply channels, drains and monitoring points. Distribution
          of the data stored in AWRIS is through the Bureau of Meteorology website and Water
          Online.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Gridded Rainfall Data</title>

        <para>In addition to the recorded rainfall data from rain gauges located in and near the
          catchment, the Bureau of Meteorology publish a grid of daily rainfall data for the whole
          of Australia covering a period from 1900 to date. This is a component of the Australian
          Water Availability Project (AWAP) <citation>b1_c4_r36,b1_c4_r45</citation>. This grid is
          at a resolution of approximately 5 km (0.05 degrees) and includes daily rainfall value for
          each grid cell for each day from 1900. The quality of the grid points varies depending on
          the period of interest since there is a better coverage of gauges in more recent times.
          The quality also varies depending on the location, with less accurate records for
          locations with high rainfall gradients and for less populated regions where there is a
          more sparse gauge density.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_cuun3">
      <title>Application of Rainfall Data for Flood Estimation</title>

      <para>Rainfall data is a critical input to the development of ARR and is
      also essential in many flood applications, with two principal
      applications.</para>

      <para>Firstly extensive statistical analysis of rainfall data has been carried out to prepare
        the Intensity Frequency Duration (IFD) input applied to many assessments. Details of the
        rainfall data analysed for the IFD development is discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch3"
        />.</para>

      <para>Secondly rainfall data is applied for analysis of historical
      events for flood analysis, and in this application, recorded rainfall
      data is required for these historical events.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Other Precipitation Types</title>

    <para>Other sources of precipitation include snow, hail or dew. These are
    usually a relatively minor component of the water balance in Australia,
    but there are some locations and occasions where this data may be of
    interest or value for particular projects.</para>

    <para>In parts of Australia, snow may contribute a significant amount of
    precipitation affecting water resources, but this is not common.</para>

    <para>The Bureau of Meteorology and specialist agencies in mountainous and
    southern regions collect this data, and use it for specific studies and
    supply it on request.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_x3gxf">
    <title>Water Levels</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_ug6gk">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>Water level data is a principal data type, and as well as being
      used in its own right, is also used to calculate streamflow data.</para>

      <para>A major source of water level data is at formal stream flow
      stations operated by the major water authorities. This data is usually
      converted into streamflow data as discussed further below, but there are
      some locations where only water level data is collected or published.
      Water authorities publish data and it is usually freely available. The
      published data usually has an indication of the accuracy and
      completeness, but some checking is needed.</para>

      <para>In addition, there are many stations, especially those operated by
      the Bureau of Meteorology and local authorities, mainly for flood
      forecasting and warning, where stream flows are not calculated and water
      levels only are available. The larger agencies usually make this data
      available, sometimes on line.</para>

      <para>Water level data may be in the form of continuous records
      monitored by an automatic recorder or as manually read records. Most of
      the earlier records were manually read at staff gauges, but many of
      these are now replaced by automatic water level recorders. Manually read
      records were usually recorded once a day with supplementary more
      frequent readings during flood events. Because of the rapid response of
      many streams, the manually read records may not provide the peak levels
      and may even totally miss short duration flood events. Manually read
      records are usually better quality for large slowly responding streams
      and this data can be used with confidence, but smaller catchments may be
      significantly in error. More often than not, manually read records show
      smaller flood peaks and lower discharges than automatic recorders.
      However practically all records from before the 1960s are manually read,
      so this data forms the only available information for long term
      stations. Therefore data from manually read stations is usually the only
      available record and has to be used, but careful consideration is needed
      to make sure the records are interpreted correctly.</para>

      <para>In addition to the formal water level records, informal records
      can also be obtained usually following a major flood event. These
      records are usually obtained by a Council or other stakeholder who sends
      surveyors on-site soon after an event to survey flood marks to indicate
      the maximum water levels reached. This data provides an indication of
      the variation of water levels across the floodplain and an indication of
      the flow patterns. The quality of this data may sometimes be
      questionable, and the records need to be carefully checked. These checks
      can include checking for consistency and reasonableness as well as a
      review of the reliability of the agency or person who has collected the
      data. When this type of data is collected, it is important that the
      records include careful descriptions of the circumstances of the
      collection and an indication of the expected accuracy.</para>

      <para>Common concerns with this data is the level of observed debris
      marks, whether the water levels have been collected at the peak level of
      the flood and the source of the water level, either local drainage or
      backwater for example. Therefore while very useful data can be obtained,
      it must be carefully reviewed otherwise the data may lead to incorrect
      conclusions in the resulting analysis.</para>

      <para>However water levels are often only used as the source of
      streamflow or discharge data, as discussed below, and while water levels
      are useful in many applications, streamflow data is usually of far
      greater value for many water resources studies.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_lfdv5">
      <title>Historical Flood Level Data</title>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_qhfqb">
        <title>Continuous Water Level Recorders</title>

        <para>Continuous water level recorders measure water levels at nominated intervals and,
          where a rating curve (stage-discharge relationship) exists, these can be converted to
          discharge. Flow is derived from stage using a stage-discharge relationship and it is
          critical that maximum gauged flow is known so that the extent of extrapolation underlying
          the ‘recorded’ flow is clear (refer to <xref linkend="b1_ch4_s_brxk2"/>). These records
          are very important as,
          <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151007T170059+1100" comment="What happens if they are not intact?"?>if
          intact, they will show the complete hydrograph <?oxy_comment_end?>(i.e. the rise, peak and
          fall of the flood). Historical records for continuous water level recorders are typically
          stored by government agencies and one needs to be careful with the datum of these records
          as may not be to AHD (Australian Height Datum) and some conversion may be required. In
          case of large events, these recorders can fail and the data needs to be inspected for
          'flat' areas, which may indicate failure of the gauge or they may rise steeply in case of
          a landslip occurs. Typically, each stage record has an accuracy code assigned and these
          should be noted before use.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_v4u99">
        <title>Maximum Height Gauges</title>

        <para>Maximum height gauges simply record the peak flood level reached
        during a particular event. Again, data is often held by a government
        agency and one needs to be careful while converting the gauge datum to
        AHD. Failure of these gauges is difficult to detect as they are simply
        recording the peak level, and if the gauge fails before the peak of an
        event, it may still provide a 'peak level' value, which will refer the
        flood level reached prior to the peak at the time of gauge failure.
        Time of peak is sometimes also available, however, it is recommended
        that this is checked to ensure that the peak was recorded at
        approximately the correct time.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_yn46c">
        <title>Peak Level Records</title>

        <para>If the flood event has been of a significant nature, it is likely that stakeholders
          have been able to collect some actual flood levels at a variety of locations. This is
          typically done by mobilising agency staff to place markers (paint, stakes, nails,
          surveyor’s tape) either indicating maximum flood extent (e.g. spray paint on a road, stake
          in ground) or peak flood levels (e.g. nail in a tree). Ideally, each marker should have
          the time and the staff member’s name recorded at the marker site. Following the event,
          surveyors can measure <emphasis>x,y</emphasis> location data and z flood level data at
          each of these markers. It is also useful to photograph the site and to record ground
          level. Surveyors should also include the time at which the markers were placed, by whom
          and type (e.g. nail in tree) in their meta-data. Residents often also record peak flood
          levels, particularly if the flood has inundated any buildings on their property. Post
          event flood levels can be collected by residents by a questionnaire and reliable marks
          surveyed. An assessment as to the reliability of these levels can only be made after
          viewing the marks themselves and noting the care with which the recording has been made.
          Have different event dates been recorded by the resident or is the resident relying on
          memory to determine one event from another? Has the location of the marks changed in any
          way since the record was made? For example, if the marks are made near the front door, has
          the house been raised at any time since? Detailed discussion with the resident can often
          unearth important details otherwise unknown.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_gjizs">
        <title>Debris Marks</title>

        <para>Debris marks are a typical means of measuring the maximum flood
        level and are best measured as soon as possible after the event, when
        the debris or scum line is still fresh. This ensures that the mark is
        attributable to the event of interest and has not been subsequently
        degraded.</para>

        <para>Debris marks can be inaccurate for a number of reasons. They can be influenced by
          dynamic hydraulic effects such as waves, eddies, pressure surges, bores or transient
          effects, which may not be accounted for in a hydraulic model. For example, if the debris
          mark is located within a region of fast flowing floodwater it is possible that the
          floodwater has pushed the debris up against an obstacle, lodging it at a higher level than
          the surrounding flood level. More common though is the fact that debris often lodges at a
          level lower than the peak flood level. The reason for this is that for debris to be
          deposited it needs to have somewhere to lodge and this elevation is not always at the peak
          flood level. For example, the classic place for debris lodgement is a barbwire fence with
          horizontal strands of wire. If the flood level almost reached the top strand of barbwire,
          debris will not lodge in the top strand but rather on the second from top strand, which
          may be about 0.3 m lower than the peak flood level. It is recommended that the surveyor be
          asked to record as much information as possible about the mark itself (e.g. debris on
          barbwire fence spacing 0.35 m) so the modeller is able to consider reasons for
          discrepancies in the calibration process, if they arise.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_yiylp">
        <title>Anecdotal Information</title>

        <para>Anecdotal information is usually qualitative in nature but can be very valuable in
          determining flow behaviour and subsequently verifying that the flood analysis represents
          these observations in the hydraulic modelling undertaken. Photograph and video evidence
          can also be beneficial in this regard and can often assist long-term residents remember
          details of historical floods long past. The flood modeller will need to be mindful of the
          fact that memories can sometimes fade or be skewed by other events that have occurred
          particularly when several floods occur close together. In addition, information providers
          may not be able to provide unbiased information due to a vested interest (e.g. pride or
          financial gain etc) in the level to which an historic event reached. Again, detailed
          discussions with residents and stakeholders can provide the modeller with a general feel
          for the reliability of all anecdotal evidence. Inconsistent facts have to be identified
          and discarded and discrepancies have to be studied and explained.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Application of Water Level Data in analysis</title>

      <para>The principal application of observed water level data in flood
      projects is in the calibration of hydraulic models and to ensure that
      the models represent reality.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_brxk2">
    <title>Streamflow Data</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_xk90m">
      <title>Introduction to Streamflow Records</title>

      <para>Streamflow data is one of the most important data requirements for
      individual projects and for development of regional procedures. As noted
      above, streamflow data is calculated from records of water levels,
      usually collected by major water authorities. The water levels are used
      to calculate streamflow data by the application of a stage-discharge
      relationship (rating curve) developed for the station. Continuous
      records of streamflow can be calculated from the continuous records of
      water levels. The stage-discharge relationship is often uncertain and
      application is one of the major sources of uncertainly in the
      data.</para>

      <para>As with water level data, the major water authorities have well
      established systems for storage and dissemination of their streamflow
      data. This data is usually available from these agencies, often on line,
      and almost always free of charge. The data dissemination systems are
      well organised and data can be supplied accurately and quickly.</para>

      <para>Different agencies around Australia maintain appropriate databases
      of their records. These systems include considerable detail on the type,
      accuracy and reliability of the gauged data including rating curve
      accuracy, periods of missing record, number of gaugings and variation in
      rating curves. In many cases, the system includes photos and maps of the
      station. This is valuable information and is valuable to ensure that the
      data is used most effectively. The water agencies are state based and
      there are differences between the states. Their on-line documentation
      should be consulted to ensure that the quality and limitations of the
      record are understood.</para>

      <para>There are few other agencies that collect streamflow data, because
      of the difficulties of calculating the flows from water levels. Where
      there are other sources of this data, it is usually limited as a part of
      the research project for a limited duration and locality, and the data
      is sometimes difficult to obtain. This data is also usually only for a
      short period of record, but sometimes, it may include an important
      event. However it is also possible for practitioners to calculate
      discharge records from water level data using individually developed
      rating curves that can be prepared from hydraulic models or other
      theoretical methods.</para>

      <para>There are many checks needed when analysing streamflow data. The
      principal check is on the accuracy and completeness of the
      stage-discharge relationship. This can be checked by assessment of the
      number of discharge measurements that have been taken and the maximum
      discharge (as compared to the maximum recorded water level). As well the
      variability in the stage-discharge curve indicates that the relationship
      has changed over time and therefore may be less reliable for particular
      events. The stage-discharge relationship may be poor for the lower flows
      because of regular changes in low flow controls. As well it may also be
      poor at higher flows because of the lack of discharge measurements at
      higher flows. There are difficulties in extrapolation of the
      relationships, where there is a change in conditions, for example where
      the river overtops the banks.</para>

      <para>Different gauges in the same catchment can be compared to test for
      consistency and the water balance and there is a range of other checks
      that can be carried out. Having more than one gauge in a catchment
      though is not particularly common.</para>

      <para>Poor quality streamflow data may mean poor quality model
      calibration, so a high standard for checks of data is important. However
      it is noted that it is very difficult to check the accuracy of the
      discharge records for a station, and poor quality data may be
      accepted.</para>

      <para>Streamflow records are the basic data source used in developing
      reliable surface water resources because the records provide data on the
      availability of streamflow and its variability in time and space. The
      records, therefore, are used in planning and design of surface water
      related projects, and are also used in management or operation of
      projects after construction of the projects is complete.</para>

      <para>In addition, streamflow records are used for calibrating catchment modelling systems
        that, for example, are used for predicting flood behaviour and for predicting hazards
        arising from design flood events. Records of flood events obtained at gauging stations also
        serve as one of the basic data sources for design flood estimation, necessary for designing
        bridges, culverts, dams and flood control reservoirs, floodplain delineation and flood
        warning systems; and in development of methods applicable to locations where data is not
        available.</para>

      <para>It is essential, to have valid records for a full range of
      streamflows. The streamflow records referred to above primarily are
      continuous records of discharge at stream-gauging stations; a gauging
      station being a site instrumented and operated so that a continuous
      record of stage and discharge can be obtained. A network of continuous
      recording gauging stations, however, often is augmented by auxiliary
      networks of partial record stations to fill a particular need for
      streamflow data at a relatively low cost. For example, an auxiliary
      network of sites, instrumented and operated to provide only
      instantaneous peak level data, is often established.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_ptlni">
      <title>General Stream Gauging Procedures</title>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_3ufed">
        <title>Introduction</title>

        <para>Gauging stations are installed where the need for streamflow
        records at a site has been recognised. This gauging station will
        comprise of instruments for measuring the river stage and a location
        selected to take advantage of the best locally available conditions
        and discharge measurement and for developing a stable stage-discharge
        relationship, sometimes referred to as a rating curve. While there are
        instruments that simultaneously monitor river stage and discharge, the
        more common instrumentation requires the use of a stage-discharge
        relationship to convert the monitored river stage into an equivalent
        river discharge rate. Artificial controls such as low weirs or flumes
        are constructed at some stations to stabilise the stage-discharge
        relationships in the low discharge range. These control structures are
        calibrated by stage and discharge measurements in the field.</para>

        <para>Selection of the gauging station site and the development of the
        stage-discharge relationship are important components in the
        management of a gauging station and hence the discussion herein will
        focus on these aspects of management of a gauging station. While there
        are many other aspects important in management of a gauging station,
        these two aspects have the most significant impact on prediction of
        design flood characteristics.</para>

        <para>It is rare to find an ideal site for a gauging station and it is more common that the
          limitations of a site must be considered with respect to the desired data from the site.
          There are numerous guides on gauging station site selection with the aim of these guides
          on ensuring the data is reliable and criteria suggested by
            <citation>b1_c4_r48+1</citation> are often adopted. When applying data recorded at a
          stream gauging station, the practitioner must review details of the station carefully and
          make an assessment of the quality and limitations of the record.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_yw6bd">
        <title>Data Collected at a Gauging Station</title>

        <para>There are many different approaches to collection of data at a
        stream gauging station and flood investigations are not necessarily
        the principal objective of any particular gauging station. As stated
        previously, the purpose of a gauging station is to collect data about
        the time history of discharge at that point in the catchment drainage
        network. In general, the data collected consists of the gauge heights,
        sometimes referred to as stages. These gauge heights are used as the
        independent variable in a stage-discharge relationship to estimate the
        discharge at that point in time. Reliability of the discharge record
        is dependent on the accuracy and precision of the gauge-height record
        as well as the accuracy and precision of the stage-discharge
        relationship.</para>

        <para>Gauge-height records may be obtained by systematic observation
        of a non-recording gauge, or with automatic water level sensors and
        recorders. Furthermore, various types of transmitting systems are used
        to relay gauge-height information from remote gauging stations to
        storage databases.</para>

        <para>New technology, especially in the field of electronics and
        computer based management of field data, has led to a number of
        innovations in sensing, recording, and transmitting gauge height data.
        In the past most gauging stations used floats in stilling wells as the
        primary method of sensing gauge height and these are still in common
        use today. However, the current trend is toward the use of submersible
        or non-submersible pressure transducers which do not require a
        stilling well. Additionally, electronic data recorders and various
        transmission systems are being used more extensively.</para>

        <para>Details of the instruments and associated structures for a stream gauging station are
          outlined by <citation>b1_c4_r48+1</citation>, <citation>b1_c4_r49+1</citation>, and
            <citation>b1_c4_r44+1</citation> and hence are not repeated herein. Nonetheless, users
          of stream discharge data for design flood estimation should ensure that they are
          conversant with the instruments and structures employed for the collection of streamflow
          data.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_id9c8">
        <title>Stage-Discharge Relationships</title>

        <para>The conversion of a record of gauge-height to a record of
        discharge is through use of a stage-discharge relationship. The
        physical element or combination of elements in the stream channel or
        floodplain that maintains the relation is known as a control. One
        major classification of controls differentiates between section
        controls and channel controls. Another classification differentiates
        between natural and artificial controls. Artificial controls are
        structures built for the specific purpose of controlling the
        stage-discharge relation, such as a weir, flume, or small dam. A third
        classification differentiates between complete, partial and compound
        controls.</para>

        <para>The two attributes of a satisfactory control are stability and sensitivity. If the
          control is stable the stage-discharge relationship will be stable. If the control is
          subject to change, the stage-discharge relationship will be subject to change and frequent
          discharge measurements will be required for the continual re-calibration of the
          stage-discharge relationship. This increases the operating cost of the gauging station and
          also increases the uncertainty of streamflow records extracted from the database.
          Additional data about controls can be found in <citation>b1_c4_r34+1</citation>.</para>

        <para>The traditional way in which a stage discharge relationship is derived for a
          particular gauging station is the measurement of discharge at convenient times.
          Traditionally, this measurement is undertaken with a current meter measuring the discharge
          velocity at enough points over the river cross-section so that the discharge rate can be
          obtained for that particular stage. By taking such measurements for a number of different
          stages and corresponding discharges over a period of time, a number of points can be
          plotted on a stage-discharge diagram, and a curve drawn through those points, giving what
          is hoped to be a unique relationship between stage and discharge, the stage discharge
          relationship, as shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_tlc1u"/>. This rating curve is used in a
          manner whereby the routinely measured stages are converted to discharges by assuming that
          the corresponding discharge can be obtained from the curve.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_tlc1u">
          <title>Typical Rating Curve</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1012.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>There are a number of factors which might cause the rating curve not to give the
          actual discharge, some of which will vary with time. <citation>b1_c4_r6+1</citation>
          quotes <citation>b1_c4_r50</citation> as describing a list of factors affecting the rating
          curve, or what he called a <emphasis>shifting control</emphasis>. These include:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The channel and hydraulic control changing as a result of
            modification due to dredging, bridge construction, or vegetation
            growth;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Sediment transport - where the bed is in motion, which can have an effect over a
              single flood event, because the effective bed roughness can change during the event.
              As a flood increases, any bed forms present will tend to become larger and increase
              the effective roughness, so that friction is greater after the flood peak than before,
              so that the corresponding discharge for a given stage height will be less after the
              peak. This will also contribute to a flood event showing a looped curve on a stage
              discharge diagram as shown on <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_5gqn1"/>. Both
                <citation>b1_c4_r51+1</citation> and <citation>b1_c4_r33+1</citation> have examined
              this phenomenon and presented approaches for dealing with this issue;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Backwater effects - changes in the conditions downstream
            such as the construction of a dam or flooding in the next waterway
            downstream;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Unsteadiness - in general the discharge will change rapidly
            during a flood, and the slope of the water surface will be
            different from that for a constant stage, depending on whether the
            discharge is increasing or decreasing. The effect of this is for
            the trajectory of a flood event to appear as a loop on a
            stage-discharge diagram as shown in <xref
            linkend="b1_ch4_f_5gqn1"/>;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Variable channel storage - where the stream overflows onto
            floodplains during high discharges, giving rise to different
            slopes and to unsteadiness effects; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Vegetation - changing the roughness and hence changing the
            stage-discharge relationship.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_5gqn1">
          <title>Loop in Rating Curve</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1002.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>In addition to these generic problems associated with the use of
        rating curves, there are several problems associated with the use of
        rating curves for prediction of a design flood characteristic. These
        include:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The assumption of a unique relationship between stage and
            discharge, in general, is not justified;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Discharge is rarely measured during a flood, and the quality of data at the high
              discharge end of the curve typically is quite poor because there are usually few
              velocity measurements at high flow. As a result estimation of the peak discharge of a
              flood event usually involves extrapolation of the stage-discharge relationship beyond
              the recorded data points;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The relationship is usually a line of best fit through the data points defining
              the stage-discharge relationship. The approach recommended for estimation of this line
              of best fit in many guidance documents (for example, <citation>b1_c4_r44+1</citation>)
              is a visual fit. This approach provides minimal data on the uncertainty of the
              relationship and the reliability of any extrapolation of the relationship. This limits
              the estimation of the propagation of the uncertainty in the flood characteristic
              prediction approach; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>It has to describe a range of variation from no discharge
            through small but typical discharges to very large extreme flood
            events.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>As highlighted in the previous discussion, the unsteadiness of the discharge during a
          flood event (i.e. the variation of discharge with time) and its influence on a discharge
          estimate is ignored in the traditional application of a rating curve. In a flood event the
          slope of the water surface for a given stage will be different from that for the same
          stage during steady flow conditions; this difference will depend on whether the discharge
          is increasing or decreasing. As the flood increases, the surface slope in the river is
          greater than the slope for steady flow at the same stage, and hence, according to
          conventional hydraulic theory more water is flowing down the river than the rating curve
          would suggest. The effect of this is shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_5gqn1"/>. When the
          water level is falling, the slope and, hence, the discharge inferred is less. The effects
          might be important - the peak discharge could be significantly underestimated during
          highly dynamic floods, and also since the maximum discharge and maximum stage do not
          coincide, the arrival time of the peak discharge could be in error and may influence flood
          warning predictions. Finally, the use of a discharge hydrograph derived inaccurately by
          using a single-valued rating relationship may distort estimates for resistance
          coefficients during calibration of an unsteady flow model.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_xx8wc">
        <title>Extrapolation of Stage-Discharge Relationships</title>

        <para>The stage-discharge relationship can be considered to consist of
        two zones. These zones are:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>An interpolation zone where the relationship is within the
            range of the stage measurements used to develop the relationship;
            and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>An extrapolation zone where the relationship is not defined
            by gaugings taken to develop the relationship.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>A diagrammatic illustration of these two zones is shown in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch4_f_hez3n"/>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_hez3n">
          <title>Stage-Discharge Relationship Zones</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentdepth="100%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="../../figures/3005.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>While it is preferable that all stage measurements are within the interpolation zone,
          the nature of the data needed for design flood estimation, and for flood prediction in
          general, the reliability of data from measurements within the extrapolation zone will
          require consideration of the extrapolation methodology. The need for extrapolation is
          shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_a160s"/> where the discharges for the Annual Maxima
          Series extracted for the Stream Gauge are plotted as a function of the rating ratio (the
          rating ratio is the ratio of the recorded discharge to the highest gauging used to develop
          the stage-discharge relationship). All points in the Annual Maxima Series where the rating
          ratio is greater than 1 require use of the extrapolation zone of the stage-discharge
          relationship.</para>

        <para><figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_a160s">
            <title>Annual Maximum Series</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1013.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>As shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_a160s"/>, a number of
        the values in the Annual Maxima Series are in the extrapolation zone.
        The accuracy of the values in the extrapolation zone has the potential
        to influence fitting of the statistical model to the Annual Maxima
        Series, thereby influencing the predicted design flood quantiles.
        Fitting a statistical model to data points where the higher values are
        subject to estimate errors is discussed in <xref
        linkend="b3_ch2"/>.</para>

        <para>There are a number of alternative techniques for development of
        the extrapolation zone of the stage-discharge relationship, with a
        logarithmic extrapolation being often recommended. This approach
        however may not be applicable because in many cases, the extrapolation
        may extend from a confined channel into a floodplain.</para>

        <para>An alternative approach is the use of a hydraulic model to
        develop the extrapolation zone of the stage-discharge relationship.
        Similar to the application of a logarithmic technique, the suitability
        of this approach needs to be confirmed prior to its application. Of
        particular concern is the modelling of the energy losses associated
        with flow in the channel and adjacent floodplains where it is
        necessary to assume that the parameter values obtained during
        calibration are suitable for the larger discharges being simulated in
        the extrapolation zone of the stage-discharge relationship.</para>

        <para>The important point in this discussion, however, is a
        recognition that the values of the data extracted from a discharge
        record for fitting of a statistical model will contain values where
        the conversion of the recorded level to an equivalent discharge
        occurred through extrapolation of the stage-discharge relationship.
        Consideration of this in the fitting of a statistical model to the
        Annual Maxima Series is discussed later in <xref
        linkend="b3_ch2"/>.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_86j19">
        <title>Uncertainty of Discharge Measurements</title>

        <para>The accuracy, or uncertainty, of a discharge measurement is very
        important for purposes of assessing the quality and reliability of
        that measurement. The concept of error and error analysis is a
        long-standing practice in the field of hydraulics and hydrology. The
        concept of uncertainty, however, is relatively new. Nonetheless,
        methods for evaluating, defining and expressing the uncertainty of
        streamflow measurements have developed.</para>

        <para>Uncertainty and accuracy are terms that are sometimes used
        interchangeably even though they have two very distinct meanings.
        Accuracy (or error) refers to the agreement, or disagreement, between
        the measurement of stream discharge and the true or correct value of
        the discharge at the time of measurement. Since we can never know the
        true value of the discharge, we can never know the exact amount of
        error in the discharge measurement.</para>

        <para>The uncertainty of a discharge measurement, on the other hand,
        acknowledges that no measurement is perfect. It is defined, therefore,
        as a parameter associated with the result of a measurement that
        characterises the dispersion of values that could reasonably be
        attributed to the measurement. It is typically expressed as a range of
        values in which the measurement value is estimated to lie, within a
        given statistical confidence. It does not attempt to define or rely on
        a unique true value. To summarise, common usage of the word 'accuracy'
        for quantitatively describing the characteristics of a discharge
        measurement is incompatible with its correct meaning. The proper term
        for expressing the statistical confidence of possible values for a
        discharge measurement is uncertainty.</para>

        <para>The sources of uncertainty in discharge measurements can be categorised as:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Measurement - these are the uncertainties associated with
            taking the measurements. The primary component in this category is
            instrument accuracy. The accuracy of both the velocity meter and
            the level recorder need to be considered.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Methodology - these are the uncertainties associated with the analysis of the
              recorded measurements to enable the development of a point on the stage-discharge
              relationship. In this category, features such as the assumption of linear variation in
              the cross-section between the bathymetric points, the assumption of a logarithmic
              vertical velocity profile, wind effects, changing stage during measurement, etc need
              to be considered.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para><citation>b1_c4_r44+1</citation> guidance on the likely standard errors encountered in
          undertaking a gauging point are:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>For rod suspension, the standard error ranges from 2% for an
            even, firm, smooth and stable streambed, to 10% for a mobile,
            shifting sand, or dunes streambed;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>For cable suspension, the standard error ranges from 2% to
            15% for an unstable streambed, high velocity, and vertical angles;
            and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>For acoustic depth measurements, the standard error ranges
            from 2% for a stable streambed to 10% for a mobile, shifting sand,
            and dunes streambed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_hf3fo">
    <title>Catchment Data</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_fhvhc">
      <title>General</title>

      <para>Catchment data is an essential component for estimation of design
      flood characteristics and there are various types of catchment data
      required. Furthermore, data is available from different sources and with
      a range of accuracies. Generally, it is advisable that practitioners
      seek the most suitable data in each instance and assess the required
      accuracy of that data in respect of the desired accuracy of the
      outputs.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_rjnt7">
      <title>Types of Catchment Data</title>

      <para>There are many alternative types and forms of catchment data
      relevant to estimation of design flood characteristics, one of the major
      forms being those associated with assessment of flood behaviour. To
      predict this flood behaviour, the following types of data may be
      required:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Topographic and infrastructure data including structures
          within the floodplain including culverts, bridges, and pipe
          networks;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Land use information;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Vegetation data; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Soil data.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_dig3e">
      <title>Topographic and Infrastructure Data</title>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_dqnga">
        <title>General</title>

        <para>Topographic data is an important component of any design flood
        investigation. Proper scoping of topographic and infrastructure data
        collection can have a significant impact on the cost effective
        delivery of flood investigations. The scope of the required
        topographic and infrastructure data is driven by the nature of flood
        behaviour for a given area. The desired elements of topographic and
        infrastructure data include:</para>

        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Catchment extent;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Catchment slope;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Drainage topology (i.e. the drainage flow paths and network of channels);</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Channel cross-sections;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Waterway structures (weirs, levees, regulators, dams,
              culverts and bridges etc);</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Overland flowpath definition; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Infrastructure (bridges, culverts, pits, pipes
              etc).</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>

        <para>There are a number of alternative approaches to obtaining the
        necessary topographic data including:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Field survey;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Airborne techniques; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Available spatial mapping.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_8ij5b">
        <title>Field Survey</title>

        <para>Discussed in this section are details of the scoping of the
        field survey component for an investigation for design flood
        estimation. The focus is on those features where field survey is
        needed to capture the desired information. These features
        include:</para>

        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Channel and overland flow path cross-sections (and
              potentially long-sections);</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Waterway Structures - weirs and regulators;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Infrastructure - bridges, pipes, pits and culverts;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Road and rail embankments;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Levees; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Property data (floor level, type of building, size,
              location).</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>While it is possible to obtain existing field survey
        data from other sources, it is important to assess its suitability for
        the intended purpose. In other words, it is necessary to obtain both
        the data and the meta-data, which includes items related to date of
        capture, accuracy, etc.</para>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_1j7ly">
          <title>Cross-Sections</title>

          <para>A survey of cross-sections is required only when the design flood estimation
            requires application of a catchment modelling system to generate data that is not
            available from a catchment monitoring program. Hence, the scope of a cross-section
            survey depends on the type of the catchment modelling being used. Where catchment
            modelling is focussed on hydrologic simulation (using, for example, a conceptual
            rainfall-runoff model), the cross-section data required is minimal. However, where the
            catchment modelling requires hydraulic simulation (using, for example, a one dimensional
            network model), the cross-section data required will be more extensive.</para>

          <para>The important characteristics of the cross-section data include the lateral extent
            and longitudinal spacing of cross-sections. The lateral extent of the cross-section must
            be sufficient to include key in-bank elements and extend to above the highest flood
            level, which often extends onto the floodplain and outside the stream channel. When
            surveying in-bank cross-sections, good field notes and/or photos describing the nature
            of the channel are vital for proper interpretation post collection. There are numerous
            references such as <citation>b1_c4_r41+1</citation> that describe flood study
            cross-section survey requirements in detail. The overriding principle being that the
            cross-section data is adequate to estimate the shape and slope of the channel so that
            suitable estimates of the flow conveyance capacity of the channel can be
            calculated.</para>

          <para>The influence of in-bank features on flood discharge behaviour
          tends to reduce as the magnitude of the flood discharges increases.
          For example, bank-full capacity of a river channel may represent
          100% of a 0.2 or 0.5 EY discharge but less than 10% of a 1% AEP
          discharge.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_f5p72">
          <title>Structures and Drainage Infrastructure</title>

          <para>Structures in the waterway and on the floodplain may have a
          significant influence on flood behaviour. Structures requiring
          survey include:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Levees;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Road and rail embankments;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Hydraulic structures such as weirs, bridges and
              culverts;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Fences; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Drainage infrastructure such as pipes and pits.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>Often these structures constrict and obstruct flood discharges
          thereby influencing the design flood estimation. The effects on
          flood behaviour may be intentional (such as a weir) or unintentional
          (such as blockage at a culvert). Where the effect on flood discharge
          is unintentional, it is worth noting that the effect may be
          stochastic and hence the likelihood of the effect needs to be
          considered by a suitable joint probability technique. Irrespective
          of whether the influence is intentional or unintentional, these
          structures will have an influence on the estimation of the design
          flood characteristic.</para>

          <para>Hydraulic structures generally act to control the discharge
          behaviour in accordance with a particular management strategy. As
          most management strategies are concerned with frequent discharges,
          there are control structures designed to operate under flood
          conditions as part of an operational flood management strategy.
          Hence, the impact of these structures will vary with the management
          strategy and flood magnitude.</para>

          <para>The purpose of a levee is to divert discharges as part of an
          operational flood management strategy. As part of this strategy,
          levees are designed only to protect floodplains for a specified
          portion of the relationship between the likelihood and magnitude of
          a flood event; in other words, there is a defined probability that a
          levee can be overtopped (with or without failure of the levee bank)
          by a flood rarer than the levee was designed to protect against.
          Hence, in design flood estimation, the geometric properties of a
          levee are important to enable suitable estimation of the flood
          magnitudes (and hence probabilities) of design events likely to
          result in hydrologic (and/or structural) failure of the
          levee.</para>

          <para>Similar to field survey of cross-sections, field
          practicalities such as vegetation, access and water depth and
          flowrate may influence the location and details surveyed for a given
          structure.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_lyk4o">
          <title>Field Survey Techniques</title>
          <para>The techniques used for collection of field survey data (typically by surveyors) are
            discussed in this section. Details of three techniques are presented; namely Traditional
            Ground Survey, Real Time Kinematic (RTK) Global Positioning Systems (GPS)/ Differential
            GPS, and Photogrammetry. Typical accuracies for each of these techniques are provided in
              <xref linkend="b1_ch4_t_nmezo"/>. The techniques to measure topography and other
            survey features generally fall into two main categories:</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Direct measurement - where the survey technique involves a ground based
                instrument measuring features by physical contact and relating the measurement
                directly related to know ground control such as a State Survey Mark (SSM); or</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Remote sensing - where features are measured without physical contact with the
                object, and generally refers to measurement by an airborne or satellite mounted
                instrument.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <table frame="void" xml:id="b1_ch4_t_nmezo">
            <caption>Typical Accuracies of Field Survey </caption>
            <col width="33%"/>
            <col width="33%"/>
            <col width="33%"/>
            <thead align="left">
              <tr>
                <th rowspan="2">Survey Technique</th>
                <th colspan="2">Nominal Accuracy (+/- m)</th>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <th>Vertical</th>
                <th>Horizontal</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody align="left">
              <tr>
                <td>Traditional Ground Survey</td>
                <td>0.01</td>
                <td>0.01</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RTK GPS</td>
                <td>0.05</td>
                <td>0.05</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Photogrammetry</td>
                <td>0.1-0.3</td>
                <td>0.2-0.5</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ALS (LiDAR)</td>
                <td>0.15-0.4</td>
                <td>0.2-0.5</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_xtum2">
            <title>Traditional Ground Survey</title>
            <para>Traditional ground survey (that is, survey collected by traditional or total
              station ground survey techniques) is the most accurate survey technique with vertical
              and horizontal accuracies as shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_t_nmezo"/>. However, this
              technique is manual and labour intensive and is therefore best suited to small and/or
              difficult areas for other techniques, to supplement data obtained from other
              techniques, and to validate data obtained from other techniques.</para>
            <para>In the context of a design flood estimation, traditional ground survey methods are
              often used for:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Checking remote sensed data sets; and/or</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Supplementing remote sensed data in:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Areas that are impenetrable from the air (for example, satellites and
                      aeroplanes have difficulty in sensing the ground in areas like the bank of
                      channels and/or heavily vegetated areas);</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Areas that are critical for the data being sought from the catchment
                      modelling system (for example, critical hydraulic controls such as levees and
                      weirs) where topographic accuracy is important.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </section>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_y6cvb">
        <title>Real Time Kinematic Global Positioning Systems and Differential
        Global Positioning Systems</title>

        <para>Real Time Kinematic Global Positioning Systems (RTK GPS)
        involves coordinated use and comparison of two Global Positioning
        Systems (GPS) using the same satellite signals. The first GPS,
        sometimes referred to as the 'base station', is positioned over a
        known location (typically a permanent survey mark) and maintains a
        continuous record of the location relative to numerous satellite
        positions. The second GPS, referred to as a 'roving GPS', can be
        hand-held or mounted to a car, boat or an all-terrain vehicle; this
        unit collects data defining the location of the roving GPS position
        from the same satellites. The accuracy of the roving GPS location is
        enhanced by comparison of the satellite signals for the two stations.
        Shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_z85f4"/> is the concept underpinning
        field survey using RTK GPS techniques.</para>

        <para>RTK GPS has the advantage that it can collect a reasonable
        amount of data at higher accuracy than remote sensed data and much
        faster than by traditional means. The disadvantage is that if the
        vehicle in which the RTK GPS is mounted is unable to access an area,
        the system may have to be dismantled to gain access by some other
        means or measurement of data is not possible in the inaccessible area.
        RTK GPS methods also rely on the instrument having line of sight
        access to an array of satellites. This can be a limitation to the
        technique in areas underneath a tree canopy.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_z85f4">
          <title>Concept of RTK GPS Technique of Field Survey</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1011.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_s7w52">
        <title>Airborne Techniques</title>

        <para>Defining flood behaviour within an area containing overland
        flowpaths requires extensive topographic data. Aerial techniques are
        well suited to capture this topographic data across a broad area.
        Commonly, this topographic data is represented as a Digital Elevation
        Model (DEM). It should be noted that there is no universal definition
        of the terms Digital Elevation Model (DEM), Digital Terrain Model
        (DTM) and Digital Surface Model (DSM) in scientific literature. In
        most cases, the term DSM represents the earth's surface and includes
        all objects on it. In contrast to a DSM, the DTM represents the bare
        ground surface without any objects like plants and buildings. Both DTM
        and DSM may be referred to as DEM.</para>

        <para>Usually, a DEM is represented as a raster (a grid of squares) or a vector-based
          Triangular Irregular Network (TIN). According to <citation>b1_c4_r42+1</citation>, the TIN
          DEM data set is referred to as a primary (measured) DEM, whereas the Raster DEM is
          referred to as a secondary (computed) DEM; this definition, however, predates the
          widespread availability of Airborne Laser Scanning (ALS) (also known as Light Detection
          and Ranging - LiDAR) data for definition of the catchment surface topography.</para>

        <para>Before embarking on any aerial data capture, it is worth
        liaising with other agencies that may hold topographic data to ensure
        that the existing spatial extent of data does not cover the desired
        area.</para>

        <para>At present, the two principal techniques used in aerial survey
        for obtaining topographic data are:</para>

        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Photogrammetry; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Airborne Laser Scanning.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>A general description of photogrammetry is that it is
        the science of making measurements from photographs; in the context
        being used herein, it is the science of making measurements about the
        topographic surface of catchments. Generally, topographic data
        obtained through photogrammetry consists of spot elevations plus
        linear breaklines and the topographic surface is then determined from
        the TIN model through spot elevations. The breaklines are lines in the
        TIN that represents distinct interruptions in a surface slope, such as
        a ridge, road, or stream. No triangle in a TIN may cross a breakline
        (in other words, breaklines are enforced as triangle edges). Elevation
        levels along a breakline can be constant or variable.</para>

        <para>ALS or LiDAR is a remote sensing technology that measures
        distance by illuminating a target (in this case, the ground surface)
        with a laser and analysing the reflected light. Raw ALS data consists
        of a dense cloud of spot elevations classified into ground and
        non-ground strikes. This raw ALS data usually has the non-ground
        strikes removed prior to provision. Analysis of the raw ALS data
        usually will result in a raster DEM.</para>

        <para>It should be noted that neither photogrammetry nor ALS can
        penetrate water surfaces. Only the water surface level at the time of
        capture can be measured. If the bathymetry under the water surface is
        relevant in the context of the numerical modelling, bathymetric data
        must be collected and incorporated separately. Similarly, neither of
        the two methods can penetrate dense vegetation (such as trees, sugar
        cane and mangroves) to produce ground elevations. Hence, ground survey
        may be necessary to fill gaps in the topographic data under heavy
        vegetation.</para>

        <para>It is important in a DEM to ensure key linear features such as
        levees, embankments and other infrastructure are adequately
        represented. These features can be incorporated into the topographic
        description using field data as breaklines.</para>

        <para>The ANZLIC Committee on Surveying and Mapping have developed guidelines on the
          acquisition of LiDAR <citation>b1_c4_r28</citation> in terms of accuracy, data formats and
          meta-data. They have also developed the National Elevation Data Framework.</para>

        <para>Further discussion of these two aerial survey techniques is
        provided in the following sections.</para>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_kz5at">
          <title>Photogrammetry</title>

          <para>Photogrammetry is a measurement technique where the three
          dimensional (x,y,z) coordinates of an object are determined by
          measurements made from a stereo image consisting of two (or more)
          photographs; usually, these photographs are taken from different
          passes of an aerial photography flight. In this technique, the
          common points are identified on each image. A line of sight (or ray)
          can be built from the camera location to the point on the object. It
          is the intersection of its rays (triangulation) that determines the
          relative 3D position of the point as the known control points can be
          used to give these relative positions absolute values. More
          sophisticated algorithms can exploit other information on the scene
          known as priori.</para>

          <para>The accuracy of the photogrammetric data is a function of
          flying height, scale of the photography and the number and density
          of control points. Typically, the accuracy requested when scoping
          photogrammetric data collection for flood study purposes ranges from
          +/- 0.1 m to +/- 0.3 m. Note that the accuracy of the developed
          design flood profile cannot have an accuracy better than the
          catchment data used to estimate the design flood profile.</para>

          <para>As the technique is based upon the comparison of photographic
          images, shading and obscuring of the ground surface by vegetation
          can reduce coverage in specific areas. However, as photogrammetric
          analysis can utilise manual inspection of the stereo pair of
          photographs, the photogrammetrist is sometimes able to pick the odd
          ground surface visible through tree or crop cover. In this way,
          photogrammetry is sometimes able to provide some reliable points in
          vegetated areas.</para>

          <para>Shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_79qh2"/> is a region over
          which photogrammetric data coverage and ALS data coverage will be
          demonstrated. Shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_jmqdi"/> is a typical
          sample of the raw data obtained from a photogrammetric technique
          while shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_jrzpt"/> is the raw data in
          finer detail for the area indicated in <xref
          linkend="b1_ch4_f_jmqdi"/>. These figures demonstrate the following
          specifically in relation to photogrammetry:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>The measured points are well spaced, but not always on a
              grid. Some manual manipulation has occurred in locating these
              points when necessary.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Breaklines (seen as intervals along which measured
              elevations form the vertices of the interval) are evident along
              tops and bottom of banks. These are most likely to have been
              manually derived by viewing the stereo pair of
              photographs.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_79qh2">
            <title>Aerial Photograph Example (Region A)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="../../figures/1004.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_jmqdi">
            <title>Sample of Processed Photogrammetry data set (Region A)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="../../figures/1005.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_jrzpt">
            <title>Sample of Processed Photogrammetry data set (Region A detail)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1006.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>Photogrammetry is also often used to develop contours of the land surface directly
            as polylines with an attributed elevation; these contours are then used to create the
            desired elevation data set.</para>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_rl7e4">
          <title>Airborne Laser Scanning</title>

          <para>ALS or LiDAR consists of a high frequency laser emitter and
          scanner, coupled with a GPS and an Inertial Measurement Unit (IMU),
          all mounted in fixed winged aircraft. Rapid pulses of light are
          fired toward the earth by the laser instrument. These light pulses
          rebound from a target and are sensed. The scanner records the time
          differential between the emission of the laser pulses and the
          reception of the return signal. The time taken is used to determine
          the distance between the emitter and the target. The position and
          orientation of the scanner is determined using differential
          kinematic GPS and the IMU to account for aircraft pitch.</para>

          <para>ALS produces a dense cloud of points (See <xref
          linkend="b1_ch4_f_m3tc1"/>). These points can be classified as
          ground or non-ground points. While ALS requires little ground
          control in acquisition, ground control is important for quality
          control of the ALS measurements. For example, while it may be easy
          to scan inaccessible or sensitive areas without ground survey, the
          accuracy and reliability of the collected data may be low; in other
          words, ground control is important for ensuring the accuracy and
          reliability of the ALS measurements.</para>

          <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_m3tc1">
            <title>Sample of Raw ALS data set (Region A)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="../../figures/1007.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>The vertical and horizontal accuracy of ground surface level
          measurement by ALS is a function of the laser specification, flying
          height, ground control and the surface coverage. Hard road surfaces,
          for example, normally are able to be measured accurately, but other
          surface types (for example, swamps or heavily vegetated areas) are
          not easy to measure and hence the measurements must be treated with
          caution. It is useful to note that many quoted accuracy values for
          ALS data are in reference to the data accuracy for clear hard
          ground. For clear, hard ground (that is ground with no surface
          coverage), the nominal accuracy for technology commonly applied in
          Australia is:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Horizontal accuracy:</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>1/3000 x altitude at which the aeroplane is flown; for a flying height of
                    1000 m, the horizontal accuracy is about +/-0.33 m; and</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Elevation accuracy:</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>&lt; +/-0.15 m @ 1100 m flying height</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>&lt; +/-0.25 m @ 2000 m flying height</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>&lt; +/-0.4 m @ 3000 m flying height</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>The width of the land terrain sampling per pass, commonly
          referred to as the swath varies with the flying height. While
          typical values are given in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_t_qmvc9"/>, users
          are advised to obtain the meta-data regarding their ALS to ensure
          suitability for purpose.</para>
          <table frame="void"  xml:id="b1_ch4_t_qmvc9">
            <caption>Typical Swath Values</caption>
            <col width="50%"/>
            <col width="50%"/>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Typical Swath (m)</th>
                <th>Altitude (m)</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>800</td>
                <td>1100</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>1456</td>
                <td>2000</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>2184</td>
                <td>3000</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table><para>A disadvantage of the ALS data capture method (compared to, for example,
            low-level photogrammetry) is the absence of breaklines in the data to define distinct,
            continuous topographic features and significant changes in grade. While the horizontal
            density of points usually is quite high ( average point spacing of 1 to 2 metres
            depending on flying height and sampling frequency), features such as narrow banks/levees
            or channels will only be resolved if the data are sampled on a very small grid (less
            than 1 to 2 m grid). This can result in large and unwieldy terrain files.</para>

          <para>There are a number of approaches that can be taken in relation
          to the treatment of breaklines in ALS data sets:</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sample the entire survey area at a fine resolution - say on a regularly spaced 1
                m Digital Elevation Model (DEM) grid and manually identify important salient
                topographic features and hand enter these features into the models;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use local knowledge, GIS, aerial photos, satellite imagery
              or historic plans to identify locations of important features
              and hand-digitise over the fine resolution DEM in a manner
              similar to the first approach (approach 1) and then drape values
              from the DEM to develop 3D breakline strings;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use observations as in approach 2 to determine locations
              of key features and then use field survey to develop 3D
              breakline strings; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use auto-processing/filtering algorithms to extract
              breaklines from the raw ALS data.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>

          <para>Experienced users favour a combination of technique approaches
          (2), (3) and (4). While approach (4) nominally provides the widest
          coverage and extracts the most information from the ALS data, the
          processes cannot be considered reliable as no method has been
          developed for testing the validity of the breaklines
          produced.</para>

          <para>Although requiring a greater manual input, it is considered
          that approaches (2) and (3) are better approaches for the provision
          of reliable estimates of the surface level at critical locations
          with in the floodplain. This arises from the manual checking that
          occurs during the progress of approaches (2) and (3). Furthermore,
          long-sections from the ALS can be checked for consistency and a
          sub-sample tested against field measurements as a validation
          process.</para>

          <para>Capturing ALS data results in surface level estimates from
          various ground coverages including bare earth, vegetation, and
          buildings. Thorough processing of this raw data is required to
          ensure a true representation of the ground surface is
          obtained.</para>

          <para>Raw ALS data files contain all returns can be very large leading to difficulties
            with data storage and the manipulation of this data. As a result, a common approach is
            to use 'thinned' ALS data; this is data that has been processed to remove data points
            providing limited additional definition of the terrain surface. Shown in <xref
              linkend="b1_ch4_f_6hwo6"/> is an example of the processed ALS data set to produce the
            thinned ALS data set. Illustrated in this figure are the following aspects:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>The measured spot heights are provided as a grid; in other words, each spot
                height is representative of an area defined by the grid dimensions. This grid has
                been created by "thinning" the raw ALS point cloud data set. While the dimensions of
                the grid are defined by the user, it is useful to note that the smaller the grid,
                the larger and perhaps more unwieldy the data set being used but the surface
                topography will have an apparent higher definition. Conversely, the larger the grid,
                the smaller the data set but the surface topography will have an apparent lower
                definition. It is also worth noting that definition of the surface topography only
                needs to be adequate to provide the necessary information and that any additional
                definition will not provide either additional flood data or accuracy of the
                predicted flood data.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>There are no breaklines in the model of the surface
              topography. Breaklines can be created according to the
              approaches discussed previously but typically are not determined
              solely from the ALS data.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Areas where there are no measurements and hence no points available to build the
                model of the surface topography. In these areas, the ground surface was not visible
                due to, for example, heavy vegetation or surface water. These areas can be removed
                during the processing as "non-ground" points. When using a processed ALS data set,
                there will be situations where a non-ground elevation point (for example, a point
                that has hit the canopy of trees) has not been removed during processing. As a
                result, the spot elevation remains in the data set and would be treated as a surface
                elevation. In some situations. Errors of this type are obvious and can be removed
                manually. In other situations, they may not be obvious and hence will form part of
                the DEM (Digital Elevation Model) used in the analysis. Users need to be cognisant
                of errors of this type in ALS data and the consequent significant impacts on the
                predictions obtained from the catchment modelling system.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_6hwo6">
            <title>Sample of Processed ALS data set (Region A)</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata contentdepth="200%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="../../figures/1008.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </section>

        <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_kdnkn">
          <title>Aerial Survey Quality Checks</title>

          <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_s_lyk4o"/>, survey data
          is not exact and will have a tolerance or a stated level of
          accuracy. Data obtained from aerial survey is the same. With data
          obtained from aerial survey, accuracy is dependent upon a number of
          factors, including flying height and the number of control points.
          In general, the required accuracy is advised prior to commencement
          of data collection and the surveyor designs the data collection
          program needed to achieve the desired accuracy.</para>

          <para>An important point to note is that the accuracy of the
          collected data is checked and confirmed. The resultant stated
          accuracy typically does not apply to the DTM derived from the survey
          data but rather to the individual elevation points sampled during
          the data generation program. This is an important distinction and
          users of a DTM derived from aerial survey data needs to be aware of
          this feature.</para>

          <para>There are a number of methods that may be used to check the
          accuracy of the aerial survey.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>POINT v DTM SURFACE: Independent field surveys of selected
              quality check points can be compared to the DTM. However, this
              surface has been interpolated from the aerial elevation data
              and, unless the accuracy stated by the aerial surveyor referred
              to the DEM, the correlation in accuracy values is not
              guaranteed. But, this method can provide a preliminary
              indication of accuracy, particularly if the independent field
              survey points with known accuracy are already available from
              another source;</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>POINT v POINT: Independent field surveys of selected
              quality check points can be compared to the individual aerial
              data elevation points. The selected check points must exactly
              match the coordinates of the aerial data points to ensure that a
              valid comparison is being made. To do this, the aerial survey
              must first be received in order to select the points at which
              comparison will be made, which may slow the data collection
              phase. Alternatively, early liaison with the aerial surveyor may
              allow the location of a number of points to be known before data
              provision, which may save time; and</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>STRING v DTM SURFACE: A more appropriate approach may be to field survey a
                number of breakline strings along key linear features. These strings may be some 50
                m - 200 m in length with points at regular spacing (say every 5 -15 m). A comparison
                can then be made of the profiles along the feature determined from both the aerial
                and field survey. In addition, if the strings are across conveyance paths (i.e. they
                are cross-sections), the modeller can check that conveyance cross-sectional areas
                are adequately represented. These comparisons enable a qualitative assessment of
                aerial survey accuracy for a given region within the study area. A number of
                surveyed strings may be required across the study area to gain an overall
                appreciation of accuracy.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_ohbck">
        <title>National Digital Elevation Model</title>

        <para>National grids of terrain information are available from Geoscience Australia. These
          data sets use information obtained from a variety of sources inclusive of satellites. As a
          result, these data sets tend to be coarse with grid sizes varying from 1 second (1 seconds
          in longitude and latitude is approximately 30 m) to 9 seconds (9 seconds in longitude and
          latitude is approximately 250 metres). As development of these databases occur, it is
          likely that these specifications will change. Therefore, as with other sources of data,
          users should ensure that they use the most appropriate data for their problem.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_087mx">
        <title>Bathymetric (Underwater) Techniques</title>

        <para>Many methods for generating surface data are not applicable for
        collecting bathymetric data (ground data below the water surface) in
        permanent or semi-permanent water bodies. Where a water body has not
        been surveyed adequately, a specific survey will be required to
        supplement the ground surface data.</para>

        <para>If the water body is shallow or <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151007T224019+1100" comment="Is there a set of numbers or deifinition that can define small and larger water bodies? What is the point of comparision here?"?>small<?oxy_comment_end ?>,
        then a traditional surface survey technique may be suitable. For
        deeper, larger water bodies, a specialised bathymetric survey may be
        required. Instruments such as echo sounders, side scan sonar systems
        and acoustic doppler profilers may be used for this purpose.</para>

        <para>In most cases, the bathymetric survey will need to be merged
        with ground surface data.</para>

        <para>While bathymetric surveys have been conducted for most major
        rivers, if the data is not recent and the riverbed is subject to
        change then the data should be checked for suitability prior to its
        use.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_s5huu">
        <title>Aerial Photographs</title>

        <para>Aerial photographs are an important source of qualitative data
        and can be collected during an aerial survey. Geo-referenced (or
        ortho-rectified) aerial photos can be supplied as part of a
        photogrammetric survey. These geo-referenced aerial photographs are
        aerial photos where spatial coordinates have been added to locate the
        photograph. It is important to recognise that the raw aerial
        photograph is spatially distorted, being a planar image of a curved
        surface of variable height. In ortho-rectifying the image, the image
        is scaled, rotated and stretched so that various reference locations
        move to their correct coordinate locations.</para>

        <para>A consequence of this is the location of features on an aerial
        photograph will have a degree of uncertainty. For example, if a
        rectified aerial photograph is used to locate a flood mark, the
        attributed location will be subject to a tolerance. In an area of high
        flood gradient this can result in differences between observed and
        simulated flood levels that do not accurately represent the true
        differences.</para>

        <para>Aerial photographs, while not providing quantitative data
        directly, can provide additional information about flowpaths, flow
        obstacles and floodplain vegetation that is not always immediately
        evident or accessible on a site inspection. Additionally, aerial
        photos can be a useful guide when defining parameters for floodplain
        characteristics (for example, roughness coefficients) and can be used
        to develop a spatial map of the floodplain parameter.</para>

        <para>Another example of the use of aerial photography is its use in
        urban areas to define building outlines or fence lines where these are
        to be included within the hydraulic model and can be a reasonable
        source of information for assessing the total imperviousness of a
        catchment (see <xref linkend="b5_ch4"/>).</para>

        <para>Finally, when historical aerial photography is available, it is
        useful in assessing catchment development or sourcing information on
        the floodplain development when historical events occurred.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_iw14b">
        <title>Historical Topography and Infrastructure</title>

        <para>All data collection methods covered thus far have been concerned
        with present day catchment conditions. However, when catchment
        modelling systems are used for design flood estimation, calibration to
        historical events is required and the catchment and floodplain
        conditions at the time of the historical event need to be considered
        particularly as these conditions may not be the same as present day
        conditions. In addition, if a number of events are to be used during
        the calibration process, changes to catchment conditions may occur
        between events.</para>

        <para>Conditions at each of the relevant historical points in time
        must be established and used in the model development; this is
        discussed in more detail in <xref linkend="book7"/>. Changes to
        conditions that may affect flood behaviour include dam construction,
        initial dam storage levels, dredging or siltation of river channels
        and particularly of river mouths, construction of levees and other
        associated flood mitigation works, road construction including the
        raising or duplication of roads, the realignment of road embankments,
        the construction of new culverts and/or bridges, upgraded drainage
        networks both in rural and urban environments, developments on the
        floodplain, the construction of new weirs or the removal of old weirs,
        different crop types or stage in the growing season, and others that
        have not been mentioned here. Depending upon the length of time since
        the occurrence of the calibration event, record of these changes may
        be only available anecdotally.</para>

        <para>The availability of data for historical events needs to be
        considered when the event is used as part of the design flood
        estimation. For example, there may be anecdotal or even good formal
        measurement evidence of a record flood that occurred 100 years ago but
        details of this flood event may not be adequate for its use as a
        calibration event for validation of a catchment modelling system. On
        the other hand, the data may be adequate for it to be included as a
        high discharge censored event in a flood frequency analysis (<xref
        linkend="b3_ch2"/>).</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_1ca4v">
        <title>Land Use Information</title>

        <para>Land use data is important for several aspects of projects, and
        can be obtained from land use maps, field observations or consultation
        with local authorities, land managers or property owners. Local
        authorities are often a valuable source of land use data.</para>

        <para>Land use data is used in hydrology models to determine suitable
        parameters to calculate runoff and is also used in hydraulic models to
        assist in the determination of Manning's n values.</para>

        <para>Land use data is normally supplied as a map or a GIS layer. When
        obtained from local authorities, the data is usually supplied on
        request for no charge.</para>

        <para>Information on land use can be used in the hydrologic model to
        determine percentage impervious or in hydraulic models to inform
        hydraulic roughness. Land use information may be sourced from:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Local or State Government Authorities in spatial layers of
            existing development zonings;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Local or State Government Authorities in spatial layers of
            future development zonings; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Inferred from Aerial photographs (current and
            historical).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_vnt0d">
        <title>Vegetation Data</title>

        <para>Information on vegetation type can be used in the hydrologic
        model to determine runoff characteristics or in hydraulic models to
        inform hydraulic roughness values (Manning's n). This data may be
        sourced from:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Vegetation maps;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Field inspections; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Inferred from Aerial photographs.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Care needs to be taken with vegetation maps as, in general, the
        maps are based on limited sampling and inferring the results of this
        survey to be the representative of a larger area. Additionally, the
        individual species within an area designated as one vegetation type
        may vary.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_2cgbg">
        <title>Bureau of Meteorology Geofabric</title>

        <para>The Bureau of Meteorology Australian Hydrological Geospatial Fabric (Geofabric<footnote>
            <para>http://www.bom.gov.au/water/geofabric/index.shtml</para>
          </footnote> ) consists of a number of GIS layers which include hydrological features such
          as rivers, water bodies, aquifers, and catchments. The current geofabric includes
            <citation>b1_c4_r31</citation>: <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Geofabric Surface Cartography - Cartographic representation of surface
                hydrological features;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Geofabric Surface Network - Network representation of hydrological
                features;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Geofabric Surface Catchments - Catchment boundaries derived from the 9 second
                Digital Elevation Model;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Geofabric Groundwater Cartography - Cartographic representation of groundwater
                hydrology features;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Geofabric Hydrology Reporting Catchments- Contracted nodes, contracted
                catchments and node-link network; and</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Geofabric Hydrology Reporting Regions - Reporting regions based on aggregations
                of contracted catchments.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>

        <para>It is worth noting that the catchment area is a function of the
        scale at it was estimated and therefore is likely to have inaccuracies
        at a fine scale. The current data is based on a 9 Second DEM and GA
        GEODATA TOPO 250K Series 1 (GEODATA 1) and GEODATA TOPO 250 K Series 3
        (GEODATA 3).</para>

        <para>Subsequent versions of the Geofabric will have upgrades to data and include
            <citation>b1_c4_r31</citation>:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>hydrometric monitoring features;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>more detailed surface water hydrology; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Digital Elevation Model (DEM) derived streams and catchment
            boundaries based on a 1 second resolution DEM.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_das6t">
        <title>Soil Data</title>

        <para>Some hydrologic models require information on the catchment soil
        properties (for example, information on the A and B horizon depths and
        their water holding capacity, or the soil type) to estimate losses
        from the rainfall.</para>

        <para>Soil property data is available spatially for the whole country from the Atlas of
          Australian Soils <citation>b1_c4_r39</citation>; this information is available in a GIS
          format from the Australian Soil Resource Information System website. These maps are broad
          scale (typically 1:250000 - 1:500000) and were completed between 1960 and 1968. State
          based maps are available, also. Care should be taken when using soil maps as variations in
          soil over short distances occur frequently and cannot be resolved by the reconnaissance
          style mapping used in their development <citation>b1_c4_r39</citation>.</para>

        <para>While it is possible to estimate land subject to inundation by
        floods through consideration of the soils and geomorphology, this does
        not provide any guidance on the likelihood of the flood hazard and
        therefore can be misleading. Furthermore, there is a need to ensure
        that the soil and geomorphoric data is obtained at a fine scale to
        ensure spatial variations over short distances are adequately
        recognised when using soil information to assess potential flood
        hazard.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_b3l7s">
        <title>Property Data</title>

        <para>In order to assess the magnitude of the flood hazard to people
        and property, property data (including building type, condition and
        floor level) typically are required.</para>

        <para>Property databases form the basis of most flood damage
        assessments. These databases typically require a description of the
        property attributes and features on a property by property basis.
        Typical information required for each residential property
        includes:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Street address;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Representative ground level;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Habitable Floor levels;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Building construction type (e.g. brick veneer, timber, slab on ground, on piers
              etc);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Building age;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Single/double storey; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>House size.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Commercial and industrial properties require similar
        information, but also require information on the type of business
        undertaken at the site as this can have a significant bearing on the
        value of flood damages from business to business.</para>

        <para>Ideally, this data are collected via field survey. However, it
        can be a costly process depending upon the number of properties for
        which data are required. Alternatively, there may sometimes be records
        available from the local authority, other government agency or the
        census. For broad assessments, property data may be estimated. A panel
        of people with relevant skills should review the method of estimation
        for soundness. As an example, property data may be estimated from
        aerial photography or from a general understanding of local
        conditions.</para>

        <para>A number of national data sets are also available from Geoscience Australia such
          as:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Australian Flood Risk Information Portal (Geoscience
            Australia) will be a central depository for information on flood
            studies conducted throughout the country and associated spatial
            data;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Water Observations from Space historical surface water observations derived from
              satellite imagery for all of Australia for the period of 1998 to 2012; and</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>State borders, city locations, topographic maps.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_b7d2r">
    <title>Other Data Considerations</title>

    <section>
      <title>Storage of Data and Meta-data</title>

      <para>Most large data sets on a project are produced by combining multiple sources of
        information. Most large data sets are too big to be checked and must be machine quality
        controlled. It is important that meta-data associated with quality checking is recorded to
        assist future users of the data set.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Co-ordinate Systems and Datums</title>

      <para>Most large national data sets are in latitude and longitude. Smaller data sets are in
        Map Grid of Australia (MGA 94) which is Universal Transverse Mercator projection and the
        Geocentric Datum of Australia 1994. Some older data sets may use ISG - Integrated Survey
        Grid or AMG - Australian Map Grid. Care should be taken when translating from one projection
        to another; of particular concern is the use of the correct local conversion as these
        conversions are not the same across the country.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Other hydrological Data</title>

    <section xml:id="b1_ch4_s_mhgo9">
      <title>Tidal Data</title>

      <para>In many coastal areas and areas adjacent to coasts, ocean
      <?oxy_comment_start author="RadhikaChhotai" timestamp="20151007T224125+1100" comment="Are we missing a word here? Please confirm? "?>and
      tidal data <?oxy_comment_end ?>can be an important component of the
      design flood estimation process. Tidal data may be collected by manual
      observations or by automatic recorders and needs to include astronomical
      tides as well as storm surge and long-term trends in sea levels. In some
      circumstances, wave data may also be relevant.</para>

      <para>Historical tidal data for particular events can be useful model calibration while
        long-term records can be used for statistical analysis for design flood estimation purposes
        (refer to <xref linkend="b6_ch5"/>). With increased sea levels induced by global warming,
        long-term records of tides and sea levels need to be checked for stationarity; refer to
          <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/> for a discussion of climate change data.</para>

      <para>Tidal data is collected regularly by relevant government agencies,
      being concerned for the coastal environment or engineering. This data is
      published in handbooks or websites. In addition, there are research or
      other short-term projects carried out in coastal areas, which may
      include data on tides. However, these projects are generally localised
      and of short duration.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Meteorological Data</title>

      <para>As well as rainfall and other precipitation, other meteorological
      data is used in water resources studies. This data is used to assess
      soil moisture and evapotranspiration for example. This data includes pan
      evaporation, temperature, humidity, wind speed and other
      parameters.</para>

      <para>The Bureau of Meteorology is the principal agency that collects
      this data, however there are records held by water agencies and
      agricultural departments as well as small localised records held by
      different organisations. Regional maps of key meteorological data,
      especially pan evaporation and evapotranspiration are published by the
      Bureau of Meteorology, and this regional information is often adequate
      for many requirements.</para>

      <para>Meteorological data is usually available free of charge from the
      Bureau of Meteorology and major agencies.The records from other
      organisations may be difficult to locate and then there may be
      contractual difficulties in obtaining and using the data.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Sediment Movement and Deposition</title>

      <para>Sediment movement, including scour and deposition, is one of the
      most important water quality impacts of drainage systems, both natural
      and man-made and can cause environmental problems in downstream
      receiving waters as well as damage and disruption to drainage
      systems.</para>

      <para>Data collection on sediment movement is particularly difficult and
      there is only limited available data. Most routine data collection
      programmes are carried out by water and environmental agencies, but
      these are usually somewhat limited. Tthere are some small specialised
      programmes carried out for specific projects, often as part of an
      environmental impact study. However these programmes are generally
      limited in scope and also limited in the duration for the data
      collection programme.</para>

      <para>This data is normally available only directly from the agency or
      organisation that collects the data, and may be difficult to find that
      it exists and then it may be difficult to obtain.</para>

      <para>Once data is located, it is then often difficult to access and use
      because of differences in the methods adopted for collection, analysis
      and processing. There are also differences in the treatment of bed and
      suspended loads and measurements of turbidity, all of which are used at
      times to measure sediment movement.</para>

      <para>Sediment deposition may be monitored by owners of affected assets,
      but the data is difficult to apply in investigations.</para>

      <para>Therefore application of sediment movement and deposition data is
      difficult and needs considerable skill to interpret and apply. Where
      this is an important aspect of a project, efforts should be exerted to
      find and use the data.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Water Quality</title>

      <para>As well as sediment, there are many other water quality parameters
      that are relevant to water resources and drainage programmes. The water
      quality parameters that can be monitored cover a wide range from the
      relatively routine such as nutrients and salinity to quite specialised
      contaminants.</para>

      <para>As with sediment, data collection on this topic is particularly
      difficult and there is only limited available data. Most data collection
      programmes are carried out by water and environmental agencies, and some
      of this data (especially the routine parameters, such as salinity) is
      available in formal data archiving systems. In addition to these
      programmes, there are some small specialised programmes carried out for
      specific projects, often as part of an environmental impact
      study.</para>

      <para>Some types of water quality data, especially salinity and
      nutrients are available as historical records that can be used to
      calibrate models and assess changes in conditions with time, but much of
      the data is short term and variable. Considerable skill and expertise is
      needed to apply this data to project requirements.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Climate Change Data</title>

    <para>In this section, data available to consider the impacts of climate
    change on estimation of design rainfalls and floods is described. As
    further research and development of climate change data occurs, the
    discussion and guidance presented here will change. Practitioners,
    therefore, should ensure that they are aware of these changes and the
    impact on available data.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Types of Climate Change Data</title>

      <para>Quantifying the effects of climate change on the factors that affect flood estimation is
        a difficult task, and any estimates of impacts of future climate on the inputs to flood
        assessments will include large uncertainties. The fact that the occurrence of flood events,
        and their associated causal factors, is rare limits the data available to assess changes in
        their frequency or intensity <citation>b1_c4_r13</citation>.</para>

      <para>Observed data is often used to investigate whether there are any trends apparent in
        historical flood data. The data used to project the impacts of future climate on flooding is
        generally sourced from climate modelling. “Any useful technique for the assessment of future
        risk should combine our knowledge of the present, our best estimate of how the world will
        change, and the uncertainty in both” <citation>b1_c2_r11</citation>. To study the impact of
        climate change, a plausible and consistent description of a possible future climate is
        required. The construction of such climate change scenarios relies mainly on results from
        model projections, although some information from past climates can be used
          <citation>b1_c4_r11</citation>. Refer to <xref linkend="b1_ch6"/> for more information on
        climate change and flood estimates.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Observed Data</title>

        <para>Stationarity is one of the fundamental assumptions in
        traditional design flood estimation. Climate change challenges this
        assumption as observed historical rainfall and flow data may not be a
        good indicator of future conditions. This has implications for the use
        of historical data in assessment of flood risk including in estimation
        of design rainfalls, flood frequency analysis, sea-level and storm
        surge, and estimates of design flood model parameters that account for
        losses.</para>

        <para>Detecting changes in the frequency or intensity of precipitation or flood events in
          recorded data presents a number of difficulties <citation>b1_c2_r14,b1_c4_r17</citation>.
          The ability to assess climate-driven observed changes in the magnitude and frequency of
          floods at regional scales is limited by the lack of observed records and their coverage in
          space and time, and by changes in catchments due to land-use and development
            <citation>b1_c4_r13</citation>. Attributing trends in discharge data to climate change
          is particularly difficult, as changes in catchment conditions, or river operations can
          contribute to trends in the data <citation>b1_c4_r2</citation>. Long-term records are
          needed to be able to detect trends in data, and the availability of consistent, quality
          controlled data is a major limitation in any study to detect trends in large to extreme
          rainfall or flood data <citation>b1_c4_r2</citation>. There is evidence that climate
          change will result in a larger increase in extreme sub-daily rainfalls than at a longer
          duration <citation>b1_c4_r24</citation>. The availability of long records of sub-daily
          rainfall data is limited, with an average length of Australian sub-daily rainfall stations
          of approximately 19 years compared to an average length of 65 years for daily rainfall
          stations <citation>b1_c4_r14</citation>.</para>

        <para>One of the most fundamental issues in detecting trends in precipitation or discharge
          data due to climate change is separating the influences of climate variability from
          long-term climate change in a relatively short record. Due to the normal range of climate
          variability, there is limited information available to establish the probability of a
          flood event currently, even without consideration of climate change
            <citation>b1_c4_r26</citation>. Local and regional changes in precipitation due to
          climate change are greatly affected by patterns of atmospheric circulation. Patterns of
          change in precipitation associated with ENSO can dominate the global patterns of
          variations, particularly in the tropics and over much of the mid-latitudes
            <citation>b1_c4_r22</citation>. There is little observed data available to investigate
          relationships between hemispheric scale modes of the atmosphere (such as ENSO) and climate
          change.</para>

        <para>The observed data available to directly estimate the impacts of climate change on
          antecedent conditions includes seasonal rainfalls, evapotranspiration, and soil moisture.
          Detecting changes in these parameters can be undertaken with a trend analysis, however
          long records with appropriate spatial coverage are required for this task. As for
          detecting changes in extreme precipitation or discharge events, the difficulty is in
          separating the impacts of climate change from natural variability or the influence of
          changes in catchment conditions, in the relatively short records available. The coverage
          of directly measured evapotranspiration data is relatively sparse across Australia and is
          very limited globally <citation>b1_c4_r2</citation>. Evapotranspiration data available
          from global analysis data is sensitive to the type of analysis and the uncertainty in the
          data makes it unsuitable for trend analysis <citation>b1_c4_r2</citation>. Direct
          measurements of soil moisture are available for only a few regions and are often very
          short in duration <citation>b1_c4_r2</citation>.</para>

        <para>Changes in storm surge events can be investigated using data from tide gauge records.
          Tide gauge data can be used to evaluate the Annual Exceedance Probabilities of extreme sea
          levels, however a reliable analysis of the risk of extreme events or trends in the data is
          limited by the short duration of records collected at many gauges.
            <citation>b1_c4_r3+1</citation> found only two gauges of sufficient length for use in
          this type of analysis in Australia, and only nineteen records with lengths of 40 years or
          greater (and some of these were intermittent). The limited number of tide gauges means
          that there is no data available for large stretches of coastline, which inhibits the
          assessment of this hazard even under present climate conditions, let alone future
          conditions due to climate change <citation>b1_c4_r16</citation>.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Climate Modelling</title>

        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Global scale
              modelling</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>Whilst observed historical data can be used to
        investigate trends, Global Climate Models (GCMs) are most often used
        to generate data to investigate the impacts of climate change into the
        future on a global or continental scale.</para>

        <para>Climate models are mathematical representations of the climate system, expressed as
          computer codes and run on computers <citation>b1_c4_r12</citation>. The models would be
          too complex to run on any existing computer if all variables in the climate system were
          explicitly included in the models, so simplifications are made so that the system has
          reduced complexity and computing requirements <citation>b1_c4_r11</citation>. Outputs from
          GCMs cover many variables that impact the hydrologic cycle including precipitation,
          evaporation, soil moisture and sea level. GCMs have been developed by a range of
          international agencies. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change’s (IPCC) Fourth
          Assessment Report (2007) used climate modelling output from 23 different GCMs as the basis
          of their global assessment of climate change <citation>b1_c4_r12</citation>. GCMs differ
          in their representations of climatology and thus using an ensemble including a range of
          GCMs can enhance the representation of specific weather patterns
            <citation>b1_c4_r1,b1_c4_r7</citation>.</para>

        <para>In order to address the uncertainty in future greenhouse gas emissions, a range of
          plausible futures are often run with the GCMs. <citation>b1_c4_r12+1</citation> developed
          a range of emissions scenarios (SRES emissions scenarios) that are commonly used with
          GCMs. The SRES emissions scenarios are divided into six families based on different likely
          emissions considering future technological and societal changes
            <citation>b1_c4_r4</citation>. The current GCM results for Australia can be accessed
          through the Climate Change in Australia website (<link
            xlink:href="http://www.climatechangeinaustralia.gov.au/en/"
            >http://www.climatechangeinaustralia.gov.au/en/</link>) and the Climate Futures web tool
            (<link
            xlink:href="http://www.climatechangeinaustralia.gov.au/en/climate-projections/climate-futures-tool/introduction-climate-futures/"
            >http://www.climatechangeinaustralia.gov.au/en/climate-projections/climate-futures-tool/introduction-climate-futures/</link>).</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Global Greenhouse Gas Emissions Scenarios for the 21st Century (from IPCC,
            2007)</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1037.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Confidence in GCM data</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>The fact that climate model fundamentals are based on established physical
          laws, such as conservation of mass, energy and momentum, along with a wealth of
          observations gives some confidence in the ability of models to represent the global
          climate. The models have shown a good ability to simulate important aspects of the current
          climate, and reproduce features of past climates and climate changes
            <citation>b1_c4_r12</citation>.</para>

        <para>Areas of uncertainty in the GCM projections include uncertainty in future levels of
          greenhouse gas emissions, the response of the climate to the emissions, and changes in
          regional climate <citation>b1_c4_r5</citation>. The cascade of uncertainties in
          projections is shown in <xref linkend="b1_ch4_f_j3ne8"/>. The uncertainty in the levels of
          emissions results from a lack of knowledge of the future social, economic and
          technological development of the world, and the associated greenhouse-gas emissions. The
          model uncertainty is due to deficiencies in the knowledge of the science of climate
          change, in setting initial conditions for the models, and in the representation of the
          global climate by the models <citation>b1_c2_r11</citation>. There are also deficiencies
          in the simulation of tropical precipitation, the El Niño- Southern Oscillation and the
          Madden-Julian Oscillation. Most of these errors are due to the fact that many important
          small-scale processes cannot be represented explicitly in GCMs, and so must be included in
          approximate form as they interact with larger-scale features. This is partly due to
          limitations in computing power, but also results from limitations in scientific
          understanding or in the availability of detailed observations of some physical processes
            <citation>b1_c4_r12</citation>.</para>

        <figure xml:id="b1_ch4_f_j3ne8">
          <title>From <citation>b1_c4_r11</citation></title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/1038.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis role="bold">Regional Scale Modelling</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>The outputs from GCMs give information at a global scale with a limited
          resolution, so cannot provide a detailed picture of climate variables at the regional
          scale required to investigate the factors influencing flood events
            <citation>b1_c4_r4</citation>. Some form of downscaling is required to investigate the
          impacts of future climate on specific variables at a local scale, in particular for
          precipitation and climate extremes. To address the decrease in confidence in the changes
          projected by global models at smaller scales, other techniques, including the use of
          regional climate models and downscaling methods, have been specifically developed for the
          study of local-scale climate change <citation>b1_c4_r12</citation>. Three methods are
          commonly used to scale outputs from GCMs: temperature scaling, statistical downscaling,
          and dynamical downscaling <citation>b1_c4_r24</citation>. Combinations of these methods
          are also used.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Temperature Scaling</emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Temperature scaling has been used give downscaled estimates of precipitation from
          GCMs. Extreme precipitation is directly related to the water holding capacity of the
          atmosphere. A warming climate leads to an increase in the water holding capacity of the
          air, which causes an increase in the atmospheric water vapour that supplies storms,
          resulting in more intense precipitation <citation>b1_c4_r22</citation>. The
          Casius-Clayperon relationship gives an increase of water holding capacity of approximately
          7% per degree Celsius of warming <citation>b1_c4_r22</citation>. This relationship has
          been found to hold for some sub-daily rainfalls, however daily extreme rainfalls have been
          found increase at a lower rate <citation>b1_c4_r15</citation>. The relationship also
          appears to hold only to a threshold temperature <citation>b1_c4_r8</citation>. The simple
          scaling of rainfall with temperature does not reflect all the processes that produce
          rainfall events. The true scaling relationship is more complex and is affected by the
          extremity and duration of the rainfall event, the atmospheric temperature, and access to
          atmospheric moisture <citation>b1_c4_r25</citation>. This results in differing local
          impacts of climate change and, in particular, different impacts are seen dependent on the
          duration of the rainfall event.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Statistical
            Downscaling</emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Statistical downscaling uses relationships between large-scale climate variables and
          local scale weather to develop estimates at a local scale. In the simulation of extreme
          rainfalls, a common approach is to use extreme value distributions to describe
          precipitation extremes <citation>b1_c4_r1</citation>. Another approach is to use a model
          to simulate precipitation and to then analyse the extremes <citation>b1_c4_r20</citation>.
          The advantage of statistical downscaling is that it is not computationally intense, and
          can be undertaken relatively quickly over large areas. The limitations of statistical
          downscaling include the assumption that the current observed relationships between large
          scale climate variables and local climate will persist in a changed climate regime.
          Another limitation is that the observational data set being used for the downscaling
          should cover the range of projected future climate responses
          <citation>b1_c4_r7</citation>.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Dynamical
            Downscaling</emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Dynamical downscaling takes the outputs from a host GCM as inputs to either a limited
          area model or stretched grid global climate model. The result is a fine scale dynamical
          model over the area of interest, often called a Regional Climate Model (RCM). Because a
          RCM focuses on a small area, it can provide more detail over that area than is possible
          with a GCM alone <citation>b1_c4_r7</citation>. Dynamical downscaling allows
          representation of local scale features, such as orographic effects, land-sea contrast and
          other land surface characteristics, and smaller scale physical processes that influence
          extreme precipitation <citation>b1_c4_r19</citation>. By modelling the atmosphere and
          local environment at a much finer scale than is possible using a GCM, it is expected that
          the specific processes that drive regional weather and climate will be better represented.
          Bias corrected outputs from dynamically downscaled models have been shown to be able to be
          used directly in projections of changes in extreme precipitation
            <citation>b1_c4_r26</citation>. A number of studies have used RCMs to investigate
          changes to daily precipitation extremes, however a lack of available sub-daily RCM data
          has limited studies on shorter duration events <citation>b1_c4_r9</citation>. The
          advantages of dynamical downscaling are in the ability to represent changes in rainfall
          spatial and temporal patterns, as well as impacts of local scale features. The
          disadvantage of dynamical downscaling is in computational time. There are assumptions
          inherent in the structure of each RCM and ideally a range of RCMs would be used in
          conjunction with a range of GCMs to give a more comprehensive description of local
          climate. The ability to undertake such studies is inhibited by the computational intensity
          of the task, and thus studies are generally limited to use of one or two RCMs with a range
          of GCMs.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
</chapter>
