<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" status="In Preparation" xml:id="b7_ch6" version="5.0">
 
  
  <info>
  <title>Regional Relationship for Runoff-routing Models</title>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/boyd_michael.xml"/>
    
  </info>
  
  
  <para>
    <informaltable border="1">
      <tr>
        <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Date last updated</td>
        <td>13/5/2019 </td>
      </tr>
    </informaltable>
  </para>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_m2742">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Regional relationships can be used to estimate parameter values on ungauged catchments but
      they can also be used to test the plausibility of parameters derived from limited data. Where
      no data is available some insight can also be gained from comparing how adjoining catchments
      with data compare to the regional relationship. Relationships between model parameters and
      catchment characteristics have been derived for several regions. The most recent relationships
      available for Australia are given in the following section. </para>
    <para>In all cases the reliability of regional relationships is likely to be less than parameter
      estimates derived from calibration from several recorded flood events on the catchment of
      interest. Regional relationships should be used with due caution, as most derived relations
      incorporate considerable scatter of the data from individual catchments. Also, different forms
      of relationships have been found to give equally good fits to the one set of data, but would
      give widely different estimates in some other cases <citation>b7_c6_r30</citation>.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_27myt">
    <title>Regional Relationships </title>
    <para>The following relationships for RORB and WBNM apply to catchments in natural condition.
      Regional data for RAFTS and URBS are not as extensive as for the other two models, and
      suggested parameter values for these models are included in <xref linkend="b7_ch5"/>.</para>
    <para>Regional relationships will contain some scatter about the fitted equation, partly due
      errors in rainfall and streamflow data, including insufficient spatial rainfall gauge
      coverage, but also due to limitations in the models themselves.
        <citation>b7_c6_r19+1</citation> quote typical errors of 10-20% for rainfall and 25% for
      streamflow data, with larger errors being quite possible, and note that as a consequence high
      correlation is unlikely to be obtained in the resulting regional relationships.</para>
    <para>Scatter in the relationships can also be caused by different methods of treating the data
      when parameters were originally calibrated. These include different assumptions when
      separating baseflow, and different rainfall loss models, for example proportional loss as
      opposed to continuing loss rate. These different assumptions can lead to different calibrated
      parameter values, and hence contribute to scatter in the regional relationship. This problem
      will be reduced if the regional relationship is developed using consistent methods of treating
      the data. However, when parameters are combined from several different studies to develop a
      regional relationship, care should be taken to ensure that consistent parameter values are
      used.</para>
    <para>Another cause of scatter can result from different parameters being derived from
      calibrations using floods of different magnitudes. <citation>b7_c6_r35+1</citation> found that
      calibrated values of the RORB parameter k<subscript>c</subscript> were larger for larger
      floods, when overbank flow became established, compared to smaller in-bank flows. Similar
      effects are likely in all runoff-routing models. The use of a single catchment parameter value
      in regional relationships, without regard to the magnitude of the flood, may therefore call
      into question the validity of the relationship <citation>b7_c6_r35</citation>.</para>
    <para>It is important to note that that the value of the lag parameter <emphasis role="italic"
        >k</emphasis> (<xref linkend="b5_c5_s_014"/>) (or the corresponding
        k<subscript>c</subscript>, C, B and <inlineequation>
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
          <mi>β</mi>
        </math>
      </inlineequation> parameters in RORB, WBNM, RAFTS and URBS respectively) depends on the values
      of other parameters adopted during calibration of the model. The values of these lag
      parameters used in regional relationships will be dependent on the values of, for example, the
      nonlinearity parameter <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis>, as well as the stream channel
      routing method used and the stream channel parameter values adopted. Another cause of
      variation in the lag parameter can occur if the basic model is modified, for example by
      allocating proportionally greater lag time to subareas and less to stream reaches
        <citation>b7_c6_r18</citation> in which case the calibrated <emphasis role="italic"
        >k</emphasis> values will not be consistent with those calibrated for the same events using
      the basic model.</para>
    <para>It is possible to obtain an approximate adjustment for <emphasis role="italic"
        >k</emphasis> (or K<subscript>c</subscript>, C, B or <inlineequation>
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
          <mi>β</mi>
        </math>
      </inlineequation>) values which have been derived using other values of <emphasis
        role="italic">m</emphasis> so that they correspond to a base value, for example, <emphasis
        role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8 <citation>b7_c6_r24</citation>. This is done by adjusting
        <emphasis role="italic">k</emphasis> so that the same overall lag time K is maintained for
      the different <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> values, using <xref
        linkend="b7_ch6_e_95nxr"/>. This requires an average or representative discharge for the
      particular flood, which will be half or less than half of the peak discharge
        Q<subscript>p</subscript>. <citation>arr_1987+1</citation> used an average discharge equal
      to Q<subscript>p</subscript>/2, giving the following adjustment: </para>
    <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_95nxr">
      <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
        <msub>
          <mi>k</mi>
          <mrow>
            <mn>0.8</mn>
          </mrow>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>k</mi>
          <mi>m</mi>
        </msub>
        <msup>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>Q</mi>
                    <mi>p</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>m</mi>
            <mo>−</mo>
            <mn>0.8</mn>
          </mrow>
        </msup>
      </math>
    </equation>
    <para>where <emphasis role="italic">k<subscript>m</subscript></emphasis> is the lag parameter
        (K<subscript>c</subscript>, C, B or <inlineequation>
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
          <mi>β</mi>
        </math>
      </inlineequation>) corresponding to a specified value of <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>Most regional relationships relate the lag parameter to one or more physical
      characteristics of the catchment. These are most commonly the area A, stream length L and
      stream slope S<subscript>c</subscript>, although other measures, such as elevation, average
      rainfall and drainage density are sometimes used. Different studies sometimes use different
      definitions of stream slope S<subscript>c</subscript> so that caution is needed to ensure that
      the correct definition is used when applying the relationships. Measurements of stream length
      L are dependent on the map scale used <citation>b5_c2_r2</citation> and this should also be
      considered when applying the relationships. Stream length is strongly correlated with
      catchment area <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154217+1000" content=" "?>and
      stream slope is moderately correlated with area, so that relationships involving area A alone,
      or stream length L alone are often sufficient to describe the regional relationship.</para>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_mielm">
      <title>Regional relationships for RORB</title>
      <para>The greatest number of derived parameter values and regional relationships are available
        for the RORB Model. The relationships recommended below are derived from all readily
        available data. Values of the parameters and the catchments used in deriving the
        relationships are generally listed in the cited publications. Although the nonlinearity
        parameter <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> can be varied to improve the hydrograph fit
        when calibrating the model, most studies have found <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> to
        lie in the range 0.6 to 1.0, and many studies adopt a constant value of <emphasis
          role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8
          <citation>b7_c6_r14,b8_c_r12,b7_c6_r10,b7_c6_r26</citation>. All relationships for
          k<subscript>c</subscript> given in this section are for a value of <emphasis role="italic"
          >m</emphasis> = 0.8 except where specifically noted.</para>
      <para>Most of the relationships are of similar form and involve only the single catchment
        variable, area A in km<superscript>2</superscript>, since this has been found to be the
        dominant variable. To allow comparisons, relationships developed by various researchers are
        presented, together with the number and size range of the catchments used (where available).
        The recommended regional relationships for each region are then given in boxes.</para>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_o0osh">
        <title>Queensland</title>
        <para>Relationships have been developed by <citation>b7_c6_r34+1</citation>,
            <citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation>, <citation>b7_c6_r13+1</citation>,
            <citation>b7_c6_r33+1</citation> and <citation>b5_c6_r35+1</citation>. For 14 catchments
          (158 to 3430 km<superscript>2</superscript>) generally covering the coast, plus one
          catchment near Mt. Isa, <citation>b7_c6_r34+1</citation> obtained:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_iou7u">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.69</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.63</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <equation>
          <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
            <mtext>m&#x00A0;=&#x00A0;0</mtext>
            <mtext>.73</mtext>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>For 25 catchments (56 to 5170 km<superscript>2</superscript>), with parameters
          adjusted to <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.75, <citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation>
          obtained:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_49xtl">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.35</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.71</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>For four catchments in the Darling Downs (2.5 to 50 km<superscript>2</superscript>)
          with m = 0.8, <citation>b7_c6_r13+1</citation> obtained:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_aux7r">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.80</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.62</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>For nine small catchments in south-east Queensland (0.002 to 50
            km<superscript>2</superscript>) with <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8,
            <citation>b5_c6_r35+1</citation> obtained:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_nkgk2">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.83</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.35</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>For 88 catchments (2.5 to 16,400 km<superscript>2</superscript>), covering both
          coastal and inland areas of Queensland, with parameters adjusted to <emphasis
            role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.80, <citation>b7_c6_r33+1</citation> obtained:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_m3ewb">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.88</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.53</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>Although <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_iou7u"/> to <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_ohwtn"/> appear
          to be quite different, when plotted together, with each relationship covering its range of
          catchment
          sizes<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154349+1000" content=" (Figure 5.3.4.14)"?>,
          they conform to a general trend and can be viewed as different samples from the population
          of Queensland catchments. The relationship of <citation>b7_c6_r33+1</citation>, equation
            <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_ohwtn"/>, is a good average to all relationships and is
          recommended. <citation>b7_c6_r33+1</citation> also investigated possible variations of
            K<subscript>c</subscript> within the various regions of the study, and also any effects
          of catchment slope, but no relationships were found.</para>
        <sidebar>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">The relationship of <citation>b7_c6_r33+1</citation>, <xref
                linkend="b7_ch6_e_ohwtn"/>, is a good average to all relationships and is
              recommended</emphasis>.</para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_ohwtn">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>0.88</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.53</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation>
        </sidebar>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_65ru3">
        <title>New South Wales</title>
        <para>Relationships have been developed by <citation>b7_c6_r16+1</citation>,
            <citation>b7_c6_r30+1</citation> and <citation>b7_c6_r32+1</citation>. For 26 catchments
          (0.1 to 4560 km<superscript>2</superscript>) in the Newcastle-Sydney-Wollongong region,
          with <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8, <citation>b7_c6_r30+1</citation>
          obtained:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_fcm20">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>1.09</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.45</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>No regional trends were apparent, except for some lower values of
            K<subscript>c</subscript> in the Upper Hunter valley. Addition of slope to the
          regressions did not improve the fitted relationships appreciably.
            <citation>b7_c6_r32+1</citation> added to the data of <citation>b7_c6_r16+1</citation>
          and derived relationships for 46 catchments (0.1 to 13,000
          km<superscript>2</superscript>). Relationships were derived using area A, stream length L
          and stream length divided by slope (L/S<superscript>0.5</superscript>). The fit of these
          various relationships to the data were similar, and a relationship involving area A was
          considered to be the most logical one to adopt. The relationships were:</para>
        <para>West of Great Dividing Range, upper western slopes and tablelands (12 catchments, 100
          to 4770 km<superscript>2</superscript>)</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_5cq1l">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.80</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.51</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>East of Great Dividing Range (34 catchments, 0.1 to 6465
            km<superscript>2</superscript>)</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_xkr64">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>1.18</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.47</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>Since the relationships are very similar, a combined relationship was derived for all
          46 catchments:</para>
        <para>NSW catchments</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_9xix6">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>1.18</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.46</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para><citation>b7_c6_r32+1</citation> found that most catchments had values of <emphasis
            role="italic">m</emphasis> in the range 0.75 to 1.0 and adopted a fixed value of
            <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8 for all catchments. No trends for
            K<subscript>c</subscript> to vary with event size were evident, indicating that the
          nonlinearity was adequately described by adopting <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> =
          0.8. Weighted average and direct average K<subscript>c</subscript> values were calculated
          from all events on each catchment, with little difference being apparent.</para>
        <para>When <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_fcm20"/> to <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_9xix6"/> are plotted
          to cover their range of catchment sizes, all equations are very similar, and equation<xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_9xix6"/> is recommended for catchments both east and west of the Great
          Dividing Range.</para>
        <sidebar>
          <para><emphasis role="bold"><xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_q97v8"/> is recommended for catchments
              both east and west of the Great Dividing Range.</emphasis></para>
          <para>NSW catchments</para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_q97v8">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>1.18</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.46</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation>
        </sidebar>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_d0wdn">
        <title>Victoria</title>
        <para>Regional relationships have been developed by <citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation> and
            <citation>b7_c6_r14+1</citation>.</para>
        <para><citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation> developed relationships for 16 catchments (20 to 1924
            km<superscript>2</superscript>) with <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.75:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_are96">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>1.37</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.59</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <sidebar>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Region with mean annual rainfall greater than 800 mm (19
              catchments, 38 to 3910 km<superscript>2</superscript>, mainly the eastern part of
              Victoria):</emphasis></para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_lxxl8">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>2.57</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.45</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Region with mean annual rainfall less than 800 mm (21
              catchments, 20 to 1924 km<superscript>2</superscript>, mainly the western part of
              Victoria):</emphasis></para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_pgvri">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>0.49</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.65</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation>
        </sidebar>
        <para>The relationships of <citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation> and
            <citation>b7_c6_r14+1</citation> for RF &gt; 800 mm are reasonably consistent, while the
            K<subscript>c</subscript> values for the drier part of the state are somewhat lower,
          particularly for the smaller
          catchments<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154430+1000" content=" (Figure 5.3.4.15)"?>.
          Comparing the <citation>b7_c6_r14+1</citation> relationships for the eastern and western
          parts of Victoria, predicted K<subscript>c</subscript> values are similar for catchments
          greater than about 2,000 km<superscript>2</superscript>, but the eastern region values are
          approximately double for catchment areas near to 100
          km<superscript>2</superscript>.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_q2pff">
        <title>South Australia</title>
        <para>Regional relationships have been developed by Lipp <citation>arr_1987</citation>,
            <citation>b7_c6_r20+1</citation> and <citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation>. For the
          south-east region, corresponding to zone 6 of the ARR design storm temporal patterns,
          Australian Rainfall and Runoff <citation>arr_1987</citation> recommended:</para>
        <para>For catchments smaller than 100 km<superscript>2</superscript>:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_de56m">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.60</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.67</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>For catchments larger than 100 km<superscript>2</superscript>, based on limited
          data:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_p0uk5">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>1.09</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.51</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>For the northern and western regions, corresponding to zone 5 of the ARR design storm
          temporal patterns, Australian Rainfall and Runoff <citation>arr_1987</citation>
          recommended for flat to undulating country:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_yahea">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>Coeff.</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.57</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>where the Coefficient ranges from 1.2 to 1.7 for equal area stream slopes ranging from
          1.0 to 0.2%.</para>
        <para> For the northern and western regions, undulating to steep country, with slopes
          greater than 1%, (<xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/>) for the wheatbelt, north-west and
          Kimberley regions of Western Australia was recommended by ARR 1987
            <citation>arr_1987</citation>. However, the more recent relations developed by
            <citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation> are now recommended for these arid regions.</para>
        <sidebar>
          <para><emphasis role="bold"><citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation> derived relationships for low
              and high rainfall areas, using <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8. For average
              annual rainfall RF less than 320 mm (7 catchments, 170 to 6020
                km<superscript>2</superscript>):</emphasis></para>
          <para>
            <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3">
              <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>K</mi>
                    <mi>c</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mn>7.06</mn>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>A</mi>
                    <mrow>
                      <mn>0.71</mn>
                    </mrow>
                  </msup>
                  <msup>
                    <mrow>
                      <mtext>&#x00A0;&#x00A0;&#x00A0;&#x00A0;&#x00A0;&#x00A0;&#x00A0;(RF/1000)</mtext>
                    </mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mn>2.79</mn>
                    </mrow>
                  </msup>
                </mrow>
              </math>
            </equation>
          </para>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">For average annual rainfall greater than 500 mm (17
              catchments, 5 to 690 km<superscript>2</superscript>):</emphasis></para>
          <para>
            <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_e6bp3">
              <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
                <msub>
                  <mi>K</mi>
                  <mi>c</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mn>0.89</mn>
                <msup>
                  <mi>A</mi>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>0.55</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </msup>
              </math>
            </equation>
          </para>
        </sidebar>
        <para>For the higher rainfall south-east region, near Adelaide,
          <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154602+1000" content="Figure 5.3.4.16 shows"?><?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154602+1000"?>There
          is a<?oxy_insert_end?> good agreement between <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_de56m"/>, <xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_p0uk5"/> and <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bp3"/>. <xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/> for areas with annual rainfall less than 320 mm also agrees
          with these equations for RF near to 320, the top of the applicable range. For the drier
          interior of the state, <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_yahea"/> predicts higher
            K<subscript>c</subscript> values, while <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/> predicts
          lower K<subscript>c</subscript> values. Since the <citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation> study
          is the most extensive, <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/> and <xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bp3"/> are recommended for South Australia, but with the note that
            <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/> predicts quite low K<subscript>c</subscript> values
          for the drier interior of the state.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_76o3a">
        <title>Western Australia</title>
        <para>Regional relationships have been developed by <citation>b7_c6_r34+1</citation>,
            <citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation>, <citation>b7_c6_r12+1</citation>.
            <citation>b7_c6_r25+1</citation> present some data for the Pilbara region. For 6
          catchments in the southwest (67 to 805 km<superscript>2</superscript>),
            <citation>b7_c6_r34+1</citation> derived:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_wgnrt">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>1.23</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.91</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para>The nonlinearity parameter <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> was also calibrated on
          each catchment, overall being near to <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.75.
            K<subscript>c</subscript> values for western Australia were found to be considerably
          higher than for the eastern states, which they attributed to the observed more sluggish
          response to rainfall of these catchments. <citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation> for 24
          catchments (28 to 5950 km<superscript>2</superscript>), using <emphasis role="italic"
            >m</emphasis> = 0.80 derived:</para>
        <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_trzt7">
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>2.48</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.47</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </math>
        </equation>
        <para><citation>b7_c6_r12+1</citation> derived relationships for 52 catchments (5 to 6526
            km<superscript>2</superscript>) in 4 regions of the state. A non-linearity parameter of
            <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8 was found to give best results for the
          south-west, and was adopted for the entire state. Variables used in the regressions were
          catchment area A, main stream length L, main stream equal area slope
            S<subscript>e</subscript> (m/km), and percentage of land cleared. Generally, regressions
          involving stream length L were better than those using area A. For the south west (26
          catchments, 29 to 3870 km<superscript>2</superscript>) relations for sub regions with
          different soil types were similar.</para>
        <sidebar>
          <para>The following equation is recommended for all jarrah forest catchments in the south
            west:</para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_ar8id">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>1.49</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>L</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.91</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation>
          <para>Relationships for the wheatbelt, north-west, and Kimberley regions were similar and
            the following is recommended, based on 26 catchments (5 to 6526
              km<superscript>2</superscript>) :</para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_rns62">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>1.06</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>L</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.87</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
              <msub>
                <mtext>       S</mtext>
                <mi>e</mi>
              </msub>
              <msup>
                <mrow/>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>−</mo>
                  <mn>0.46</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
            <?oxy_custom_end?>
          </equation>
          <para>For the arid interior of Western Australia, <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/> is
            recommended.</para>
        </sidebar>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154726+1000" content="Figure 5.3.4.17 compares these relationships. Equation 5.3.4.8b was used to convert "?>L
          <?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163725+1000"?>was converted
          <?oxy_insert_end?>to A
          <?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163916+1000"?>through the
          relationship established by <citation>b7_c6_r4+1</citation>
          <?oxy_insert_end?>to allow <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_ar8id"/> and <xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/>to be plotted against catchment area A.
          <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154740+1000" content="Figure 5.3.4.17 shows that t"?><?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T154740+1000"?>T<?oxy_insert_end?>he
          relationships of <citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation> and <citation>b7_c6_r12+1</citation> for
          the south west region are very similar and <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_ar8id"/> is
          recommended. <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/> for the wheatbelt, north-west and arid
          regions predicts K<subscript>c</subscript> values which are considerably lower than for
          the south-west region. The earlier relation of <citation>b7_c6_r34+1</citation> was based
          on only sixcatchments and predicts K<subscript>c</subscript> values which are considerably
          higher than those of <citation>b7_c6_r12+1</citation>, and is not recommended.</para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_xc7r2">
        <title>Northern Territory</title>
        <para>Relationships for K<subscript>c</subscript> have been derived for the northern half of
          the Northern Territory by the Department of Mines and Energy
          <citation>arr_1987</citation>. The Northern Territory was divided into the three
          zones.</para>
        
          <sidebar><para>For the humid zone, north of latitude <inlineequation>
              <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                <mn>15</mn>
                <mo>&#x00B0;</mo>
              </math>
            </inlineequation> S, with equal area slope S<subscript>e</subscript> in m/km the
            following equation is recommended:</para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_hdt9l">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>K</mi>
                  <mi>c</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mn>1.8</mn>
                <msup>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo stretchy="false">(</mo>
                    <mi>A</mi>
                    <mo>/</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>S</mi>
                      <mi>e</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow/>
                      <mrow>
                        <mn>0.5</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msup>
                    <mo stretchy="false">)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>0.55</mn>
                  </mrow>
                </msup>
              </mrow>
            </math>
          </equation>
          <para>For the transition zone, between latitudes <inlineequation>
              <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                <mn>15</mn>
                <mo>&#x00B0;</mo>
              </math>
            </inlineequation> S and <inlineequation>
              <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
                <mn>17.5</mn>
                <mo>&#x00B0;</mo>
              </math>
            </inlineequation> S:</para>
          <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_5sp5h">
            <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>0.35</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.64</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation></sidebar>
        <para><?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T155052+1000" content="Figure 5.3.4.18 shows that "?><xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_hdt9l"/> and <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5sp5h"/> are similar for
          catchments greater than 2500 km<superscript>2</superscript>, but with smaller
            K<subscript>c</subscript> values predicted for smaller catchments in the transition zone
          compared to the humid zone. </para>
        <para>For the arid zone, below latitude <inlineequation>
            <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
              <mn>17.5</mn>
              <mo>&#x00B0;</mo>
            </math>
          </inlineequation> S ARR 1987 <citation>arr_1987</citation> recommended the relationship
          for the northern and western regions of South Australia (<xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_yahea"/>)
          be used. <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_yahea"/> predicts higher K<subscript>c</subscript> values
          than both the humid and transition zones, and as discussed below, is not recommended.
            <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T155110+1000" content="Figure 5.3.4.18 shows that "?><xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/>, for the wheatbelt, north-west, Kimberley and arid interior
          of Western Australia, lies within the range of values for the drier interior of south
          Australia (<xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/>) and is close to K<subscript>c</subscript>
          values derived by <citation>b5_c3_r5+1</citation> for two catchments in the arid zone near
          to Alice Springs.</para>
        <sidebar>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Therefore <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/> is recommended for
              the arid interior of the Northern territory.</emphasis></para>
        </sidebar>
        
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_qos1x">
        <title>Arid Region of Central Australia</title>
        <para>For the arid region of Central Australia, approximately corresponding to zone 5 of the
          ARR storm temporal patterns in ARR 1987 <citation>arr_1987</citation>, and covering the
          interior of South Australia, Western Australia and the Northern Territory, the data of
            <citation>b7_c6_r12+1</citation>, <citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation>,
            <citation>b5_c3_r5+1</citation> may be used to guide selection of
            K<subscript>c</subscript>
          values.<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T155124+1000" content=" These are shown on figure 5.3.4.18."?></para>
        <para>Predicted K<subscript>c</subscript> values for the arid regions of South Australia
            (<xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/>), Western Australia (<xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"
          />) and Victoria (<xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_pgvri"/>) are lower than
            K<subscript>c</subscript> values for the higher rainfall areas of these states. Similar
          trends for lower K<subscript>c</subscript> values in lower rainfall regions have been
          found by <citation>b7_c6_r36+1</citation> and <citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation>. <xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_yahea"/> appears to be an anomaly since it predicts higher
            K<subscript>c</subscript> values for the arid zone of the Northern Territory compared to
          the humid and transition zones.</para>
        <para><xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/> for the wheatbelt, north-west and Kimberley region of
          Western Australia lies within the range of K<subscript>c</subscript> values predicted by
            <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/> for the arid zone of south Australia. The data of
            <citation>b5_c3_r5+1</citation> also agrees with equation <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"
          />. </para>
        <sidebar>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Therefore equation <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_rns62"/> is
              recommended for the arid interior of Western Australia and the Northern territory, and
              equation <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_e6bgfp3"/> for the arid region of South
              Australia.</emphasis></para>
        </sidebar>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_am5rq">
        <title>Tasmania</title>
        <para><citation>b7_c6_r24+1</citation> developed the following relation for 17 catchments
          (63 to 1780 km<superscript>2</superscript>) using <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> =
          0.75:</para>
        <para>
          <equation  xml:id="b7_ch6_e_5sq5h">
            <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>4.86</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.32</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation>
        </para>
        <para>Australian Rainfall and Runoff <citation>arr_1987</citation> presents a relation
          developed by the Tasmanian Hydro Electric Commission for western Tasmania, with <emphasis
            role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.75:</para>
        <para>
          <equation  xml:id="b7_ch6_e_5spdh">
            <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
              <msub>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mi>c</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>0.86</mn>
              <msup>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>0.57</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </math>
          </equation>
        </para>
        <para><xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5sq5h"/> and <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5spdh"/> are in good
          agreement for catchments near to 1000 km<superscript>2</superscript> but <xref
            linkend="b7_ch6_e_5sq5h"/> predicts larger K<subscript>c</subscript> values for smaller
          catchments. </para>
        <para>
          <sidebar>
            <para>In the absence of further data, equation <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5spdh"/> is
              recommended for Tasmania.</para>
          </sidebar>
        </para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_4vwbd">
      <title>Regional relationships for RORB using Area-Standardised Lag Parameter</title>
      <para><xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_iou7u"/> to <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5spdh"/> all show that the
        lag parameter K<subscript>c</subscript> of RORB is strongly correlated with catchment area A
        raised to a power slightly greater than 0.5. Since stream lengths are also strongly related
        to catchment area
        <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163436+1000" content="(equation 5.3.4.8) "?>raised
        to a very similar power, it follows that K<subscript>c</subscript> will be related to stream
        length or a measure of stream length. One measure of stream length which has been adopted in
        RORB is the average flow distance
        d<subscript>av</subscript><?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163440+1000" content=" (equation 5.3.4.15)"?>.
        McMahon and Muller <citation>b7_c6_r21,b7_c6_r22</citation> and
          <citation>b7_c6_r36+1</citation> have used these relations to form an area-standardised
        lag parameter K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript>.
          <citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation> formed a similar area-standardised lag parameter
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/A<superscript>0.57</superscript>. Because of the strong relation
        between K<subscript>c</subscript> and measures of area and stream length, the
        area-standardised lag parameter should be essentially independent of the catchment size. The
        area-standardised lag parameter can then be seen as analogous to lag parameters C
        <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163550+1000" content="(equation 5.3.4.16)"?>,
        B<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163554+1000" content=" (equation 5.3.4.18)"?>
        and
        β<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163601+1000" content=" (equation 5.3.4.20)"?>
        in the WBNM, RAFTS and URBS models respectively.</para>
      <para><citation>b7_c6_r36+1</citation> found that
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> increased as mean annual rainfall
        increased in Victoria (30 catchments) and western Australia (51 catchments), but not in New
        South Wales, Queensland or the Timor sea region of the Northern Territory (41 catchments in
        total). For all 122 catchments, the average value of
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> was found to be 1.09.
          <citation>b7_c6_r15+1</citation> found a similar increase of
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/A<superscript>0.57</superscript> as mean annual rainfall
        increased for South Australia, Victoria, Western Australia and the Alice Springs region of
        the Northern territory. The effect appears to be more pronounced in the drier winter
        rainfall regimes.</para>
      <para><citation>b7_c6_r26+1</citation> combined the data of <citation>b7_c6_r14+1</citation>,
          <citation>b7_c6_r10+1</citation> and <citation>b7_c6_r36+1</citation>, for more than 220
        catchments in Queensland, New South Wales, Victoria, Tasmania and Western Australia. The
        non-linearity parameter was set at <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.8. The mean
        value of K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> was found to range between
        0.96 and 1.25, depending on the particular region. The results of
          <citation>b7_c6_r36+1</citation> and <citation>b7_c6_r26+1</citation> allow
          K<subscript>c</subscript> to be estimated for any catchment by first calculating the
        average flow distance dav, then multiplying it by the appropriate area-standardised lag
        parameter value.</para>
      <para>These results also indicate that many of the regional relations across Australia <xref
          linkend="b7_ch6_e_iou7u"/> to <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5spdh"/>) could be fitted by either
        a single relation or a small number of similar relations. For example, the data of
          <citation>b7_c6_r14+1</citation> for 30 catchments (20 to 3910
          km<superscript>2</superscript>) produces the following relation between dav (km) and A
          (km<superscript>2</superscript>):</para>
      <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_5szzh">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>d</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mi>a</mi>
                <mi>v</mi>
              </mrow>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mn>0.98</mn>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.54</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>
      <para>Combining equation <xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5szzh"/> with the range of
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> values from 0.96 to 1.25 produces a
        general relation:</para>
      <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_5szzzp5h">
        <math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mi>c</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mtext>Coeff</mtext>
            <mtext>.</mtext>
            <msup>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mn>0.54</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
          </mrow>
        </math>
      </equation>
      <para>where the coefficient ranges from 0.94 to 1.22.</para>
      <para><xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5szzzp5h"/>
        <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163500+1000" content="is"?><?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163500+1000"?>can
        be<?oxy_insert_end?> plotted for the mid-range coefficient value
        1.08<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163524+1000" content=" in figure 5.3.4.19"?>,
        together with the recommended relationships for the various regions of Australia, and is
        seen to lie in the middle of these relationships. </para>
      <para>While the area-standardised lag parameter can be expected to be essentially independent
        of catchment size, it may be related to other variables. <citation>b7_c6_r10+1</citation>
        developed regression relationships between
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> and a range of catchment, climatic
        and RORB model properties for seven groups. The method is also presented in
          <citation>b8_c_r15+1</citation>. Catchments were placed into groups based on hydrological
        similarity, utilising Andrews curves, rather than on geographical region. All values of
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> are for <emphasis role="italic"
          >m</emphasis> = 0.8 and using a proportional loss rather than a continuing loss rate
        model. Data from 72 catchments from the east coast of Australia, Tasmania, the Adelaide
        Hills, and the south-west of Western Australia were used. The various regression equations,
        and the variables in them, were not consistent across the seven groups. Slope appeared in
        the equation for only one group. While reasonably strong regressions could be developed for
        the catchments in the data set, difficulties in assigning ungauged catchments to a
        particular group have been found to cause problems in application of the method
          <citation>b7_c6_r27,b7_c6_r26</citation>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_eovge">
      <title>Regional Relationships for WBNM</title>
      <para>In WBNM the non-linearity parameter is recommended to be set at <emphasis role="italic"
          >m</emphasis> = 0.77, unless there is strong evidence to use another value. This is very
        close to the widely adopted value of <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.80 in RORB.
        With parameter <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> set, only the lag parameter
        C<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163617+1000" content=" in equation 5.3.4.16"?>
        needs to be evaluated. As noted previously, parameter C is effectively an area-standardised
        value analogous to K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> in RORB. Therefore
        parameter C should be independent of catchment size. Additionally, if the value of the
        non-linearity parameter <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> is correct, parameter C should
        be independent of the flood size.</para>
      <para>Parameter values have been derived for WBNM by <citation>b7_c6_r5+1</citation>,
          <citation>b5_c3_r95+1</citation>, <citation>b7_c6_r30+1</citation>,
          <citation>b7_c6_r3+1</citation> and <citation>b7_c6_r4+1</citation>. Plots of parameter C
        against catchment area A have shown no trend for C to vary with catchment size,
        indicat<?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163640+1000"?>e<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163642+1000" content="ing"?>
        that the power of area A<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163625+1000" content=" in equation 5.3.4.16 "?><?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163649+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>is satisfactory. The lack of dependence between the area-standardised form
        of the lag parameter in RORB and catchment area has also been noted by
          <citation>b7_c6_r26+1</citation>. Additionally, plots of C against the peak discharge of
        the recorded flood have shown no trend for C to vary with flood size, indicating that the
        non-linearity parameter <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis> = 0.77 is
        satisfactory.<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163655+1000" content=" Figures 5.3.4.20 and 5.3.4.21 show typical plots of parameter C."?></para>
      <para><citation>b7_c6_r3+1</citation> investigated possible trends in parameter C against a
        range of storm and catchment characteristics. Storm variables which were considered included
        the peak discharge, rainfall depth, rainfall excess depth, rainfall intensity, location of
        peak burst within storm, and spatial distribution of rainfall. Catchment variables included
        area A, stream slope S<subscript>e</subscript>, stream length L, length to centroid
          L<subscript>c</subscript>, spatial distribution of area L<subscript>c</subscript>/L,
        catchment shape
        A/L<?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>2<?oxy_custom_end?>,
        catchment elevation, number of rain days, and mean annual rainfall. The study used 251
        storms on 17 catchments in eastern Queensland. While slight trends were apparent in some
        cases and for some subsets of catchments, there were no strong trends for C to vary with any
        of these variables. The independence of parameter C from these storm and catchment
        characteristics indicates that one value applies generally over a wide range of regions. A
        similar result has been obtained for the area-standardised lag parameter in RORB by
          <citation>b7_c6_r26+1</citation>.</para>
      <para>Values of the lag parameter C calibrated for south and eastern Australia are:</para>
      <para>For 207 storms on 17 coastal catchments in Queensland (164 to 7300
          km<superscript>2</superscript>), ranging from the North Johnstone to the Mary River,
          <citation>b7_c6_r3+1</citation> obtained a mean value of parameter C of 1.47.</para>
      <para>For ten catchments in the coastal region of NSW (0.4 to 250
          km<superscript>2</superscript>), <citation>b7_c6_r5+1</citation> obtained a mean lag
        parameter C of 1.68. For 17 catchments (0.1 to 800 km<superscript>2</superscript>) in the
        Newcastle, Sydney-Wollongong region <citation>b7_c6_r30+1</citation> obtained a mean C of
        1.16. Recent calibration of WBNM for 205 storms on 19 coastal catchments of NSW (0.2 to 6910
          km<superscript>2</superscript>) by <citation>b7_c6_r4+1</citation> obtained a mean C of
        1.74.</para>
      <para>For 59 storms on six catchments in Victoria on the coastal side of the Great Dividing
        Range, ranging from Bairnsdale to Ballarat (0.1 to 153 km<superscript>2</superscript>) plus
        45 storms on four catchments inland of the Great Dividing Range near Healseville and Stawell
        (63 to 259 km<superscript>2</superscript>), <citation>b7_c6_r4+1</citation> obtained a mean
        value of C = 1.74.</para>
      <para>For 90 storms on eight catchments in the Adelaide Hills near to Adelaide (4 to 176
          km<superscript>2</superscript>), <citation>b7_c6_r4+1</citation> obtained a mean value of
        C = 1.64.</para>
      <para>The small range of these mean parameter values corresponds to the similar small range of
        the area-standardised parameter K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> in RORB
        found by <citation>b7_c6_r26+1</citation>. <citation>b7_c6_r4+1</citation> calculated a mean
        value of parameter C for all 54 catchments in Queensland, New South Wales, Victoria and
        South Australia of 1.64, and 1.59 when the parameter values were weighted by the number of
        storms on each catchment. </para>
      <sidebar>
        <para>With no strong regional trends being apparent, and no strong relationships between
          parameter C and catchment or storm characteristics, an overall mean value of parameter C =
          1.60 is recommended for these states of Australia.</para>
      </sidebar>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_2e441">
      <title>Relationships between RORB, WBNM, RAFTS and URBS Lag Parameters</title>
      <para>As noted previously, all four runoff-routing models contain area-standardised lag
        parameters. These are K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript>, C, B and <inlineequation>
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <mi>β</mi>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> of the RORB, WBNM, RAFTS and URBS models respectively. It could therefore
        be expected that these parameters will be related to one another. For example, comparing
        equation<?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163118+1000"?>s<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163116+1000" content=" 5.3.4.16"?>
        for WBNM with equations
        <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163126+1000" content="5.3.4.5, 5.3.4.13 and 5.3.4.14 "?>for
        RORB reveal<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163112+1000" content="s"?> that
          CA<subscript>i</subscript><superscript>0.57</superscript> in WBNM corresponds to
          (K<subscript>c</subscript> / d<subscript>av</subscript>).L<subscript>i</subscript> in
        RORB. Note that the area term A<subscript>i</subscript> and stream length term
          L<subscript>i</subscript> in these equations refer to subcatchments and stream segments
        rather than to complete catchments.</para>
      <para>Measures of stream length, such as L
        <?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163137+1000" content="(equation 5.3.4.8) "?>and
          d<subscript>av</subscript> (<xref linkend="b7_ch6_e_5szzh"/>) are strongly related with
        catchment area, and it is reasonable to assume that stream segment lengths are also strongly
        correlated with subcatchment areas. Replacing the L<subscript>i</subscript> term by
          A<superscript>0.55</superscript><?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163215+1000" content=" from equations 5.3.4.8"?>,
        it is seen that parameter C of WBNM should be directly proportional to
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> of RORB. From the previous sections
        the average value of C is close to 1.60 and the average value of
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> is 1.1 (range 0.96 to 1.25).
        Therefore a relationship between these two parameters is:</para>
      <equation xml:id="b7_ch6_e_lsxpp">
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
          <mi>C</mi>
          <mtext> </mtext>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mtext> </mtext>
          <mn>1.45</mn>
          <mtext> </mtext>
          <msub>
            <mi>K</mi>
            <mi>c</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>/</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>d</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mi>a</mi>
              <mi>v</mi>
            </mrow>
          </msub>
        </math>
      </equation>
      <para>Similar analysis indicates that parameter <inlineequation>
          <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block">
            <mi>β</mi>
          </math>
        </inlineequation> of URBS should be directly proportional to
          K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript>. For RAFTS the proportionality coefficient<?oxy_insert_start author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163205+1000"?>
        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T162925+1000" content=" of equation 5.3.4.19 "?>should
        be related to K<subscript>c</subscript>/d<subscript>av</subscript> but with an adjustment
        required for the slope term S.</para>
      <para>It should be noted that the correspondence between the area-standardised lag parameters
        of the various models depends slightly on the power to which area A is raised, as well as
        the non-linearity parameter <emphasis role="italic">m</emphasis>, however these are not too
        dissimilar in the four models. The particular ratio between the parameters will depend on
        the way in which the lag parameter is incorporated into flood routing in the particular
        modelling platforms, as well as the method adopted for stream channel routing. The ratio
        1.45 between RORB and WBNM will not apply to RAFTS and URBS.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch6_s_w0rrz">
    <title>Modelling Urban Catchments</title>
    <para>Increased flood discharges in urban or partially urbanised catchments can be attributed to
      two factors. The increased proportion of paved or impervious surfaces produce greater runoff
      volumes, and the decreased lag times for the runoff produces higher peak discharges. These
      increases are not the same for all floods, being more pronounced for the smaller more common
      events. Data given by <citation>b7_c6_r7+1</citation>, <citation>b9_c2_r18+1</citation> and
        <citation>b4_c2_r21+1</citation> indicate that for 10% Annual Exceedance Probability events,
      urban flood peak discharges increase by 2 to 5 times, while for 1% Annual Exceedance
      Probability events urban peaks increase by less than two times.</para>
    <para>Increased runoff volumes from paved surfaces result from decreased rainfall losses. </para>
    <para>The decrease in lag time can be attributed to replacement of vegetated overland flow
      surfaces and natural stream channels by more hydraulically efficient paved surfaces, gutters,
      pipes and channels. Ratios of lag times in urban compared to otherwise equivalent natural
      catchments typically range from 0.1 to 0.5
        <citation>b9_c2_r25,b9_c2_r18,b4_c2_r21,b7_c6_r6,b5_c3_r95</citation>. Decreases in lag time
      have been related to the fraction of the catchment which is urbanised by
        <citation>b7_c6_r1+1</citation> and <citation>b8_c_r53+1</citation>. Other studies by
        <citation>b7_c6_r28+1</citation>, <citation>b7_c6_r8+1</citation>,
        <citation>b7_c6_r9+1</citation>, <citation>b7_c6_r29+1</citation> and
        <citation>b7_c6_r11+1</citation> relate lag time to the impervious fraction. A survey of
      these relations is given by <citation>b7_c6_r6+1</citation> and
        <citation>b5_c3_r95+1</citation>.</para>
    <para>All of these studies show a decrease in lag time as the catchment becomes more urbanised.
      Typically, the lag reduction is expressed in terms of the urban fraction U in the form (1+U)z
      where <emphasis role="italic">z</emphasis> ranges between –1.7 and –2.7, with an average near
      to –2.0. Equation 5.3.4.19 adopts <emphasis role="italic">z</emphasis> = -1.97 for RAFTS,
      while equation 5.3.4.20 adopts <emphasis role="italic">z</emphasis> = -2.0 for URBS. A value
      of <emphasis role="italic">z</emphasis> = -2.0 in this relation produces a lag ratio of 0.25
      for a fully urbanised catchment.</para>
    <para>The urban fraction urban often does not fully describe the state of urbanisation, since a
      100% urban catchment can be residential with typically 30% impervious surfaces, or it can be a
      high density commercial centre with close to 100% impervious. Typical relationships between
      the impervious and the urban fraction are given by <citation>b4_c2_r5+1</citation> and
        <citation>b5_c3_r95+1</citation>. The RAFTS model accounts for this by allocating an
      equivalent urban fraction U to each level of impervious fraction. For a fully impervious
      surface, this produces a lag ratio of 0.11.</para>
    <para>When a subcatchment is partly urbanised, it can be modelled in a lumped form whereby a
      single hydrograph is calculated for the combined pervious and impervious surfaces, using a
      reduced lag
      time<?oxy_delete author="ward" timestamp="20160707T163238+1000" content=" according to equations such as 5.3.4.19 and 5.3.4.20"?>.
      This is often done in the RORB, RAFTS and URBS models. Alternatively, the subcatchment can be
      split into separate pervious and impervious surfaces with separate lag times and separate
      hydrographs calculated for each surface. This is the recommended method for WBNM, where the
      lag ratio for fully impervious surfaces is set at 0.10, similar to the value recommended in
      RAFTS. However, all models can be configured to operate in either lumped or split form, and
      RAFTS has been found to produce good results in the split form for catchments in the ACT
        <citation>b7_c6_r17</citation>. Split pervious and impervious modelling is similar to the
      procedures used in detailed urban drainage modelling platform such as DRAINS.</para>
    <para>Urban catchments have other features which need to be considered when setting up a model.
      During large storms flows may be diverted out of the catchment’s stream network to form new
      overland flow routes. This can happen particularly when culvert or bridge openings become
      blocked by debris. The model should be set up to reflect these alternative flow paths. Another
      feature requiring consideration is that runoff from small development sites, and particularly
      when onsite detention storage is used to reduce flood peaks, will require routing calculations
      at small time steps and with small discharges. The stream network runoff-routing models
      currently used in Australia all have these capabilities.</para>
  </section>

 <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  

</chapter>

