<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b2_ch2"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Rainfall Models</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/jordan_phillip.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/leonard_michael.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>

  </info>

  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>

      <td>2</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>

      <td>2</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>

      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>

      <td>N/A</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>General</td>

      <td>Needs finalisation</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_1">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>The philosophical basis for use of a catchment modelling approach is
    the generation of data that would have been recorded if a gauge were
    present at the location(s) of interest for the catchment condition(s) of
    interest. For reliable and robust predictions of design flood estimates
    with this philosophical basis, there is a need to ensure that rainfall
    characteristics as one of the major influencing factors are considered
    appropriately</para>

    <para>There are many features of rainfall to consider when developing a
    rainfall model for design flood prediction; exploration of these features
    can be undertaken using historical storm events as a basis. In using this
    approach, there is a need to acknowledge that consideration of historical
    events is an analysis problem and not a design problem. Nonetheless,
    insights into the characteristics of rainfall events for design purposes
    can be obtained from this review.</para>

    <para>Rainfall exhibits both spatial and temporal variability at all
    spatial and temporal scales that are of interest in flood hydrology. High
    resolution recording instruments have identified temporal variability in
    rainfall from time scales of less than one minute to several days (Marani,
    2005). Similarly, observations of rainfall from high resolution weather
    radar and satellites have demonstrated spatial variability in rainfall at
    spatial resolutions from 1 km to more than 500 km (Lovejoy and Schertzer,
    2006).</para>

    <para>While it is important to be aware of this large degree of
    variability, for design flood estimation based on catchment modelling it
    is only necessary to reflect rainfall variability at space and time scales
    that are influential in the formation of flood events. The main focus is
    generally on individual storms or bursts of intense rainfall within storms
    that cover the catchment extent. However, it needs to be recognised that,
    depending on the design problem (e.g. flood level determination in a
    system with very large storage and small outflow capacity), the relevant
    ‘event’ to be considered may consist of rainfall sequences that include
    not just one storm but extend over several months or even years.</para>

    <para>A broad distinction between different rainfall models can be made on
    the basis of their scope. Commonly rainfall models consider only the
    temporal dimension by neglecting the spatial dimension. Inclusion of the
    spatial dimension together with the temporal dimension results in an
    alternative form of a rainfall model. A categorisation of rainfall models
    is:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Models that concentrate on significant rainfall events (storms
        or intense bursts within storms) at a point or with a typical spatial
        pattern that have the potential to produce floods;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Models that attempt to simulate rainfall behaviour over an
        extended period at a point, producing essentially a complete rainfall
        time series incorporating flood producing bursts of rainfall, low
        intensity bursts of rainfall and the dry period between bursts of
        rainfall ; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Models that attempt to replicate rainfall in both the spatial
        and temporal dimensions. Currently, models in this category are being
        researched and are not in general usage. There are, however, many
        problems where rainfall models of this form may be applicable.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Rainfall models that concentrate on the flood producing bursts of
    rainfall have the inherent advantage of conciseness (from a flood
    perspective, only the interesting bursts of rainfall are considered).
    Hence, there is great potential to consider interactions of rainfall with
    other influential flood producing factors but also a need to allow for the
    impact of varying initial conditions.</para>

    <para>Continuous rainfall models have the inherent advantage of allowing
    the initial catchment conditions (e.g. soil moisture status, initial
    reservoir content) at the onset of a storm event to be simulated directly.
    However, the need to model the rainfall characteristics of both storm
    events (intense rainfall) and inter-event periods (no rainfall to low
    intensity rainfall) adds significant complexity to continuous rainfall
    models. The greater range of events these models cover tends to be
    achieved at the cost of reduced ability to represent rarer rainfall
    events. Additionally, very long sequences of rainfall observations are
    required to properly sample rarer events. These issues make continuous
    rainfall models more suitable for simulation of frequent events.</para>

    <para>Rainfall data are mostly obtained from individual gauges (daily read
    gauges or pluviographs) and only provide data on point rainfalls. However,
    for catchment simulation the interest is on rainfall characteristics over
    the whole catchment. Rainfall models thus are needed to allow
    extrapolation of rainfall characteristics from the point scale to the
    catchment scale. In extrapolating rainfall characteristics from a point to
    a catchment or subcatchment, there is a need to ensure that the
    extrapolation does not introduce bias into the predictions. This applies
    to both continuous rainfall models and event rainfall models.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_2">
    <title>Space-time representation of rainfall events</title>

    <para>When combined, the spatial and temporal variability of rainfall will
    be referred to as the space-time variability of rainfall. The space-time
    pattern of rainfall over a catchment or study area is therefore defined in
    three dimensions: two horizontal dimensions, which are normally latitude
    and longitude (or easting and northing in a projected coordinate system)
    and one temporal dimension. In practice, the space-time pattern of
    rainfall will often be described as a three-dimensional matrix, with the
    value in each element of the matrix representing either the accumulated
    rainfall or the mean rainfall intensity for a grid cell over the catchment
    and a specified period of time for the event, as shown in <xref
    linkend="b2_ch2_f_1"/>.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch2_f_1">
      <title>Conceptual diagram of space-time pattern of rainfall</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2056.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>If the space-time pattern of rainfall is considered as a field
    defined in three-dimensions, then the temporal and spatial patterns of
    rainfall that have conventionally been used in hydrology can be considered
    as convenient statistical means of summarising that field. The temporal
    pattern of rainfall over a catchment area is derived by taking an average
    in space (over one or more grid elements) of the rainfall depth (or mean
    intensity) over each time increment of the storm. The spatial pattern of
    rainfall for an event is defined by taking an average in time (over one or
    more time periods) of the rainfall depth (or mean intensity) over each
    grid cell of the catchment. Derivation of spatial and temporal patterns is
    demonstrated with the conceptual diagram in <xref linkend="b2_ch2_f_2"/>.
    Commonly, the spatial pattern is defined by averaging over each subarea to
    be used in a model of the catchment or study area as shown in <xref
    linkend="b2_ch2_f_3"/>. The application of some catchment modelling
    systems (for example, rainfall on grid models commonly used in urban
    simulations), however, require grid based spatial patterns of rainfall. In
    these situations, each grid element can be considered as a subarea or
    subcatchment.</para>

    <para>The space-time pattern of rainfall varies in a random manner between
    events and within events. The random variability within the space-time
    pattern is influenced by spatial and temporal correlation structures that
    are an inherent observed property of rainfall. The random space-time
    variability may make it difficult to specify typical or representative
    spatial patterns for some catchments. Umakhanthan and Ball (2005) in a
    study of the Upper Parramatta River Catchment in NSW showed the variation
    in the temporal and spatial correlation between storm events on that
    catchment.</para>

    <para>However, there are often hydrometeorological drivers, as discussed
    in <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Section
    <emphasis role="bold">XX</emphasis><?oxy_custom_end ?> that cause some
    degree of similarity in spatial and space-time patterns of flood producing
    rainfall between events for a particular catchment. This similarity
    increases for the rarer events and decreases for the more frequent
    events.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch2_f_2">
      <title>Conceptual diagram showing the spatial pattern and temporal
      pattern temporal and spatial averages derived from the space-time
      rainfall field</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2057.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch2_f_3">
      <title>Conceptual diagram showing the temporal pattern over a catchment
      and the spatial pattern derived over model subareas of the
      catchment</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2058.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3">
    <title>Conceptualisation of design rainfall events</title>

    <para>Ideally, the space-time variation of rainfall over a catchment would
    be represented as moving space-time field of rainfall at the appropriate
    spatial and temporal resolution, However, while current developments are
    progressing in that direction (see, for example, stochastic –space-time
    rainfall models developed by Seed et al, 2002; Leonard et al, 2008), the
    rainfall models widely used in practice are based on a more reductionist
    approach, dealing separately with the spatial and temporal variability of
    rainfall. A result of this reductionist approach is that rainfall bursts
    are assumed to be stationary; in other words, the storm does not move
    during the period of rainfall.</para>

    <para>For ease of modelling, storm events can be conceptualised and
    represented by four main event characteristics that are analysed and
    modelled separately:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Duration of storm or burst event</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Total rainfall depth (or average intensity) over the event
        duration</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Spatial distribution (or pattern) of rainfall over the catchment
        during the event</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Temporal distribution (or pattern) of rainfall during the
        event</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>These rainfall event characteristics are discussed in separate
    sections below.</para>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_1">
      <title>Event definitions</title>

      <para>The modelling of rainfall events first requires a clear definition
      of what constitutes an event. Given the variation of rainfall in time
      and space, it is not immediately apparent when an event starts and ends.
      Start and end points of rainfall events need to be defined by rainfall
      thresholds or separation in time from preceding/subsequent rainfall. For
      an event to be significant, it may also need to exceed a total event
      rainfall threshold.</para>

      <para>Two different types of rainfall events are relevant for design
      flood estimation: complete storm events and internal bursts of intense
      rainfall. While complete storm events are the theoretically more
      appropriate form of event for flood simulation, the internal rainfall
      bursts of given duration, regardless of where they occur within a storm
      event, lend themselves more readily for statistical analysis. The IFD
      data covered in <xref linkend="b2_ch3"/> are thus for rainfall burst
      events.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_2">
      <title>Rainfall event duration.</title>

      <para>Actual storm events vary in their duration, from local
      thunderstorms lasting minutes to extended rainfall events lasting
      several days. This variation occurs in a random fashion, and rainfall
      event duration for a particular region can be characterised by a
      probability distribution. However, for practical design flood
      estimation, the occurrence of rainfalls of different durations within an
      appropriate range is generally assumed to have equal probability, and
      the ‘critical rainfall duration’ is then determined as the one that
      maximises the value of the design flood characteristic of direct
      interest.</para>

      <para>The design rainfall data provided in ARR covers the range of
      rainfall burst durations from 1 minute to 7 days.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_3">
      <title>Event rainfall depth (or average intensity)</title>

      <para>The basic methods for estimating design rainfall depths (or
      average intensities) for different durations are discussed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch3"/> (both point rainfalls and average catchment
      rainfalls). The principal modelling approach used is to fit a
      probability distribution to series of rainfall depths (annual maximum or
      peak over threshold) for the selected event duration at sites with long,
      reliable rainfall records. The results of these at-site analyses are the
      generalised over regions with similar rainfall characteristics and
      mapped over the whole of Australia.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_4">
      <title>Spatial rainfall patterns</title>

      <para>The conversion of point design rainfalls to average catchment
      design rainfalls is modelled through rainfall areal reduction factors is
      discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch4"/>. Also, presented in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4"/> are techniques for estimating the spatial pattern of
      rainfall over a catchment; models for representing the typical spatial
      variability of rainfall. These models are based either on the analysis
      and generalisation of historical storms or on spatial trends derived
      from analysis of design rainfall depths (IFD maps). The application of
      these models is explained in that chapter.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_5">
      <title>Temporal rainfall patterns</title>

      <para>There are two distinct model representations of the temporal
      variability of rainfall within events (for complete storms or internal
      bursts), depending on whether the model only reflects the central
      tendency of different observed patterns or the variability of patterns
      for different events is also modelled. These differences in modelling
      approach are further discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch2_s_4"/> and <xref
      linkend="b2_ch5"/>.</para>

      <para>In the following, a number of different approaches to model the
      space-time characteristics of event rainfall for design flood estimation
      are introduced briefly.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_4">
    <title>Spatial and temporal resolution of design rainfall models</title>

    <para>The space-time pattern of rainfall for an individual flood event
    will often have an appreciable influence on the flow hydrograph generated
    at the outlet of a catchment. Two rainfall events may have identical total
    volumes over a defined catchment area and duration but differences in
    their space-time patterns may produce very different hydrographs at the
    outlet of the catchment. Both the runoff generation and runoff routing
    processes in catchments are typically non-linear, so a space-time pattern
    that exhibits more variability will normally generate a higher volume of
    runoff and larger peak flow at the catchment outlet than a space-time
    pattern that is more uniform.</para>

    <para>Variability in hydrographs introduced by space-time variability in
    rainfall will be accentuated in catchments that have spatial and temporal
    variability in runoff generation and routing processes. For example, in a
    partly urbanised catchment, a rain storm with a spatial pattern that has
    larger depths on the urban part of the catchment than the rural part would
    normally produce both a larger volume of runoff and flood peak at the
    catchment outlet than a storm of the same depth and duration that has a
    spatially uniform rainfall pattern. Other factors in catchments that may
    accentuate the influence of the space-time rainfall pattern on the
    variability in hydrographs produced at the catchment outlet
    include:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>the presence of reservoirs and lakes, for which all rainfall is
        converted to runoff;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>the presence of dams, weirs, drains and other flow regulating
        structures;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in soil type;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in vegetation type, such as forested and
        cleared areas;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>the arrangement of the drainage network of the catchment the
        dependency of alternative flow paths on event magnitude and
        differences in contributing area with length of network;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in stream channel and floodplain
        roughness;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in slope of stream channels and
        floodplains;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in antecedent climatic conditions across
        the catchment prior to the events; and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>variations in elevation, snowpack depth, density and temperature
        in those catchments subject to rain-on-snow flood events.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The required resolution of rainfall models to adequately reflect the
    variability of rainfall in historical rainfall events has been
    investigated by Umakhanthan and Ball (2005) for the Upper Parramatta River
    catchment. They categorised the variability of recorded storm events in
    the spatial and temporal domains and confirmed that the degree of spatial
    and temporal resolution of rainfall inputs to flood estimation models can
    have a significant impact on resulting flood estimates. A range of other
    studies have come to similar conclusions but have found it difficult to
    give more than qualitative guidance on the required degree of spatial and
    temporal resolution of rainfall for different modelling applications. The
    conclusions can be summarised in qualitative terms as:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>“Spatial rainfall patterns are understood to be a dominant
        source of variability for very large catchments and for urban
        catchments but for other hydrological contexts, results vary. Much of
        this knowledge is either site specific or is expressed qualitatively”
        (Woods and Sivapalan, 1999).</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Where short response times are involved in urban catchments,
        inadequate representation of temporal variability of rainfall can lead
        to significant underestimation of design flood peaks (Ball, 1994).
        More generally, the importance of temporal variability of rainfall in
        flood modelling depends on the degree of ‘filtering’ of shorter term
        rainfall peaks through catchment routing processes (i.e. the amount of
        storage in the catchment system) and the interaction of flood
        contributions from different parts of a catchment system</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Sensitivity analyses can be applied to determine for a specific
    application the influence of the adopted spatial and temporal resolution
    of design rainfalls on flood estimates and their uncertainty
    bounds.</para>

    <para/>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_5">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Diermanse, F.L.M., Carroll, Beckers, J.V.L., Ayre, R. and
    Schuurmans, J.M. (2014). A Monte Carlo framework for the Brisbane River
    Catchment Flood Study. Engineers Australia, Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium 2014), pp 62-69.</para>

    <para>Hoang, T., Rahman, A., Weinmann, P. E., Laurenson, E. M., Nathan, R.
    J. (1999). Joint probability descriptions of design rainfalls. Intl.
    Hydrology and Water Resour. Symp of the I.E. Aust. and 2nd Int. Conference
    on Water Resour. and Env. Research, Brisbane, Australia, 6-8 July,
    1999.</para>

    <para>Jordan, P., Nathan, R and Seed, A. (2015) Application of spatial and
    space-time patterns of design rainfall to design flood estimation.
    Engineers Australia, Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium 2015), pp
    XX-XX.</para>

    <para>Leonard, M., Lambert, M. F., Metcalfe, A. V., Cowpertwait, P. S. P.
    (2008) A space-time Neyman–Scott rainfall model with defined storm extent.
    <emphasis role="italic">Water Resources Research</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="italic">44</emphasis>(9), 1–10.
    http://doi.org/10.1029/2007WR006110</para>

    <para>Lovejoy, S. and D. Schertzer, 2006: Multifractals, cloud radiances
    and rain, J. Hydrology, 322, 59-88.</para>

    <para>Marani, M., 2005: Non-power-law-scale properties of rainfall in
    space and time, Water Resour. Res., 41, W08413,
    doi:10.1029/2004WR003822.</para>

    <para>Seed, A. W., Srikanthan, R., &amp; Menabde, M. (2002). Stochastic
    space-time rainfall for designing urban drainage systems. Proc.
    International Conference on Urban Hydrology for the 21st Century, (pp.
    109-123). Kuala Lumpur.</para>

    <para>Umakhanthan, K and Ball, JE (2005). Rainfall models for catchment
    simulation. Australian Journal of Water Resources, 2005, 9 (1), pp. 55 –
    67.</para>

    <para>Woods and Sivapalan (1999). A synthesis of space-time variability in
    storm response: rainfall, runoff generation and routing. Water Resources
    Research, Vol. 35, No. 8, 1999, p. 2469-2485.</para>

    <para/>

    <para/>

    <para/>
  </section>
</chapter>
