<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b2_ch2" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
  xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Rainfall Models</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/jordan_phillip.xml"/>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/seed_alan.xml"/>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/nathan_rory.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/leonard_michael.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
    
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>13/5/2019 </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_1">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>The philosophical basis for use of a catchment modelling approach is the generation of
      data that would have been recorded if a gauge were present at the location(s) of interest for
      the catchment condition(s) of interest. For reliable and robust predictions of design flood
      estimates with this philosophical basis, there is a need to ensure that rainfall
      characteristics as one of the major influencing factors are considered
      appropriately<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T183702+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
    <para>There are many features of rainfall to consider when developing a rainfall model for
      design flood prediction; exploration of these features can be undertaken using historical
      storm events as a basis. In using this approach, there is a need to acknowledge that
      consideration of historical events is an analysis problem and not a design problem.
      Nonetheless, insights into the characteristics of rainfall events for design purposes can be
      obtained from this review.</para>
    <para>Rainfall exhibits both spatial and temporal variability at all spatial and temporal scales
      that are of interest in flood hydrology. High resolution recording instruments have identified
      temporal variability in rainfall from time scales of less than one minute to several days
        <citation>b2_c2_r6</citation>. Similarly, observations of rainfall from high resolution
      weather radar and satellites have demonstrated spatial variability in rainfall at spatial
      resolutions from 1 km to more than 500 km <citation>b2_c2_r5</citation>.</para>
    <para>While it is important to be aware of this large degree of variability, for design flood
      estimation based on catchment modelling it is only necessary to reflect rainfall variability
      at space and time scales that are influential in the formation of flood events. The main focus
      is generally on individual storms or bursts of intense rainfall within storms that cover the
      catchment extent. However, it needs to be recognised that, depending on the design problem
      (e.g. flood level determination in a system with very large storage and small outflow
      capacity), the relevant ‘event’ to be considered may consist of rainfall sequences that
      include not just one storm but extend over several months or even years.</para>
    <para>Rainfall models are designed to capture in a simplified fashion those aspects of the
      spatial and temporal variability of rainfall that a relevant to specific applications. A broad
      distinction between different rainfall models can be made on the basis of their scope.
      Commonly rainfall models consider only the temporal dimension by neglecting the spatial
      dimension. Inclusion of the spatial dimension together with the temporal dimension results in
      an alternative form of a rainfall model. This leads to the following categorisation of
      rainfall models:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Models that concentrate on significant rainfall events (storms or intense bursts
          within storms) at a point or with a typical spatial pattern that have the potential to
          produce floods;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Models that attempt to simulate rainfall behaviour over an extended period at a point,
          producing essentially a complete (continuous) rainfall time series incorporating flood
          producing bursts of rainfall, low intensity bursts of rainfall and the dry periods between
          bursts of
            rainfall<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184029+1000" content=" "?>(<xref
            linkend="b2_ch6"/>); and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Models that attempt to replicate rainfall in both the spatial and temporal dimensions.
          Currently, models in this category are being researched and are not in general usage.
          There are, however, many problems where rainfall models of this form may be
          applicable.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Rainfall models that concentrate on the flood producing bursts of rainfall have the
      inherent advantage of conciseness (from a flood perspective, only the interesting bursts of
      rainfall are considered). Hence, there is great potential to consider interactions of rainfall
      with other influential flood producing factors but they also need to allow for the impact of
      varying initial conditions.</para>
    <para>Continuous rainfall models
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184152+1000"?>(<?oxy_insert_end?><xref
        linkend="b2_ch6"/><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184152+1000"?>)
      <?oxy_insert_end?>have the inherent advantage of allowing the initial catchment conditions
      (e.g. soil moisture
      status<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184224+1000"?>
      and<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184223+1000" content=","?>
      initial reservoir content) at the onset of a storm event to be simulated directly. However,
      the need to model the rainfall characteristics of both storm events (intense rainfall) and
      inter-event periods (no rainfall to low intensity rainfall) adds significant complexity to
      continuous rainfall models. The greater range of events these models cover tends to be
      achieved at the cost of reduced ability to represent rarer, higher intensity rainfall events.
      Additionally, very long sequences of rainfall observations are required to properly sample
      rarer events. These issues make continuous rainfall models more suitable for simulation of
      frequent events.</para>
    <para>Rainfall data are mostly obtained from individual gauges (daily read gauges or
      pluviographs) and only provide data on point rainfalls. However, for catchment simulation the
      interest is on rainfall characteristics over the whole catchment. Rainfall models thus are
      needed to allow extrapolation of rainfall characteristics from the point scale to the
      catchment scale. In extrapolating rainfall characteristics from a point to a catchment or
      subcatchment, there is a need to ensure that the extrapolation does not introduce bias into
      the predictions. This applies to both continuous rainfall models and event rainfall
      models.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_2">
    <title>Space-Time Representation of Rainfall Events</title>
    <para>When combined, the spatial and temporal variability of rainfall will be referred to as the
      space-time variability of rainfall. The space-time pattern of rainfall over a catchment or
      study area is therefore defined in three dimensions: two horizontal dimensions, which are
      normally latitude and longitude (or easting and northing in a projected coordinate system) and
      one temporal dimension. In practice, the space-time pattern of rainfall will often be
      described as a three dimensional matrix, with the value in each element of the matrix
      representing either the accumulated rainfall or the mean rainfall intensity for a grid cell
      over the catchment and a specified period of time within the event, as shown in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch2_f_1"/>.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b2_ch2_f_1">
      <title>Conceptual Diagram of Space-Time Pattern of Rainfall</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2056.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>If the space-time pattern of rainfall is considered as a field defined in three
      dimensions, then the temporal and spatial patterns of rainfall that have conventionally been
      used in hydrology can be considered as convenient statistical means of summarising that field.
      The temporal pattern of rainfall over a catchment area is derived by taking an average in
      space (over one or more grid elements) of the rainfall depth (or mean intensity) over each
      time increment of the storm. The spatial pattern of rainfall for an event is defined by taking
      an average in time (over one or more time periods) of the rainfall depth (or mean intensity)
      over each grid cell of the catchment. Derivation of spatial and temporal patterns is
      demonstrated with the conceptual diagram in <xref linkend="b2_ch2_f_2"/>. Commonly, the
      spatial pattern is defined by averaging over each subarea to be used in a model of the
      catchment or study area as shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch2_f_3"/>. The application of some
      catchment modelling systems (for example,
      rainfall<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184717+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184717+1000" content=" "?>on<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184720+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184720+1000" content=" "?>grid
      models commonly used
      <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184803+1000" content="in "?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184803+1000"?>to
      simulate floods in <?oxy_insert_end?>urban
      <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184814+1000" content="simulations"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T184814+1000"?>areas<?oxy_insert_end?>),
      however, require grid based spatial patterns of rainfall. In these situations, each grid
      element can be considered as a subarea or subcatchment.</para>
    <para>The space-time pattern of rainfall varies in a random manner between events and within
      events influenced by spatial and temporal correlation structures that are an inherent observed
      property of rainfall. The random space-time variability may make it difficult to specify
      typical or representative spatial patterns for some catchments.
        <citation>b2_c2_r8+1</citation> in a study of the Upper Parramatta River Catchment in NSW
      showed the variation in the temporal and spatial correlation between storm events on that
      catchment.</para>
    <para>However, there are often hydrometeorological drivers, as discussed in <xref
      linkend="b2_ch4"/> that cause some degree of similarity in spatial and space-time
      patterns of flood producing rainfall between events for a particular catchment. This
      similarity increases for the rarer events and decreases for the more frequent events.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b2_ch2_f_2">
      <title>Conceptual Diagram of the Spatial Pattern and Temporal Pattern Temporal and 
        Spatial Averages Derived from the Space-Time Rainfall Field</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2057.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <figure xml:id="b2_ch2_f_3">
      <title>Conceptual Diagram Showing the Temporal Pattern over a Catchment and the 
        Spatial Pattern Derived over Model Subareas of the Catchment</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2058.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Orographic Enhancement and Rain Shadow Effects on Space-Time Patterns</title>
    <para>Orographic precipitation, also known as relief precipitation, is precipitation generated
      by a forced upward movement of air upon encountering a physiographic upland. This lifting can
      be caused by two mechanisms:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Upward deflection of large scale horizontal flow by the topography; or</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Anabatic or upward vertical propagation of moist air up an orographic slope caused by
          daytime heating of the mountain barrier surface.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Upon ascent, the air that is being lifted will expand and cool. This adiabatic cooling of
      a rising moist air parcel may lower its temperature to its dew point, thus allowing for
      condensation of the water vapour contained within it, and hence the formation of a cloud.
      Rainfall can be generated from the cloud through a number of physical processes
        <citation>b2_c4_r12</citation>. The cloud liquid droplets grow through collisions with other
      droplets to the size where they fall as rain. Rain drops from clouds at high altitude may fall
      through the clouds near the surface that have formed because of the uplift due to topography
      and grow as a result of collisions with the cloud droplets. Air may also become unstable as it
      is lifted over higher areas of terrain and convective storms may be triggered by this
      instability. These influences combine to typically produce a greater incidence of rainfall on
      the upwind side of hills and mountains and also typically larger rainfall intensities on the
      upwind side than would otherwise occur in flat terrain.</para>
    <para>The space-time pattern will vary between every individual rainfall event that occurs in a
      catchment. In catchments that are subject to orographic influences, there will commonly be
      similarity in the space-time pattern of rainfall between many of the different events that are
      observed over the catchment. This will typically be the case for catchments that are subject
      to flood producing rainfall events that have similar hydrometeorological influences. For
      example, the spatial patterns of rainfall for different events may often demonstrate similar
      ratios of total rainfall depth in the higher elevations of the catchment to total rainfall
      depth at lower elevations.</para>
    <para> The spatial patterns of rainfall in catchments that are influenced by orographic effects
      represent a systematic bias away from a completely uniform spatial pattern. The influence of
      this systematic bias in spatial pattern of rainfall should be explicitly considered in design
      flood estimation. Other hydrometeorological influences, such as the distance from a
      significant moisture source like the ocean may also give rise to systematic bias in the
      spatial pattern of rainfall.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3">
    <title>Conceptualisation of Design Rainfall Events</title>
    <para>Ideally, the space-time variation of rainfall over a catchment would be represented as
      <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185351+1000"?>a
      <?oxy_insert_end?>moving space-time field of rainfall at the appropriate spatial and temporal
      resolution<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185359+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185359+1000" content=","?>
      However, while current developments are progressing in that direction
      (<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185407+1000" content="see, "?>for
      example,
      stochastic<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185410+1000" content=" –"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185411+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?>space-time
      rainfall models developed by <citation>b2_c2_r7,b2_c2_r4</citation>, the rainfall models
      widely used in practice are based on a more reductionist approach, dealing separately with the
      spatial and temporal variability of rainfall. A result of this reductionist approach is that
      rainfall bursts are assumed to be stationary; in other words, the storm does not move during
      the period of rainfall.</para>
    <para>For ease of modelling, storm events can be conceptualised and represented by four main
      event characteristics that are analysed and modelled separately:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Duration of storm or burst
          event<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185441+1000"?>;<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Total rainfall depth (or average intensity) over the event duration, at a point or
          over a
          catchment<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185444+1000"?>;<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Spatial distribution (or pattern) of rainfall over the catchment during the
          event<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185448+1000"?>; and
          <?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Temporal distribution (or pattern) of rainfall during the
          event<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185454+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>These rainfall event characteristics are discussed in
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185517+1000" content="separate sections below"?><xref
        linkend="b2_ch2_s_3_1"
      /><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185517+1000"?>. to
        <?oxy_insert_end?><xref linkend="b2_ch2_s_3_4"/></para>
    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_1">
      <title>Event Definitions</title>
      <para>The modelling of rainfall events first requires a clear definition of what constitutes
        an event <citation>b4_c3_r48</citation>. Given the variation of rainfall in time and space,
        it is not immediately apparent when an event starts and ends. Start and end points of
        rainfall events need to be defined by rainfall thresholds or separation in time from
        preceding/subsequent rainfall. For an event to be significant, it may also need to exceed a
        total event rainfall threshold.</para>
      <para>Two different types of rainfall events are relevant for design flood estimation:
        complete storm events and internal bursts of intense rainfall. While complete storm events
        are the theoretically more appropriate form of event for flood simulation, the internal
        rainfall bursts of given duration, regardless of where they occur within a storm event, lend
        themselves more readily for statistical analysis. The
        I<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185803+1000"?>ntensity
        <?oxy_insert_end?>F<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185809+1000"?>requency <?oxy_insert_end?>D<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185812+1000"?>uration<?oxy_insert_end?>
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190036+1000"?>(IFD)
        <?oxy_insert_end?>data covered in <xref linkend="b2_ch3"/> are thus for rainfall burst
        events.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_2">
      <title>Rainfall Event
        Duration<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185758+1000" content="."?></title>
      <para>Actual storm events vary in their duration, from local thunderstorms lasting minutes to
        extended rainfall events lasting several days. This variation occurs in a random fashion,
        and rainfall event duration for a particular region can be characterised by a probability
        distribution. However, for practical design flood estimation, the occurrence of rainfalls of
        different durations within an appropriate range is generally assumed to have equal
        probability, and the ‘critical rainfall duration’ is then determined as the one that
        maximises the value of the design flood characteristic of direct interest.</para>
      <para>The design rainfall data provided in ARR covers the range of rainfall burst durations
        from 1 minute to 7 days.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_3">
      <title>Event Rainfall Depth (or Average Intensity)</title>
      <para>The basic methods for estimating design rainfall depths (or average intensities) for
        different durations are discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>  for both point rainfalls .
        The principal modelling approach used is to fit a probability distribution to series of
        rainfall depth observations (annual maximum or peak over threshold) for the selected event
        duration at sites with long, reliable rainfall records. The results of these at-site
        analyses are
        the<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T185954+1000"?>n<?oxy_insert_end?>
        generalised over regions with similar rainfall characteristics and mapped over the whole of
        Australia. The conversion of point design rainfalls to average catchment design rainfalls is
        modelled through rainfall areal reduction factors is discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch4"
        />.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Temporal
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190134+1000"?>Patterns of
        <?oxy_insert_end?>Rainfall
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190131+1000" content="Patterns"?></title>
      <para>There are two distinct model representations of the temporal variability of rainfall
        within events (for complete storms or internal bursts), depending on whether the model only
        reflects the central tendency of different observed patterns or the variability of patterns
        for different events is also modelled. These differences in modelling approach are further
        discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch2_s_4"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch5"/>.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_3_4">
      <title>Spatial
        <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190124+1000"?>Patterns of
        <?oxy_insert_end?>Rainfall<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190129+1000" content=" Patterns"?></title>
      <para>In larger catchments and where there is a consistent spatial trend in observed rainfall
        depths, (see <xref linkend="b2_ch2_s_3"/>) this needs to be represented by a non-uniform
        spatial rainfall pattern. . The models for representing the typical spatial variability of
        rainfall are based either on the analysis and generalisation of historical storms or on
        spatial trends derived from analysis of design rainfall depths (IFD maps). The application
        of these models is explained in <xref linkend="b2_ch4_s_4ho8s"/></para>
      <para>In the following, a number of different approaches to model the space-time
        characteristics of event rainfall for design flood estimation are introduced briefly.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b2_ch2_s_4">
    <title>Spatial and Temporal Resolution of Design Rainfall Models</title>
    <para>The space-time pattern of rainfall for an individual flood event will often have an
      appreciable influence on the flow hydrograph generated at the outlet of a catchment. Two
      rainfall events may have identical total volumes over a defined catchment area and duration
      but differences in their space-time patterns may produce very different hydrographs at the
      outlet of the catchment. Both the runoff generation and
      runoff<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190247+1000"?>-<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190246+1000" content=" "?>routing
      processes in catchments are typically non-linear, so a space-time pattern that exhibits more
      variability will normally generate a higher volume of runoff and larger peak flow at the
      catchment outlet than a space-time pattern that is more uniform.</para>
    <para>Variability in hydrographs introduced by space-time variability in rainfall will be
      accentuated in catchments that have spatial and temporal variability in runoff generation and
      routing processes. For example, in a partly urbanised catchment, a <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190316+1000" content="rain storm"?><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160620T194412+1000"?>rainfall<?oxy_insert_end?>
      <?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190319+1000"?>event
      <?oxy_insert_end?>with a spatial pattern that has larger depths on the urban part of the
      catchment than the rural part would normally produce both a larger volume of runoff and flood
      peak at the catchment outlet than a storm of the same depth and duration that has a spatially
      uniform rainfall pattern. Other factors in catchments that may accentuate the influence of the
      space-time rainfall pattern on the variability in hydrographs produced at the catchment outlet
      include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>the presence of reservoirs and lakes, for which all rainfall on the water surface is
          converted to runoff;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>the presence of dams, weirs, drains and other flow regulating structures;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in soil type;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in vegetation type, such as forested and cleared areas;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>the arrangement of the drainage network of the catchment the dependency of alternative
          flow paths on event magnitude and differences in contributing area with length of
          network;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in stream channel and floodplain roughness;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in slope of stream channels and floodplains;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>significant variations in antecedent climatic conditions across the catchment prior to
          the events; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>variations in elevation, snowpack depth, density and temperature in those catchments
          subject to rain-on-snow flood events.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The required resolution of rainfall models to adequately reflect the variability of
      rainfall in historical rainfall events has been investigated by <citation>b2_c2_r8</citation>
      for the Upper Parramatta River catchment.
        <?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190605+1000" content="They"?><citation>b2_c2_r8</citation><?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190605+1000"?>
      <?oxy_insert_end?> categorised the variability of recorded storm events in the spatial and
      temporal domains and confirmed that the degree of spatial and temporal resolution of rainfall
      inputs to flood estimation models can have a significant impact on resulting flood estimates.
      A range of other studies have come to similar conclusions but have found it difficult to give
      more than qualitative guidance on the required degree of spatial and temporal resolution of
      rainfall for different modelling applications. The conclusions can be summarised in
      qualitative terms as:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>“Spatial rainfall patterns are understood to be a dominant source of variability for
          very large catchments and for urban catchments but for other hydrological contexts,
          results vary. Much of this knowledge is either site specific or is expressed
          qualitatively” <citation>b2_c2_r9</citation>.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Where short response times are involved in urban catchments, inadequate representation
          of temporal variability of rainfall can lead to significant underestimation of design
          flood peaks <citation>b2_c5_r2</citation>. More generally, the importance of temporal
          variability of rainfall in flood modelling depends on the degree of ‘filtering’ of shorter
          term rainfall peaks through catchment routing processes
          (i<?oxy_delete author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190727+1000" content="."?>e. the
          amount of storage in the catchment system) and the interaction of flood contributions from
          different parts of a catchment
          system<?oxy_insert_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160616T190644+1000"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Sensitivity analyses can be applied to determine for a specific application the influence
      of the adopted spatial and temporal resolution of design rainfalls on flood estimates and
      their uncertainty bounds.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Applications Where Flood Estimates are Required at Multiple Locations</title>
    <para>Design flood estimates are often required at multiple locations within a catchment or
      study area. Ideally, flood simulation (e.g. using Monte Carlo approaches) should consider a
      large number of complete storm events that cover the whole AEP spectrum of interest and have
      internal characteristics which automatically reproduce the critical rainfall bursts over a
      range of temporal and spatial scales. Unfortunately, such comprehensive ensembles of synthetic
      storm events are not currently available, and combined system wide analysis is thus not yet
      feasible. Instead, separate analysis at the different locations (subcatchments) of interest is
      required, using design rainfall events for the relevant space and time scales. To this end, it
      is necessary to derive design rainfall inputs for the catchment upstream of each required
      location. This involves:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Deriving average values of the point design rainfalls for the total catchment upstream
          of each location;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Conversion of average point design rainfall values to areal estimates by multiplying
          by the ARF applicable to the total catchment area upstream of each location; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Adoption of space-time patterns of rainfall relevant to the total catchment area
          upstream of each location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>It is commonly found that design flood estimates are required at one or more locations in
      a catchment where flow gauges are not located. If so, it will be necessary to use the above
      procedure to derive design rainfalls for the catchment upstream of each gauge location so that
      the rainfall-based design floods estimates can be verified against estimates derived from
      Flood Frequency Analysis at each flow gauge. Different sets of design rainfall intensities,
      ARF and space-time patterns should be calculated for the each of the catchments draining to
      the other locations of interest, which are not at flow gauges.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Climate Change Impacts</title>
    <para>Statistically significant increases in rainfall intensity have been detected in Australia
      for short duration rainfall events and are likely to become more evident towards the end of
      the 21st century <citation>b2_c5_r33</citation>. Changes in long duration events are expected
      to be smaller and harder to detect, but projections analysed by
        <citation>b1_c2_r7+1</citation> show that an increase in daily precipitation intensity is
      likely under climate change. It is worth noting that a warming climate can lead to decreases
      in annual rainfall along with increases in flood producing rainfall.</para>
    <para>The impact of climate change on storm frequency, mechanism, spatial and temporal behaviour
      is less understood. </para>
    <para>Work by <citation>b1_c4_r1+1</citation> suggests that increases are likely to be more
      pronounced in areas with strong orographic enhancement. There is insufficient evidence to
      confirm whether this result is applicable to other parts of Australia. Work by
        <citation>b2_c5_r30+1</citation> analysing historical storms found that, regardless of the
      climate region or season, temperature increases are associated with patterns becoming less
      uniform, with the largest fractions increasing in rainfall intensity and the lower fraction
      decreasing.</para>
    <para>The implications of these expected climate change impacts on the different design rainfall
      inputs to catchment modelling are discussed further in the relevant sub-sections of the
      following chapters. </para>
  </section>
  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
  
</chapter>
