<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" status="Internal Review" xml:id="b7_ch2">
  <info>
    <title>Use of a Catchment Model</title>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/testoni_isabelle.xml"/>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>
    
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>
    
    
  </info>
  
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190505T153427+1000" content="06/07/16 "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190505T153423+1000"?>24/4/2018
        <?oxy_insert_end?></td>
    </tr>
    <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190505T153431+1000" content="&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Content&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Working draft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;General&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Subject to industry feedback &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;"?>
  </informaltable>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch2_s_uuv2s">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>A catchment model system is a very useful way of estimating how a system will perform
      under a number of different conditions. Catchment modelling systems are usually built from the
      series of modelling elements that are described in <xref linkend="book4"/>, <xref
        linkend="book5"/> and <xref linkend="book6"/>. These are combined to replicate the key
      processes for a particular flood estimation problem. </para>
    <para>The catchment modelling system can be used probabilistically (for estimating design flood
      behaviour) or can be used to estimate observed or historic flood behaviour. The catchment
      modelling system can be used to represent existing, historical or altered catchment
      conditions. </para>
    <para>It is important when developing a catchment modelling system that the possible future uses
      of the model are properly identified so that the key processes are properly considered. The
      challenges in modelling are the need to represent various processes which introduces
      complexity, against the data available for calibrating these process and parameter and
      component interaction (<xref linkend="b7_ch3"/>). </para>
    <para>There are often subtle differences in how some of the key processes perform in frequent
      events than in rarer events. These differences mean that only rarer events can be used for the
      calibration which limits the data available for the calibration of complex models. Two simple
      examples are:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>during very frequent rainfall events the storage capacity of the soils is very
          important but during rarer intense events the rate of infiltration becomes more important
          ; and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>the hydraulics of a stream change significantly when flow moves from in-bank to the
          floodplain.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In both cases calibrating to just frequent events can give a very poor estimate of larger
      events.</para>
    <para>In many modelling situations calibration exposes significant parameter interaction where
      very similar calibrations can be achieved with a range of parameters, while this often does
      not significantly change the behaviour of similar magnitude events it can make a significant
      difference to how larger events behave. When modelling
      <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190502T123329+1000" content="comments"?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190502T123329+1000"?>components<?oxy_insert_end?>
      are combined into a catchment modelling system it is possible for this interaction to occur
      across modelling components. This problem is very common when only level data is available to
      calibrate a catchment modelling system that includes hydraulic and hydrologic components. A
      satisfactory fit can often be obtained for a range of flows and corresponding roughness
      values. </para>
    <sidebar>
      <para>Catchment modelling system results can be sensitive to the chosen parameter values.
        Different combinations of parameters can give the same answer at a single point. However as
        is often the case, when extrapolating to larger events they give different answers and very
        different representations of the flow behaviour.</para>
    </sidebar>
    <para>In many situations it is never completely clear what the correct combination of overbank
      and channel Manning’s n is. The following example shows the results from a simple hydraulic
      model where the overbank and channel Manning’s n were selected to match the 1% AEP flow and
      level. While different combinations give identical results at the adopted 1% AEP level and
      flow they give very different velocity distributions. The cases also give very different level
      vs flow relationships for different sized events. This is one of the key reasons why its
      important not to adopt models for problems outside the range they were designed for. <xref
        linkend="b7_ch2_f_rsfsx"/> depicts the difference in conveyance, K (<xref
        linkend="b6_ch2_s_yug0o"/>) for a range of levels. At extreme flows the conveyance ranges
      from 11 500 to 16 000 m<superscript>3</superscript>/s. At lower levels the flow can
      double.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b7_ch2_f_rsfsx">
      <title>Conveyance Comparison – Different Manning’s n Combinations</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/7014.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b7_ch2_s_w3pq3">
    <title>Overview of Modelling Applications</title>
    <para>The application of a catchment modelling system should follow the process outlined within
      this chapter and book. While it is possible to create a catchment modelling system without
      following a rigorous process, it will lend itself to errors and wasted time in redoing work. A
      practitioner should first analyse the problem presented before deciding how to solve it. The
      data available must also be investigated, as it is likely that insufficient data exists for
      the ideal solution that the practitioner has already come up with.</para>
    <para>A simplified overview of the steps involved in the application of a catchment modelling
      system (<xref linkend="b7_ch2_f_exlkj"/>):</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Conceptualisation of Modelling Approach (<xref linkend="b7_ch3"/>); </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Developing a Catchment Modelling System (<xref linkend="b7_ch4"/>);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Testing Parameterisation, Calibration, and Validation of a Catchment Modelling System
            (<xref linkend="b7_ch5"/> and <xref linkend="b7_ch6"/>);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Application of Catchment Modelling System to a Specific Design Problem (<xref
            linkend="b7_ch7"/>); and</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Interpretation of the Results and Understanding the Reliability and Uncertainty (<xref
            linkend="b7_ch8"/> and <xref linkend="b7_ch9"/>).</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para> These steps can be applied to an individual process, but it is important to apply them to
      the overall catchment modelling system. You need to confirm performance the overall CMS rather
      than just the individual components. Optimising individual components might not provide an
      overall robust CMS. The development of the CMS is constrained by the data that is available,
      the time/cost and experience of the practitioner.</para>
    <figure xml:id="b7_ch2_f_exlkj">
      <title>Steps in the Application of a Catchment Modelling System</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/7012.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>Review of the conceptualisation of the catchment modelling system should be undertaken at
      each step in the process of creating and applying the catchment modelling system. This review
      does not have to be exhaustive. The reality is that most practitioners are undertaking this
      review as a sanity check already. It is highlighted here that this is a key step in the
      overall creation of a catchment modelling system or a component of it.</para>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch2_s_7c6kv">
      <title>Conceptualisation of Modelling Approach</title>
      <para>It is important at the start of a project to accurately define the problem and identify
        the key process/es that must be modelled in order to understand and accurately model the
        problem (<xref linkend="b7_ch3"/>). In this stage limitations of the modelling approach must
        be explored. Available data, time, cost and model availability need to be defined for the
        problem in question. Preliminary selection of a catchment modelling system is carried out in
        this stage, though the selection may change as the practitioner develops the catchment
        modelling system.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch2_s_5i9zd">
      <title>Developing a Catchment Modelling System</title>
      <para>The schematisation of a catchment in a modelling platform (<xref linkend="b7_ch4"/>)
        depends heavily on the chosen modelling platform. Different modelling platforms have varied
        ways of representing the same catchment characteristics and features. In practice, the ease
        of representing key catchment features and key processes (discussed in <xref
          linkend="b7_ch3"/>) plays a major role in developing a catchment modelling system.
        Decisions on conceptualisation and the representation of key features may be need to be
        revisited at this stage. Revising modelling platform choice is recommended if the initial
        selection is no longer appropriate in schematising the catchment.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch2_s_gwgl7">
      <title>Testing Parameterisation, Calibration, and Validation of a Catchment Modelling
        System</title>
      <para>Ideally, all catchment models should be well calibrated and validated. However, data
        constraints mean this is not always possible or only limited calibration is possible. <xref
          linkend="b7_ch5"/> provides discussion on the best way to make use of the data that is
        available and discussion on data in general is in <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>.
        <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>The calibration process
        of a model is not limited to matching historic records, but can include the overall
        estimation of parameters. The estimation of parameters aims to preserve the representation
        of the catchment characteristics as described by the conceptualisation of the
        catchment.<?oxy_custom_end?> Guidance on parameter values for ungauged catchments is
        provided in <xref linkend="b7_ch5"/>. Validation techniques are used to independently test
        that the chosen parameters represent observed behaviour (<xref linkend="b7_ch6"/>). </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch2_s_90tj7">
      <title>Application of Catchment Modelling System to a Specific Design Problem </title>
      <para>Typically, at the start of setting up a catchment modelling system a specific design
        problem required a solution is already defined. Design applications of catchment modelling
        systems will vary depending on the specific problem under consideration. <xref
          linkend="b7_ch7"/> discusses different design applications after a catchment modelling
        system is established.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b7_ch2_s_6f9q4">
      <title>Interpretation of the Results and Understanding the Reliability and Uncertainty </title>
      <para>The final step in the application of a catchment modelling systems is to provide
        information to decision makers, the community and designers regarding design flood
        behaviour. This information needs to be scrutinised and final checks should always be
        undertaken to ensure the modelled flow behaviour makes sense (<xref linkend="b7_ch9"/>).
        Catchment modelling systems are only representations of the real world based on data and
        mathematical models. Results can be inaccurate if any key processes or features are
        misrepresented in the catchment modelling system, which is not always easy to determine.
        This misrepresentation can be due to practitioner error, model error or incomplete and
        inaccurate data. The uncertainty surrounding design flood estimates should not be overlooked
        (discussed in <xref linkend="b7_ch8"/>).</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>