<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="Internal Review" xml:id="b7_ch2"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Application of Catchment Modelling</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/ball_james.xml"/>
  </info>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>In the application of a catchment modelling system the ultimate aim
    usually is the generation of information that has not been recorded at a
    gauging station within the catchment. This information may be at locations
    remote from the gauged information and due to storm events, or sequences
    of storm events, that may, or may not, have occurred. This later situation
    being the design problem. In addition, the desired information may relate
    to the catchment conditions that may or may not exist. In all of these
    situations, the catchment modelling system is being used for extrapolation
    of the available data. As with any extrapolation, the user needs to be
    concerned with the validity of the process used for the extrapolation and
    needs to treat extrapolated data with care.</para>

    <para>Shown in Figure 1.1.1 is the general concept of a catchment
    modelling system whereby the input information is transformed by the
    catchment modelling system into predictions of the catchment
    response.</para>

    <figure>
      <title>Concept of a Catchment Modelling System</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="B7C2_Figures/Figure7_2_1.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>As discussed in earlier sections of Australian Rainfall and Runoff,
    it is important to note that no process model or combination of process
    models as found in a catchment modelling system is an exact reproduction
    of the catchment. A process model mathematically replicates a process that
    influences the catchment response to storm inputs. As suggested in this
    definition of a process model, the simulated catchment response to storm
    inputs is the result of the summation of many individual process models
    and hence is based on a reductionist approach.</para>

    <para>When incorporated into a catchment modelling system, there are many
    aspects to a process model which will influence the simulations obtained.
    These aspects include:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>the theoretical basis for the mathematical
        representation,</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>the manner in which the process models are combined to produce
        the catchment modelling system, and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>the numerical implementation of the mathematical
        representation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>While it is obvious that the theoretical representation of a
    catchment process will influence the predicted flow, it is not as obvious
    that the manner in which the process models are combined and the numerical
    algorithm employed to solve the mathematical expressions can result in
    potential errors in the predicted flows.</para>

    <para>A simple example of the impact of different systems of process
    models can be obtained by considering the manner in which loss models may
    be used in the estimation of direct runoff from a catchment. Shown in
    Figure 1.1.2, are two alternative approaches for the inclusion of loss
    models in a catchment modelling system.</para>

    <figure>
      <title>Alternative Approaches for Inclusion of Loss Models</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="B7C2_Figures/Figure7_2_2.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>In the first approach, continuing losses are subtracted from the
    rainfall to produce rainfall excess which is then routed through the
    catchment storage while, in the second approach, the rainfall enters the
    catchment storage with continuing losses subtracted from water within the
    catchment storage while, at the same time, being routed to the catchment
    outlet. For the first approach, losses cease at the cessation of rainfall
    while for the second approach losses continue while water remains in
    catchment storage. Consequently loss model control parameter values
    appropriate for the first approach are not appropriate for the second
    approach. Hence, the manner in which the process models are combined
    influences the control parameter values used in the application of the
    process model.</para>

    <para>In a similar manner, the impact of the numerical algorithm has been
    shown by Ball (1987) who showed that two different numerical algorithms
    solving the same set of equations (ie the same theoretical model) can
    result in two different predictions of the flow or stage. In this
    application, a hydrograph was routed through a pipe network using
    numerical solutions of the dynamic wave equations. Two different numerical
    algorithms were employed with these algorithms being a Preissmann “box”
    scheme in PIPENET (Ball, 1991) and a modified Euler scheme in the EXTRAN
    block (Roesner et al., 1998) of SWMM (Huber and Dickinson, 1998). As shown
    in Figure 1.1.3, different predicted stage hydrographs were obtained as a
    result of the different numerical algorithms rather than through the
    application of different theoretical models of hydrograph
    propagation.</para>

    <para>All three of these aspects of a catchment modelling system can be
    considered to introduce structural errors. Other sources through which
    errors may be introduced into the application of a catchment modelling
    system include</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Data used to represent the storm and catchment characteristics;
        and</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Recorded or Gauged Data used to evaluate the appropriateness of
        the control parameter values adopted to represent the catchment
        characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>As discussed in later sections, a common assumption in the
    application of catchment modelling systems is that the recorded data used
    in the application is error free. This is rarely the case with errors
    likely to be present in both the data used as input information to the
    catchment modelling system and in the data used to assess the reliability
    of the control parameters (ie the calibration of the catchment modelling
    system). An example of the first type of error in the input information is
    the assumption that rainfall measured at a single point within the
    catchment is representative of the rainfall across the entire catchment.
    Measurement of rainfall at a single point using a standard pluviometer or
    daily read gauge represents a sample ration of 1 sample in 25,000,000
    (check numbers) when the gauge density is one gauge per square kilometre
    of catchment area. In many cases, this sampling density may be
    appropriate, but there are also many cases where this sampling ratio is
    inappropriate and it cannot be assumed that a single point measurement of
    rainfall is representative of the rainfall across the catchment.
    Similarly, the use of a single cross-section to represent a channel reach
    may be inappropriate if the channel varies longitudinally. Errors of this
    type are representative of systematic errors in the predicted flows from
    the catchment modelling system.</para>

    <figure>
      <title>Predicted Stage Hydrographs by Ball (1987)</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="B7C2_Figures/Figure7_2_3.tif"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>The second potential source of errors in the measured data relates
    to the recorded data used to evaluate the control parameters (ie to
    calibrate and validate the catchment modelling system). Implicitly, it is
    assumed usually that this form of measured data is error free. This
    assumption is made as the calibration process is one of minimising the
    difference between the predicted flow and the recorded flow. If the If the
    assumption is not made, then the difference between the predicted and the
    recorded flows may not be due to errors in control parameter values (ie
    errors which can be reduced or removed by selecting appropriate values for
    the control parameters) but rather due to errors in the measurement of the
    recorded flow. The problem then becomes one of selection between the two
    potential sources of error so that appropriate techniques for control
    parameter evaluation can be utilised.</para>

    <para>While it is not possible to remove all forms of error from the
    application of a catchment modelling system, the desire is to minimise the
    magnitude of errors in the predicted flows and hence to produce robust
    predictions from the catchment modelling system. One approach to achieving
    this is to use the steps outlined in the following sections in the process
    of applying a catchment modelling system.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Steps in Catchment Modelling System Usage</title>

    <para>Management of the water quantity within catchments has become
    increasingly important to communities in recent years. The information
    required for this management increasingly is being developed through the
    application of catchment modelling systems as these systems allow for the
    assessment of alternative management strategies not only for existing
    catchment conditions but for potential future catchment conditions without
    the necessity of implementing the changes and then monitoring flows at the
    catchment outlet and within the catchment. If the impacts of different
    management scenarios assessed from the analysis of catchment simulations
    are to be relied upon, then the predictions from the catchment modelling
    system have to be robust and reliable. In this context, robust and
    reliable predictions are those that are reproducible with an accuracy
    appropriate for the problem being considered.</para>

    <figure>
      <title>Steps in the Application of Catchment Modelling Systems</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata contentdepth="100%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="B7C2_Figures/Figure7_2_4.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>For robust and reliable predictions from a catchment modelling
    system, it is desirable that the various errors outlined earlier are
    minimised. Achievement of this requires the modeller to implicitly or
    explicitly follow a number of steps which may be linear or may be
    iterative. As shown in Figure 1..4, these steps are</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Definition of goals and objectives</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Collation of data</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Selection of process models</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Selection of software</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Calibration, validation and use of the catchment modelling
        system</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Interpretation of predictions from catchment modelling
        system</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section>
      <title>Definition of Goals and Objectives</title>

      <para>In this step of the process, the problem requiring resolution is
      outlined with the goals and objectives defined. The goals describe the
      broad general information required for the problem resolution while the
      objectives define the specific end results or information expected from
      the catchment modelling system. As such information required from the
      catchment modelling system to meet the management aims are defined.
      Examples of the information defined at this stage include</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>information necessary to allow determination of the impacts
          associated with changed management strategies arising from
          urbanisation of the catchment;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>information necessary to allow the design of a single physical
          component of the catchment drainage system such as a bridge.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>It is important in this step that the goals for the information
      and that the objectives of the modelling are defined and achievable.
      Finally, the time frame for the generation of information needs to be
      defined as this can influence significantly the volume of data that
      needs to be collected, collated and utilised during the modelling
      project, and the complexity of the modelling attempted.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Collation of Data</title>

      <para>Within this step, the available data is collected, collated and
      analysed to ensure suitability for use with the goals and objectives
      defined in the previous stage. If sufficient data for the desired goals
      and objectives is not available either from existing databanks or from a
      dedicated collection program, then it is necessary to return to the
      previous step and revise the criteria and/or the aims of the
      investigation/design.</para>

      <para>Furthermore, the volume of data required varies in direct
      proportion to the complexity of the problem and the desired accuracy of
      information. The more simplistic simulations require very little data
      and can be implemented in a short time-frame. On the other hand, the
      more complex simulations require significantly more data and hence time
      for proper establishment of the relevant database.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Selection of Process Models</title>

      <para>Having defined the information desired from the catchment
      modelling system and the data available for use with the catchment
      modelling system, this step in the application of a catchment modelling
      system determines the process models (generation, hydrologic, hydraulic,
      and disposal) which are necessary to achieve the goals and aims
      previously defined for the simulation are selected. In this selection of
      process models, the form of information that is required needs to be
      considered. For example, the prediction accuracy required for a scoping
      or screening study will be different to that required for a design or
      operational study. A consequence of this is that the degree of process
      detail required will differ and hence the process model complexity will
      vary. A second consequence is that a catchment modelling system
      developed for one goal may not be appropriate for a different
      goal.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Software Selection</title>

      <para>Note that it is desirable that the process models and the software
      be selected with a full knowledge of the project goals rather than the
      aims of the project be modified to suit the process models and software.
      Also, it should be noted that if appropriate software is not available,
      then it is necessary to develop appropriate software or to review the
      project goals and aims.</para>

      <para>As discussed above, it needs to be emphasised that the selection
      and use of software for analysis of a particular problem requires
      consideration of</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Software incorporating the desired process models is
          available; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Suitable data is available for use with the selected software
          system.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Inherently it is assumed with these issues that a modeller has
      knowledge of the theoretical basis of the process models incorporated in
      a software package and through this an understanding of the applications
      and also the limitations of the various software packages. Limitations
      in the software package may result from the simplifications necessary to
      develop a process model or they may result from the simplification
      necessary to implement the process model. The result of these
      limitations, however, is that a software system may be appropriate for a
      problem at one location but inappropriate for a different problem at the
      same location.</para>

      <para>An example where a software system is suitable for one problem but
      inappropriate for a different problem at the same location is the use of
      the EXTRAN block (Roesner et al., 1988) from the SWMM software system
      (Huber and Dickinson, 1988) for the analysis of unsteady flows through a
      culvert in an urban drainage system. If the problem is one of routing
      the hydrograph through the culvert then EXTRAN will replicate adequately
      the processes involved. However, if the problem is one of a detailed
      analysis of the local and conduit energy losses at the culvert then
      EXTRAN is not suitable for the analysis. Similar comments can be made
      with respect to the use of MIKE-11 (DHI, 1992) or other similar channel
      and river models for the routing of flood waves along the river channels
      and through the various structures constructed on the river.</para>

      <para>In many cases these limitations result from the need to make
      simplifications in the hydrologic and hydraulic process models, the need
      to introduce numerical algorithms to enable use of the process models,
      and the need to be able to collect and supply to the catchment modelling
      system appropriate data. As a result of individual developers
      conceptualising these process model simplifications, numerical
      algorithms and data availability differently, a considerable volume of
      alternative software systems for catchment modelling have become
      available. In general, these alternative systems have evolved due to the
      wide variety of problems encountered and the need to ensure that the
      software employed in resolution of the problem includes appropriate
      process models. Furthermore, as indicated earlier, it is not possible to
      specify which model or software package should be used for a particular
      analysis without prior specification of the goals and aims of the
      analysis, the problem that is being investigated, and the available data
      for use with the catchment modelling system.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>System Usage</title>

      <para>Within this step, the modeller implements the process models using
      either hand calculations or a software package. In general, most
      catchment modelling systems require the use of a software system.</para>

      <para>The generic steps followed with implementation of a catchment
      modelling system are</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Verification -</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Establishment - Within this step of the generic process of
          catchment modelling system usage, the catchment modelling system
          embodying the software and base data is implemented in a form
          whereby it is feasible for evaluation of the catchment modelling
          system control parameters so that the response of a catchment to
          different individual or series of storm events, or different
          management practices can be predicted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure>
        <title>Types of Catchment Modelling System Control Parameter
        Evaluation</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" scalefit="1" width="100%" fileref="B7C2_Figures/Figure7_2_5.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Calibration - The primary purpose of the this step within the
          generic process of catchment modelling system usage is the
          evaluation of the control parameters for the catchment modelling
          system. As discussed later in Section ?, evaluation of control
          parameters may be required for a catchment where historical flow and
          rainfall information is available or for a catchment where no
          historical flow information is available. Shown schematically in
          Figure 1.1.5 is this classification of calibration .</para>

          <para>While there are many approaches to the calibration of a
          catchment modelling system, one commonly used approach for
          calibration of flow hydrographs is</para>

          <para>Step 1 Adjust the runoff depth or volume. Without a fairly
          accurate representation of the runoff depth, the process of
          adjusting parameters that affect the hydrograph shape or values will
          be much more difficult.</para>

          <para>Step 2 Adjust the hydrograph shape.</para>

          <para>It should be noted that these steps are iterative. This arises
          from the potential for changes in control parameter values aimed at
          obtaining a better fit to the shape of the hydrograph to change the
          fit previously obtained for the depth of runoff. Similar comments
          are valid for the control parameters used for water quality
          simulation. Furthermore, it should be noted that calibrated control
          parameter values for one event or sequence of events may not be
          applicable to a second event or series of events. All of this leads
          to the conclusion that the final calibration control parameters are
          a comprise that does not reproduce any one event or series of events
          exactly but which will replicate the catchment response adequately
          to meet the aims for which the catchment modelling system was
          developed.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>In general, the calibration process is one of systematically
          adjusting the values of the control parameters until satisfactory
          reproduction of the monitored catchment performance is achieved.
          This systematic adjustment may be manual or it may be automatic;
          both approaches, however, are based, in essence, on a trial and
          error approach to evaluation of the control parameters. Approaches
          for adjustment of the trial values for the control parameters are
          presented in subsequent sections. These approaches, however, are
          applied usually during automatic adjustment due to the large number
          of calculations necessary to obtain optimal or near optimal values
          of the control parameters.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Validation is obtained by testing the modelling system
          response to previously unseen data and assessing the accuracy of the
          predictions. Unless validation of the model parameters is
          undertaken, the calibration values for the control parameters remain
          untested and there is a distinct potential for the selected values
          of the control parameters to be those that best “curve-fit” the
          monitored information.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Validation - At this stage in the usage of a catchment
          modelling system, the selected values for the control parameters are
          tested to ensure reliability and robustness of the selected values.
          It is not suggested nor is it intended that the successful
          completion of this stage of the process will result in the ‘true’
          values for control parameters. Rather it is suggested that the
          outcome from this stage of the usage process is the determination of
          robust values for the control parameters.</para>

          <para>The processes of calibration and validation are extremely
          important steps in the use of any modelling system. Completion of
          these processes provides the modeller with information regarding the
          robustness of the modelling system and the reliability of the system
          predictions. • Production- The final step in the generic process of
          catchment modelling system usage</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Production- The final step in the generic process of catchment
          modelling system usage is the production of the desired information
          (catchment modelling system predictions). As discussed previously in
          Section ?, this production of the desired information, in many
          cases, will require extrapolation of the catchment modelling system
          parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>At this stage in the usage of the catchment modelling system,
      information pertinent to resolution of the problem requiring
      implementation of the catchment modelling system is available. This
      information, however, still needs to be applied to resolution of the
      problem requiring the catchment simulation and the predictions from the
      catchment modelling system need to be interpreted with respect to the
      goals and aims of the simulations.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Interpretation of Predictions</title>

      <para>The final step in the usage of a catchment modelling system is the
      interpretation of the information obtained from the catchment modelling
      system to ensure that the aims of the project defined in the first step
      are satisfied. This final step relies on the experience of the user for
      the practical application of the simulation results to the resolution of
      the problem and the satisfaction of the gaols and aims of the
      project.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Case Study Applications</title>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">REFERENCES</emphasis></para>

      <para>Abustan, I, (1997), Modelling of phosphorous transport in urban
      stormwater runoff, <emphasis>Doctoral Dissertation</emphasis>, School of
      Civil and Environmental Engineering, The University of New South Wales,
      Sydney, Australia</para>

      <para>Ball, JE, (1987), A Comparison of the Hydraulics in Three Urban
      Drainage Models, <emphasis>Proc. 3rd Conference on Hydraulics in Civil
      Engineering,</emphasis> Melbourne, Australia, I.E.Aust. Nat. Conf. Pub..
      No. 87/14, Barton, ACT, pp 88 - 92.</para>

      <para>Ball, JE, (1991), Unsteady Flow Simulation in Urban Sewer
      Networks, <emphasis>Research Report No. 177</emphasis>, Water Research
      Laboratory, Dept. of Water Engineering, School of Civil Engineering, The
      University of New South Wales, 113 pages</para>

      <para>Ball, JE and Luk, KC, (1998), Modelling the spatial variability of
      rainfall over a catchment, <emphasis>ASCE, Journal of Hydrologic
      Engineering,</emphasis> 3(2):122-130.</para>

      <para>Ball, JE and Powell, M, (1998), Inference of catchment modelling
      system control parameters, <emphasis>Proc. UDM‘98,</emphasis> London,
      UK, pp 313 - 320.</para>

      <para>Bewsher Consulting, (1999), Cabramatta Creek - Floodplain
      Management Study and Plan, <emphasis>Unpublished Report for Liverpool
      and Fairfield City Councils,</emphasis> Bewsher Consulting Pty Ltd,
      Sydney, Australia.</para>

      <para>Burnham, M and Davis, D, (1986), Accuracy of computer water
      surface profiles, <emphasis>Research Document No. 26,</emphasis>
      Hydrologic Engineering Centre, US Army Corps of Engineers, Davis,
      California.</para>

      <para>Choi, KS, (2001), Application of hydroinformatic tools for
      catchment modelling system, <emphasis>Doctoral Dissertation,</emphasis>
      School of Civil and Environmental Engineering, The University of New
      South Wales, Sydney, Australia</para>

      <para>Choi, KS and Ball, JE, (2002), Parameter estimation for urban
      runoff modelling, <emphasis>Journal of Urban Water,</emphasis>
      4(1):31-41.</para>

      <para>DHI, (1992), Mike-11: Technical reference Manual,
      <emphasis>Unpublished Report,</emphasis> Danish Hydraulic Institute,
      Horsholm, Denmark</para>

      <para>Duan, Q, Sorooshian, S, and Ibbitt, RP, (1988), A Maximum
      Likelihood Criterion for Use with Data Collected at Unequal Time
      Intervals, <emphasis>Water Resources Research,</emphasis> Vol. 24, No.
      7, pp 1163 - 1173.</para>

      <para>Duan, Q, Sorooshian, S, and Gupta, V, (1992), Effective and
      efficient global optimisation for conceptual rainfall-runoff models,
      <emphasis>Water Resources Research,</emphasis> Vol. 28, No. 4, pp 1015 -
      1031.</para>

      <para>Farissier, P. and Givone, P., (1993), Mapping and management of
      flood plains, <emphasis>Proc. International Conference on the
      Application of Geographic Information Systems in Hydrology and Water
      Resources Management,</emphasis> Vienna, Austria, published as IAHS
      Publication No. 211, pp 485 - 490.</para>

      <para>Fread, DL and Smith, GF, (1978), Calibration Technique for 1-D
      Unsteady Flow Models, ASCE, <emphasis>Journal of the Hydraulics
      Division,</emphasis> 104(HY7):1027-1044.</para>

      <para>Gupta, VK, (1984), The identification of conceptual
      rainfall-runoff models, PhD Dissertation, Uni. of Arizona, Tucson, AZ,
      USA.</para>

      <para>Huber, W.C. and Dickinson, RE, (1988), Stormwater Management Model
      Version 4: User's Manual, <emphasis>Report No.
      EPA/600/3-88/001a,</emphasis> Environmental Research Laboratory, Office
      of Research and Development, US Environmental Protection Agency, Athens,
      Georgia, USA</para>

      <para>Ibbitt, RP, (1991), Model Calibration and Software Applications,
      <emphasis>Proc. Int. Hydrology and Water Resources Sym.,</emphasis>
      IEAust., Perth, IEAust. Nat Conf. Pub. 91/22, Vol. 2, pp 466 -
      472.</para>

      <para>Jamieson, DG, Wilkinson, JC, and Ibbitt, RP, (1972), Hydrologic
      forecasting with sequential deterministic and stochastic stages,
      <emphasis>Proc. Int. Sym. On Uncertainties in Hydrologic and Water
      Resources Systems,</emphasis> Tuscon, AZ, Vol. 1, pp 177 - 187.</para>

      <para>Kinhill Engineers Pty Ltd, (1992), Lower Cabramatta Creek
      Floodplain Management Study, <emphasis>Unpublished Report for Liverpool
      Councils,</emphasis> Kinhill Engineers Pty Ltd, Sydney,
      Australia.</para>

      <para>Krohn, SN, Misson, CJ, and Wilson, DR, (1994), A windows based
      time series management system used for real-time flow forecasting,
      <emphasis>Proc. of the First International Conference on
      Hydroinformatics, Delft,</emphasis> The Netherlands, pub by AA Balkema,
      Rotterdam, The Netherlands, pp 75 - 80.</para>

      <para>Kuczera, G, (1983), Improved parameter inference in catchment
      models, 1: Evaluating parameter uncertainty, <emphasis>Water Resources
      Research,</emphasis> Vol. 19, No. 5, pp 1151 - 1162.</para>

      <para>Kuczera, G, (1994), NLFIT - A Bayesian Nonlinear Regression
      Program Suite, Dept. of Civil Eng and Surveying, University of
      Newcastle.</para>

      <para>Pilgrim, DH, (1987), <emphasis>Chapter 9 - Runoff Routing
      Methods</emphasis> in Australian Rainfall and Runoff - A Guide to Flood
      Estimation, The institution of Engineers, Australia, Barton, ACT.</para>

      <para>Press, WH, Flannery, BP, Teukolsky, SA and Vetterling, WT, (1986),
      <emphasis>Numerical Recipes: The Art of Scientific Computing,</emphasis>
      Cambridge University Press.</para>

      <para>Roesner, LA, Aldrich, JA, and Dickinson, RE, (1988),
      <emphasis>Storm Water Management Model, Version 4, Part B: EXTRAN
      Addendum,</emphasis> Report No EPA/600/3-88/001B, NTIS PB88-236658/XAS,
      University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</para>

      <para>Savic, D and Waters, GA, (1996), Stochastic optimization
      techniques in hydraulic engineering and management, <emphasis>Proc.
      Stochastic Hydraulics ‘96,</emphasis> pp 65- 72.</para>

      <para>Schilling, W and Fuchs, L, (1986), Errors in stormwater modelling,
      ASCE, <emphasis>Journal of Hydraulic Engineering,</emphasis>
      112(2)111-123.</para>

      <para>Sefe, FT and Boughton, WC, (1982), Variation of Model Parameter
      Values and Sensitivity with Type of Objective Function,
      <emphasis>Journal of Hydrology,</emphasis> 21(2):117 - 132.</para>

      <para>Umakhanthan, K and Ball, JE, (2001), Uncertainty in catchment
      prediction due to the spatio-temporal variability of rainfall,
      <emphasis>Submitted to ASCE, Journal of Hydrologic
      Engineering</emphasis></para>

      <para>Umakhanthan, K and Ball, JE, (2002), Importance of Rainfall Models
      in Catchment Simulation,<emphasis> Proc. 13 Congress of Asia Pacific
      Division th of IAHR, IAHR,</emphasis> Singapore (Advances in Hydraulics
      and Water Engineering, World Scientific Publications, Ed. JJ Guo),
      Volume 1, pp 551-556, ISBN 981-238-108-2.</para>

      <para>Urbonas, BR, Guo, JC, and Jansekok, MP, (1991), Hyetograph density
      effects on urban runoff modelling, <emphasis>Proc. Int. Conf. On
      Computer Application in Water Resources,</emphasis> Tamkang University,
      Tamsui, Taiwan, pp 32-37.</para>

      <para>Weeks et al. (2002),</para>

      <para>Williams, BJ and Yeh, William W-G, (1982), Parameter estimation in
      rainfall-runoff models, <emphasis>Journal of Hydrology,</emphasis>
      63:373-393.</para>

      <para>Wylie, SJ, and Sena, N, (1990), An efficient system of
      hydrological data capture storage and distribution, <emphasis>Proc. 1990
      Conference on Hydraulics in Civil Engineering,</emphasis> IEAust.,
      Sydney, Australia, IEAust.Nat. Conf. Pub. 90/4, pp 130 - 135.</para>

      <para>XP-Software, (2001), RAFTS-XP: <emphasis>Runoff Analysis and Flow
      Training Simulation incorporating the Expert User Environment - User’s
      Manual,</emphasis> Unpublished Report, WP Software, Belconnen, ACT,
      Australia</para>

      <para>Zaman, S and Ball, JE, (1994), Simulation of small events in an
      urban catchment, <emphasis>Proc. Water Down Under ‘94,</emphasis>
      Adelaide, Aust., IEAust Nat Conf Pub 94/15, pp 353 - 358.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
