<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="b4_ch4" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    status = "In Preparation">
    
    <title>Treatment of Joint Probability</title>
    
    <para>
        <informaltable border="1">
            <tr>
                <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Book</td>
                <td>4</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Chapter</td>
                <td>4</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Date</td>
                <td>27/11/2015</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Content</td>
                <td>In preparation</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Graphs and Figures</td>
                <td>In preparation</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Examples</td>
                <td>In preparation</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>General</td>
                <td/>
            </tr>
        </informaltable>
    </para>
    <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>Introduce generic nature of joint probability requirements, referring to factors
            involved in the transformation of rainfall to runoff, and other factors (eg initial
            reservoir level or tide levels) that may influence the design performance of interest.
            Outline the need to focus on as few factors as possible, the different approaches to
            characterisation, and the derivation of exceedance probabilities.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Selection and treatment of factors</title>

        <para>Describe use of sensitivity analysis to identify the factors of most importance to the
            problem. Emphasise the importance of selecting as few factors as possible, the potential
            for dependence between factors, and the likelihood of their dependence on event
            severity.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Stochastic sampling</title>

        <para>Describe different methods of stochastic sampling: bootstrap sampling from ensembles,
            non-parametric, and parametric approaches. Discuss random number generation, the
            generation of correlated variables, and conditional sampling.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Estimation of Exceedance Probabilities</title>

        <para>Discuss the two main approaches to deriving frequency curves based on direct sampling
            and stratified sampling. Discuss how large sample sizes allow the use of simple
            frequency analyses (compared to procedures presented in Book 3), and describe Total
            Probability Theorem for analysis of stratified solutions, including mention of
            importance sampling.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Worked Examples</title>

        <para>Provide worked examples for sampling, construction of frequency plot, and analysis of
            a stratified sample.</para>
    </section>
    
</chapter>
