<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version = "5.0" xml:id="b2_ch5"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Temporal Patterns</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/loveridge_melanie.xml"/>


    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/testoni_isabelle.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/podger_scott.xml"/>
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Advanced draft</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Subject to industry feedback and final testing with 2016 IFDs </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_01">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>The majority of  hydrograph estimation methods used for flood estimation require a
      temporal pattern that describes how rainfall falls over time as a design input. Traditionally
      a single burst temporal pattern has been used for each rainfall event duration. The use of a
      single pattern has been questioned for some time <citation>b2_c5_r15</citation> as the
      analysis of observed rainfall events from even a single pluviograph shows that a wide variety
      of temporal patterns is possible.</para>

    <para>The importance of temporal patterns has increased as the practice of flood estimation has
      evolved from peak flow estimation to full hydrograph estimation. There has been a strong move
      toward storage-based mitigation solutions in urban catchments which require realistic temporal
      patterns that reproduce total storm volumes as well as the temporal distribution of rainfall
      within the event.</para>
    <para>This chapter discusses use of temporal patterns for design flood estimation where a fixed
      temporal pattern is applied over the entire catchment. <xref linkend="b2_ch6_6"/> discusses
      the more complex case of space-time patterns. </para>

    <para>This chapter is structured as follows:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_02"/> – discusses fundamental temporal pattern concepts and
          how the concept of using ensembles of temporal pattern developed;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_06"/> – discusses the storm database that was used to develop
          temporal patterns; </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_10"/> – describes the estimation of pre-burst rainfall;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_11"/> – describes the development of ensembles of design
          temporal patterns;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_12"/> – discusses areal temporal patterns;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_15"/> – discusses possible effects of climate change on
          temporal patterns;</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_16"/> – discusses the application of design temporal
          patterns;</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_02">
    <title>Temporal Pattern Concepts</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_03">
      <title>Storm Components</title>
      <para>In order to properly understand the temporal patterns it is necessary to understand the
        components of a storm event and how they relate to Intensity Frequency Duration Data (IFD)
        and catchment response. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_01"/> depicts a typical storm pattern and
        how components of the storm can be characterised. It is important to note the components can
        be characterised either by IFD relationships or by catchment response and are highly
        dependent on the definitions used. The components of a storm include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">antecedent rainfall</emphasis> - is rainfall that has fallen
            before the storm event and is not considered part of the storm but can affect catchment
            response. This is not considered in this chapter but is introduced for
            completeness.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">pre-burst rainfall - </emphasis>is storm rainfall that
            occurs before the main burst. With the exception of relatively frequent events, it
            generally does not have a significant influence on catchment response but is very
            important for understanding catchment and storage conditions before the main rainfall
            burst.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">the burst - </emphasis>represents the main part of the storm
            but is very dependent on the definition used. Bursts have typically been characterised
            by duration. The burst could be defined as the <emphasis role="italic">critical rainfall
              burst </emphasis>, the rainfall period within the storm that has the lowest
            probability, or <emphasis role="italic">the critical response burst</emphasis> that
            corresponds to the duration which produces the largest catchment response for a given
            rainfall Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">post-burst rainfall</emphasis> - is rainfall that occurs
            after the main burst and is generally only considered when aspects of hydrograph
            recession are important. This could be for drawing down a dam after a flood event or
            understanding how inundation times affect flood recovery, road closures or agricultural
            land.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_01">
        <title>Typical Storm Components</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2070.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>If the critical response burst is not the same as the critical rainfall burst then the
        critical response burst is either:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>part of a longer critical rainfall burst; or</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a storm that contains rarer shorter duration bursts.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Rarer shorter duration bursts within a burst are typically called embedded bursts and
        can cause problems in modelling as, while the intention may be to assess the catchment
        response to a burst of a defined duration and probability, the response to a rarer shorter
        duration burst is also being assessed.</para>
      <para>The distinction between a burst and a complete storm is important as complete storms are
        used for calibration and bursts are typically used for design. Though this difference is
        less important for catchments with long duration responses, as the bursts typically
        represent nearly the entire storm event.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_04">
      <title>Pattern Variability</title>

      <para>It has been well recognised that temporal patterns exhibit significant variability
        between rainfall events of similar magnitude, and the adopted pattern can have a significant
        effect on the estimated peak flow. <citation>b2_c5_r1+1</citation>,
          <citation>b2_c5_r14+1</citation>, <citation>b2_c5_r3+1</citation>,
          <citation>b2_c5_r37+1</citation>, <citation>b2_c5_r4+1</citation> give examples of
        differences of up to 50% in flood peaks resulting from different assumed temporal patterns.
          <citation>b2_c5_r2+1</citation> discusses how catchment peak flow tends to increase as the
        variability of the pattern increases.</para>

      <para><citation>b2_c5_r22+1</citation> describe the variability of patterns:</para>

      <para><quote>In nature, a wide range of patterns is possible. Some
      storms have their period of peak intensity occur early, while other
      storms have the peak rainfall intensity occur towards the end of the
      storm period and a large number have a tendency for the peak to occur
      more or less centrally.</quote></para>

      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_02"/> depicts two very different storms from Sydney Observatory
        Hill that have similar IFD characteristics from 15 min to 12 hrs and a 2 hr critical
        rainfall burst, however on other criteria they are very different. The first pattern has 182
        mm before the 2 hr burst, while the second pattern has 16 mm. For the 2nd event the
        commencement of runoff will be closely aligned with the main burst while the former event is
        likely to have significant runoff prior to the main burst. The rainfall burst also exhibits
        significant variability, <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_03"/> presents the temporal patterns (as
        dimensionless mass curves) of ten 2 hr bursts of similar probability that show the
        variability described by <citation>b2_c5_r22+1</citation>.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_02">
        <title>Two Different Storm Events with Similar Intensity Frequency Duration Characteristics
          (Sydney Observatory Hill) – Two Hyetographs plus Burst Probability Graph</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2071.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_03">
        <title>Ten 2 hr Dimensionless Mass Curves</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2072.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Most of the historical research on temporal patterns has assumed that the central
        tendency of the pattern is more important than the variability, with the aim of producing a
        typical, representative or median pattern. <citation>b6_c3_r6+1</citation> describes how a
        pattern can be considered a two dimensional quantity with most methods breaking the pattern
        into two manageable one dimensional quantities that describe the magnitude of the element
        and the order of the elements. This can be described as a rank order vector and a decay
        curve that describes how the magnitude decreases between ranks.</para>

      <para>Monte Carlo and ensemble modelling techniques try to overcome the problems associated
        with this simplification by using an ensemble of temporal patterns. A short history of
        temporal patterns helps explain that, while the complexity of temporal patterns has been
        well understood for a long time, it has been difficult to produce a simple set of design
        patterns.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_05">
      <title>History of Design Temporal Pattern Development</title>
      <para>Australian Rainfall and Runoff 1977 <citation>b2_c5_r18, b9_c3_r14</citation> notes that
        there has historically been a slow change in the application of temporal distributions of
        rainfall in hydrologic studies from more arbitrary approaches to approaches that reproduce
        the IFD characteristics (<citation>b2_c5_r11+1</citation> and
          <citation>b2_c5_r10+1</citation>). The modern interpretation is the duration independent
        storm <citation>b2_c5_r38</citation>. These approaches reproduce the IFD loading and at best
        can reproduce aspects of a single storm. Such approaches have some applicability for peak
        flow estimation but cannot reproduce realistic hydrographs.</para>
      <para>Other early approaches included in the development of patterns based on observed
        pluviograph records were for complete storms rather than bursts. Such approaches require the
        scaling of complete storms. Other methods have allowed the arbitrary rearrangement of
        patterns to maximise peak discharge. Such approaches are very far removed from concept of
        probability neutrality.</para>
      <para>The development of the Average Variability Method by <citation>b2_c5_r22+1</citation>
        and <citation>b2_c5_r23+1</citation> analysed the variability of patterns by separating the
        analysis of the magnitude or the ranks from the analysis of rank order. This approach is
        only applicable to bursts and was applied in ARR 1977 and in a very detailed way in ARR
        1987. A variation of this approach was developed by <citation>b2_c5_r7+1</citation>. During
        the finalisation of ARR 1987 some problems where found with the use of the patterns and
        extensive testing was carried out which resulted in some changes to remove some embedded
        bursts, including some arbitrary rank order changes. It has been assumed that an AVM pattern
        would preserve probability neutrality. Single burst per duration AVM patterns have been
        extensively used since ARR 1987 and appear to have performed reasonable well for peak flow
        estimation. </para>
      <para>By their very nature AVM patterns do preserve the average rank magnitudes. <xref
          linkend="b2_ch5_f_odj34"/> plots the magnitude or decay curve for the ten dimensionless
        curves in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_03"/> and the AVM curve from these events and all 10
        events that would be considered in a AVM analysis.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_odj34">
        <title>Decay Curve of Ten Dimensionless Patterns and AVM Patterns</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2085.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The issues that have arisen have been discussed in
        <citation>b2_c5_r25+1</citation><?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160622T200814+1000" comment="can we add others"?>:<?oxy_comment_end?></para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Specific durations tend to dominate;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Big changes in pattern and corresponding peak flow occur at some region
            boundaries;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The burst only approach has made conversion of observed losses to burst losses
            difficult;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The design patterns often contain significant embedded bursts; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Filtering to remove embedded bursts that was recommended in ARR 1987
              <citation>arr_1987</citation> has had a mixed uptake and sometimes produces
            unrealistically long critical durations.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The AVM approach also works best when there is a dominant typical pattern shape. As part
        of the AVM approach the average and standard deviation of the rank of each period is
        calculated, when there is no dominant pattern these averages can be very similar and the
        resultant AVM pattern need not bare any resemblance to any of the observed
        patterns.<?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20160704T181802+1000" comment="possible text if we add a figure: &quot;Figure z shows such an AVM pattern&quot;"?></para>
      <?oxy_comment_end?>
      <para>The complexity of producing a representative or median pattern has led many
        practitioners to question the concept and ask whether it is better to specifically account
        for this variability by modelling an ensemble of temporal patterns.</para>
      <para>The problems with the AVM method and other median or representative patterns is that it
        assumes the variability of actual patterns is much less important than their central
        tendency. Such an approach does not account for how temporal patterns interact with
        catchments to produce peak flows and hydrographs. The response can be very
        catchment-specific, and there is no guarantee that a representative pattern will produce the
        medium response from an ensemble of patterns that properly captures the variability of
        observed patterns. These problems can become more pronounced when changes are made to the
        catchment response or storage characteristics. <citation>b2_c5_r20+1</citation> examined the
        impact of storage on an ensemble of events for the lot, neighbourhood and subcatchment
        scale.</para>
      <para>It is unclear who first proposed the concept of running an ensemble of temporal patterns
        to account for the variability of patterns. Practitioners have a long history of comparing
        the peak flow estimates from design patterns to estimates from patterns extracted from real
        storms that occurred on that catchment of interest. The development of Monte Carlo methods
          <citation>b2_c5_r9, b2_c5_r24, b2_c5_r32</citation> that stochastically sample from
        observed events based on complete storms and embedded bursts of maximum intensity (“storm
        cores”) is well documented and has helped highlight the value of using ensembles. Others,
        such as <citation>b2_c5_r16+1, b2_c5_r17+1</citation> have used ensembles of storm bursts
        based on observed point and areal storms to facilitate their use directly with design IFD
        information. The development of the Bureau of Meteorology significant storm database
          <citation>b2_c5_r13</citation> enabled practitioners to easily test ensembles of areal
        patterns and how they affected other flood characteristics; examples include
          <citation>b2_c5_r31+1</citation>. While there is a long history of testing ensembles of
        temporal patterns, <citation>b2_c5_r29+1</citation> is the first example of detailed testing
        of ensemble patterns as a design input outside a Monte Carlo environment. This long
        development history of ensemble simulation can probably be explained by the fact that the
        concept could not be confirmed until rigorous Monte Carlo techniques became available for
        validation.</para>
      <para>Parallel to the development of ensemble and Monte Carlo approaches, practitioners have
        become concerned with using burst patterns where complete storm volume is important.
          <citation>b2_c5_r26+1</citation> suggest the entire burst approach needed to be reviewed
        and design storms needed to replace design bursts. For the Wollongong area
          <citation>b2_c5_r26+1</citation> demonstrated that historically most short duration events
        were embedded in longer duration events. They recommended that short duration events could
        be embedded in a 24 hour event of the same probability. They particularly cautioned against
        using bursts on catchments with significant natural or man-made storages.
          <citation>b2_c5_r19+1</citation> had found similar problems in the upper Parramatta River
        and suggested embedded storms were more realistic, and that basin storages would be
        underestimated with a burst approach unless the embedded nature of events was factored into
        the starting volumes. <citation>b2_c5_r27+1</citation> extended the earlier work to include
        guidance on using the embedded design storms. <citation>b2_c5_r28+1</citation> recommended a
        storm based approach be used when there are significant storages or diversions present in
        the catchment. <citation>b2_c5_r12+1</citation>, inspired by
          <citation>b2_c5_r26+1</citation>, explored basin performance using a theoretical catchment
        at Observatory Hill, Sydney in a continuous simulation approach and found similar problems
        with peak flow being underestimated by a similar amount when storages were present. All of
        these studies were based on catchments less than 110 km<superscript>2</superscript> that are
        close to Sydney.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_06">
    <title>Storm Database</title>

    <para>As part of the IFD revision (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>) the Bureau of Meteorology produced
      a quality controlled pluviograph database, containing 2280 stations with more than 8 station
      years (refer to<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/> and <xref linkend="b1_ch4"/>). The average station
      record length is 25 years, with a combined record length of 57 000 years. A total of 754 of
      the stations are owned by the Bureau of Meteorology and the other 1526 are owned by other data
      agencies throughout Australia. This data was provided by the Bureau of Meteorology, who
      undertook quality controlling to identify suspect data, such as missing data, accumulated
      totals and time shifts <citation>b2_c5_r6</citation>. All station data was provided as time
      series data sampled at a 5 minute time step. In addition to the rainfall depths, each data
      point had a quality code indicating the quality of the data. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_04"/>
      below depicts the geographical distribution of the pluviographs across Australia. Each station
      is represented as a circle, with the size of the circle indicating the record length of the
      station.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_04">
      <title>Pluviograph Stations Record Lengths</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2073.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_00"/> presents the maximum number stations available in any year
      for decadal periods. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_00"/> demonstrates that most of the pluviograph
      record is from 1960 onwards. Though overall the data comes from a period that starts before
      1900, over half of the data is from the period from 1993 onwards.</para>

   
    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_00" frame="void">
        <caption>Number of Pluviographs by Decade</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Decade</th>
            <th>Maximum Number of Pluviographs in any Year</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;1900</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1900-1940</td>
            <td>24</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1940-1960</td>
            <td>154</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1960-1970</td>
            <td>392</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1970-1980</td>
            <td>923</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1980-1990</td>
            <td>1273</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1990 -2000</td>
            <td>1926</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2000-2010</td>
            <td>1837<footnote>
              <para>Not all data was available from 2009 onwards</para>
            </footnote></td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

    <para>As shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_04"/> the highest density of pluviograph stations is
      typically found along coastal areas of Australia around key population centres. In <xref
        linkend="b2_ch5_f_05"/>, the pluviograph stations are seen to be clustered around urban
      areas, such as Sydney, Wollongong, Melbourne and Canberra. Less data is available in central
      Australia, with the exception of the Alice Springs area. Large areas of central Western
      Australia contain no data.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_05">
      <title>Pluviograph Stations used Throughout South-Eastern Australia with Record Lengths </title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2074.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_07">
      <title>Data Quality</title>

      <para>Where a single station is being analysed it is important that it has a reasonably long
        record (preferably longer than 30 years) and only a small percentage of missing data.
        However, for studies that pool data the quality of the data is a bigger issue than record
        length. It is however, important to remember that most of the pluviograph data is from the
        last few decades.</para>

      <para>The pluviograph database contains a significant number of events
      with long periods of apparently uniform rainfall. While some of this
      could be from events with relatively uniform rainfall, most appears to
      be the result of disaggregating accumulated rainfall totals uniformly.
      Even if rainfall is uniform, a tipping bucket rain gauge recording at 5
      minutes will only record uniform rainfall over an extended period if the
      depth in each five minute period is equal or slightly larger than an
      integer multiple of the tipping bucket capacity. It was concluded that
      most of the periods of uniform rainfall are probably caused by
      digitisation and resampling at different time steps. Events with large
      periods of uniform rainfall were disregarded, while events were kept if
      the uniform period was only a small portion of the entire event.</para>

      <para>In addition, several other issues with the data quality were
      found. Some records contained significant periods of missing data. There
      were also periods of interpolated data, where several data points were
      indicated as interpolated from a later point, presumably at the end of
      an event. Events where a significant part of the rainfall was
      interpolated were excluded from further analysis. There were also
      sections where the rainfall was uniform over many intervals within an
      event, indicating that the data points were interpolated, even though
      the quality control value did not specify that to be the case. Since
      storms generally do not have uniform rainfall at the local scale, events
      that had a significant part of their total rainfall depth occurring in
      consecutive identical intervals were also excluded.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_08">
      <title>Event Selection and Analysis</title>
      <para>Once the data quality checking was complete, all events with a burst greater than 1
        Exceedance per Year (EY) using the
        <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160622T202541+1000" comment="what are we going to do with this"?>2013
        IFD <?oxy_comment_end?>and which were not flagged with problems were extracted for further
        analysis. For each event the start and finish of the event was defined using the methodology
        described in ARR Revision Project 3 - Temporal Patterns of Rainfall Report Part 1
          <citation>b2_c5_r34</citation>, which was consistent with the storm event definition used
        in the ARR Revision Project 6 - Losses  <citation>b2_c5_r8</citation>. Once all events with
        a burst greater than 1EY were defined for every duration, the following properties where
        calculated:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>burst rainfall depth probabilities for each duration;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>start and finish time for each burst;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>time when 50% of the burst depth occurred (ie. burst loading);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>pre-burst rainfall depth for each burst duration;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>pre-burst to burst rainfall ratio for each duration; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Post-burst depth.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>For each event the rarest or critical rainfall burst (of any duration and location
        within the overall event) was also calculated.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_09">
      <title>Regional Characteristics</title>

      <para>To assess the regional characteristics, 12 temporal pattern regions were defined based
        on the 54 Natural Resource Management (NRM) sub-regions used for investigating the impacts
        of climate change <citation>b2_c5_r5</citation>. The adopted regions follow drainage basin
        boundaries. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_001"/> depicts the adopted temporal pattern regions.
          <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_001"/> summarises the number of rainfall gauges and storm events
        that exist in each region.</para>
      <table  xml:id="b2_ch5_t_001" frame="void">
        <caption>Regions- Number of Gauges and
          <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160622T203106+1000" comment="isabelle - did you rename the regions? need to update this table "?>Events<?oxy_comment_end?></caption>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Region</th>
            <th>Number of Gauges</th>
            <th>Number of Station Years</th>
            <th>Number of Events</th>
            <th>Average Number of Events per Station Year</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern Slopes (Tasmania)</td>
            <td>110</td>
            <td>2954</td>
            <td>3477</td>
            <td>1.18</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern Slopes (mainland)</td>
            <td>356</td>
            <td>8536</td>
            <td>20581</td>
            <td>2.41</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Murray Basin</td>
            <td>233</td>
            <td>6316</td>
            <td>18399</td>
            <td>2.91</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Central Slopes</td>
            <td>118</td>
            <td>2767</td>
            <td>7167</td>
            <td>2.59</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>East Coast South</td>
            <td>331</td>
            <td>8067</td>
            <td>19856</td>
            <td>2.46</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>East Coast North</td>
            <td>210</td>
            <td>5187</td>
            <td>12123</td>
            <td>2.34</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Wet Tropics</td>
            <td>99</td>
            <td>2474</td>
            <td>5437</td>
            <td>2.20</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Monsoonal North</td>
            <td>211</td>
            <td>5054</td>
            <td>12287</td>
            <td>2.43</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Rangelands West</td>
            <td>93</td>
            <td>2334</td>
            <td>5391</td>
            <td>2.31</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Rangelands</td>
            <td>226</td>
            <td>5561</td>
            <td>12618</td>
            <td>2.27</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Flatlands West </td>
            <td>349</td>
            <td>9113</td>
            <td>26402</td>
            <td>2.90</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Flatlands East </td>
            <td>56</td>
            <td>1401</td>
            <td>3450</td>
            <td>2.46</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_001">
        <title>Temporal Pattern Regions</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2075.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The term ‘burst loading’ refers to the distribution of rainfall
      within a burst and is a defining characteristic of a rainfall event. For
      each event the burst loading was calculated as the percentage of the
      time taken for 50% of the burst depth to occur. The burst loading can be
      used as a simple measure of when the heaviest part of the burst occurs
      and can be used to categorise events as ‘front’, ‘middle’ or ‘back’
      loaded. Events where categorised into three groups, depending on where
      50% of the burst rainfall occurs:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>front loaded – 0 to 40% of the time,</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>middle loaded – 40 to 60% of the time, and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>back loaded – 60 to 100% of the time.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_06"/> depicts a typical event from each category.</para>

      <para><figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_06">
          <title> Example of Front, Middle and Back Loaded Events</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2076.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure></para>

      <para>This simple categorisation provides a pragmatic means of capturing when the peak loading
        occurs, as described by <citation>b2_c5_r22+1</citation>, though it is worth recognising
        that for a double peaked event, when most of the rainfall is in the early and later part of
        the burst, the loading can somewhat illogically fall into the middle category.</para>

      <para>Each region was characterised by its burst loading distribution, which describes the
        percentage of front, middle and back loaded events for different durations. The proportion
        of front/middle/back loading for each region was determined for less than and greater than 6
        hours duration (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_01"/>). The proportion was assumed to be constant
        across all AEPs.</para>

      <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_01" frame="void">
        <caption>Burst Loading by Region and
          <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160622T203359+1000" comment="have the region names changed"?>Duration<?oxy_comment_end?></caption>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Region</emphasis></th>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Duration</emphasis></th>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Front Loaded (%)</emphasis></th>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Middle Loaded (%)</emphasis></th>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Back Loaded (%)</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Southern Slopes (Tasmania)</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>21.5</td>
            <td>64.1</td>
            <td>14.4</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>20.5</td>
            <td>60.0</td>
            <td>19.5</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Southern Slopes (mainland)</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>30.1</td>
            <td>53.0</td>
            <td>16.9</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>22.7</td>
            <td>53.7</td>
            <td>23.6</td>
            <td/>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Murray Basin</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>28.3</td>
            <td>53.8</td>
            <td>17.9</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>24.7</td>
            <td>52.5</td>
            <td>22.7</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Central Slopes</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>31.0</td>
            <td>53.3</td>
            <td>15.7</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>27.0</td>
            <td>46.9</td>
            <td>26.1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">East Coast South</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>26.5</td>
            <td>57.1</td>
            <td>16.4</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>17.1</td>
            <td>58.6</td>
            <td>24.3</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">East Coast North</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>28.9</td>
            <td>56.5</td>
            <td>14.6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>23.4</td>
            <td>48.5</td>
            <td>28.1</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Wet Tropics</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>16.0</td>
            <td>71.8</td>
            <td>12.2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>18.7</td>
            <td>58.1</td>
            <td>23.2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Monsoonal North</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>27.6</td>
            <td>63.7</td>
            <td>8.8</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>27.5</td>
            <td>41.4</td>
            <td>31.2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Rangelands West</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>23.7</td>
            <td>62.5</td>
            <td>13.8</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>23.6</td>
            <td>49.2</td>
            <td>27.2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Rangelands</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>29.0</td>
            <td>56.6</td>
            <td>14.3</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>24.4</td>
            <td>49.2</td>
            <td>26.4</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Flatlands West</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>30.8</td>
            <td>49.3</td>
            <td>19.9</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>31.4</td>
            <td>48.9</td>
            <td>19.7</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td rowspan="2">Flatlands East</td>
            <td>≤ 6hr</td>
            <td>27.6</td>
            <td>52.4</td>
            <td>20.0</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&gt; 6hr</td>
            <td>17.4</td>
            <td>54.4</td>
            <td>28.2</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

     
    
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_10">
    <title>Pre Burst Rainfall and Antecedent Conditions</title>

    <para>The events database allowed the pre-burst behaviour of rainfall events to be
      characterised, regionalised and mapped.
      <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160622T203624+1000" comment="fix reference "?>Temporal
      Patterns report 2 <citation>b2_c5_r34+1</citation><?oxy_comment_end?> presents the detailed
      analysis, regionalisation and mapping of pre-burst behaviour for Australia. Due to the
      relatively short pluviograph records, the approach assumes that this behaviour can be pooled
      to develop reasonably sized samples by transferring storms from nearby locations with similar
      IFD characteristics. This was done on a Region of Influence basis and not a fixed region
      basis, as the ratio of pre-burst rainfall has some correlation with Intensity Frequency
      Duration characteristics. In many parts of Australia the pre-burst rainfall generally
      represents a very small amount of the event and generally does not contribute to the runoff
      response, so it can be treated in a relatively simply manner. However, in some parts of the
      country pre-burst rainfall can represent a significant part of the rainfall event and runoff
      response. Pre-burst can also be important in urban catchments with large directly connected
      impervious areas (<xref linkend="book5"/>). Storage strategies need to account for this
      additional runoff when sizing storage tanks and basins (<xref linkend="book9"/>). The
      pre-burst was characterised based on the rarest rainfall duration burst within the storm using
      the 2013 IFDs. <citation>b5_c3_r38+1</citation> found this approach gave a biased estimate of
      the average pre-burst, systematically underestimating the depth of the pre-burst. Following
      from this work and the expected update of the IFDs from the Bureau of Meteorology in 2016 this
      work will be updated and <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_08"/>, <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_09"/> and
        <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_10"/> will be updated accordingly.</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_08"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_09"/> depict the median ratio of
      the pre-burst to burst and the depth of pre-burst in mm for the 6hr duration and probabilities
      mapped across Australia. The full data set of maps is available online at the
      <?oxy_comment_start author="retallick" timestamp="20160622T203703+1000" comment="link?"?>ARR
      data repository<?oxy_comment_end?> (<link xlink:href="http://data.arr.org.au/"/>).</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_10"/> shows the probability distribution of the pre-burst rainfall
      for each region.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_08">
      <title>Pre-burst Rainfall</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2077.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_09">
        <title>Pre-burst to burst ratio</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2078.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_10">
        <title>Standardised pre-burst to burst ratio distributions</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2079.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    <para>The manner in which pre-burst rainfall is treated depends on the
    magnitude of the pre-burst rainfall, how this compares to losses and
    whether pre-burst runoff is likely and will have a significant effect on
    hydrograph volumes. As longer duration bursts tend to represent most of
    the storm events, it is generally only an issue for smaller catchments. If
    pre-burst rainfall is unlikely to affect the runoff responses, it is best
    treated in a simple manner with losses. For simple urban cases pre-burst
    rainfall can be used to condition storage starting conditions. Where
    pre-burst is influential for flood response, it can be sampled from its
    distribution and applied with a typical pre-burst temporal pattern.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_11">
    <title>Design Point Temporal Patterns</title>

    <para>As part of the ARR Revision Project 3 - Temporal Patterns of Rainfall
        <citation>b2_c5_r36</citation> a series of temporal pattern techniques were trialled. A
      total of 35 test catchments were adopted across Australia, ranging in area from 30 to 80
        km<superscript>2</superscript>. The aims of the testing were to assess the performance of
      the design method using best estimates of the revised inputs and to determine what influence
      the temporal patterns have on design estimates. Temporal pattern ensembles were tested within
      a Monte Carlo framework and a simpler quantile ensemble framework. Two methods were trialled,
      the regional temporal patterns (as discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_09"/>) along with a
      Region of Influence (ROI) approach. Three event types were trialled being burst only, burst
      plus pre-burst and complete storm events (for ROI only). A range of initial loss approaches
      were trailed, including burst and storm losses, combined with the median value or a
      distribution of values. The nature of regional temporal pattern ensembles requires AEP bins to
      be derived. The ensembles for each AEP bin were trialled across all AEPs to assess the
      sensitivity of the AEP bins.</para>

    <para>Based on the results of this performance testing, the temporal patterns derived by
      theregional burst approach are recommended for general use. Temporal patterns for complete
      storms derived by the ROI approach are left as an alternative for small, volume-sensitive
      systems where pre- and post-burst rainfall is important, though it may be that such systems
      are better analysed using continuous simulation approaches.</para>

    <para>Other major findings from ARR Revision Project 3 - Temporal Patterns of Rainfall
        <citation>b2_c5_r36</citation> were:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Irrespective of the method used to derive the temporal patterns, when using a
          representative ensemble of patterns all methods produce relatively similar results; and </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Frequent patterns should not be used for rarer events; scaling a
        temporal pattern introduces more variability and produces higher
        design estimates.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>Ensembles of 20 temporal patterns were initially envisaged, however a large number of
      regions had insufficient data available to warrant a sample of this size. Different ensemble
      sizes were tested to determine the sensitivity to ensemble size, with little bias found
      between the ensemble sizes. Samples of 10 temporal patterns were therefore adopted as an
      appropriate compromise between pattern variability and data availability. Ensembles were
      generated for each AEP bin, duration and region. The four AEP bins adopted (see <xref
        linkend="b2_ch5_t_02"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_11"/>) were based on the burst AEP at
      the source of the event. Temporal Pattern were extracted for the following durations from 15
      minutes to 7 days, as shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_03"/>.</para>

    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_02" frame="void">
      <caption>Regional Temporal Pattern Bins</caption>
      <col width="50%"/>
      <col width="50%"/>
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">AEP Group</emphasis></th>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">AEP Range</emphasis></th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>Very Rare</td>
          <td>Rarest 10 within region</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Rare</td>
          <td>Rarer than 3.2% AEP</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Intermediate</td>
          <td>Between 3.2% and 14.4% AEP</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Frequent</td>
          <td>More frequent than 14.4% AEP</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
    


    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_11">
      <title>Temporal Pattern Ranges</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2080.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_03" frame="void">
      <caption>Temporal Pattern Durations</caption>
      <col width="33%"/>
      <col width="33%"/>
      <col width="33%"/>
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th colspan="3"><emphasis role="bold">Duration</emphasis></th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td><emphasis role="italic">Minutes</emphasis></td>
          <td><emphasis role="italic">Hours</emphasis></td>
          <td><emphasis role="italic">Days</emphasis></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>15</td>
          <td>0.25</td>
          <td>0.010</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>0.5</td>
          <td>0.021</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>60</td>
          <td>1</td>
          <td>0.042</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>120</td>
          <td>2</td>
          <td>0.083</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>180</td>
          <td>3</td>
          <td>0.125</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>270</td>
          <td>4.5</td>
          <td>0.188</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>360</td>
          <td>6</td>
          <td>0.250</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>540</td>
          <td>9</td>
          <td>0.375</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>720</td>
          <td>12</td>
          <td>0.500</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>1080</td>
          <td>18</td>
          <td>0.750</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>1440</td>
          <td>24</td>
          <td>1</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>2160</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>1.5</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>2880</td>
          <td>48</td>
          <td>2</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>4320</td>
          <td>72</td>
          <td>3</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>5760</td>
          <td>96</td>
          <td>4</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>7200</td>
          <td>120</td>
          <td>5</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>8640</td>
          <td>144</td>
          <td>6</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>10080</td>
          <td>168</td>
          <td>7</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
    

  

    <para>When selecting a small ensemble of temporal patterns it is important
    to capture the typical variability of the observed events. A methodology
    was therefore adopted that samples from observed events with the intent of
    generating a representative ensemble in terms of the variability of actual
    events, with no obvious bias. Whilst it is difficult to quantify or verify
    the achievement of this objective, steps have been undertaken to ensure
    the samples are broadly representative, including a visual check of all
    ensembles.</para>

    <para>There are a large number of frequent events from which to select,
    however, the choice is more limited for rarer events.</para>

    <para>For each AEP and duration bin the sampling of an ensemble of 10 patterns used the
      preferred criteria in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_06"/>. The relaxed criteria were used where less
      than 10 suitable patterns could be found using the preferred criteria.</para>

    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_06" frame="void">
      <caption>Temporal Pattern Selection Criteria</caption>
      <col width="50%"/>
      <col width="50%"/>
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">Preferred Criteria (for Data Rich Regions)</emphasis></th>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">Relaxed Criteria (for Data Sparse Regions)</emphasis></th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>No rarer embedded bursts</td>
          <td>n/a</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>No events overlapping in time</td>
          <td>n/a</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Loading characteristics enforced</td>
          <td>Loading characteristics ignored</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Events from within a region</td>
          <td>Sampled from within region and neighbouring region with similar climatic
            characteristics</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>

      <para>While patterns containing embedded rarer bursts at their recording
    location were not selected, events can still have embedded bursts at other
    locations within the region. The presence of major embedded bursts may
    warrant filtering of patterns.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_12">
    <title>Temporal Patterns for Areal Rainfall Bursts</title>
    <para>As part of ARR Revision Project 3 - Temporal Patterns of Rainfall a series of areal
      average temporal patterns have been produced for different sized hypothetical catchments.
      These patterns average the spatial variability of rainfall in each time step which does remove
      some of the variability of actual space-time rainfall fields. The process of calculating areal
      temporal patterns involves identifying high rainfall areal events and calculating areal
      temporal patterns. A brief summary is provided in this chapter (refer to
        <citation>b2_c5_r39+1</citation> for more detail). Areal rainfall temporal patterns were
      calculated for the area and duration combinations listed in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_3js8f"
      />.</para>
    <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch5_t_3js8f">
      <caption>Areal Rainfall Temporal Patterns - Catchment Areas and Durations</caption>
      <col width="50%"/>
      <col width="50%"/>
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th><emphasis role="bold">Variable </emphasis></th>
          <th/>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>Catchment Area (km<superscript>2</superscript>)</td>
          <td>100, 200, 500, 1000, 2500, 5000, 10 000, 20 000, 40 000</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Durations (Hours)</td>
          <td>12, 18, 24, 36, 48, 72, 96, 120, 144, 168</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
     
  
    <section>
      <title>Areal Rainfall Time Series Grid for All Australia</title>
      <para>To create sets of areal temporal patterns an areal rainfall grid was derived for 30
        minute time steps using the events database (described in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_06"/>, ie.
        2280 pluviographs). Rainfall values from these pluviographs were further filtered for long
        disaggregations and erroneously high rainfall values. A grid resolution of 0.025° identical
        to the grid cell size used for the design rainfalls (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>) was chosen
        for simplicity of use. A natural neighbours algorithm, which is a variant of Thiessen
        polygons, was used to interpolate rainfall values from the pluviograph stations to each grid
        cell with rainfall values for each time step from January 1960 to December 2010.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Average Areal Rainfall Calculation</title>
      <para>The approach aims to identify the largest set of independent areal rainfall events
        within the Temporal Pattern Regions shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_001"/> by not
        restricting catchments to a particular shape. For each combination of duration and area, a
        set of rectangular hypothetical catchments were used to sample the areal rainfall time
        series and create catchment average rainfalls. At each catchment centroid, 12 hypothetical
        catchments were trialled using the combinations of 3 aspect ratios (1.5, 2.3 and 3.6) and 4
        rotations (0, 45, 90 and 135 degrees) shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_dn49w"/>. To best
        represent Australian catchments, the aspect ratios were chosen by selecting the 20th, 50th
        and 80th percentiles of shape factors calculated for the 798 catchments that were adopted
        for the RFFE method described in <xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>. Average areal rainfall was
        calculated for a hypothetical catchment’s each time step simply by averaging the rainfall of
        all the grid cells with midpoints within the catchment area. To lessen computational
        requirements, larger time steps were used for larger catchment areas.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_dn49w">
        <title>Combinations of Aspect Ratio and Rotation for Hypothetical Catchments</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2081.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Areal Temporal Pattern Selection</title>
      <para>Event rainfall totals were calculated for the sampled areal temporal patterns. For each
        of the temporal pattern regions (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_001"/>) a set of events for all
        combinations of catchment area and durations (as per <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_3js8f"/>) with
        the largest depths and no space-time overlap were selected. The space-time filter required a
        minimum of 3 days between the end of one event and the start of another and for catchment
        centres to be a minimum of either twice their longest side or 100 km apart.</para>
      <para>To ensure data quality, hypothetical catchments that did not contain the minimum number
        of pluviograph stations (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_jre30"/>) within their vicinity that were
        producing quality data at the time of the event were disregarded. An additional filter was
        then applied to remove events that had too much area assigned to a single gauge or
        erroneous/unrealistic rainfall values. Each space-time independent areal temporal pattern
        had a Pearson correlation coefficient derived between the areal pattern and all the
        corresponding temporal patterns of pluviograph stations within its vicinity. Patterns that
        had a very high correlation to a single gauge and no others or did not have enough stations
        with a reasonable correlation to the areal pattern were removed.</para>
      <table frame="void"  xml:id="b2_ch5_t_jre30">
        <caption>Minimum Number of Pluviographs Required for Event
          Selection for Each Catchment Area</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Catchment Areas (km<superscript>2</superscript>)</emphasis></th>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Minimum Number of Pluviographs</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>100</td>
            <td>3</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>200</td>
            <td>3</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>500</td>
            <td>3</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1000</td>
            <td>6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2500</td>
            <td>6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>5000</td>
            <td>6</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>10 000</td>
            <td>9</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>20 000</td>
            <td>20</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>40 000</td>
            <td>40</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
     
      <para>Given that events were chosen simply based on their total rainfall depth, many of the
        longer duration patterns selected represented a shorter duration. Using the same procedure
        implemented in defining event extents in the events database, events that had extents less
        than the duration shorter than the duration of interest were removed. </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Design Areal Temporal Patterns</title>
      <para>Due to the constraints on data quality, a full set of areal temporal patterns for every
        region, duration and area could not be generated. Therefore, to use areal temporal patterns
        for data sparse regions, it is necessary to sample patterns from climatically similar or
        nearby regions. This is especially a problem for longer durations, with some durations such
        as the 7 days not having enough patterns in any region. For these durations patterns must
        therefore be sampled from all of Australia, although data dense areas contain the majority
        of these events.</para>
      <para>Like the point temporal patterns, meta-data on each pattern has been provided that
        allows practitioners to track the location and time of the event. <xref
          linkend="b2_ch5_f_j5k3w"/> compares the cumulative mass curves for 24 hour point and area
        temporal patterns. This demonstrates how the spatial averaging produced by areal temporal
        patterns reduces the variability. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_wqan4"/> compares areal temporal
        patterns to the temporal patterns of the pluviograph closest to the area’s centroid, further
        highlighting a reduction in variability with the areal temporal patterns.</para>
      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_j5k3w">
        <title>Comparison of Point Temporal Patterns and Areal Temporal Patterns - East Coast South
          Region - 1 Day </title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2082.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_wqan4">
        <title>Comparison of Areal Temporal Patterns and the Temporal Pattern of the Closest
          Pluviograph for the Same Event</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2083.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section  xml:id="b2_ch5_s_12dgr">
    <title>Other Temporal Pattern Options</title>
    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_13">
      <title>Use of Historical Temporal Patterns</title>
      <para>On a large catchment with good quality temporal rainfall data it is not uncommon to have
        a reasonable number of historical patterns for events rarer than the 20% AEP event. Where
        there is a reasonable amount of local temporal data of appropriate AEPs across the
        catchment, it is appropriate to use this local data in place of regional temporal patterns.
        On large catchments, local point patterns will exhibit more variability and generally
        produce higher flow estimates than locally derived areal temporal patterns and should be
        used with caution. Some guidance on the use of local temporal patterns is provided in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch6_6"/>. </para>
      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch6_6"/> provides advice on the assignment of historical temporal
        patterns when modelling observed events for calibration or analysis.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_14">
      <title>Complete Storm Patterns</title>
      <para>The methodology developed for the pre-burst estimation pooled storm events from nearby
        catchments based on distance and IFD similarity. This approach was extended to develop
        ensembles of complete storms based on their critical burst duration by selecting events that
        can be put in a site specific duration probability bin with minimal scaling. The approach is
        somewhat experimental and has performed as well as burst approaches in limited testing.
        While categorising events on the basis of critical storm burst solves a lot of event
        selection problems but it is different from more traditional burst approaches. Aspects of
        the approach are described in ARR Revision Project 3 – Temporal Patterns of Rainfall Report
          <citation>b1_c3_r21</citation>.</para>
      <para>The major differences are:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Events are selected and duration binned on the basis of the critical rainfall
            duration;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>An event can only be used in one duration so a large storm sample is required;
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Duration bins represent a range of storm durations instead of a fixed
            duration;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Event filtering is not required; and </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A new sample needs to be created at each location so a regional approach is not
            possible.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The process of binning events on the basis of their critical rainfall duration means
        that events that produce a catchment response because of rainfall over a certain duration
        can be placed in a bin of a very different duration. This means that under a critical
        duration approach these event are unlikely to influence the design estimate even if they
        produce the largest catchment response. This problem would not occur in a Monte Carlo
        framework that samples across durations. </para>
      <para> Despite these limitations, a complete storm approach has the advantage of producing
        realistic rainfall storm events that have the correct burst IFD and storm volume
        characteristics. <citation>b2_c5_r40+1</citation> showed considerable difference in basin
        performance on a small urban catchment between burst and complete storm approaches.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Continuous Data</title>
      <para>While continuous simulation is generally more appropriate for modelling very frequent
        events there are some situations where event models might be appropriate. For these
        situations temporal patterns could be sampled from a local pluviograph or sampled from a
        generated continuous sequence using the techniques described in<xref linkend="b2_ch6"
        />.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_15">
    <title>Climate Change Impacts</title>
    <para>Very little information is known about how climate change will affect storm or burst
      temporal patterns. The most definitive work is by <citation>b2_c5_r30+1</citation> which
      analysed the relationship between burst patterns from 79 Australian rainfall gauges and
      temperature variations. This study found that, regardless of the climate region or season,
      temperature increases are associated with patterns becoming less uniform, with the largest
      fractions increasing in rainfall intensity and the lower fraction decreasing. The scaling of
      the largest fractions was more pronounced in short duration bursts, and rainfall gauges to the
      north of the country showed more pronounced changes. While this work is based on the present
      climate, it provides an insight into how patterns could change under a future warming. Such
      climate changes would also affect IFD characteristics.</para>
    <para><citation>b2_c5_r33+1</citation> proposed rainfall sequences for future climates could be
      constructed by sampling historical rainfall patterns corresponding to warmer days at the same
      location, or from locations which have an atmospheric profile more reflective of expected
      future climate. Such an approach could conceptually be applied in the selection of design
      burst patterns but would require significant testing.</para>
    <para>It is currently not possible to provide practical advice to practitioners on this aspect
      of temporal patterns. It is recommended that until further studies are completed, for
      simulations applying projected climate change, the temporal patterns applied should be those
      derived for existing climatic conditions but recognising the additional uncertainty in
      simulation results.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_16">
    <title>Temporal Pattern Application and Pre-burst</title>
    <section>
      <title>General</title>
      <para>For the majority of problems, the practitioner needs to select a temporal pattern based
        on the area and probability of the event they are modelling. For Very Rare and Extreme
        events specific advice is provided in <xref linkend="book8"/>. The derivation of long
        duration events (both point or areal temporal patterns) present a number of challenges. Many
        of the events selected in the IFD Annual Maxima Series were from shorter duration events and
        can not be selected as longer duration temporal patterns. Some long duration events are more
        like consecutive events with none or little rainfall in between shorter events. For this
        reason, in most locations, it was necessary to borrow temporal patterns (point and areal)
        from adjoining regions. Daily rainfall gauges located in the catchment of interest should
        give a good insight into the applicability of longer duration temporal patterns approaching
        7 days.</para>
      <para>Point temporal patterns should be used for catchments less than 75
          km<superscript>2</superscript>. Areal temporal patterns have been derived for a number of
        different catchment areas. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_heg84"/> provides a guide to applying the
        areal patterns.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch5_t_heg84">
        <caption>Areal Temporal Pattern Sets for Ranges of Catchment Areas</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Range of Target Catchment Areas (km<superscript>2</superscript>)</emphasis>
            </th>
            <th><emphasis role="bold">Catchment Area of Designated Areal Temporal Pattern Set
              (km<superscript>2</superscript>)</emphasis></th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>75 – 140</td>
            <td>100</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>140 – 300</td>
            <td>200</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>300 – 700</td>
            <td>500</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>700 – 1600</td>
            <td>1000</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1600 – 3500</td>
            <td>2500</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>3500 – 7000</td>
            <td>5000</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>7000 – 14,000</td>
            <td>10,000</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>14,000 – 28,000</td>
            <td>20,000</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>28,000 +</td>
            <td>40,000</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
     
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Ensemble Considerations</title>
      <para>The use of an ensemble of 10 temporal patterns as discussed in <xref
          linkend="b2_ch5_s_11"/> is recommended. The temporal patterns have been chosen to
        represent the variability in observed patterns. Given the run times of two dimensional
        hydraulic models it is not practical to run all 10 patterns (for multiple durations). A more
        practical approach would be to run a separate hydrological modelling process of the whole
        catchment of interest in order to determine the average pattern in terms of peak flow or
        volume depending on the problem (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_j4892"/>). It is not recommended
        that the temporal pattern that represents the worst (or best) case be used by itself for
        design. Testing has demonstrated that on most catchments large number of events in the
        ensemble patterns are clustered around the mean and median. <sidebar>
          <para>When selecting a single representative (average) pattern the practitioner needs to
            look at the whole catchment response hydrograph and not local inflow hydrographs.</para>
        </sidebar></para>
      <para>The ensemble of 10 pattern provides a range of plausible answers. The practitioner
        should consider the benefits of investigating multiple temporal patterns or Monte Carlo for
        sensitive designs and solutions. </para>
      <sidebar>
        <para>Running an ensemble of ten temporal patterns through a two dimensional model could be
          time consuming. One option is to double the grid cell size which will decrease run time 8
          fold.</para>
      </sidebar>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Upscaling of Patterns</title>
      <para>Practitioners are cautioned to avoid or minimise upscaling patterns from frequent events
        to rare events. In some locations the dominate rainfall mechanism might change with
        probability and frequent events can exhibit more variability than rarer events. While there
        are good meteorological reasons for very rare events to exhibit less variability then
        frequent events (need reference) the causes are probably more complex than a single reason
        and somewhat region specific. Testing carried out as part of the ARR Revision Project 3 –
        Temporal Patterns of Rainfall has shown that in some locations that upscaling can be a
        significant issue <citation>b2_c5_r41</citation> while in other locations results were
        insensitive. In nearly all testing locations results were relatively insensitive to down
        scaling of patterns.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Dealing with Inconsistencies and Smoothing of Results</title>
      <para>Testing has demonstrated that inconsistent results can sometimes occur with AEP when the
        bin patterns are drawn from changes particularly between the frequent and intermediate bins.
        The problem was more pronounced in drier regions where a large part of the rainfall was
        taken up by losses. In some cases, flood magnitude decreased for rarer AEPs while in others
        the change with AEP was very stepped. On some catchments, the critical duration varied
        inconsistently with AEP. Where problems are mainly caused by the pattern bin changing two
        simple options are suggested, either: <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Draw from both bins at the boundary effectively doubling the ensemble size which
              effectively smooths the results; or</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Replacing the frequent probability bin with the intermediate bin to ensure a
              smooth catchment response with rainfall.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>
      <para>Consideration should be given to filtering out (or excluding) embedded bursts of lower
        AEP by re-distributing rainfalls of high intensity to other time increments proportionally
        to their magnitude (eg. <citation>b8_c_r18+1</citation>). In some situations results will
        still need to be smoothed.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Practical Issues</title>
      <para>If modelling events greater than 5 day, the practitioner should look at the daily
        rainfall gauge totals for gauges within the catchment and confirm what the 7 day events look
        like in the catchment compared to the regional patterns. </para>
      <para>If 10 temporal patterns are not available for a given region, duration and frequency bin
        then patterns were taken from other similar regions (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_fjeh2"/>). For
        7 day events there was not enough patterns and all regions were pooled. Local knowledge can
        be used to add events to the ensemble that weren’t selected in the regional sample.</para>
      <table frame="void" xml:id="b2_ch5_t_fjeh2">
        <caption>Alternate Regions Used for Data</caption>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Region</th>
            <th>Alternate Region</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern Slopes (Tasmania)</td>
            <td>Southern Slopes (mainland), Murray Basin</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern Slopes (mainland)</td>
            <td>Murray Basin, Southern Slopes (Tasmania), Central Slopes, East Coast South</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Murray Basin</td>
            <td>Central Slopes, Southern Slopes (mainland), Flatlands East, East Coast South</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Central Slopes</td>
            <td>Murray Basin, East Coast South, East Coast North, Southern Slopes (mainland)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>East Coast South</td>
            <td>East Coast North, Central Slopes, Murray Basin, Southern Slopes (mainland)</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>East Coast North</td>
            <td>East Coast South, Wet Tropics, Central Slopes, Murray Basin</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Wet Tropics</td>
            <td>Monsoonal North, East Coast North</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Monsoonal North</td>
            <td>Wet Tropics, East Coast North, Rangelands West</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Rangelands West</td>
            <td>Rangelands, Flatlands West </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Rangelands</td>
            <td>Flatlands West, Flatlands East, Flatlands West</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Flatlands West </td>
            <td>Flatlands East, Rangelands West</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Flatlands East </td>
            <td>Flatlands West, Flatlands West, Rangelands</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Point and Areal Temporal Pattern Meta-Data</title>
      <para>Meta-data is provided (accessed via <link xlink:href="data.arr.org.au"
          >data.arr.org.au</link>) which describes where the regional point and areal temporal
        patterns were originally located and when they occurred. This includes: </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Event ID</emphasis> - Unique ID given to each pattern;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Region</emphasis> - The region in which the pattern applies;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Region (Source)</emphasis> - The region the temporal pattern occurred
            in;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Burst Loading</emphasis> - Classified events as front, middle or back (see
              <xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_09"/>);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <?oxy_comment_start author="testoni" timestamp="20160704T185152+1000" comment="CHECK THIS!!"?>
          <para><emphasis>Burst Loading (%)</emphasis> - The percentage of the event that falls into
            the loading category;</para>
          <?oxy_comment_end?>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Burst Depth</emphasis> - Source temporal pattern burst depth. This is the
            total depth the original pattern had, patterns are given in percentages and not original
            depths;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>AEP (source)</emphasis> - The source temporal pattern AEP at the location
            it was recorded. This AEP is based of the 2016 IFDs and the burst depth of the
            event;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Burst Start </emphasis>- The time and date at which the burst
            began;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Burst End</emphasis> - The time and date at which the burst ended;
            and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Pluviograph number</emphasis> - The ID of the pluviograph as from the
            Bureau of Meteorology. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>There will be events that weren’t picked up in the regional sample however, local
        experience will allow them to be used in the ensemble (note when doing this the front,
        middle and back loading of the regional needs to be considered).</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Very Rare Point Temporal Patterns</title>
      <para>For point temporal patterns 4 bins are provided (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_11"/>). The
        very rare bin contains the rarest ten patterns within the region. These patterns may not
        feature in the rare bin for the region as the rare bin is sampled randomly. </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Region Considerations</title>
      <para>The regional point temporal patterns have been sourced from various locations throughout
        the region and due to IFD gradients within the regions embedded bursts may occur. Depending
        on the severity of the embedded burst, filtering of rarer bursts is recommended. When minor
        embedded bursts occur in only a few of the 10 patterns in the ensemble filtering can be
        neglected. Testing has shown with the 2013 Intensity Frequency Duration data that there are
        some locations where all observed temporal patterns would have embedded bursts.</para>
      <para>Locations close to region boundaries might experience storm mechanisms represented by
        both regions. In these cases it is recommended to run a larger ensemble of all patterns, ie.
        All 10 patterns from each neighboring region.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Pre-burst</title>
      <para>The treatment is dependent on the approach taken to model losses and the magnitude of
        the pre-burst. In most cases practitioners will use just the median pre-burst and median
        storm initial loss. However, in some cases the practitioner may sample from distributions of
        pre-burst and initial loss. As pre-burst varies with location, duration and probability the
        adopted approach will vary, but it is probably sensible to adopt a consistent approach
        across durations and probabilities being assessed. </para>
      <para>In locations and for durations that do not have significant pre-burst (<xref
          linkend="b2_ch5_f_09"/>), the pre-burst depth can be ignored when applying a temporal
        pattern. Therefore the Burst IL (IL<subscript>b</subscript>) can be taken as the Storm IL
          (IL<subscript>s</subscript>). In those locations where the pre-burst is significant a
        number of approaches are possible:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Storm IL is greater than Pre-burst</emphasis> – Pre-burst
            should be taken out of the storm IL</para>
          <para>ie. IL<subscript>s</subscript> – Pre-burst = IL<subscript>b</subscript>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Storm IL is approximately equal to Pre-burst</emphasis> – In
            the case where storm IL and pre-burst are close to equal IL is satisfied and no IL needs
            to be taken from the burst temporal pattern;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="italic">Pre-burst is greater than storm IL</emphasis> - In the case
            where pre-burst is larger than the storm IL there are a number of options:</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Apply a pre-burst temporal pattern after taking out the Storm IL. There is
                little research that has investigated pre-burst temporal patterns; </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Test the sensitivity of pre-burst on the resultant flood estimate and determine
                if it can be ignored;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Apply a complete storm approach instead of a burst approach eg.
                  <citation>b2_c5_r40+1</citation>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_j4892">
    <title>Example</title>
    <para>The Tennant Creek Catchment is located in the Northern Territory and was used for the ARR
      research Projects 3 and 6. The catchment and catchment location is shown in <xref
        linkend="b2_ch5_f_j3en9"/>. It is located in the Rangeland Region for temporal patterns. The
      temporal pattern data for the region can be extracted at data.arr.org.au. In this particular
      example a RORB model was set up for the catchment. The model was previously calibrated with an
        IL<subscript>b</subscript>=0 and a CL=7 mm/hr. As the catchment area is 72.3
        km<superscript>2</superscript> it was decided that the critical duration would be between 60
      minutes and 1440 minutes (1 day). </para>
    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_j3en9">
      <title>Tennant Creek Catchment</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2086.PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>For this example only the 1% AEP patterns were run through the hydrologic model. 10
      patterns from the rare AEP bin and the Rangelands region were run for each of the following
      durations:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>60 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>120 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>180 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>270 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>360 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>540 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>720 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>1080 minute</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>1440 minute</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_9k53d"/> is a presentation of the results in a box plot. The
      results are also presented in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_jeb39"/>, it should be noted that even
      though the columns are labelled bursts 1 to 10 they are not the same storms across the
      durations. The box plot presents clearly that the 180 minute duration is critical. The average
      peak flow of the 180 minute duration bursts (277.35 m<superscript>3</superscript>/s) should
      then be taken as the 1% AEP flow. If a practitioner wanted to run a pattern through a
      hydraulic model and it was not practical to run all 10 patterns, the pattern closest to the
      average (shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_jeb39"/>) is Burst number 1.</para>
    <figure  xml:id="b2_ch5_f_9k53d">
      <title>Duration Box plot for the 1% AEP</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2084.PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <table frame="void" width="720" xml:id="b2_ch5_t_jeb39">
      <caption>Flows for the 1% Annual Exceedance Probability for Ten Burst Events</caption>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <col width="7%"/>
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th rowspan="2">Duration</th>
          <th colspan="12">1% AEP Peak Flow (m<superscript>3</superscript>/s)</th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>Burst 1</td>
          <td>Burst 2</td>
          <td>Burst 3</td>
          <td>Burst 4</td>
          <td>Burst 5</td>
          <td>Burst 6</td>
          <td>Burst 7</td>
          <td>Burst 8</td>
          <td>Burst 9</td>
          <td>Burst 10</td>
          <td>Average</td>
          <td>Median</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>60</td>
          <td>146.9</td>
          <td>173.8</td>
          <td>179.6</td>
          <td>145.7</td>
          <td>157.2</td>
          <td>159.6</td>
          <td>169.4</td>
          <td>141.6</td>
          <td>148.8</td>
          <td>150.2</td>
          <td>157.28</td>
          <td>153.7</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>120</td>
          <td>221.5</td>
          <td>230.2</td>
          <td>261.9</td>
          <td>238.1</td>
          <td>260.3</td>
          <td>259.5</td>
          <td>233</td>
          <td>240.2</td>
          <td>244.9</td>
          <td>262.6</td>
          <td>245.22</td>
          <td>242.55</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>180</td>
          <td>279.4</td>
          <td>264.8</td>
          <td>279.6</td>
          <td>274.4</td>
          <td>263.5</td>
          <td>273.5</td>
          <td>264.1</td>
          <td>272.8</td>
          <td>273.1</td>
          <td>268.3</td>
          <td>277.35</td>
          <td>273.95</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>270</td>
          <td>262.5</td>
          <td>241.1</td>
          <td>284.1</td>
          <td>288.5</td>
          <td>306.6</td>
          <td>264.7</td>
          <td>266.8</td>
          <td>261.2</td>
          <td>287.8</td>
          <td>254.4</td>
          <td>271.77</td>
          <td>265.75</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>360</td>
          <td>255.5</td>
          <td>285.5</td>
          <td>214.4</td>
          <td>243.9</td>
          <td>199.7</td>
          <td>223.2</td>
          <td>246.3</td>
          <td>246.3</td>
          <td>269.8</td>
          <td>283.9</td>
          <td>246.85</td>
          <td>246.3</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>540</td>
          <td>230.9</td>
          <td>163.1</td>
          <td>168.7</td>
          <td>195.4</td>
          <td>254.7</td>
          <td>203.2</td>
          <td>236.6</td>
          <td>235.6</td>
          <td>177.5</td>
          <td>259.7</td>
          <td>212.54</td>
          <td>217.05</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>720</td>
          <td>193.7</td>
          <td>173.5</td>
          <td>188.1</td>
          <td>143.8</td>
          <td>254.9</td>
          <td>243.6</td>
          <td>195.2</td>
          <td>210.3</td>
          <td>172.3</td>
          <td>224.2</td>
          <td>199.96</td>
          <td>194.45</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>1080</td>
          <td>197.7</td>
          <td>159.2</td>
          <td>103.8</td>
          <td>239</td>
          <td>179.1</td>
          <td>151.3</td>
          <td>191.2</td>
          <td>160.5</td>
          <td>148.1</td>
          <td>151.5</td>
          <td>168.14</td>
          <td>159.85</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>1440</td>
          <td>177.9</td>
          <td>113.5</td>
          <td>144</td>
          <td>108.8</td>
          <td>222.5</td>
          <td>103.4</td>
          <td>173.2</td>
          <td>156.9</td>
          <td>272</td>
          <td>130.5</td>
          <td>160.27</td>
          <td>150.45</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  
  </section>

  <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
    <xi:fallback>
      <para>No included references yet...</para>
    </xi:fallback>
  </xi:include>
</chapter>
