<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="In Preparation" xml:id="b2_ch5"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Temporal Patterns</title>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/babister_mark.xml"/>

    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/retallick_monique.xml"/>
  </info>

  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Book</td>

      <td>2</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Chapter</td>

      <td>4</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Date</td>

      <td>27/11/2015</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Graphs and Figures</td>

      <td>Working draft</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>Examples</td>

      <td>In preparation</td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>General</td>

      <td>IFD subject to change</td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_01">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Nearly every hydrograph estimation method used for flood estimation
    needs a temporal pattern that describes how rainfall falls over time as a
    design input. Traditionally a single burst temporal pattern has been used
    for each rainfall event duration. The use of a single pattern has been
    questioned for some time (Nathan and Weinmann, 1995) as the analysis of
    observed events from even a single pluviograph shows that a wide variety
    of patterns is possible.</para>

    <para>The importance of temporal patterns has increased as the practice of
    flood estimation have evolved from peak flow estimation to full hydrograph
    estimation. There has been a strong move toward storage-based mitigation
    solutions in urban catchments which need realistic temporal patterns that
    reproduce total storm volumes as well as the temporal distribution within
    the event.</para>

    <para>This chapter is structured as follows:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Section 2 – discusses fundamental temporal pattern concepts and
        how the concept using ensembles of temporal pattern developed</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Section 3 – discusses the storm database that was used to
        develop temporal patterns</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Section 4 – describes the estimation of pre burst
        rainfall</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Section 5 – describes the development of ensembles of design
        temporal patterns</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Section 6 – discusses areal temporal patterns</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Section 6 – discusses possible effects of climate change on
        temporal patterns</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Section 7 – discusses the application of design temporal
        patterns</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Section 8 – demonstrate the application of temporal
        pattern</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_02">
    <title>Temporal pattern concepts</title>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_03">
      <title>Storm Components</title>

      <para>To properly understand the temporal patterns it is necessary to understand the
        components of a storm event and how they relate to Intensity Frequency Duration Data (IFD)
        and catchment response. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_01"/> shows a typical storm pattern and how
        components of the storm can be characterised. It is important to note the components can be
        characterised either by IFD relationships or by catchment response and are highly dependent
        on the definitions used. The components of a storm include:</para>

      <para>- <emphasis role="italic">antecedent rainfall</emphasis> - that
      has fallen before the storm event and is not considered part of the
      storm but can affect catchment response. This is not considered in this
      chapter but is introduced for completeness.</para>

      <para>- <emphasis role="italic">pre-burst rainfall - </emphasis>is storm
      rainfall that occurs before the main burst. Except for relatively
      frequent events, it generally does not have a significant influence on
      catchment response but is very important for understanding catchment and
      storage conditions before the main rainfall burst.</para>

      <para>- <emphasis role="italic">the burst - </emphasis>represents the
      main part of the storm but is very dependent on the definition used.
      Bursts have typically been characterised by duration. The burst could be
      defined as the <emphasis role="italic">critical rainfall burst,
      </emphasis>the rainfall period within the storm that has the lowest
      probability, or <emphasis role="italic">the critical response
      burst</emphasis> that corresponds to the duration which produces the
      largest catchment response for a given rainfall AEP.</para>

      <para>- <emphasis role="italic">post-burst rainfall</emphasis> - is
      rainfall that occurs after the burst and is generally only considered
      when aspects of hydrograph recession are important. This could be for
      drawing down a dam after a flood or understanding how inundation times
      affect flood recovery, road closures or agricultural land.</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_01">
        <title>Typical Storm Components</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2070.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>If the critical response burst is not the same as the critical
      rainfall burst then the critical response burst is either:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>part of a longer critical rainfall burst or</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>a storm that contains rarer shorter duration bursts.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Rarer shorter duration bursts within a burst are typically called
      embedded bursts and can cause modelling problems as, while the intention
      may be to assess the catchment response to a burst of a defined duration
      and probability, the response to a rarer shorter duration burst is also
      being assessed.</para>

      <para>The distinction between a burst and a complete storm is important
      as complete storms are used for calibration and bursts are typically
      used for design. Though this difference is less important for catchments
      with long duration responses, as the bursts typically represent nearly
      the whole storm event.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_04">
      <title>Pattern Variability</title>

      <para>It has been well recognized that temporal patterns exhibit
      significant variability between rainfall events of similar magnitude,
      and the adopted pattern can have a significant effect on the estimated
      peak flow. Askew (1975), Milston (1979), Brown (1982), Wood and Alvarez
      (1982), Cordery et al. (1984) give examples of differences of up to 50%
      in flood peaks resulting from different assumed temporal patterns. Ball
      (1994) discusses how catchment peak flow tends to increase as the
      variability of the pattern increases.</para>

      <para>Pilgrim et al. (1969) describe the variability of patterns:</para>

      <para><quote>In nature, a wide range of patterns is possible. Some
      storms have their period of peak intensity occur early, while other
      storms have the peak rainfall intensity occur towards the end of the
      storm period and a large number have a tendency for the peak to occur
      more or less centrally.</quote></para>

      <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_02"/> shows two very different storms from a location at Sydney
        Observatory Hill that have similar IFD characteristics from 15 min to 12 hrs and a 2hr
        critical rainfall burst, however on other criteria they are very different. The first
        pattern has 182 mm before the 2 hr burst, while the second pattern has 16 mm. <xref
          linkend="b2_ch5_f_03"/> presents the temporal patterns (as dimensionless mass curves) of
        ten 2 hr bursts of similar probability that show the variability described by Pilgrim et al.
        (1969).</para>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_02">
        <title>Two different storm events with similar IFD Characteristics
        (Sydney Observatory Hill) – 2 hyetographs plus burst probability
        graph</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2071.PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_03">
        <title>Ten 2 hr dimensionless mass curves</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2072.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Most of the historical work on temporal patterns has assumed that
      the central tendency of the pattern is more important than the
      variability, with the aim of producing a typical, representative or
      median pattern. French (1986) describes how a pattern can be considered
      a two-dimensional quantity with most methods breaking the pattern into
      two manageable one-dimensional quantities that describe the magnitude of
      the element and the order of the elements. This can be described as a
      rank order vector and a decay curve that describes how the magnitude
      decreases between ranks.</para>

      <para>Monte Carlo and ensemble modelling techniques try to overcome the
      problems associated with this simplification by using an ensemble of
      patterns. A short history of temporal patterns helps explain that, while
      the complexity of temporal patterns has been well understood for a long
      time, it has been difficult to produce a simple set of design
      patterns.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_05">
      <title>History of design temporal pattern development</title>

      <para>ARR 1977 (Pattison (Ed), 1977) notes that there has historically
      been a slow change in the application of temporal distributions of
      rainfall in hydrologic studies from more arbitrary approaches to
      approaches that reproduce the IFD characteristics (Keifer and Chu (1957)
      and Huff (1967)). The modern interpretation is the duration independent
      storm (Morris, 1996). These approaches reproduce the IFD loading and at
      best can reproduce aspects of a single storm. Such approaches have some
      applicability for peak flow estimation but cannot reproduce realistic
      hydrographs.</para>

      <para>Other early approaches included in the development of patterns
      based on observed pluviograph records were for complete storms rather
      than bursts. Such approaches require the scaling of complete storms.
      Other methods have allowed the arbitrary rearrangement of patterns to
      maximise peak discharge. Such approaches are very far removed from
      concept of probability neutrality.</para>

      <para>The development of the Average Variability Method by Pilgrim et
      al. (1969) and Pilgrim and Cordery (1975) analysed the variability of
      patterns by separating the analysis of the magnitude or the ranks from
      the analysis of rank order. This approach is only applicable to bursts
      and was applied in ARR 1977 and in a very detailed way in ARR 1987. A
      variation of this approach was developed by Hall and Kneen (1973).
      During the finalisation of ARR 1987 some problems where found with the
      use of the patterns and extensive testing was carried out which resulted
      in some changes to remove some embedded bursts, including some arbitrary
      rank order changes. It has been assumed that an AVM pattern would
      preserve probability neutrality. Single burst per duration AVM patterns
      have been extensively used since ARR 1987 and appear to have performed
      reasonable well for peak flow estimation. The issues that have arisen
      have been discussed in Retallick et al (2009):</para>

      <para>· Specific durations tend to dominate;</para>

      <para>· Big changes in pattern and corresponding peak flow occur at some
      region boundaries;</para>

      <para>· The burst-only approach has made conversion of observed losses
      to burst losses difficult;</para>

      <para>· The design patterns often contain significant embedded bursts;
      and</para>

      <para>· Filtering to remove embedded bursts that was recommended has had
      a mixed uptake and sometimes produces unrealistically long critical
      durations.</para>

      <para>The complexity of producing a representative or median pattern has
      led many practitioners to question the concept and ask whether it is
      better to specifically account for this variability by modelling an
      ensemble of patterns.</para>

      <para>The problems with the AVM method and other median or reprehensive
      patterns is that it assumes the variability of actual patterns is much
      less important than their central tendency. Such an approach does not
      account for how patterns interact with catchments to produce peak flows
      and hydrographs. The response can be very catchment specific, and there
      is no guarantee that a representative pattern will produce the medium
      response from an ensemble of patterns that properly captures the
      variability of observed patterns. These problems can become more
      pronounced when changes are made to the catchment response or storage
      characteristics. Phillips and Yu (2015) examined the impact of storage
      on an ensemble of events for at the lot, neighbourhood and sub-catchment
      scale.</para>

      <para>It is unclear who first proposed the concept of running an
      ensemble of patterns to account for the variability of patterns.
      Practitioners have a long history of comparing the peak flow estimates
      from design patterns to estimates from patterns extracted from storms
      that occurred on that catchment. The development of Monte Carlo methods
      (Hoang et al, 1999, Rahman 2001, Weinmann 2000) that stochastically
      sample from observed events based on complete storms and embedded bursts
      of maximum intensity (“storm cores”) is well documented and has helped
      highlight the value of using ensembles. Others, such as Nathan et al
      (2002, 2003) have used ensembles of storm bursts based on observed point
      and areal storms to facilitate their use directly with design IFD
      information. The development of the BoM significant storm database
      (Meighen, J. and M.R. Kennedy 1995) enabled practitioners to easily test
      ensembles of areal patterns and how they affected other flood
      characteristics; examples include Webb McKeown and Associates (2003).
      While there is a long history of testing ensembles of temporal patterns,
      Sih et al. (2008) is the first example of detailed test of ensemble
      patterns as a design input outside a Monte Carlo environment. This long
      development history of ensemble simulation can probably be explained by
      the fact that the concept could not be confirmed until rigorous Monte
      Carlo techniques became available for validation.</para>

      <para>Parallel to the development of ensemble and Monte Carlo
      approaches, practitioners have become concerned about using burst
      patterns where complete storm volume is important. Rigby and Bannigan
      (1996) suggest the whole burst approach needed to be reviewed and design
      storms needed to replace design bursts. For the Wollongong area they
      demonstrated that historically most short duration events were embedded
      in longer events. They recommended that short duration events could be
      embedded in a 24 hour event of the same probability. They particularly
      cautioned against using bursts on catchments with significant natural or
      man-made storages. Phillips et al. (1994) had found similar problems in
      the upper Parramatta River and suggested embedded storms were more
      realistic, and that basin storages would be under estimated with a burst
      approach unless the embedded nature of events was factored into the
      starting volumes. Rigby et al. (2003) extended their earlier work to
      include guidance on using the embedded design storms. Roso and Rigby
      (2006) recommended a storm based approach be used when there are
      significant storages or diversions present in the catchment. Kuczera et
      al. (2003), inspired by Rigby and Bannigan (1996), explored basin
      performance using a theoretical catchment at Observatory Hill Sydney in
      a continuous simulation approach and found similar problems with peak
      flow being underestimated by a similar amount when storages were
      present. All of these studies were based on catchments less than 110 km<superscript>2</superscript>
      that are close to Sydney.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_06">
    <title> Storm database</title>

    <para>As part of the IFD revision (<xref linkend="b2_ch3"/>) the BoM produced a quality
      controlled pluviograph database, containing 2280 stations with more than 8 station years. The
      average station record length is 25 years, with a combined record length of 57,000 years. A
      total of 754 of the stations are owned by the BoM and the other 1526 are owned by other data
      agencies throughout Australia. This data was provided by the BoM, who undertook quality
      controlling to identify suspect data, such as missing data, accumulated totals and time shifts
      (Green et al. 2011). All station data was provided as time series data sampled at a 5 minute
      time step. In addition to the rainfall depths, each data point had a quality code indicating
      the quality of the data. <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_04"/> below depicts the geographical
      distribution of the pluviographs across Australia. Each station is represented as a circle,
      with the size of the circle indicating the record length of the station.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_04">
      <title>Pluviograph stations record lengths</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2073.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_00"/> shows the maximum number stations available in any year for
      decadal periods. This Table demonstrates that most of the pluviograph record is from 1960
      onwards. Though overall the data comes from a period that starts before 1900, over half of the
      data is from the period from 1993 onwards.</para>

   
    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_00" frame="void">
        <caption>Number of Pluviographs by Decade</caption>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <col width="50%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Decade</th>
            <th>Maximum Number of Pluviographs in any year</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;1900</td>
            <td>2</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1900-1940</td>
            <td>24</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1940-1960</td>
            <td>154</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1960-1970</td>
            <td>392</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1970-1980</td>
            <td>923</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1980-1990</td>
            <td>1273</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1990 -2000</td>
            <td>1926</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2000-2010</td>
            <td>1837(1)</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Not all data was available from 2009 onwards</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>As shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_04"/> the highest density of pluviograph stations is
      typically found along coastal areas of Australia around key population centres. In <xref
        linkend="b2_ch5_f_05"/>, the pluviograph stations are seen to be clustered around urban
      areas, such as Sydney, Wollongong, Melbourne and Canberra. Less data is available in in
      central Australia, with the exception of the Alice Springs area. Large areas of central
      Western Australia contain no data.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_05">
      <title>Pluviograph stations used throughout south eastern Australia with
      record lengths indicated</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2074.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_07">
      <title>Data Quality</title>

      <para>Where a single station is being analysed it is important that it
      has a reasonably long record (preferably longer than 30 years) and only
      a small percentage of missing data. However, for studies that pool data
      together the quality of the data is a bigger issue than record length.
      It is however, important to remember that most of the pluviograph data
      is from the last few decades.</para>

      <para>The pluviograph database contains a significant number of events
      with long periods of apparently uniform rainfall. While some of this
      could be from events with relatively uniform rainfall, most appears to
      be the result of disaggregating accumulated rainfall totals uniformly.
      Even if rainfall is uniform, a tipping bucket rain gauge recording at 5
      minutes will only record uniform rainfall over an extended period if the
      depth in each five minute period is equal or slightly larger than an
      integer multiple of the tipping bucket capacity. It was concluded that
      most of the periods of uniform rainfall are probably caused by
      digitisation and resampling at different time steps. Events with large
      periods of uniform rainfall were disregarded, while events were kept if
      the uniform period was only a small portion of the entire event.</para>

      <para>In addition, several other issues with the data quality were
      found. Some records contained significant periods of missing data. There
      were also periods of interpolated data, where several data points were
      indicated as interpolated from a later point, presumably at the end of
      an event. Events where a significant part of the rainfall was
      interpolated were excluded from further analysis. There were also
      sections where the rainfall was uniform over many intervals within an
      event, indicating that the data points were interpolated, even though
      the quality control value did not specify that to be the case. Since
      storms generally do not have uniform rainfall at the local scale, events
      that had a significant part of their total rainfall depth occurring in
      consecutive identical intervals were also excluded.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_08">
      <title>Event selection and analysis</title>

      <para>Once the data quality checking was complete, all events with a
      burst greater than 1 Exceedance per Year (EY) using the 2013 IFD and
      which were not flagged with problems were extracted for further
      analysis. For each event the start and finish of the event was defined
      using method described in ARR Revision Project 3-Temporal Patterns of
      Rainfall Report Part 1 (WMAwater, 2015), which was consistent with the
      storm event definition used in the losses report (Hill et al, 2014).
      Once all events with a burst greater than 1EY were defined for every
      duration, the following properties where calculated:</para>

      <para>-burst rainfall depth probabilities for each duration;</para>

      <para>- start and finish time for each burst;</para>

      <para>- time when 50% of the burst depth occurred (burst
      loading);</para>

      <para>- pre-burst rainfall depth for each burst duration;</para>

      <para>- pre-burst to burst rainfall ratio for each duration; and</para>

      <para>- Post-burst depth.</para>

      <para>For each event the rarest or critical rainfall burst (of any
      duration and location within the overall event) was also
      calculated.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_09">
      <title>Regional characteristics</title>

      <para>To assess the regional characteristics, 12 temporal pattern regions were defined based
        on the 54 Natural Resource Management (NRM) sub-regions used for investigating the impacts
        of climate change (CSIRO, 2015). The adopted regions follow drainage basin boundaries. <xref
          linkend="b2_ch5_f_001"/> depicts the adopted temporal pattern regions. <xref
          linkend="b2_ch5_t_001"/> summarises how many gauges and storm events exist in each
        region.</para>
      <table  xml:id="b2_ch5_t_001" frame="void">
        <caption>Regions- Number of Gauges and Events</caption>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <col width="20%"/>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th>Region</th>
            <th>Number of Gauges</th>
            <th>Number of Station Years</th>
            <th>Number of Events</th>
            <th>Average Number of Events per Station Year</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern Slopes (Tasmania)</td>
            <td>110</td>
            <td>2954</td>
            <td>3477</td>
            <td>1.18</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern Slopes (mainland)</td>
            <td>356</td>
            <td>8536</td>
            <td>20581</td>
            <td>2.41</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Murray Basin</td>
            <td>233</td>
            <td>6316</td>
            <td>18399</td>
            <td>2.91</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Central Slopes</td>
            <td>118</td>
            <td>2767</td>
            <td>7167</td>
            <td>2.59</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>East Coast South</td>
            <td>331</td>
            <td>8067</td>
            <td>19856</td>
            <td>2.46</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>East Coast North</td>
            <td>210</td>
            <td>5187</td>
            <td>12123</td>
            <td>2.34</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Wet Tropics</td>
            <td>99</td>
            <td>2474</td>
            <td>5437</td>
            <td>2.20</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Monsoonal North</td>
            <td>211</td>
            <td>5054</td>
            <td>12287</td>
            <td>2.43</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Rangelands West</td>
            <td>93</td>
            <td>2334</td>
            <td>5391</td>
            <td>2.31</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Rangelands</td>
            <td>226</td>
            <td>5561</td>
            <td>12618</td>
            <td>2.27</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern and South Western Flatlands (West)</td>
            <td>349</td>
            <td>9113</td>
            <td>26402</td>
            <td>2.90</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Southern and South Western Flatlands (East)</td>
            <td>56</td>
            <td>1401</td>
            <td>3450</td>
            <td>2.46</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_001">
        <title>Temporal Pattern Regions</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2075.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The term ‘burst loading’ refers to the distribution of rainfall
      within a burst and is a defining characteristic of a rainfall event. For
      each event the burst loading was calculated as the percentage of the
      time taken for 50% of the burst depth to occur. The burst loading can be
      used as a simple measure of when the heaviest part of the burst occurs
      and can be used to categorise events as ‘front’, ‘middle’ or ‘back’
      loaded. Events where categorised into three groups, depending on where
      50% of the burst rainfall occurs:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>front loaded – 0-40% of the time,</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>middle loaded – 40-60% of the time, and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>back loaded – 60-100% of the time.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Figure 8 shows a typical event from each category.</para>

      <para><figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_06">
          <title> Example of Front, Middle and Back Loaded Events</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2076.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure></para>

      <para>This simple categorisation provides a pragmatic means of capturing
      when the peak loading occurs, as described by Pilgrim et al (1969),
      though it is worth recognising that for a double-peaked event, when most
      of the rainfall is in the early and later part of the burst, the loading
      can somewhat illogically fall into the middle category.</para>

      <para>Each region was characterised by its burst loading distribution, which describes the
        percentage of front, middle and back loaded events for different durations. The proportion
        of front/middle/back loading for each region was determined for less than and greater than 6
        hours duration (<xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_01"/>). The proportion was assumed to be constant
        across all AEPs.</para>



      <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_01">
        <title>Burst loading by region and duration</title>
        <tgroup cols="5">
          <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>

          <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>

          <colspec colname="col3" colnum="3"/>

          <colspec colname="col4" colnum="4"/>

          <colspec colname="col5" colnum="5"/>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry><emphasis role="bold">Region</emphasis></entry>

              <entry><emphasis role="bold">Duration</emphasis></entry>

              <entry><emphasis role="bold">Front Loaded (%)</emphasis></entry>

              <entry><emphasis role="bold">Middle Loaded
              (%)</emphasis></entry>

              <entry><emphasis role="bold">Back Loaded (%)</emphasis></entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Southern Slopes (Tasmania)</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>21.5</entry>

              <entry>64.1</entry>

              <entry>14.4</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>20.5</entry>

              <entry>60.0</entry>

              <entry>19.5</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Southern Slopes (mainland)</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>30.1</entry>

              <entry>53.0</entry>

              <entry>16.9</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>22.7</entry>

              <entry>53.7</entry>

              <entry>23.6</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Murray Basin</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>28.3</entry>

              <entry>53.8</entry>

              <entry>17.9</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>24.7</entry>

              <entry>52.5</entry>

              <entry>22.7</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Central Slopes</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>31.0</entry>

              <entry>53.3</entry>

              <entry>15.7</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>27.0</entry>

              <entry>46.9</entry>

              <entry>26.1</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">East Coast South</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>26.5</entry>

              <entry>57.1</entry>

              <entry>16.4</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>17.1</entry>

              <entry>58.6</entry>

              <entry>24.3</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">East Coast North</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>28.9</entry>

              <entry>56.5</entry>

              <entry>14.6</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>23.4</entry>

              <entry>48.5</entry>

              <entry>28.1</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Wet Tropics</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>16.0</entry>

              <entry>71.8</entry>

              <entry>12.2</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>18.7</entry>

              <entry>58.1</entry>

              <entry>23.2</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Monsoonal North</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>27.6</entry>

              <entry>63.7</entry>

              <entry>8.8</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>27.5</entry>

              <entry>41.4</entry>

              <entry>31.2</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Rangelands West</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>23.7</entry>

              <entry>62.5</entry>

              <entry>13.8</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>23.6</entry>

              <entry>49.2</entry>

              <entry>27.2</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Rangelands</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>29.0</entry>

              <entry>56.6</entry>

              <entry>14.3</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>24.4</entry>

              <entry>49.2</entry>

              <entry>26.4</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Southern and South Western Flatlands
              (West)</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>30.8</entry>

              <entry>49.3</entry>

              <entry>19.9</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>31.4</entry>

              <entry>48.9</entry>

              <entry>19.7</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry morerows="1">Southern and South Western Flatlands
              (East)</entry>

              <entry>≤ 6hr</entry>

              <entry>27.6</entry>

              <entry>52.4</entry>

              <entry>20.0</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>&gt; 6hr</entry>

              <entry>17.4</entry>

              <entry>54.4</entry>

              <entry>28.2</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_10">
    <title>Pre Burst Rainfall and Antecedent Conditions</title>

    <para>The events database allowed the pre-burst behaviour of rainfall
    events to be characterised, regionalised and mapped. Temporal Patterns
    report 2 (WMAwater (2015)) presents the detailed analysis, regionalisation
    and mapping of pre-burst behaviour for Australia. Due to the relatively
    short pluviograph records, the approach assumes that this behaviour can be
    pooled to develop reasonable size samples by transferring storms from
    nearby locations with similar IFD characteristics. This was done on a
    Region of Influence basis and not a fixed region basis, as the ratio of
    pre-burst rainfall has some correlation with IFD. In many parts of
    Australia the pre-burst rainfall generally represents a very small amount
    of the event and generally does not contribute to the runoff response, so
    it can be treated in a relatively simply manner. However, in some parts of
    the country pre-burst rainfall can represent a significant part of the
    rainfall event and runoff response. Pre-burst can also be important in
    urban catchments with large directly connected impervious areas (<xref
    linkend="book5"/>). Storage strategies need to account for this additional
    runoff when sizing storage tanks and basins (<xref
    linkend="book9"/>).</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_08"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_09"/> depict the median ratio of
      the pre-burst to burst and the depth of pre-burst in mm for the 6hr duration and probabilities
      mapped across Australia. The full data set of maps is available online at the ARR data
      repository.</para>

    <para><xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_10"/> shows the probability distribution of the pre-burst rainfall
      for each region.</para>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_08">
      <title>Pre-burst rainfall</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2077.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_09">
        <title>Pre-burst to burst ratio</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2078.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_10">
        <title>Standardised pre-burst to burst ratio distributions</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2079.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    <para>The manner in which pre-burst rainfall is treated depends on the
    magnitude of the pre-burst rainfall, how this compares to losses and
    whether pre-burst runoff is likely and will have a significant effect on
    hydrograph volumes. As longer duration bursts tend to represent most of
    the storm events, it is generally only an issue for smaller catchments. If
    pre-burst rainfall is unlikely to affect the runoff responses, it is best
    treated in a simple manner with losses. For simple urban cases pre-burst
    rainfall can be used to condition storage starting conditions. Where
    pre-burst is influential for flood response, it can be sampled from its
    distribution and applied with a typical pre-burst temporal pattern.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_11">
    <title>Design Temporal Patterns</title>

    <para>As part of the ARR temporal pattern Revision project (ARR Project 3, WMAwater (2015)) a
      series of temporal pattern techniques were trialled. A total of 35 test catchments were
      adopted across Australia, ranging in area from 30 to 80 km<superscript>2</superscript>. The
      aims of the testing were to assess the performance of the design method using best estimates
      of the revised inputs and to determine what influence the temporal patterns have on design
      estimates. Temporal pattern ensembles were tested within a Monte Carlo framework and a simpler
      quantile ensemble framework. Two methods were trialled, the regional temporal patterns (as
      discussed in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_s_09"/>) along with a Region-of-Influence (ROI) approach.
      Three event types were trialled with burst only, burst plus pre-burst and complete storm
      events (for ROI only). A range of initial loss approaches were trailed, including burst and
      storm losses, combined with the median value or a distribution of values. The nature of
      regional temporal pattern ensembles requires AEP bins to be derived. The ensembles for each
      AEP bin were trialled across all AEPs to assess the sensitivity of the AEP bins.</para>

    <para>Based on the results of this performance testing, the temporal
    patterns derived by the Regional burst approach are recommended for
    general use. Temporal patterns for complete storms derived by the ROI
    approach are left as an alternative for small, volume-sensitive systems
    where pre- and post-burst rainfall is important, though it may be that
    such systems are better analysed using continuous simulation
    approaches.</para>

    <para>Other major findings from ARR Project 3 were:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Irrespective of the method used to derive the temporal patterns,
        when using a representative ensemble of patterns all methods produce
        relatively similar results,</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Frequent patterns should not be used for rarer events; scaling a
        temporal pattern introduces more variability and produces higher
        design estimates.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>Ensembles of 20 temporal patterns were initially envisaged, however a large number of
      regions had insufficient data available to warrant a sample of this size. Different ensemble
      sizes were tested to determine the sensitivity to ensemble size, with little bias found
      between the ensemble sizes. Samples of 10 temporal patterns were therefore adopted as an
      appropriate compromise between pattern variability and data availability. Ensembles were
      generated for each AEP bin, duration and region. The four AEP bins adopted (see <xref
        linkend="b2_ch5_t_02"/> and <xref linkend="b2_ch5_f_11"/>) were based on the burst AEP at
      the source of the event. Temporal Pattern were extracted for the following durations from 15
      minutes to 7 days, as shown in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_03"/></para>

    

    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_02">
      <title>Regional Temporal Pattern bins</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>

        <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="bold">AEP Group</emphasis></entry>

            <entry><emphasis role="bold">AEP Range</emphasis></entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Very Rare</entry>

            <entry>Rarest 10 within region</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Rare</entry>

            <entry>Rarer than 3.2% AEP</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Intermediate</entry>

            <entry>Between 3.2% and 14.4% AEP</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Frequent</entry>

            <entry>More frequent than 14.4% AEP</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <figure xml:id="b2_ch5_f_11">
      <title>Temporal Pattern Ranges</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../../figures/2080.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

   

    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_03">
      <title>Temporal Pattern Durations</title>
      <tgroup cols="3">
        <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>

        <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>

        <colspec colname="col3" colnum="3"/>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry nameend="col3" namest="col1"><emphasis
            role="bold">Duration</emphasis></entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="italic">Minutes</emphasis></entry>

            <entry><emphasis role="italic">Hours</emphasis></entry>

            <entry><emphasis role="italic">Days</emphasis></entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>15</entry>

            <entry>0.25</entry>

            <entry>0.010</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>30</entry>

            <entry>0.5</entry>

            <entry>0.021</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>60</entry>

            <entry>1</entry>

            <entry>0.042</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>120</entry>

            <entry>2</entry>

            <entry>0.083</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>180</entry>

            <entry>3</entry>

            <entry>0.125</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>270</entry>

            <entry>4.5</entry>

            <entry>0.188</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>360</entry>

            <entry>6</entry>

            <entry>0.250</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>540</entry>

            <entry>9</entry>

            <entry>0.375</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>720</entry>

            <entry>12</entry>

            <entry>0.500</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>1080</entry>

            <entry>18</entry>

            <entry>0.750</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>1440</entry>

            <entry>24</entry>

            <entry>1</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>2160</entry>

            <entry>36</entry>

            <entry>1.5</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>2880</entry>

            <entry>48</entry>

            <entry>2</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>4320</entry>

            <entry>72</entry>

            <entry>3</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>5760</entry>

            <entry>96</entry>

            <entry>4</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>7200</entry>

            <entry>120</entry>

            <entry>5</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>8640</entry>

            <entry>144</entry>

            <entry>6</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>10080</entry>

            <entry>168</entry>

            <entry>7</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <para>When selecting a small ensemble of temporal patterns it is important
    to capture the typical variability of the observed events. A methodology
    was therefore adopted that samples from observed events with the intent of
    generating a representative ensemble in terms of the variability of actual
    events, with no obvious bias. Whilst it is difficult to quantify or verify
    the achievement of this objective, steps have been undertaken to ensure
    the samples are broadly representative, including a visual check of all
    ensembles.</para>

    <para>There are a large number of frequent events from which to select,
    however, the choice is more limited for rarer events.</para>

    <para>For each AEP and duration bin the sampling of an ensemble of 10 patterns used the
      preferred criteria in <xref linkend="b2_ch5_t_06"/>. The relaxed criteria were used where less
      than 10 suitable patterns could be found using the preferred criteria.</para>



    <table xml:id="b2_ch5_t_06">
      <title>Temporal Pattern selection criteria</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>

        <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="bold">Preferred Criteria (for data rich
            regions)</emphasis></entry>

            <entry><emphasis role="bold">Relaxed Criteria (for data sparse
            regions)</emphasis></entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>No rarer embedded bursts</entry>

            <entry>n/a</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>No events overlapping in time</entry>

            <entry>n/a</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Loading characteristics enforced</entry>

            <entry>Loading characteristics ignored</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Events from within a region</entry>

            <entry>Sampled from within region and neighbouring region with
            similar climatic characteristics</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <para>While patterns containing embedded rarer bursts at their recording
    location were not selected, events can still have embedded bursts at other
    locations within the region. The presence of major embedded bursts may
    warrant filtering of patterns.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_12">
    <title>Temporal Patterns for Areal Rainfall Bursts</title>

    <para>As part of the temporal pattern project a series of areal average
    temporal patterns have been produced for different sized hypothetical
    catchments. These patterns average the spatial variability of rainfall in
    each time step which does remove some of the variability of actual
    space-time rainfall fields.</para>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_13">
      <title>Use of Historical Temporal Patterns</title>

      <para>On a large catchment with good data it is not uncommon to have a
      reasonable number of historical patterns for events rarer than 20%
      AEP.</para>

      <para>PLACEHOLDER MORE TO COME</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_14">
      <title>Complete Storm Patterns</title>

      <para>PLACEHOLDER MORE TO COME</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_15">
    <title>Climate Change Impacts</title>

    <para>Very little information is known about how climate change will
    affect storm or burst temporal patterns. The most definitive work is by
    Wasco and Sharma (2015) which analysed the relationship between burst
    patterns from 79 Australian rain gauges and temperature variations. This
    study found that, regardless of the climate region or season, temperature
    increases are associated with patterns becoming less uniform, with the
    largest fractions increasing in rainfall intensity and the lower fraction
    decreasing. The scaling of the largest fractions was more pronounced in
    short duration bursts, and gauges to the north of the country showed more
    pronounced changes. While this work is based on the present climate, it
    provides an insight into how patterns could change under a future warming.
    Such climate changes would also affect IFD characteristics.</para>

    <para>Westra et al (2013) proposed rainfall sequences for future climates
    could be constructed by sampling historical rainfall patterns
    corresponding to warmer days at the same location, or from locations which
    have an atmospheric profile more reflective of expected future climate.
    Such an approach could conceptually be applied in the selection of design
    burst patterns but would require significant testing.</para>

    <para>It is currently not possible to provide practical advice to
    practitioners on this aspect of temporal patterns. It is recommended that
    until further studies are completed, for simulations applying projected
    climate change, the temporal patterns applied should those derived for
    existing climatic conditions but recognising the additional uncertainty in
    simulation results.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_16">
    <title>Temporal Pattern Application and Pre-burst</title>

    <para>PLACEHOLDER MORE TO COME</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_17">
    <title>Examples</title>

    <para>PLACEHOLDER MORE TO COME</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b2_ch5_s_18">
    <title>References</title>

    <para>Askew, A.J. (1975). Use of Risk Premium in Chance-Constrained
    Dynamic Programming. Water Resources Research 11(6):862-866.</para>

    <para>Ball, J.E. (1994), 'The influence of storm temporal patterns on
    catchment response', Journal of Hydrology, vol. 158, no. 3-4, pp.
    285-303.</para>

    <para>Brown J.A.H. (1982), A Review of flood estimation procedures,
    Proceedings of the workshop on spillway design, Department of National
    Development and Energy, AWRC Conference Series No. 6</para>

    <para>Cordery I., Pilgrim D.H and Rowbottom I.A. (1984). Time patterns of
    rainfall for estimating design floods on a frequency basis. Wat. Sci.
    Tech., 16(8-9), 155-165</para>

    <para>CSIRO and Bureau of Meteorology 2015, Climate Change in Australia
    Information for Australia’s Natural Resource Management Regions: Technical
    Report, CSIRO and Bureau of Meteorology, Australia</para>

    <para>Green, J.H., Xuereb, K. and Siriwardena, L. (2011), Establishment of
    a Quality Controlled Rainfall Database for the Revision of the (IFD)
    Estimates for Australia, Proceedings of 34th IAHR World Congress,
    Brisbane, 26 June–1st July 2011</para>

    <para>Hall, A.J. and Kneen, T.H. (1973) Design Temporal Patterns of Storm
    Rainfall in Australia, Proc. Hydrology Symposium, Inst. Eng. Aust., pp
    77-84</para>

    <para>Hill, P.H., Graszkiewicz, Z., Taylor, M., and Nathan, R. (2014),
    Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 6: Loss Models for
    Catchment Simulation, Phase 4, October 2014, Report No. P6/S3/016B</para>

    <para>Hoang TMT, Rahman A, Weinmann PE, Laurenson E, Nathan R, Joint
    Probability description of design rainfall, Water 99 Joint congress-
    Brisbane 1999</para>

    <para>Huff, A. (1967), Time distribution in heavy storms, Water Resources
    Research, 3, 1007-1019</para>

    <para>Keifer, C. J., and H. H. Chu (1957), Synthetic storm pattern for
    drainage design, ASCE Journal of the Hydraulics Division, 83 (HY4),
    1-25.</para>

    <para>Kuczera G, Lambert M, Heneker T, Jennings S, Frost A, Coombes P,
    Joint Probability and design storms at the cross roads, (2003) Proceedings
    of the 28th International Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium,
    Wollongong, 2003</para>

    <para>Meighen, J. and Kennedy, M.R. (1995) Catalogue of Significant
    Rainfall Occurrences over Southeast Australia , HRS Report No. 3,
    Hydrology Report Series, Bureau of Meteorology, Melbourne, Australia,
    October 1995</para>

    <para>Milston, A.K. (1979), The influence of temporal patterns of design
    rainfall in peak flood discharge, Thesis (M.Eng.Sci.), University of New
    South Wales</para>

    <para>Nathan, R.J. and Weinmann, P.E. (1995): The estimation of extreme
    floods - the need and scope for revision of our national guidelines. Aus J
    Water Resources, 1(1): 40-50.</para>

    <para>Nathan, R.J., Weinmann, P.E., and Hill, P.I. (2002): Use of a
    Monte-Carlo framework to characterise hydrologic risk. Proc., ANCOLD
    conference on dams, Adelaide, 2002</para>

    <para>Nathan, R., Weinmann, E., Hill, P. (2003) Use of Monte Carlo
    Simulation to Estimate the Expected Probability of Large to Extreme
    Floods, Proc. 28th Int. Hydrology and Water Res. Symp., Wollongong, pp
    1.105-1.112.</para>

    <para>Pattison, A, (ed) 1977, Australian Rainfall and Runoff: Flood
    Analysis and Design, The Institution of Engineers Australia</para>

    <para>Phillips, BC; Lees, SJ and Lynch, SJ. Embedded Design Storms - an
    Improved Procedure for Design Flood Level Estimation?. In: Water Down
    Under 94: Surface Hydrology and Water Resources Papers; Preprints of
    Papers. Barton, ACT: Institution of Engineers, Australia, 1994: 235-240.
    National conference publication (Institution of Engineers, Australia) ;
    no. 94/15.</para>

    <para>Phillips P and Yu S, (2015), How robust are OSD and OSR Systems?,
    2015 WSUD &amp; IECA, Sydney</para>

    <para>Pilgrim D, Editor, Australian Rainfall and Runoff: A Guide to Flood
    estimation, Engineers Australia, 1987</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, D.H., Cordery, I. And French, R. (1969). Temporal patterns
    of design rainfall for Sydney, Institution of Engineers, Australia, Civil
    Eng. Trans., Vol CE11, 9-14.</para>

    <para>Pilgrim, D.H. and Cordery, I. (1975), Rainfall temporal patterns for
    design floods, Journal of the Hydraulics Division, Vol. 101, No. 1,
    January 1975, pp. 81-95</para>

    <para>Rahman, A., Weinmann, P. E., Hoang, T. M. T., &amp; Laurenson, E. M.
    (2002). Monte Carlo simulation of flood frequency curves from rainfall.
    Journal of Hydrology</para>

    <para>Retallick M, Babister M, Varga C, Ball J, Askew A (2009), Do
    Filtered patterns resemble real patterns? Proceedings of the Hydrology and
    Water Resources Symposium, Newcastle 2009, Engineers Australia,</para>

    <para>Rigby E and Bannigan D (1996) The Embedded design storm concept – A
    critical review, 23rd Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium Hobart
    1996</para>

    <para>Rigby E, Boyd M, Roso S, Van Drie R (2003), Storms, Storm bursts and
    flood estimation- A need for review of the AR&amp;R procedures,
    Proceedings of the 28th International Hydrology and Water Resources
    Symposium, Wollongong 2003</para>

    <para>Roso S and Rigby E, (2006), The impact of embedded design storms on
    flows within a catchment, Proceedings of the 30th Hydrology and Water
    Resources Symposium Launceston 2006</para>

    <para>Sih, K; Hill, P and Nathan, R. (2008), Evaluation of Simple
    Approaches to Incorporating Variability in Design Temporal Patterns . In:
    Lambert, Martin (Editor); Daniell, TM (Editor); Leonard, Michael (Editor).
    Proceedings of Water Down Under 2008. Modbury, SA: Engineers Australia;
    Causal Productions, 2008: 1049-1059.</para>

    <para>Wasco C and Sharma A (2015) Steeper temporal distribution of rain
    intensity at higher temperatures within Australian storms, Nature
    Geoscience Letter, 8 June 2015</para>

    <para>Webb McKeown and Associates, (2003), Assessment of the variability
    of rates of rise for hydrographs on the Hawkesbury Nepean River, December
    2003</para>

    <para>Weinmann P, Rahman A, Hoang T, Laurenson E, Nathan R, (2000), Monte
    Carlo Simulation of flood Frequency Curves, Proceedings of Hydro 2000, 3rd
    International hydrology and water resources symposium, Perth, Inst. Of
    Engineers Australia, pp 564-569.</para>

    <para>Westra S, Evans J, Mehrotra R, Sharma A, (2013), A conditional
    disaggregation algorithm for generating fine time-scale rainfall data in a
    warmer climate, Journal of Hydrology, 479, 86-99</para>

    <para>WMAwater, (2015) Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 3:
    Temporal Patterns of Rainfall, Part 1 – Development of an Events Database,
    Stage 3 Report, October 2015</para>

    <para>WMAwater, (2015) Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 3:
    Temporal Patterns of Rainfall, Part 2 – Analysis of Pre-burst Rainfalls,
    Stage 3 Report, October 2015</para>

    <para>WMAwater, (2015) Australian Rainfall and Runoff Revision Project 3:
    Temporal Patterns of Rainfall, Part 3 – Preliminary Testing of Temporal
    Pattern Ensembles, Stage 3 Report, October 2015</para>

    <para>Wood, J.F. and Alvarez, K. (1982), Review of Pindari Dam Design
    Inflow Flood Estimate, Proceedings of the workshop on spillway design,
    Department of National Development and Energy, AWRC Conference Series No.
    6</para>

    <para>Varga C, Ball J, Babister M, An Alternative for Developing Temporal
    Patterns, Proceedings of the Hydrology and Water Resources Symposium,
    Newcastle 2009, Engineers Australia, 2009</para>

    <para/>
  </section>
</chapter>
