<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter>
<chapter status="In Preparation" version="5.0" xml:id="b7_ch9"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
 
    <info> 
       
       <title>Application to Design</title>
       
           <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weeks_william.xml"/>
           
           <xi:include href="../../common/authors/weinmann_erwin.xml"/>
       
       </info>  
       
       <informaltable border="1">
              <tr>
                     <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                     <td>Date last updated</td>
                     <td><?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190505T153212+1000" content="06/07/16 "?><?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190505T153217+1000"?>24/4/2018
                            <?oxy_insert_end?></td>
              </tr>
              <?oxy_delete author="testoni" timestamp="20190505T153222+1000" content="&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Content&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Working drafts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;General&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Subject to industry feedback &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;"?>
       </informaltable>
       <section>
              <title>Overview</title>
              <para>Once the practitioner is satisfied with the calibration and validation, the next
                     step in the application of a catchment modelling system is to apply it to the
                     design problem. Australian Rainfall and Runoff is principally concerned with
                     design flood estimation problems where floods of defined probabilities are
                     required, but other applications are required for flood forecasting and warning
                     or for assessment of impacts. A concern is that the calibration and validation
                     processes concentrate on recorded historic flood events, whereas the design
                     applications are more theoretical probabilistic events.</para>
              <para>In the analysis of these probabilistic events, an important objective is to
                     transfer probabilistic rainfalls into probabilistic flood levels, through the
                     calculation of flood discharges. These design events are quite different from
                     the historic floods and care must be taken in transferring the catchment
                     modelling system application from the variable historic events into the design
                     results. </para>
              <para>As discussed in <xref linkend="b7_ch7"/>, the parameters selected for
                     application to the design conditions must be appropriate for the required
                     application as well as consistent with the calibration to the available
                     historic data.</para>
              <para>There are therefore three conditions where model parameters may be
                     required:</para>
              <itemizedlist>
                     <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="italic">Historic Floods </emphasis>
                            - These are the floods where the data has been used to estimate
                                   parameters and to validate the models. Where there is more than
                                   one flood event, there may be a variety of conditions
                                   represented, with different spatial and temporal rainfall
                                   distributions possible. The flood events will sample a limited
                                   range of conditions that have applied during the period when data
                                   could be collected and these may not necessarily be
                                   representative of the conditions where the model must be applied.
                                   In addition, catchment conditions may have changed since the
                                   historic flood event occurred. Historic floods may also be
                                   analysed in the “design” application of models where flood
                                   impacts may be required to assess how development would have
                                   affected a historic flood for example.</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="italic">Design Applications</emphasis>
                             - This is the main application where models discussed in
                                   Australian Rainfall and Runoff will be required and require
                                   results for floods of defined probability to be calculated. This
                                   is a more theoretical application than the analysis of historic
                                   floods and the parameters need to be established to ensure that
                                   the probability is calculated correctly. It is likely that the
                                   probabilistic floods calculated will be larger than the historic
                                   floods used to estimate the model parameters. The probabilistic
                                   design flood estimates must consider the relevant requirements.
                                   In some cases, flood peaks may be the only requirement, while
                                   flood hydrographs or flood volumes may be relevant at other
                                   times. There are different issues for each requirement.</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="italic">Real Time Flood Estimation</emphasis>
                             - This is the requirement to use the model for a flood
                                   forecasting and warning application. This is different from the
                                   design application since timing is critical and the parameters
                                   must be available to carry out the analysis as the event is
                                   occurring. This is a far more complex application than the design
                                   situation, and while similar conditions apply in model
                                   application, this chapter concentrates on the design
                                   conditions.</para>
                     </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <para> This chapter concentrates on the probabilistic applications, though there are
                     some similarities with the others.</para>
              
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Issues with Historical Calibration Floods</title>
              <section>
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                     <para>Where parameters estimated from historical events must be transferred to
                            design applications, a common concern is how representative the historic
                            events are of the design flood events that must be estimated with the
                            catchment modelling system.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Magnitude of the Calibration Events</title>
                     <para>A common issue is that the historic calibration events are relatively
                            frequent, while the design applications may be needed for floods up to
                            1% Annual Exceedance Probability or rarer. It is therefore important
                            that the model parameters selected for design application should still
                            be appropriate for analysis of the rarer flood events.</para>
                     <para> A common assumption is that the model parameters calibrated on
                            relatively frequent events remain constant for all rarer events. This
                            may or may not be correct, so this assumption should be checked with
                            regard to the representativeness of the calibration floods and with the
                            model processes and whether there is a change in response for rarer
                            flood events.</para>
                     <sidebar>
                            <para>In general constant parameters are recommended for the range of
                                   design events unless there is some evidence otherwise.</para>
                     </sidebar>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Calibration Event Conditions</title>
                     <para>The calibration events used to determine catchment modelling system
                            parameters are generally all that is available, and the practitioner
                            must apply the data from these events without the luxury of making a
                            selection of the most appropriate events.</para>
                     <para>During calibration the practitioner must carefully review the properties
                            of the historic floods used for calibration and determine how
                            appropriate these are to be applied to the design problem. For example,
                            the available calibration floods may be localised on a part of the
                            catchment while the design flood event should be a more widely
                            distributed event. On larger catchments, floods may be usually produced
                            from a part of the catchment and the actual contributing section may
                            vary from one event to another. The design case must therefore allow for
                            the different catchment properties while estimating the probabilistic
                            floods correctly. Some of these issues are discussed in <xref
                                   linkend="book4"/> but there may be an impact on the transfer of
                            the model parameters from the historic calibration events to the design
                            flood events.</para>
                     <para>The calibrated parameters are for the situation/time when the calibration
                            event occurred. However, there may be significant changes from one event
                            to another. For example, in agricultural regions, the pattern of
                            cropping may be different from one event to another. These varying
                            catchment conditions may be considered in the individual calibration
                            events, but they then need to be generalised for the design application.
                            There are questions concerning how this is implemented. For example,
                            sugar cane agriculture has areas of very high floodplain roughness in
                            some locations and areas of fallow ground in other parts. These patterns
                            vary from year to year and are difficult to determine for historic
                            events. There is a question of the “average” conditions that should
                            apply for the design application. A common approach is to adopt an
                            average value of two very different conditions and then carry out some
                            sensitivity tests to assess the impact of changes in the pattern of
                            agriculture.</para>
                     <para> Similarly in arid areas, the antecedent conditions may have a major
                            impact on catchment conditions for individual flood events, but these
                            conditions then need to be represented in the design situation.</para>
              </section>
              <section>
                     <title>Applied Parameters</title>
                     <para>Calibration usually works with historic flood events while the design
                            requirements are for probabilistic events. The parameters calculated for
                            the historic recorded flood events may not be applicable to the design
                            flood events and the results may not be consistent.</para>
                     <para>It is therefore important to confirm the model performance with
                            probabilistic results. For situations where sufficient streamflow
                            gauging is available, the model parameters can be confirmed using the
                            Flood Frequency Analysis results to confirm that the model is
                            representing the probabilistic flood discharges. Where there is
                            insufficient streamflow records for a Flood Frequency Analysis, the
                            model can be cross checked with a regional flood frequency results
                                   (<xref linkend="b3_ch3"/>). Similarly, the model output can be
                            confirmed with other anecdotal data, to confirm that the parameters are
                            appropriate for the design application.</para>
                     <para> When applying hydrologic and hydraulic models to design situations,
                            there are additional details that add complexity to the process. Often
                            the historic floods are calibrated to the conditions that apply when the
                            flood event occurred, so there are set values for antecedent conditions,
                            losses, baseflow and the particular conditions that applied in the
                            event, such as spatial or temporal patterns of rainfall. These
                            additional factors are often not a part of the calibration process but
                            must be incorporated into the design conditions.</para>
              </section>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>The ARR Data Hub</title>
              <para>The ARR Data Hub holds the design input data required for the application of ARR
                     for design flood estimation. By inputting catchment centroid or a shape file
                     you can download: the River basin, long duration ARF, Short duration ARF, storm
                     loss value, pre-burst and temporal patterns.
                     Entering<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190502T143454+1000"?>
                     the<?oxy_insert_end?> catchment
                     outlet<?oxy_insert_start author="testoni" timestamp="20190502T143459+1000"?>
                     location<?oxy_insert_end?> allows the practitioner to download baseflow
                     factors. As the data underlying ARR will progressively change as new data and
                     techniques are available practitioners are recommended to visit the data hub at
                     the start of each project <link xlink:href="Http://data.arr.org.au"
                            >http://data.arr.org.au</link>. The data can be downloaded as a text
                     file and included as an appendix to a project report. </para>
       </section>
</chapter>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>