<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter status="External Review" version="5.0" xml:id="b9_ch8"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
      <title>Safety Design Criteria</title>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/smith_grantley.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="../../common/authors/cox_ron.xml"/>
      
  </info>
  <informaltable border="1">
    <tr>
      <td colspan="2">Chapter Status</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Date last updated</td>
      <td>06/07/16 </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Content</td>
      <td>Advanced draft</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>General</td>
      <td>Subject to industry feedback </td>
    </tr>
  </informaltable>

  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_ot4c5">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>The safety of people in floods is of major concern in floodplain management for both rural
      and urban areas. Consideration of the circumstances for individual flood fatalities, both in
      Australia and internationally, indicates that flood fatalities occur most commonly when people
      enter floodwaters either on foot or in a vehicle
        <citation>b6_c7_r9,b6_c7_r5,b6_c7_r11</citation>. However, where floodwaters rise rapidly
      and unexpectedly in flash flood areas, people may also perish trapped inside buildings as
      occurred in the Lockyer Valley QLD in 2010 <citation>b6_c7_r21</citation> and in Dungog, NSW
      in 2015. Further, recent analysis of the Queensland floods in 2011 by the Queensland
      Commission for Children, Young People, and Child Guardian <citation>b6_c7_r14</citation> and
      the Queensland Fire and Rescue Service, 2012 has reinforced the conclusion that floodwaters
      are extremely dangerous to both people trapped inside building or wading or driving vehicles
      of all types in floods. While floodplain management activities aim to reduce the risk arising
      from flooding events, ongoing human interaction with floodwaters during flood events is
      largely unavoidable, as significant areas of existing development and transport infrastructure
      in Australia remain within flood prone regions.</para>
    <para>Records for past floods show that exposure of the community to flooding can result in
      significant death tolls and 1859 flood fatalities have occurred nationally between 1900 and
      2015 <citation>b6_c7_r11</citation>. Flood fatalities are significantly higher in flash flood
      events with rapidly rising violent flood flows than in comparably slower rising and moving
      riverine flooding. Two hundred and six (206) flash flood fatalities occurred in Australia
      between 1950 and March 2008 <citation>b6_c7_r5</citation>. The cause of death for the majority
      of these cases was drowning. Other fatalities were a result of heart attacks or overexertion,
      or indirect causes such as electrocution or fallen trees <citation>b6_c7_r5</citation>.
      Similarities have been observed in the United States, where 93 % of flash flood deaths can be
      attributed to drowning <citation>b6_c7_r9</citation>. Details about the activity of flash
      flood victims immediately prior to death are available for just under 50 % of the victims. Of
      these, almost 53 % perished attempting to cross a watercourse, either by wading/swimming, or
      by using a bridge or ford <citation>b6_c7_r5</citation>. These values include those in
      vehicles. The motivation behind the activity leading to the death was known for 47 % of the
      study group. Of these, almost 22 % were undertaking business as usual, either attempting to
      reach a destination, ignoring the flood warnings or unaware of the flood intensity
        <citation>b6_c7_r5</citation>.</para>
    <para>The majority (31 %) of the Australian flash flood fatalities, for which the mode of
      transport is known, were inside a vehicle at the time of death. Similar results have been
      observed around the world, 42 % of the 93 % US flash flood drowning fatalities were
      vehicle-related <citation>b6_c7_r9</citation> and 63 % of US riverine and flash flood
      fatalities were found to be vehicle-related <citation>b6_c7_r19</citation>.
        <citation>b6_c7_r23+1</citation> noted that vehicle-related fatalities occurred most
      frequently (33 %) in European and US floods.</para>
    <para>The Lockyer Valley floods of January 2011 dramatically demonstrated that sheltering in a
      residential building was also not a safe option where flood flows have high force and damage
      potential. Of the nineteen people who perished in the Lockyer Valley floods, thirteen were
      sheltering in buildings that were either completely inundated or collapsed under the force of
      the flood flows <citation>b6_c7_r21</citation>.</para>
    <para>Regardless, the high numbers of people that die in vehicles or on foot highlights the
      considerable risk in fleeing flash flood events. In many cases, people become exposed to
      greater risk when attempting to flee a flood affected area
        <citation>b6_c7_r19,b6_c7_r20,b6_c7_r27,b6_c7_r23</citation>. The risks to those fleeing are
      not just the floodwaters themselves, but also include poor driving conditions, the danger of
      being hit by falling debris, electrocution from fallen power lines, lightning and mudslides
        <citation>b6_c7_r11</citation>.</para>
    <para>Whilst evacuation is generally considered the safest of emergency management options
      during flood events, it is not always possible. Subsequently, it is an important aspect of
      emergency planning to ensure that in flood prone locations where timely evacuation may not be
      possible people will not be in greater danger remaining in their homes.</para>
    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
    <para><?oxy_custom_end?><citation>b6_c7_r23+1</citation> highlighted that in most floods, people
      are more likely to be killed or injured if they are outside of their home or in their cars
      during the flood. Subsequently, undertaking evacuation at inappropriate times, such as when
      the floodwaters have risen in depth and velocity, is likely to increase chance of death
        <citation>b6_c7_33</citation>.</para>
    <para>Sound floodplain management and emergency planning requires identification of the
      location, timing and duration of potentially hazardous floodplain areas for design flood
      conditions and the careful assessment of the most suitable mitigation options taking into
      consideration the specifics of each floodplain location. The intention of this chapter of
      Australian Rainfall and Runoff is to provide background information and guidance on the
      application of approaches for prediction of flood hazard in those locations; additional
      background information can be obtained from <citation>b6_c7_r7+1</citation>,
        <citation>b6_c7_r16+1</citation> and <citation>b6_c7_r18+1</citation>. Note that while
      guidance is provided on predicting the flood hazard and flood risk, it is the role of the
      relevant floodplain management authority to define the acceptability or otherwise of the
      predicted risk.</para>
    <para>A detailed discussion of risk with respect to floodplain management is presented in <xref
        linkend="b1_ch5"/> of Australian Rainfall and Runoff.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_4h86s">
    <title>Flood Hazard</title>

    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_hjt53">
      <title>General Introduction</title>
      <para>In terms of floodplain management, hazard can be defined as a source of potential harm
        or a situation with potential to result in loss. Hence, the primary hazard is the result of
        a flood event that has the potential to cause damage or harm to the community. Associated
        with the hazard is the probability of its occurrence. </para>
      <para>There are a number of factors to be considered where assessing the hazard associated
        with floods. The usual starting point is to predict the flood characteristics and
        particularly the flow characteristics of the inundated areas of the floodplain. The main
        characteristics of interest typically are the flow depth and the flow velocity. In addition,
        the assessment of the flood hazard needs to consider a range of other social, economic and
        environmental factors, though these are often more difficult to quantify.</para>
      <para>The magnitude of flood hazard can be variously influenced by the following
        factors:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Velocity of Floodwaters;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Depth of Floodwaters;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Combination of Velocity and Depth of Floodwaters;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Isolation During a Flood;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Effective Warning Time; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Rate of Rise of Floodwater;</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>When quantifying and classifying flood hazard, it is important to understand the
        underlying causes of the hazard level. For example, if the hazard level is classified as
        ‘high’ then it is important to understand the key reason that it is high e.g. high depth,
        high velocity, high velocity and depth in combination, isolation issues, short warning time?
        If the core reasons that the hazard is high are not well understood, then attempts to modify
        and lower the hazard level may not be successful.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_o75fx">
      <title>Flood Hazard Assessment</title>

      <para>The base data that underpins assessment of floodplain risk typically comprises the flow
        characteristics (the flow depth and velocity) in the flood-affected areas of the catchment.
        A common approach to obtaining this information is the analysis of predictions obtained from
        catchment numerical modelling systems although physical models of the flood affected area
        may be used. More information on the application of catchment modelling systems is presented
        in <xref linkend="book4"/> to <xref linkend="book7"/> of Australian Rainfall and
        Runoff.</para>

      <para>The data used for assessment of the floodplain hazard are
      presented commonly as maps of flood depth (see <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.1"/>) and flood velocity (speed and direction).
      Typically, these maps are shown as an envelope of maxima; a time series
      of flow behaviour, however, is an alternative presentation
      format.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.1">
        <title>Example of a Flood Study Depth Map (<citation>b6_c7_r17+1</citation>)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="384" fileref="../../figures/9001.bmp"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para><citation>b6_c7_r17+1</citation> investigated the effects of alternative grid
        resolutions on prediction of the flood hazard. The predicted flood hazard (computed as D.V –
        flood depth times flood velocity) for two model grid resolutions, namely 1m and 10m, for the
        2007 flood event at Merewether, NSW are shown in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.2"/>. Comparing
        the predicted flood hazard estimates, it can be seen that those derived using the 1m grid
        are higher than those obtained with the 10m grid. Furthermore,
          <citation>b6_c7_r17+1</citation> report that the predicted velocity and depth
        characteristics for the 1m grid more closely replicated those obtained from a physical model
        of the same area.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.2">
        <title>Comparison of Provisional Flood Hazard Estimates from Numerical
        Models at Differing Grid Resolutions (after Smith and Wasko,
        2012)</title>



        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/9002.png"
                       scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
        <para>a) 1 m grid resolution b) 10 m grid resolution</para>
      <para>An important conclusion of <citation>b6_c7_r17+1</citation> was that predictions from 2D
        numerical hydrodynamic models require further interpretation in order to ensure that
        suitable, representative flood behaviour information was obtained for application,
        especially in emergency planning and management decisions.</para>
      <para>As described in the introduction to this chapter, people tend to be at risk in one of
        three main categories; on foot, in vehicles or in buildings. Subsequently, in order to
        further assess the vulnerability of a flood under the predicted conditions, flood hazard
        assessment can be divided into three categories; people stability, vehicle stability and
        structural stability.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_44z8a">
      <title>People Stability</title>

      <para>The two recognised hydrodynamic mechanisms by which people may lose stability in flood
        flows are <emphasis>moment instability </emphasis>and <emphasis>friction
          instability</emphasis> (<xref linkend="figure_9.6.3"/>). A summary description of these
        mechanisms is provided here based on the comprehensive discussion of the topic presented in
          <citation>b6_c7_r7+1</citation>.</para>

      <para>In brief, moment (toppling) instability occurs when a moment induced by the oncoming
        flow exceeds the resisting moment generated by the weight of the body
          <citation>b6_c7_r1</citation>. This stability parameter is sensitive to the buoyancy of a
        person within the flow and to body positioning and weight distribution.</para>

      <para>Frictional (sliding) instability occurs when the drag force
      induced by the horizontal flow impacting on a person’s legs and torso is
      larger than the frictional resistance between a person’s feet and the
      ground surface. This stability parameter is sensitive to weight and
      buoyancy, clothing type, footwear type and ground surface
      conditions.</para>

      <para>Additionally, loss of stability may also be triggered by adverse
      conditions, which should be taken into account when assessing safety
      such as:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Bottom conditions:</emphasis> uneven,
          slippery, obstacles;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Flow conditions:</emphasis> floating
          debris, low temperature, poor visibility, unsteady flow and flow
          aeration;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Human subject:</emphasis> standing or
          moving, experience and training, clothing and footwear, physical
          attributes additional to height and mass including muscular
          development and/or other disability, psychological factors;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Other issues:</emphasis> strong wind,
          poor lighting, etc.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.3">
        <title>Typical Modes of Human Instability in Floods <citation>b6_c7_r7</citation></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="294" fileref="../../figures/9003.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Determining safety criteria for people requires an understanding of the physical
        characteristics of the subjects along with the nature of the flow. The best measure of
        physical attributes for human stability is the parameter H.M (mkg), the product of subject
        height (H; m) and mass (M; kg) <citation>b6_c7_r7</citation>. The measure of flow attributes
        is the parameter D.V (m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>), the
        product of flow depth (D, m) and flow velocity (V, ms<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para>While distinct relationships exist between a subject’s height and
      mass and the tolerable flow value, definition of general flood flow
      safety guidelines according to this relationship is not considered
      practical given the wide range in such characteristics within the
      population.</para>

      <para>In order to define safety limits, which are applicable for all persons, hazard regimes
        are defined based on H.M for representative population demographics. Each classification is
        based on laboratory testing of subject stability within floodwaters. The following suggested
        classifications, after <citation>b6_c7_r7+1</citation> are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Adults, where H.M &gt; 50 mkg;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Children, where H.M is between 25 and 50 mkg; and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Infants and very young children, where H.M &lt; 25 mkg.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Several hazard regimes are recommended based on D.V flow values
      for each H.M classification. The hazard regimes, as suggested from
      laboratory testing of subject stability and response within variable
      flow conditions, are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Low hazard zones where D.V &lt; 0.4
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          children and D.V &lt; 0.6
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          adults;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A Significant hazard zone for children exists where flow
          conditions are dangerous to most between D.V = 0.4 to 0.6
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Moderate hazard zone where conditions are dangerous for some
          adults and all children is defined between D.V = 0.6 to 0.8
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> for
          adults. This is inferred to define the limiting working flow for
          experienced personnel such as trained rescue workers;</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Significant hazard zone where flow conditions are dangerous to
          most adults and extremely dangerous for all children is suggested
          between flow values of D.V = 0.8 to 1.2
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>;
          and</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Extreme hazard where flow conditions are dangerous to all
          people is suggested for D.V &gt; 1.2
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para><citation>b6_c7_r7+1</citation> concluded that self-evacuation of the most vulnerable
        people in the community (typically small children, and the elderly) is limited to relatively
        placid flow conditions. Furthermore, a D.V as low as 0.4
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> would prove problematic for
        people in this category, i.e. the more vulnerable in the community.</para>

      <para>These hazard regimes for tolerable flow conditions (D.V) as
      related to the individual’s physical characteristics (H.M) are presented
      in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.4"/> and <xref
      linkend="table_9.6.1"/>.</para>

      <table frame="box" rules="all" xml:id="table_9.6.1">
        <caption>Flow Hazard Regimes for People <citation>b6_c7_r7</citation></caption>

        <thead>
          <tr align="center">
            <th>DV
            (m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</th>

            <th>Children (H.M = 25 to 50)<superscript>1</superscript></th>

            <th>Adults (H.M &gt; 50)</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <th>0</th>

            <td>Safe</td>

            <td>Safe</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0 - 0.4</th>

            <td>Low Hazard if depth &lt; 0.5m and velocity &lt; 3m/s otherwise
            Extreme Hazard</td>

            <td rowspan="2">Low Hazard if depth &lt; 1.2m and velocity &lt;
            3m/s otherwise Extreme Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0.4 - 0.6</th>

            <td>Significant Hazard; Dangerous to most if depth &lt; 0.5m and
            velocity &lt; 3m/s otherwise Extreme Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0.6 - 0.8</th>

            <td rowspan="3">Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</td>

            <td>Moderate Hazard; Dangerous to some<superscript>2</superscript>
            if depth &lt; 1.2m and velocity &lt; 3m/s otherwise Extreme
            Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>0.8 - 1.2</th>

            <td>Significant Hazard; Dangerous to
            most<superscript>3</superscript> if depth &lt; 1.2m and velocity
            &lt; 3m/s otherwise Extreme Hazard</td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <th>&gt; 1.2</th>

            <td>Extreme Hazard; Dangerous to all</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Maximum depth stability limit of 0.5 m for
      children and 1.2 m</emphasis> for adults under good condition. <emphasis
      role="bold">Maximum velocity stability limit of 3.0
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript> </emphasis>for both adults and
      children.</para>

      <para><superscript>1</superscript>More vulnerable community members such
      as infants and the elderly should avoid exposure to floodwater. Flood
      flows are considered extremely hazardous to these community members
      under all conditions</para>

      <para><superscript>2</superscript>Working limit for trained safety
      workers or experienced and well equipped persons (D.V &lt; 0.8
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para><superscript>3</superscript>Upper limit of stability observed
      during most investigations (D.V &gt; 1.2
      m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.4">
        <title>Safety Criteria for People in Variable Flow Conditions
            <citation>b6_c7_r7+1</citation></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9004.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_aky0g">
        <title>Physical considerations</title>
        <para>There is a lack of test data for infants and very young children as well as
          frail/older persons <citation>b6_c7_r6</citation>. These populations are unlikely to be
          safe in any flow regimes and as such, care is required in locating aged care and
          retirement villages as well as childcare centres and kindergartens.</para>
        <para>For physically and/or mentally disabled people, similar intolerance criteria to the
          very young children and frail/older persons should be applied as subjects are considered
          vulnerable to all flow values. This is because while the H.M values may be similar to
          regular adults, they are clearly at a physical (e.g. muscular development, control of
          limbs) and/or psychological disadvantage (e.g. cognisant of the real/perceived danger,
          inability to cope with external stimulus).</para>
        <para>Emergency personnel tasked with carrying evacuees should be aware that the additional
          H.M gained by carrying a person is not necessarily a benefit to their stability. This was
          demonstrated in a particular laboratory test of human stability criteria,
            <citation>b6_c7_r12+1</citation>, who note that their test subject (a trained stuntman)
          considered balancing in the flowing water more difficult when carrying extra weight such
          as a child or elderly person.</para>
        <para>It should also be noted that while these criteria are based on experimental data for
          loss of stability for persons wading in floodwaters, it is also inherently dangerous to
          swim through floodwaters. Swimming through floodwaters should not be attempted.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_7rcjc">
        <title>Psychological/behavioural considerations</title>

        <para>A person’s ability to withstand flood flows is affected by their
        mental disposition, perception, specific training and
        experience.</para>

        <para>Where specific training has been undertaken or a subject has recent and relevant
          experience, personnel are able to tolerate situations of high D.V
            <citation>b6_c7_r12</citation>. A limiting working flow of D.V = 0.8
            m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> is suggested for experienced
          personnel such as trained rescue workers. These personnel should, where possible, be
          equipped for dangerous flow conditions with safety restraints, floatation aids and other
          safety apparatus, and be trained to cope with high D.V situations. It is trained emergency
          personnel who are likely to be instructing, driving and guiding evacuation paths, and
          consequently to whom the upper limit of safety design criteria is directed.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_mzrum">
      <title>Vehicle stability</title>

      <para>The two recognised hydrodynamic mechanisms by which stability of vehicles is lost
        include <emphasis>buoyancy</emphasis> or <emphasis>floating</emphasis> and
          <emphasis>friction instability or sliding instability</emphasis> (refer <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.5"/>). More comprehensive discussion is presented within
          <citation>b6_c7_r16+1</citation> but briefly, vehicle floating instability occurs when the
        upward buoyancy force exceeds the downward force exerted by the vehicle mass. This
        instability is dominant in low velocity, high depth flows. Frictional or sliding instability
        occurs when the horizontal force exerted on one or more car panels is greater than the
        vertical restoring force, which is dependent on the vehicle mass, buoyancy and the friction
        between the car tyres and road surface.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.5">
        <title>Typical Modes of Vehicle Instability <citation>b6_c7_r16</citation></title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="414" fileref="../../figures/9005.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Note that in the context of this discussion <emphasis>friction
      instability</emphasis> is associated with slow moving or stationary cars
      as distinct to <emphasis>hydroplaning</emphasis>, which occurs when a
      vehicle at high speed encounters very shallow, evenly distributed water
      covering a road, typically a highway or freeway. Hydroplaning is not
      considered further within this report.</para>

      <para>Determining safety criteria for vehicles requires an understanding
      of the physical characteristics of the vehicle along with the nature of
      the flow.</para>

      <para>The measure of physical attributes for vehicle stability analysis
      is the vehicle classification as based on length (L, m), kerb weight (W,
      kg) and ground clearance (GC, m). Three vehicle classifications are
      suggested:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger: L &lt; 4.3 m, W &lt; 1250 kg, GC &lt; 0.12
          m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger: L &gt; 4.3 m, W &gt; 1250 kg, GC &gt; 0.12
          m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD: L &gt; 4.5 m, W &gt; 2000 kg, GC &gt; 0.22 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The measure of flow attributes for vehicle stability analysis is
      D.V m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>,
      determined as the product of flow depth (D, m) and flow velocity (V,
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript>)</para>

      <para>Limiting conditions exist for each classification based on limited
      laboratory testing of characteristic vehicles. The upper tolerable
      velocity for moving water is defined based on the frictional limits, and
      is a constant 3.0 ms<superscript>-1</superscript> for all vehicle
      classifications.</para>

      <para>The upper tolerable depths within still water are defined by the
      floating limits:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger vehicles: 0.3 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger vehicles: 0.4 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD vehicles: 0.5 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The upper tolerable depths within high velocity water (at 3.0
      ms<superscript>-1</superscript>) are defined by the frictional
      limits:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Small passenger vehicles: 0.1 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large passenger vehicles: 0.15 m</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Large 4WD vehicles: 0.2 m</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>While specifically equipped vehicles may remain stable in water of
      greater depths, the intention of the presented criteria is to focus on
      the more vulnerable of typical vehicle types in common use.</para>

      <para>Note that for all flow conditions in all vehicle classes, <emphasis>the proposed vehicle
          safety criteria remain below the moderate hazard criteria for adults</emphasis>
        <citation>b6_c7_r7</citation>. This ensures that adults occupying vehicles are, in
        principle, safe if exiting a vehicle in floodwaters with attributes within the specified
        hazard ranges.</para>

      <para>During flood events, the majority of flood deaths are vehicle related, more than half of
        all deaths during floods in the United States are vehicular-related
          <citation>b6_c7_r10</citation>. Regardless of how often people see the power of water in
        flash floods or are notified through community advertising that driving through high water
        is dangerous, there remain sections of the community who will continue with ‘business as
        usual’ irrespective of the flooding conditions <citation>b6_c7_r10</citation>.</para>

      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_vqhqr">
        <title>Vehicle Modernisation and Scale</title>

        <para>A limiting aspect of the advice provided in this report is that vehicle stability data
          sets are limited to dated laboratory data <citation>b6_c7_r16</citation>. The properties
          of contemporary vehicles have significantly changed vehicle stability criteria through
          modified buoyancy properties (e.g. improve dust sealing), weight and ground clearance.
          These changes apply to all scales of vehicles from small passenger to large commercial
          vehicles.</para>

        <para>As a result, the hazard criteria provided in this report are
        identified as interim recommended limits based on interpretation of
        existing information. The criteria presented here are subject to
        change once acceptable data for modern vehicles becomes
        available.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_dg43w">
        <title>Stability Criteria for Vehicles</title>

        <para>Stability criteria based on the best available information for
        stationary small passenger cars, large passenger cars and large 4WD
        vehicles in various flow situations are presented in <xref
        linkend="figure_9.6.6"/> and <xref linkend="table_9.6.2"/>.</para>

        <table xml:id="table_9.6.2">
          <title>Interim Flow Hazard Regimes for Vehicles <citation>b6_c7_r16</citation></title>

          <tgroup cols="8">
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Class of vehicle</entry>

                <entry>Length (m)</entry>

                <entry>Kerb Weight (kg)</entry>

                <entry>Ground clearance (m)</entry>

                <entry>Limiting still water
                depth<superscript>1</superscript></entry>

                <entry>Limiting high velocity flow
                depth<superscript>2</superscript></entry>

                <entry>Limiting velocity<superscript>3</superscript></entry>

                <entry>Equation of stability</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Small passenger</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 4.3</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 1250</entry>

                <entry>&lt; 0.12</entry>

                <entry>0.3</entry>

                <entry>0.1</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry><emphasis>DV</emphasis> ≤ 0.3</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Large passenger</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 4.3</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 1250</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 0.12</entry>

                <entry>0.4</entry>

                <entry>0.15</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry><emphasis>DV</emphasis> ≤ 0.45</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Large 4WD</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 4.5</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 2000</entry>

                <entry>&gt; 0.22</entry>

                <entry>0.5</entry>

                <entry>0.2</entry>

                <entry>3.0</entry>

                <entry><emphasis>DV</emphasis> ≤ 0.6</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>

        <para><superscript>1</superscript>At velocity = 0
        ms<superscript>-1</superscript>; <superscript>2</superscript>At
        velocity = 3.0 ms<superscript>-1</superscript>;
        <superscript>3</superscript>At low depth</para>

        <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.6">
          <title>Interim Safety Criteria for Vehicles in Variable Flow Conditions
              <citation>b6_c7_r16</citation></title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9006.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><citation>b6_c7_r16+1</citation> concludes that the available datasets do not
          adequately account for the following factors and that more research is needed in these
          areas:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Friction coefficients for contemporary vehicle tyres in
            flood flows;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Buoyancy changes in modern cars;</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The effect of vehicle orientation to flow direction
            (including vehicle movement);</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Information for additional categories including small and
            large commercial vehicles and emergency service vehicles</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Building Stability</title>
      <para>A comprehensive summary of available literature describing the stability of buildings in
        floodwaters is provided in <citation>b6_c7_r18+1</citation>. Numerous hazard threshold
        curves for building were collated from international literature and are compared in <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.6"/>. The collated curves have a variety of origins. As discussed by
          <citation>b6_c7_r28</citation>, it can be difficult to synthesise the different building
        stability curves and associated data, as they are derived by various means of analysis.
        Subsequently, comparison between theory based curves, (e.g.
        <citation>b6_c7_r24+1</citation>; <citation>b6_c7_r31+1</citation>) field derived curves
        (e.g. <citation>b6_c7_r25+1</citation>) and curves derived from modelling and analysis
        (<?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>e.g. Becker<emphasis
          role="italic"> et al.</emphasis>, 2011<?oxy_custom_end?>) is difficult. Further, different
        damage thresholds may apply for each of these curves e.g. some threshold curves presented
        represent the initiation of structural damage, while others represent the flood conditions
        for complete destruction of the building. The spread of curves in <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.6"/> highlights the overall uncertainty surrounding building stability
        during flood events.</para>
      <para>Investigation and review of the available information concerning the failure of building
        structures under flood loads has also been conducted by <citation>b6_c7_r26+1</citation> and
          <citation>b6_c7_r28</citation>. Amongst a range of relevant conclusions, these reviews
        noted that while a series of studies had theoretically analysed incident flood forces
        compared to the resisting strength of various building structures, most of these studies had
        considered components of flood forces in isolation or in limited combinations e.g.
        hydrostatic and simplified hydrodynamic (velocity head) or buoyancy and drag forces.</para>
      
        <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.61">         
          <title>Comparison of Building Stability Curves</title>
          <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6117.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      
      <para>While the considerable variability in building construction is acknowledged, the
        analysis of building damage leading to collapse reported by
          <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Mason<emphasis
          role="italic"> et al.</emphasis>, (2012) <?oxy_custom_end?>for the Lockyer Valley floods
        in January 2010 is compelling. This analysis shows that buildings constructed for Australian
        conditions are vulnerable to damage and collapse under flood hazard conditions at the lower
        end of the scale presented in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.6"/>.</para>
      <para>On this basis, the green curve in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.6"/> is proposed as a lower
        threshold for residential homes, built without consideration of flood forces. This curve can
        be used as a minimum criterion for building stability in existing flood affected
        areas.</para>
      <para>The hazard zone between the green curve and the upper limit red curve in <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.6"/> identifies flood hazard conditions where it is considered, if
        required, possible to construct a purpose built structure that is an appropriately
        engineered structure specifically designed to withstand the full range of anticipated flood
        forces including:</para>
      <para> </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Hydrostatic forces </emphasis></para>
          <para>resulting from standing water or slow moving flow around the structure;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Buoyant forces </emphasis></para>
          <para>due to displaced volume of water;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Hydrodynamic forces</emphasis></para>
          <para> arising from moderate-to-high-velocity water flow around the structure;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Impulsive Forces</emphasis></para>
          <para>caused by the leading edge of the water impacting the structure;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Uplift forces</emphasis></para>
          <para> on elevated floors of a structure that are submerged during a flood event;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Debris Impact Forces </emphasis></para>
          <para>generated by floating debris colliding with the structure;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Damming of Waterborne Debris </emphasis></para>
          <para>due to the accumulation of debris on the upstream side of the structure, which
            results in an increase in the hydrodynamic force.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Wave actions </emphasis></para>
          <para>from wind and wakes; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Erosion and Scour </emphasis></para>
          <para>due to flood actions.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>In locations where timely evacuation is not possible, such purpose built structures may
        be required for vertical evacuation, not dissimilar to the process used in Japan for
        tsunamis. However, it would be important to ensure the structure was purpose built for the
        conditions it would be likely to encounter, up to and including the PMF or a similar extreme
        flood event. The bottom floor of such structures may need to be somewhat sacrificial during
        a flood event, for example, the windows and doors may ‘blow out’ under high flow conditions,
        however the building’s structural members will be required to remain intact.</para>
      <para>The red curve in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.6"/> is a suggested upper limit for all
        buildings. Buildings in areas classified with flood hazard above this threshold are
        considered vulnerable to collapse under these extreme flood conditions.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title/>
      <para>Previous hazard classification curves (e.g.
          <citation>b6_c7_r30+1</citation>;<citation>b6_c7_r29+1</citation>) provided a single set
        of hazard curves that divide flood hazard levels into generic classifications of low,
        medium, high etc. While the thresholds between these classifications had some basis in data
        collected for stability/vulnerability of people and risk to life, in practice, such
        threshold curves have been widely interpreted (sometimes mis-interpreted) and applied in
        myriad ways.</para>
      <para>It is interesting to compare the curves summarised for people, vehicle and building
        stability compiled for this report. <xref linkend="figure_9.6.61"/> provides a direct
        comparison of these three sets of curves. The first observation to be made is that for slow
        moving floodwaters at depths greater than 0.5 m, adults wading through floodwater are
        generally considered more stable than vehicles i.e. in most cases, vehicles are equally
        unstable or more unstable than adults wading through the same flow conditions. Secondly, the
        stability limit for an untrained adult walking through floodwater (D x V = 0.8) is almost
        the same level as the lower threshold limit for building stability (D x V = 1.0). Also, that
        for shallow fast moving flows, building stability (through foundation erosion/scour) may be
        less than the stability of a person walking through the same flow conditions. In some
        situations, this means that you would be safer to walk out through the prevailing
        floodwaters rather than sheltering in a poorly constructed building.</para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.72">
        <title>Comparison of Updated Hazard Curves (after Smith et al. 2014)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6118.png"/>
          </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The third observation is that the flood water level that is used as the basis of a hazard
        depth varies between people and vehicle stability, where the flood depth is referenced to
        the ground level and building stability where the flood depth is nominally referenced to the
        floor level.</para>
      <para>On a practical level, this would mean that once physical flood behaviour has been
        quantified in terms of flood depth and velocity, flood hazard could be classified
        individually for people, vehicles or building thresholds separately. In many instances, this
        will suit the requirements of specific analyses. For example, if the required assessment is
        to determine whether a road evacuation route is trafficable for a given flood event, then
        the vehicle stability threshold curves should be applied. Likewise, if the assessment is to
        determine which buildings would be suitable for shelter in place during a PMF event, then
        the building stability thresholds for flood hazard should be used in the analysis.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>General Flood Hazard Curves</title>
      <para>When dealing with specific floodplain management or emergency management analysis there
        may be a clear need to use specific thresholds as described above. However, particularly in
        a preliminary assessment of risks or as part of a constraints analysis such as might be
        applied as part of a strategic floodplain management assessment, there is also an
        acknowledged need for a combined set of hazard vulnerability curves, which can be used as a
        general classification of flood hazard on a floodplain. A suggested set of curves based on
        the referenced thresholds presented above is provided in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.73"
        />.</para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.73">
        <title>Combined Flood Hazard Curves <citation>b6_c7_r18</citation></title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6119.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The combined flood hazard curves presented in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.73"/> set hazard
        thresholds that relate to the vulnerability of the community when interacting with
        floodwaters. The combined curves are divided into hazard classifications that relate to
        specific vulnerability thresholds as described in <xref linkend="table_9.6.21"/>. <xref
          linkend="table_9.6.4"/> provides the limits for the classifications in <xref
          linkend="table_9.6.21"/></para>
      <table xml:id="table_9.6.21" frame="all" >
        <title>Combined Hazard Curves - Vulnerability Thresholds
          <citation>b6_c7_r18</citation></title>
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry>Hazard Vulnerability Classification</entry>
              <entry>Description</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>H1</entry>
              <entry>Generally safe for vehicles, people and buildings.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H2</entry>
              <entry>Unsafe for small vehicles.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H3</entry>
              <entry>Unsafe for vehicles. children and the elderly.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H4</entry>
              <entry>Unsafe for vehicles and people.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H5</entry>
              <entry>Unsafe for vehicles and people. All buildings vulnerable to structural damage.
                Some less robust buildings subject to failure.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H6</entry>
              <entry>Unsafe for vehicles and people. All building types considered vulnerable to
                failure.</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table xml:id="table_9.6.4" frame="all">
        <title>Combined Hazard Curves - Vulnerability Thresholds Classification Limits
            <citation>b6_c7_r18</citation></title>
        <tgroup cols="4">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <colspec colname="newCol4" colnum="3" colwidth="1*"/>
          <colspec colname="newCol3" colnum="4" colwidth="1*"/>
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry>Hazard Vulnerability Classification</entry>
              <entry>Classification Limit (D and V in combination)</entry>
              <entry>Limiting Still Water Depth (D)</entry>
              <entry>Limiting Velocity (V)</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>H1</entry>
              <entry>D*V ≤ 0.3</entry>
              <entry>0.3</entry>
              <entry>2.0</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H2</entry>
              <entry>D*V ≤ 0.6</entry>
              <entry>0.5</entry>
              <entry>2.0</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H3</entry>
              <entry>D*V ≤ 0.6</entry>
              <entry>1.2</entry>
              <entry>2.0</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H4</entry>
              <entry>D*V ≤ 1.0</entry>
              <entry>2.0</entry>
              <entry>2.0</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H5</entry>
              <entry>D*V ≤ 4.0</entry>
              <entry>4.0</entry>
              <entry>4.0</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>H6</entry>
              <entry>D*V > 4.0</entry>
              <entry>-</entry>
              <entry>-</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <para>Importantly, the vulnerability thresholds identified in the flood hazard curves
        described above can be applied to the best description of flood behaviour available for a
        subject site. In this regard, the hazard curves can be applied equally to flood behaviour
        estimates from measured data, simpler 1D numerical modelling approaches, through to complex
        2D model estimates with the level of accuracy and uncertainty of the flood hazard estimate
        linked to the method used to derive the flood behaviour estimate.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Isolation, Effective Warning Time, Rate of Rise and Time of Day</title>
      <para>The effective warning time available to respond to a flood event, the rate of rise of
        floodwaters, the time of day a flood occurs, and isolation from safety by floodwaters and
        impassable terrain are all factors that may increase the potential for people to be exposed
        to hazardous flood situations. These factors are important considerations that influence the
        vulnerability of communities to flooding and are important considerations in managing flood
        risk.</para>
      <section>
        <title>Isolation</title>
        <para>As outlined in AEM Handbook 7 <citation>b6_c7_r4</citation>, flooding can isolate
          parts of the landscape and cut-off evacuation routes to flood-free land. This can result
          in dangerous situations, because people may see the need to cross floodwaters to access
          services, employment or family members. Many flood fatalities result from the interactions
          of people, often in vehicles, with floodwaters. Any situation that increases people’s need
          to cross floodwaters increases the likelihood of an injury or fatality. </para>
        <para>AEM Handbook 7 recommends that the floodplain be classified by precinct or community
          based on flood emergency response categories. This classification is separate to the
          quantification of hazard outlined in this guideline and is addressed in the complementary
            <emphasis role="italic">Technical Flood Risk Management Guideline on Flood Emergency
            Response Classification of the Floodplain</emphasis>. </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Effective Warning Time</title>
        <para>As outlined in of AEM Handbook 7, effective warning time is the time available for
          people to undertake appropriate actions, such as lifting or transporting belongings and
          evacuating.</para>
        <para>Lack of effective warning time can increase the potential for the exposure of people
          to hazardous flood situations. In contrast, having plenty of effective warning time
          provides the opportunity to reduce the exposure of people and their property to hazardous
          flood situations.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Rate of Rise</title>
        <para>Rate of rise of floodwaters is discussed in AEM Handbook 7. A rapid rate of rise can
          lead to people evacuating being overtaken or cut off by rising floodwaters. It is often
          associated with high velocities but it can be an issue if access routes are affected by
          flooding.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Time of Day</title>
        <para>The time of day influences where people are and what they are doing. This can
          influence their ability to receive any flood warnings and respond to a flood threat.
          Inability to receive and respond to a warning can increase the potential for people to be
          exposed to hazardous flood situations. </para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_9o464">
    <title>Examples of Hazard Assessment</title>
    <para>This section presents practical examples of the interpretation of flood hazard criteria in
      a floodplain management context. The examples are not intended to be a comprehensive analysis
      of all possible circumstances, but rather provide representative case studies, which
      illustrate practical interpretation of flood hazard criteria for floodplain planning and
      management.</para>

    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_ke4u8">
      <title>Example - Warehouse Car Park</title>
      <para>Flood behaviour quantification, including flood hazard analysis, is used to guide land
        use planning in floodplains <citation>b6_c7_r4</citation>. Often, a general, first pass
        assessment of flood hazard is required to provide floodplain planners the opportunity to
        have a general overview of the magnitude of flood hazard and potential flood risks over a
        floodplain. This type of preliminary assessment of risks might also be used as part of a
        constraints analysis for a strategic floodplain management assessment.</para>
      <para>Effective strategic land use planning is about responding to flood risks in a way that
        minimises future flood consequences. Consideration of flood hazard is therefore important so
        that development of land is encouraged in areas of low or no flood risk wherever possible. A
        clear understanding of flood risks early in the strategic land use planning process can help
        steer development away from areas that are not sustainable due to the likely impacts of the
        development on flood behaviour and guide land use zonings and development controls that
        support sustainable development on the floodplain in consideration of the flood risk</para>
      <para>The following figures provide both a broad-scale example of the base data (variation in
        velocity and depth across a floodplain) and hazard mapping that can be developed as a first
        pass using standard two dimensional numerical model outputs from a flood study analysis. The
        flood hazard mapping presented in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.1"/> was developed by
        classifying the numerical flood model results shown in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.74"/> using
        the flood hazard thresholds listed in <xref linkend="table_9.6.4"/>. </para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.74">
        <title>Flood Depth Map From Numerical Model Output (Courtesy WMAwater Pty Ltd)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6120.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.75">
        <title>Flood Hazard Classification From Numerical Model Output (Courtesy WMAwater Pty
          Ltd)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/6121.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Flood Mitigation - Warehouse Car Park</title>
      <para>A large multinational retailer has identified an existing industrial area in an inner
        city suburb as a suitable site for re-development as a warehouse-style retail outlet. The
        site is gently sloping from the northwest to the southeast and, having been previously
        prepared for development, is clear of vegetation. An aging, concrete-lined channel runs
        along the eastern side of the site.</para>
      <para>The retailer has submitted a development application, illustrated in <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.7"/>, “Schematic of Proposed Warehouse Development”, which
        conceptually has a warehouse building situated in the northwest corner of the site with the
        area between the building and the concrete-lined channel earmarked as a car park.</para>
 
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.7">
        <title>Schematic of Proposed Warehouse Development</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9007.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The local council as the consent authority has identified a series of development
        constraints including flooding criteria. Amongst other criteria, the development must
        have:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>All retail floor space above the designated flood planning level defined as the 1%
            Annual Exceedance Probability (AEP) flood surface plus 500 mm freeboard;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A flood free evacuation route for floods above the flood planning level; and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>All car park areas compliant with ARR flood hazard criteria for vehicle
            stability;</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>As there was no existing flood study, following consultation with Council, the developer
        engaged an experienced flood consultant to undertake flood modelling of the site to estimate
        1% AEP flood behaviour. Flood modelling of the site for the 1% AEP event completed using
        industry best practice guidance as provided by ARR reference “Two Dimensional Modelling in
        Urban and Rural Floodplains” <citation>b6_c7_r8</citation> predicted that while the
        warehouse building met the flood planning criteria, the car park was inundated by
        floodwaters. <xref linkend="figure_9.6.8"/> illustrates the extent of flood inundation for
        the existing site.</para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.8">
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth Map – Existing Site</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9008.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Interrogation of the flood model results to determine provisional flood hazard as the
        product of flood depth (D) multiplied by flood velocity (V) showed that the peak flood
        hazard (D.V) corresponded with the maximum inundation of the site at the peak of the flood
        hydrograph. Provisional flood hazard for the 1% AEP flood on the existing site as
        illustrated by <xref linkend="figure_9.6.9"/> showed that flooding in most of the area
        identified for car parking exceeds the ARR stability criteria for small cars defined in
          <xref linkend="table_9.6.2"/> and illustrated in <xref linkend="figure_9.6.6"/>. In <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.9"/>, areas coloured blue (D.V &lt;0.3
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript>) indicate locations where
        small cars are likely to resist being moved by flood flows, whereas areas coloured green
        through red indicate areas where small cars are very likely to be pushed across the
        floodplain by floodwaters, with the flow having the potential to move larger cars closer to
        the creek channel. Based on this information, Council’s preliminary advice to the developer
        was that the existing flood hazard conditions for the designated car parking area were
        incompatible with the nominated use.</para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.9">
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Existing Car Park</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9009.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>As the concrete lined channel had low environmental value, Council was not opposed to
        the developer’s proposed adjustment of the channel flow conveyance capacity to reduce the
        proportion of overbank flow at the site. The developer, in consultation with the flood
        consultant ran a range of cut and fill scenarios through the flood model aimed at expanding
        the channel capacity while raising the relative ground level of the car park to the flood
        peak. <xref linkend="figure_9.6.10"/> shows the adjustment of the channel and overbank area
        through the car park on the longitudinal section identified as ‘A-A’ in <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.7"/>.</para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.10">
        <title>Comparison of Car Park Cross Sections (A-A)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentdepth="100%" fileref="../../figures/9010.jpg" scalefit="1"
              width="100%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>This section is representative of a balance between the minimum volume of earthworks to
        meet the car parking capacity criteria for the development. The car park area adjacent to
        section A-A was graded to meet the natural surface areas outside of the development
        site.</para>
      <para>Flood modelling for the revised site including the proposed earthworks is presented in
          <xref linkend="figure_9.6.11"/>. The flood model results show that the site flood
        inundation area is significantly reduced with the works in place.</para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.11">
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth Map – Revised Car Park</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9011.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Importantly, analysis of the provisional flood hazard as presented in <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.12"/> shows that flood hazard for the area designated as car park in
        the conceptual site design now meets the ARR flood stability criteria for small vehicles.
        The nominated car park area has a D.V product of less than 0.3
          m<superscript>2</superscript>s<superscript>-1</superscript> as indicated by the blue
        shaded area of <xref linkend="figure_9.6.12"/>. This indicates that it is now unlikely that
        cars inundated by floodwaters in the 1% AEP flood will be pushed across the floodplain and
        potentially into the channel creating a possible downstream blockage hazard.</para>
      <para>Council’s planners also suggested to the developer that the yellow zone of <xref
          linkend="figure_9.6.12"/> could be landscaped as gardens providing clear separation of the
        car park from the channel. From a floodplain management perspective, this suggested change
        would provide a significant further reduction in exposure risk with little impact on
        available car parking space.</para>
      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.12">
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Revised Car Park</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9012.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_plnl6">
      <title>Example - Detention Basin</title>

      <para>Council’s conditions of consent for a proposed retirement village
      development require that on-site detention be provided so that peak
      flows from the site in floods up to the 1% AEP event remain similar to
      existing local runoff conditions.</para>

      <para>The developer considers that a centralised detention basin on the
      site can be designed to have a dual use and integrated into the site
      grounds as a bowling green when not operating as a detention basin.
      <xref linkend="figure_9.6.13"/> illustrates the proposed design.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.13">
        <title>1% AEP Flood Depth - Proposed Flood Detention Basin</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9013.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>As the catchment contributing runoff to the site is steep,
      Council’s flood expert considers that there is some risk in a dual
      purpose design for the basin due to flash flooding in prevailing
      thunderstorms. Council’s advice is that the developer engage a qualified
      flood expert to determine whether the basin meets the ARR hazard
      criteria for people safety.</para>

      <para>The basin design philosophy is that the local catchment stormwater
      will collect both overland flows and also surcharge from the pit and
      pipe stormwater system. If the basin capacity is exceeded, flows spill
      at a designated location and flow overland to the adjacent creek
      channel. Flows that remain in the basin discharge through a grated pit
      in the lowest location in the basin floor.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.14">
        <title>1% AEP Provisional Flood Hazard Map - Proposed Flood Detention
        Basin</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9014.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>An assessment of the provisional flood hazard (flood depth
      multiplied by the flood velocity) is presented in <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.14"/>. When compared to flood hazard criteria
      presented in <xref linkend="table_9.6.1"/> and <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.4"/>, the provisional hazard meets the safety
      criteria for the elderly in most areas of the basin. This is because at
      full capacity, the basin is no greater than 0.5m deep. Analysis shows
      that a dangerous flood hazard is likely to occur near to the basin’s
      outlet pit when the basin begins to drain at full capacity.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.15">
        <title>Basin Overflow Spillway – Flood Depth</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9015.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Further analysis of the full design presented in <xref
      linkend="figure_9.6.15"/> shows that when the basin capacity is exceeded
      overflows will cross a public footpath adjacent the creek reserve.
      Provisional flood hazard analysis of the overflow path presented in
      <xref linkend="figure_9.6.16"/> shows that the flood hazard in the flow
      path will exceed the people stability criteria for adults and be a
      dangerous hazard to passing pedestrians.</para>

      <figure xml:id="figure_9.6.16">
        <title>Provisional Flood Hazard Map – Basin Overflow Spillway</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../figures/9016.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>As a result of the analysis, Council consent criteria require signage to be placed in
        appropriate locations informing residents of the retirement village and the public passing
        the site on the public footpath of the dual purpose use of the basin and the danger of
        entering floodwaters when the basin is inundated. Further, Council’s consent criteria
        require that the developer upgrade the footpath to include a bridge of suitable span over
        the basin spillway flow path so that safe thoroughfare of the footpath can be maintained
        during flood conditions.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="b9_ch6_s_dcep5">
    <title>Conclusions and Recommendations</title>
    <para>Recent flood events on the east coast of Australia in 2010 and 2011 have highlighted that
      people continue to be exposed to dangerous and life threatening flow conditions in urban and
      rural floodplains. While floodplain management activities are continuing to mitigate problems
      associated the community’s exposure to floodwaters, ongoing human activity in floods is
      largely unavoidable while significant areas of existing development and transport
      infrastructure in Australia remain flood prone.</para>
    <para>This chapter of Australian Rainfall and Runoff presents a summary with an explanation of
      the limitations of recent analysis of flood stability thresholds for pedestrians and vehicles
      in floodwaters. Recommended flood hazard criteria for use within Australia based on the
      stability of people and vehicles in flood flows has also been presented.</para>
    <para>Finally, the presented examples illustrate practical applications of these flood hazard
      criteria. While not exhaustive of all cases, the examples show how the criteria can be
      pragmatically applied to reduce the community’s exposure to flood danger.</para>
  </section>

  
       <xi:include href="chap_refs.xml">
              <xi:fallback>
                     <para>No included references yet...</para>
              </xi:fallback>
       </xi:include>


</chapter>
